What's going on guys?
Super excited to get into this
video because we're getting into
the fun stuff, the actual sales
call itself, and it all starts
with discovery.
And before I get into this, I want
to stress the importance of
discovery because a lot of people
will just undermine it and be
like, okay, if I have a good
pitch, everything else is going to
work out.
Very, very, very false.
I can tell you personally, we have
eight closers and the majority of
our time in terms of ongoing
training is spent on the discovery
and then holding people
accountable at the end of the
call, closing, setting proper next
steps, follow up, as opposed to
the pitch.
And when it comes to holding
somebody accountable at the end of
the call to get the leverage that
we need to close, we're getting
that stuff inside of discovery.
So all that goes to say, pitch
itself, a lot of that is just
having a really good offer and
then putting time into creating a
good pitch once and then it's
pretty easy to replicate that on
an ongoing basis.
The discovery is usually what
people need to fine tune and
obviously having a structure like
this that's worked for us for over
thousands of calls is going to be
a huge, massive shortcut for you
guys.
So just if you're not familiar
with the process, the goal of
discovery, really the top half of
the call is to qualify the
prospect, understand their current
situation, what they're looking to
accomplish, create urgency and
gather ammo.
That's going to help you close
them.
Going back to video one on the
service driven mindset.
If we can help them, it's our duty
to close them.
That's our moral obligation to
close them.
Like I said earlier, having a good
pitch is not enough.
We need to have a bulletproof
discovery.
So let's talk about how to run a
successful discovery.
If you can, I almost always
recommend a one call close.
Now, just to cover that topic real
quick, the reason why is because
if we have them sat on a sales
call, I believe that most calls
can be closed in 30 minutes to an
hour.
And if we want to keep the slots
at 30 minutes to make it
attractive, even then you can
usually ask somebody, hey, do you
have a hard out at 930 if the call
is booked at 9 or do you have a
hard stop at 10 o'clock if the
call is booked at 930?
Usually when people say no, okay,
cool.
We've got 45 minutes.
We've got the whole hour.
And the reason why it's like,
okay, they're already there.
We're pitching to business owners.
Their time is valuable.
Time kills deals.
So just in having an extra sales
call, just in having more time
from when their excitement is
highest, which is typically when
they book in a call and when that
first pitch is heard, we want to
try to close them as quickly as
possible.
That's when we want to be making
the ask for the sale, because once
again, their excitement's the
highest at that point.
If you have a second call, more
time elapses, which goes against
us.
And also you're going to have the
call show rate for call one.
You're going to have the call show
rate for call two, and there's
going to be a drop off 100%,
right?
And there are some situations in
which you need a two call close.
So if you want to talk about that
more than happy to jam on it,
because for some offers, it just
makes plain sense.
But the majority of the time, if
you can do it, do one call close.
So this would be the first half of
the call, right?
It's generally like the first, I
would say, if we're booking out
and having a 30 minute sales call,
this is going to take up about 15
minutes.
I also want you to realize that
this, what I'm showing you here is
simply a structure.
I'm going to bounce into an actual
script throughout the video to
give you an idea as to what this
looks like.
But I think it's important to
teach you guys what each section
serves because it is a structure.
It's not a script as if you're an
actor, because if you try to stick
to that, you're always going to
fail because people are going to
knock you off your game almost
every single call.
It's like if I was an actor and I
had a script and the other person
didn't, it's going to be like,
holy shit, this is not making any
sense or just not going the way
that I intended it to.
Right.
So it's going to take turns and
that's okay.
This is simply the guide you can
refer back to up until you make
the pitch to make sure we're on
track and getting the information
we need.
That's it.
Right.
This is a checklist of sorts.
To know, okay, are we having a
productive conversation?
And two more things here real
quick.
One, we're going for quality of
information, not volume of
questions.
Super important concept.
Reason why is because for some
prospects, they kind of understand
what you're trying to do on this
call.
And they're going to be pretty
open with their situation.
So I may ask them one question.
I may ask them what motivated them
to book in a call and they may
rattle off the majority of stuff
that I need to understand their
situation, qualify them, get the
ammo I need to close them.
They already have clear urgency.
I don't need to go into each part
of the script then.
In fact, if I do, it's going to
rub them the wrong way just
because it's going to sound so
redundant.
Right.
They just gave me information.
And then for the sake of following
a quote unquote script, I'm going
to go into a part of the script
where I ask a question for
information I already gave us.
So we're going for quality of
information, which means
essentially a prospect could give
us all the information we need in
one question for others that are
super close to the chest.
They don't want to tell us
anything.
We may need to ask 15, 20, 30, 40
questions.
Right.
On that same note, we'd rather go
a mile deep than a mile wide in
discovery every single time.
And what I mean by that is once
again, this is a checklist.
So if you check all of the boxes,
good.
That's a bulletproof way to have a
successful discovery.
But if I check one quicker than
the other, that's completely fine.
Because if I have a prospect that
has a very clear issue that's
going to keep them from closing, I
want to dig into that.
And I'd rather go a mile deep on
that singular thing as opposed to
a mile wide to give you an
example.
Let's say somebody you're selling
cold email as a service and
somebody had a horrible experience
with another agency that also had
a performance based guarantee with
a cold email offer.
Like I need to go into what
actually happened there so I can
help this guy understand why we're
different and why this experience
would be different.
Because if I don't address that
and he's just kind of sitting on
the call, just super jaded the
whole time, like, well, last pitch
sound good.
Last agency I thought would work
and they screwed me over.
If we don't go deep on that
specific thing and dig into that
specific thing, none of the rest
just matters.
Same thing with a guy who's super
lackadaisical about his timeline,
who doesn't have any urgency.
It's very important that we go
into actually creating that
urgency, figuring out why his
timeline is like that, figuring
out if his own timeline is even
aligned with his goals.
Because most of the time it's not
reminding him of our timeline
versus his timeline, right?
He seems super lackadaisical on
the call, yet he wants to get
calls booked in the next three
weeks.
Which if you're running a cold
email offer, you kind of know if
somebody wants to book calls in
three weeks, they need to be
signed up yesterday, right?
And the second best time next to
yesterday would be today because
you have your onboarding process,
you have your warm-up process.
He's just not of the mindset,
right?
That's actually going to be
productive for his own goals.
Once again, we're trying to help
this person.
So I would need to go deep into
that timeline issue with this
person as opposed to being
hyper-obsessed with like making
sure I check every single box and
not going deep on that one thing.
So hopefully that all makes sense,
but let's get into it.
It all is going to start with
rapport.
It's not going to be something
that's super make or break for the
call, but just be a normal person.
You're going to be having a long
conversation with the person, so
we don't want them to feel like
it's going to be an awkward one
and shutting down before it
starts.
Nor should you be trying to be
their best friend.
Be respectful of them, their time,
jump into things.
Like I said, if you try to really
suck up and be somebody's friend
like too hard right off the bat,
it's going to come off as almost
ingenuine like, oh, here goes the
sales guy.
And then also it's going to come
off as a little subservient with,
you know, like I said on the last
video talking about status games
there.
People don't necessarily want to
work with people that are beneath
them.
They want to work with people that
are of equal or higher status.
So don't overthink it.
Don't be weird.
Keep it brief.
Jump into the call.
Now, it all starts with the
agenda.
Like it or not, we're leading
these prospects on the sales call.
So if we don't set the expectation
that this is going to be a
productive sales call, it's not
going to be.
If we're sleepwalking through the
sales call, they're going to
sleepwalk through the sales call.
If I don't want to be there,
they're not going to want to be
there.
Right.
So super important that we always,
always, always set an agenda.
Have one completely written out.
Like this is a part of the call
that can be scripted and should be
clean just because mentally it's
just going to get you off to a
nice little win.
All right, cool.
We checked that box.
We're off to a good start.
And trust me, you'd want to get
off to a good start versus
stumbling out of the gates every
single time.
But essentially what we're trying
to get off is there should be a
casual conversation about their
current efforts, what's working,
what's not, what they're looking
to accomplish.
And if it seems like, you know,
you can help, then you walk them
through what that would look like
to work with you or not.
No worries.
And you two are on the same team,
right?
Like I don't like the sales closer
mindset of like having to be like
icy cold and calling them a pussy.
And like, I mean, sometimes
there's, there's room for that
maybe at the very, very end of the
call.
But before that, like we want to
build up goodwill and we don't
want it to be a super awkward
conversation because that's going
to be draining for both of us.
We want it to feel like, yo, my
arms around you, we're going to be
talking about what you're looking
to accomplish, what you're trying
right now, what's working right
now.
If, if it seems like we know,
cool.
I'll walk you through how we can
get started on that today.
And if not, no worries, right?
Just give you an example of what
this would actually look like
here.
Just sort of thought, can't even
read.
Just start us off here.
These call the super casual.
I'll get some context on what you
guys do and specifically how your
business development lead gen is
currently operating.
If it seems like there's an
opportunity for us to make an
impact, I'll walk you through what
that would look like and see if it
makes sense for us to get this set
up today.
Today, right?
I mean, once again, like we're
leading these guys.
If we don't set the expectation
that this is going to be a one
call close, if all works out,
we're not likely to get a one call
close.
Fair enough.
Cool.
Jump into it.
We're on the next part.
Now, before diving into this call,
like really diving into it, we
just set the agenda.
I typically just ask them what
motivated them to book a call in
the first place.
Simple, but so, so, so effective.
I can't tell you how many times
I've seen somebody set the agenda
and then just go straight into
business background.
Hey, cool.
Tell me about the business.
Tell me what you guys do.
Tell me who you do it for.
Where you can get into a situation
with a talkative prospect where if
you do that first, five, ten
minutes go by, you have no idea
why they even signed up for the
call.
You have no idea what they're
looking to get out of this
meeting.
So, literally, just start off by
asking, and this is a great place
to ask a question because a lot of
times those prospects who kind of
been around the block and know
what to do, they'll tell you
exactly what they're looking for.
So, ask them, what problem are
they looking to fix?
Oftentimes, after that first
question, I'll get half the
information I need to know, like I
said here, if I'm going to be able
to help them and what that would
look like.
Also, get some talking, right?
And this is the first step in
making them feel heard.
One thing that's super important
to realize is that it's not enough
if we understand that there's a
problem.
They also have to understand their
So, discovery is about everything
I talked about up here, but it's
also about making them feel heard.
So, when we do make a pitch, it
doesn't feel like unsolicited
advice because people like getting
help from an expert, but nobody
likes getting unsolicited help
from anybody.
Whether it's a friend, like you're
kind of trying to vent to them
about your problems, and then all
of a sudden, it's like, yeah,
dude, I get it.
This is what you need to do.
It's like, dude, you need to hear
me out.
Or even an expert, like you go to
a doctor, you walk in there,
you've only explained one of your
symptoms, like you've got a sore
throat, but you also have a
massive headache that feels like
you're about to fucking pass out
because of it.
And he's like, yeah, bro, you got
strep.
Take these pills.
You're gonna make, what the fuck?
I didn't even get into things,
right?
So, super important that they're
gonna be felt, that they're gonna
feel like they've been heard
throughout.
So, that's why we get in the
background questions next, right?
Kind of like I said, people hate
getting advice from people they
feel like lack context.
So, it's important that we
understand their business, and
even more important that we make
them feel like we understand their
business, right?
Because that's one of the things,
it's like, I've been trying to fix
this fucking issue of not being
able to create content, of not
being able to get my lead
generation up.
So, when we come in and we just
say like, yeah, we can help with
that, it feels disingenuous.
But if we actually understand the
ins and outs of what they've done,
what they've tried, then that
pitch is gonna be welcome.
So, how are they framing their
offer to cold traffic?
How many clients do they have?
How does their pricing work?
What's their monthly revenue look
like?
Who's your ideal client?
There's a number of different
things here that are either going
to, one, qualify them to you, and
then two, at the very least,
gather information for us to be
able to close them at the end of
the call.
For example, let's say we charge
$3,000 a month.
I'm asking about their clients,
what's their average client
lifetime value, and their average
client lifetime value is $10,000.
I get that information.
It's pretty easy for me to make a
logical sales argument at the end
of the call that they should do
this because there's clear ROI if
they can sign even one client per
month, right?
So, that's where we're gonna be
gathering this information.
Current efforts, what are they
currently doing to accomplish X,
Y, Z?
Even if it's nothing, super
important to get that, right?
Because let's say, once again, I'm
selling lead generation.
Hey, what are you guys currently
doing to get new leads on
calendar?
Well, we're not doing anything at
the moment.
You guys aren't doing any type of
outbound or paid marketing?
No, not right now.
Oh, okay.
Just the tonality of what I said
that this person would be like,
oh, shit.
I've got an issue, right?
This is not normal, right?
Because once again, it's not
enough that we're problem aware.
They also need to be problem
aware.
So, what have they tried in the
past?
What are they looking into now?
Once again, like that example I
used earlier of if they were
burned by an agency before, super
important that we understand the
ins and outs of what actually went
down.
And what are they looking into
now?
I want to be able to understand
what I'm selling against.
It's all important stuff.
Then we want to go into
quantifying current efforts,
right?
If we can't get real clarity on
where they're at, it's very tough
to know if and how much we can
help this person.
So, like we talked about, these
people are generally trying to go
from A to B.
They're looking to make some sort
of transformation.
We need to understand what point A
is and exactly what point A is.
And the reason I said this, be
wary of ranges because even though
people, these people are looking
for help, they often don't want
things to seem as bad as they are
because they think it makes them
seem less competent.
I talked a lot about this in the
last video too, right?
So, when it comes to how many
calls you're getting on calendar,
we can't accept 10 to 15 calls.
That's not a real number, right?
Because then when I follow up,
like I should and ask, hey, like
how many calls exactly did you
guys get in the last 30 days?
It's so funny, but oftentimes when
they go and check, oh, we had
eight, which isn't even in 10 to
15.
And it gives me like a real clear
point A.
And they'll come up with excuses.
Oh, you know, it was a busy month
and I was traveling for a little
bit and this and that.
It's typically 10 to 15.
But yeah, last month it was eight.
Cool.
I have some of the anchor on,
right?
And I mean, the lower the bar is
for point A, the easier it is to
show them how much we could help
them.
And also them actually realizing,
oh shit, it was only eight.
That's going to be big once again
in terms of them realizing things
might be worse than I thought they
were.
And once again, just makes them
more problem aware.
So, now we got point A.
Let's find point B.
Find out exactly what they're
looking to accomplish.
If they don't have a solid answer,
lead them.
Once again, we're leading them on
this call, whether we like it or
not.
So, we might as well do a good job
of it.
Because, like I said, at this
point in the call, we understand
what point A looks like.
Now, we want to define what point
B looks like, even if they do not
know.
Because that will allow us to
pitch our service as a straightest
line from point A to point B.
And then it just becomes a game of
if they also believe that they can
get to their goals.
That this thing that you pitch as
the straight line from point A to
point B can actually act as you
pitched it.
Right?
And if it's yes, then it makes a
whole lot of sense to sign up for
your service.
Right?
So, pretty straightforward.
But I can't tell you the amount of
times where people are like, hey,
you know, so looking forward six
months, finishing up 2025 here.
Yeah, what are your goals?
Where do you want to be at?
And some of you are like, yeah,
well, you know, we want to grow.
We want to make more revenue.
You can't define that.
Right?
Like, we understand where they're
at right now.
Hey, okay, cool.
But you guys right now are at
eight calls a month.
Tell me, like, do you have a
specific goal in terms of a number
of calls you guys are looking to
get?
Like, a revenue number?
As a company, just trying to
figure out, like, what exactly is
the measurement of success that
would make you look back and say,
yeah, I mean, this was worth doing
six months from now.
And it's okay if they stop there
and think a little bit.
That's exactly what we want.
Right?
Because then, once again, we
define point B, we know how to
pitch our service.
It's a straight line from point A
to point B.
So, up to this point, we
understand why they're here.
Background questions are all good.
We have context in their business.
We understand what their current
efforts are.
We've quantified what those
current efforts are resulting in.
We understand what their goals
are.
Now, this is where we dive into a
little bit more pain.
Okay.
And how long, you know, at this
point, they haven't been able to
hit their goals because of the
reasons they've shared.
How long has that been going on?
Six months?
Oh, okay.
And if they don't seem like
they're having any type of urgency
at that point, I would ask them,
okay, so I guess, you know, why
not?
It's been going on for six months.
I guess what's kind of made you
get to the point here where it's
like, yeah, I've kind of had
enough.
Once again, this is the part where
we're diving in.
We're twisting the knife a little
bit.
We're creating a little bit more
urgency.
We want them to kind of feel it in
their belly.
How likely, right?
So, after we just dove into some
pain, we want to be real with
them, right?
We want to figure out how likely
they are to hit the previously
mentioned goal without addressing
the previously mentioned issues.
Then we want to get their
commitment that they're willing to
address this issue and that
they're ready to do it now,
whether that means working with
you or not.
We're establishing the opportunity
costs here.
What I mean by that, guys, is our
biggest competitor is almost
always in action.
It's not the other agency.
It's not the larger company that
we may sell against.
It's just them doing nothing,
which is, once again, why we want
to ask them, hey, like, why not?
I guess it's been going on for six
months.
Why not continue as is?
Because that's the most likely
outcome if they don't sign with
us.
They just continue carrying on as
is.
So, if we establish the
opportunity costs and make them
realize that if they continue on
as is, that has a real price tag
associated to it.
And them not signing with you is
not simply them just telling the
sales guy that they met today, no,
it's them not being able to hit
their goals because of it.
That's where we can create real
urgency.
leverage that we can use at the
end of the call to close them,
right?
The cost of them not doing
something is them continuing to
experience these struggles for
even longer and not being able to
accomplish their goals.
We can establish those two things.
And I'm telling you, going back to
the fact that we have eight
closures, this is the one thing
they struggle with most when it
comes to discovery.
Whereas when they do this, the
urgency is created.
It's a whole lot easier to ask for
the sale and actually get that
sale on that first call.
After that, pretty
straightforward, we're going to
recap their situation, ask if your
understanding is fair, and then
just double check to make sure
that you didn't miss anything that
you should have covered.
Once again, this is super
important for us to make sure that
they feel heard.
And then after that, we're on to
the pitch.
So to show you guys just
continuation of that, because I
showed you guys the agenda itself,
motivation, problem
identification.
So why are they here?
First off, I'm curious.
What motivated you booking this
call today?
Business background, right?
Once again, gathering the
information of the business to
qualify them, gather ammo to close
them later.
I mentioned this.
What's your average CLTV question?
Current efforts.
What's that resulting in?
Clarifying their goals.
I even call it goals
clarification, because once again,
it's so common that people give
you a BS general range answer.
It's on the sales guy to lead them
to have specificity there.
And ideally, you get a verbal
commitment that we're on the same
page in terms of goals.
Great.
So you guys want to be at $100K a
month by the end of the year, and
you're thinking you need about 20
calls a month to get there.
Once again, that's specific.
That's a real clear point B.
Pain duration and impact, which is
basically how long, right?
How long have you guys been
struggling to find the way to
generate X calls?
Or how long have you guys been
struggling to find a way to
actually increase your digital
footprint?
Have a real personal brand.
How does that impact the business?
Right?
Then opportunity cost.
How likely do you think you are to
hit that goal without changing
your current outbound process?
I mean, I don't know.
I think we probably need to do
something.
Yeah, it sounds like it.
And you booked this call today, so
it sounds like a priority then.
So I guess my question there, so
whether you're looking to work
with us or not, working with
somebody else,
to ramp up your lead generation,
it sounds like this is a problem
you're looking to address and fix
now.
Yeah, it is.
Okay, cool.
Now I've kind of ruled out our
biggest competitor, which is an
action, and I could just sell
against them doing it themselves
or, you know, an alternative
situation.
But once again, I like my chances
rolling into that.
If they don't seem like they have
any urgency, hey, totally fair if
this isn't a top priority right
now.
But I guess I'm curious, what
sparked you exploring other
options in the first place if
things were generally working as
is?
Talked about that a little
earlier.
And then transition.
Hey, let me summarize what I'm
hearing here to make sure I
understand this correctly.
Concise recap of their situation,
their challenges, their goals.
Is that fair?
Is there anything I haven't
covered that you feel like I
should know?
Once again, no.
Cool.
Now I've kind of got the
permission to pitch.
And we'll talk a little bit more
about the start of the pitch
itself in the next video.
But we do these things at the top
from this on down.
Like I said, rapport isn't
typically make or break.
But from agenda on down, if we can
master this, I promise you, you're
going to be ahead of 99% of your
competition.
I know that sounds like a corny,
cheesy, cliche thing to say.
But just book a sales call with
anybody.
Book a sales call with somebody
and tell me if they're doing this
correctly.
Because you will feel a huge
difference when somebody does and
when they don't.
And most people just don't.
Like most corporate sales gigs are
kind of just like, they'll ask a
few questions, they'll get onto
the pitch.
And then all of a sudden when you
give them a BS excuse as to why
you don't want to sign,
they don't really have the ammo
that they need to close you.
They're kind of just like, okay,
cool.
When am I going to hear back from
you?
What can I send over via email?
Awesome.
Anybody else need to loop in?
Cool.
And then they're off.
They don't really know how to set
themselves up for a one call
close,
which starts at the top of half of
the call here.
So I'm going to wrap it up there.
But hopefully you guys enjoyed
this thing.
Super, super important as I
mentioned.