What's going on guys, super
excited for this video
because finally, drum roll,
the video you guys have all been
waiting for,
this is the updated, I literally
just went through
and combed over every single
sentence in this thing,
the updated high ticket B2B sales
script template.
And this is a super important
video, obviously,
but there's a reason why I put
this video
after videos like this for your
discovery
and this for your pitch and this
to dive deeper
specifically into ROI based
closing logic.
And it's because all of this,
watching these videos first,
so if you haven't already,
I'd recommend going back and
watching these,
is going to give you such a better
understanding
as to how to actually make this
script your own,
which is super important
because this is templatized
purposefully, obviously,
so anybody in here that shows any
of the agency models
can use this, but it's not just a
simple,
like let me change a few words
around type of script.
It's going to require real
thought.
And if you were expecting anything
different,
think about that logically.
Like would having a good pitch
that can beat out our competitors
be a super easy task to make?
Now, with this template
and with watching these videos
beforehand,
it's going to be very
straightforward for you guys,
but it's not going to be easy.
It's going to require some
brainpower
because once again,
if I was to just give you this
video up front
and say,
hey, just change a couple words
around,
that'd be like,
just giving you guys a bunch of
junk food.
So super important that you're
coming into it
with the context and the baseline
sales understanding
that you've gotten from the
previous videos,
because if you do,
this can help you build a pitch
that I promise you,
I'm not trying to use this as a
cliche,
will be better than 95% of the
competition out there.
So let's get into it.
First thing I started with
is the service-driven mindset.
Now, before we get into discovery,
one thing that's super important
going back to this video
is this is a guide
that you can refer back to
all of the time
to know if you're on track
to have a productive conversation
or not
and just make sure like,
okay, did I get this information?
Did I get that information?
But it's also important to
remember
that we're going for quality of
information,
not volume of questions.
And we'd rather go a mile deep
than a mile wide in discovery.
And I expand on that more
in this video specifically.
But what I mean by that
is I can ask one question here.
I'm curious,
what specifically motivated you
to book in this call today?
This guy can give me basically
all the business background I need
and all of the current efforts
that they're doing right now.
And it's like, okay,
even though I didn't have to ask
all these questions,
I got this information.
I can just continue on
to what those current efforts
are actually resulting in.
Right?
So just one example
of why you want to watch
these previous videos beforehand.
Right?
Now, let's just start at the top.
Opening a report.
It's not going to make
or break the call.
Don't be weird.
Don't seem subservient.
Be respectful of their time.
Keep it brief.
Jump right into the call.
Setting the agenda.
This is just a real quick sample.
This does not need to be
what your agenda looks like,
but it should get the point
across.
Right?
Hey, just so you know
what to expect,
this call is going to be
a casual conversation
to understand what
your current situation looks like,
what's working,
what's not,
what you're looking to accomplish.
If it seems like we can help,
I'll walk you through
what working together
would look like
so you can decide
if you want to get started today.
Right?
Once again,
if we're trying to go
for one call closes,
let's set that expectation
right at the top.
If not,
it's completely fine too.
Either way,
just look in the point
in the right direction.
Sound good?
So once again,
you can make this your own,
but this is the general tone
and the point
that we're trying to get across.
Also guys,
before diving in any deeper,
this is pretty much optimized
for a 30 minute one call close.
That said,
if you do actually one call
close these people,
a lot of times
those are going to stretch out
to 40 minutes,
45 minutes.
So having a longer call
going over on time
isn't always a bad thing.
Actually,
a lot of times it's a good thing.
It means they're at really asking
buyer level questions
or really thinking about going
forward.
So they have more questions
than somebody who's just info
gathering
and getting off the call.
That's completely fine.
I would still keep the slot
at 30 minutes
just because one,
it seems less intimidating
to book in,
but two,
if you have a 30 minute
appointment,
booked out
and most people nowadays
have calendars with buffers,
but let's say I booked a call at
1030.
I mean,
it's late over here,
but let's say I booked a call
from 1030 to 11.
A quick question
that I can throw in
somewhere on the top here,
right?
It could be,
you know,
right around here,
even a business background,
but just to kind of be conscious
of the time that you have,
you can just straight up ask him.
I can even put this
call
shouldn't take two.
long by the way,
but just to make sure
we have time
to go over everything.
Do you have a hard stop
at time?
Meeting is scheduled to end.
So once again,
you asked this question,
if somebody doesn't have a hard
stop
at 11 in this situation,
you're good
for usually the next 15 to 30
minutes
at least.
So we can actually just put this
right below the agenda itself
because it makes more sense here.
Cool.
So I put it in there
right below the agenda itself.
Now,
the first question
after we do set the agenda
and if we want to check on time,
we say something like this
is typically,
I'm curious,
man,
what motivated you
to book in this call today?
I promise you
this is going to be
a much more effective question
than asking them,
hey,
tell me a little bit more
about the business.
Tell me how many clients
you have
because you're going to get
more talkative prospects
at that point
who if you ask those questions
about what are your business,
I mean,
it's not even
trying to be demeaning
to the prospects.
Like people are just
naturally passionate
about their business.
A lot of times
it's their baby.
They can talk for a long time
which means that
you could get into a situation
where you're 10,
maybe even 15 minutes
into the call
and you really haven't
made much groundwork
in terms of what we're
looking to accomplish here.
So do yourself a favor
and start with this question.
Curious,
what motivated you
to book in this call today?
A lot of times
we're just going to tell you
a lot of the most valuable
information that we're
looking for in the first place.
Right?
If they don't give you
any information
and we want to dig
a little bit more,
we can ask questions like,
okay,
cool,
that makes sense.
I guess,
what's the ideal outcome
that you're looking for
in this meeting?
But usually this question
right here just does a trick
which is why I didn't
add anything else.
So now,
business background.
We talked about
why this is important
in this discovery video itself
so I won't go too deep into it
but here's some sample questions.
Also,
I added in a quick line up here.
Cool.
So I checked out your website
and noticed you do ABC for XYZ.
Hey,
I noticed you do
roofing
for homeowners
and businesses
in the Houston area
but it's always good
to hear straight from the source.
How are you guys currently?
positioning your offer
to potential clients,
right?
You're just starting off
with a question
that is going to basically
help you get the information
that you need
to number one,
qualify these people
and number two,
gather info and ammo
as I call it
that we can use
at the end of the call
to close them.
So that's why you ask
what's your typical
client lifetime value
because if it's $50
versus $10,000
obviously,
these guys are going to need
a lot more clients
to close
but if it's $10,000
a lot of times
selling these services,
one singular client
in the first three months
is going to make this
a massively ROI
positive investment,
right?
So you can think
a little bit more
about what information
is actually relevant here
and I would actually
recommend as you guys
go through this,
don't overthink it
to start
but start to analyze
your calls,
start to watch back
some of your calls
and just be like,
hmm,
did this help me
qualify the person?
Did this help me
gather ammo
that I could use
to close them?
and what I mean
by that
is showcasing
the ROIs
so like LTV
or information
that really helps
you tailor the pitch
and helps it hit
more for this person.
So did it help
you gather
useful information
for pitching
and closing the prospect
or did it help
us qualify them?
Because if it didn't
achieve either
of those functions,
it's really not
serving a purpose
so we don't need
to ask about it
and this is where
we can shave time.
I've had a lot
of closers
who do a perfect
job of just getting
the need-to-know basis.
I've also had a lot
of closers who tend
to ask almost too much
about the business
which isn't going
to kill you,
right?
It's always good
to get context
and the reason
why we start off
with this is so
they feel like
they're being heard
and they feel like
whatever recommendations
we make
don't lack context
but those people
who spend too much
time in this section
or just ask
useful questions
that one,
don't qualify them
or two,
don't help us
tailor the pitch
or close them,
they tend to have
discoveries that
aren't as productive
just because they'll
get to a point
where they're like
10-15 minutes in
and they're kind
of looking at the clock
and they're like
fuck,
I should just go
in and pitch,
right?
And we kind of know
here the pitches
or the discovery phases
you know,
you want to be
about 15 minutes,
a little bit longer,
a little bit shorter,
not going to be
a huge issue there.
This is definitely
like the timing aspect,
this is a guesstimation,
it's definitely
not an exact science.
Also,
just in terms of help
for navigating the script,
like actual sample things
that I would say,
on a call
are put in quotations
and then anything
that is like
more so an instruction
or just kind of like
my thoughts on it
is either italicized
or I put it in between
whatever you call
these little star things here
which you'll see later
in the pitch.
so we get context
in their business,
let's get into
the current efforts
so essentially
what are they doing
for content creation,
for paid ads,
what are they doing
for cold email,
whatever your service
happens to be,
we're trying to figure out
what are they currently
doing for that right now
and if they're doing nothing
right,
so if we're asking
about their lead generation
they're like
well I'm not doing anything
tonality plays a big role there
because we want to
essentially just be like
oh you guys aren't
you guys aren't doing
anything at all
oh okay
scribble on your notepad
and like that response
will start to create
that like urgency
and they'll start
to bubble up
they're like oh shit
like this isn't usual
most businesses
in my situation
are doing lead generation
and that can be helpful
right to start generating
some pain
to start generating
some urgency
for that prospect
so continuing on
you guys can see
what other things
so like okay
what are you guys
currently doing
what's working
what's not
what have you tried
in the past
what other solutions
are you considering
right now
and the reason why
like these questions
are important right now
is because
maybe they're not
doing paid ads
at the moment
but maybe they did
have a really bad
experience with paid
ads agency a year ago
super important
to know about that
because if I don't
ask about that
and they just say
I'm not doing
any paid ads
I'm like okay
cool I'll continue on
and then I get to the pitch
not knowing this
they can just be like
yeah dude this sounds good
but like we worked
with the paid ads agency
a year ago
they were saying
a lot of the stuff
that you're saying
right here
cool right
like that's exactly
what we're looking
to avoid
so if they did try
something in the past
let's ask more
questions about that
right
hey how'd that go
didn't work out
not at all
didn't get a single
client
why not
what do you think
the issue was there
right
like let's get
more context here
once again
this is just
kind of an estimation
of what questions
you would be asking
here
there's definitely
going to be a situation
where to get the
quality of information
that we want
and to go a mile
deep as opposed
to a mile wide
once again
all stuff that I've
talked about in this
video
so if you haven't
watched it
make sure that you do
really important
to kind of dig
on those specific
like key factors
here
what other solutions
are you guys
considering right now
because once again
we don't want to get
blindsided at the end
of the call
when they're like
yeah this is all
good and well
but like I'm actually
looking at this agency
and they're a lot
less expensive
than you guys
so I'm going to
take that call
and then we're going
to see how it goes
where
if I get blindsided
by that I may not
have a good comeback
I may not have a good
response
I may not
you know
be able to reframe
that question
just because I'm
caught off guard
but if I understand
that going into the
pitch
okay I'm registering
that right
so when somebody
does say something
like that
I know how to
position our service
against theirs
I can use the
framework
that I talked
about in the
perfect flow
conversation video
which I don't
have the gamma doc
pulled up here
but I can understand
how to acknowledge
that question
associate
and ask a better
question to reframe
and get them to
change their
perspective
so once again
going into previous
videos
this is why
I showed this
thing last
so you guys
can make a
real killer
script
quantifying current
results
okay so this is
what they're doing
this is exactly
what it's resulting
in
like I said
in the discovery
video
be wary of ranges
we want to get
like a real
understanding of
what point A
is when I say
be wary of ranges
I mean
don't accept them
saying
we typically get
10 to 15 calls
a month
okay cool
like how many
calls a month
exactly did you
guys get in the
last 30 days
I'm curious
right
a lot of times
like I said
it ends up
being 8
which doesn't
fall in 10
to 15
but once again
we want to
have them
speak
and say
how bad
the situation
is
at this point
because once again
that's what's
going to create
the urgency
that actually
gets them
to realize
that they need
this
we want them
to come to
realization
that they need
this on their
own
and create
a little bit
of urgency
once again
these are just
more questions
to ask
like how is
what they're
doing
resulting in
any
meaningful
results
if it is
right
now goals
clarification
right
so we
understand
what point
A is
pretty well
let's go
on to the
goals
like I talked
about here
we want to
lead them
if they don't
have a specific
answer
and then
we're getting
into the
pain duration
and impact
and once again
you guys can see
what I mean
about the
instruction
with this
being in
quotations
and this
being just
italicized
right
good example
here
like if
they're just
like yeah
we want
more revenue
more views
like that's
not a real
goal
the reason
we define
the goal
is to define
what point B
looks like
because the
whole point
of the pitch
is we want
to position
ourselves
as a straight
line from
point A
to point B
and an
example of
leading them
would be
like got
it
more clients
is definitely
our goal
too
right
so we
don't
want to
make them
feel like
an asshole
for not
having like
a defined
goal
once again
it's hard
to have
to lead
them
yeah got
it
more clients
is definitely
our goal
too
but just
so we can
define success
here so I
know what to
shoot for
what would
make you
look back
in three
months
and make
you say
yeah this
was absolutely
worth it
right they're
gonna they're
gonna think a
little bit
more and
they may
pause they
may talk
to you
back and
forth about
what's typically
good and
what's not
good we
want that
conversation
to happen
pain
duration and
impact this
basically goes
back to
the how
long and
how likely
concept here
right how
long they've
been struggling
with their
goals or
struggling
with this
problem if
they seem
indifferent let's
dig for more
pain
that's one
of those
things you
guys are
just gonna
have to be
able to
realize like
okay this
guy doesn't
actually seem
like he has
an issue
that's that's
within itself
kind of a
problem hey
how's that
impact the
business during
this time is
another question
we can ask
if we're
digging for
more pain
hey so if
things have
generally been
working as
is I guess
what has
you looking
into paid
ads help
at the moment
right we
want to in
situations like
this where they
just seem
very indifferent
like you
almost want to
lean out if
you guys have
ever heard that
concept
once again
that's lean
out I feel
like I just
mumbled that
for whatever
reason but the
reason why you
want to do
that is because
one we want
to obviously
dig up more
pain like we're
talking about but
two we don't
want to seem
overly needy
right so if we
lean out as
opposed to being
like are you
sure you don't
want this right
now like I
think we could
really help you
hey so things
are generally
working as is
what has you
looking into
paid ads in
the first place
we'll get some
more information
out of them
opportunity cost
and readiness
this is the
how likely
portion how
likely do you
think you are
to hit those
goals without
addressing issues
we discussed
right obviously
like tailor this
to whatever your
pitch is okay
it sounds like
this priority
then so I
guess whether
you're working
with us or
not once again
like this is
another almost
like a form of
leaning out
because we're
not trying to
just seem like
we're shamelessly
shilling our
service because
we haven't
pitched yet so
I mean they
can't give you
guys a commitment
here at this
point I wish it
was that easy
but we can say
so whether you're
working with us
or not on this
issue is that
something that
you're wanting
ready to address
now which
obviously you're
going to have a
high take rate on
this question if
they're like no
we don't think
we're going to
hit this goal
they're going to
be like yeah
dude we do and
sometimes they
maybe like a
yeah no shit
type of response
for them at
this point but
that's perfectly
fine because this
is ammo that we
can use in the
closing process
because we're
essentially when
they try to delay
at the end of
the call we
have their own
words to flip
back on them
because they
earlier had told
us yeah they're
ready to address
this now once
again if they
seem like they
don't need you
let's dig hey
I guess if you're
confident you're
going to get to
this goal
regardless and
you're currently
only at eight
calls a month
what's what's
the plan oh I
think you know we
may be able to
just wrap up our
internal legion
systems yeah I
guess why not just
do that once again
I'm leaning out
here yeah I guess
you know we're
kind of just
looking at
different situations
here where it's
like we could do
that but historically
it hasn't worked
for us okay so
I'll get into what
we're doing here in
a second because
at this point there
may be a little
bit like fucking
pitch me already
which is fine right
if anybody gets
impatient I'll talk
about that in a
second but we can
say okay so I'll
get into what we're
doing here in a
second but if it
seems like we're a
better alternative
than you guys
doing what you
have been doing
or you know
potentially just
revamping things
internally is this
something you'd pull
the trigger on
because that's all I
can look for right
I can't get them to
commit to it at
this point but I
at least want some
verbal commitment
that okay if it
seems better than
that alternative that
they just mentioned
which probably isn't
that good right
because these guys
haven't hit these
goals yet is this
something you'd pull
the trigger on right
we get that
information we
transition to the
pitch now what I
was saying about
when it seems like
somebody is almost
like uneasy and
discovery or almost
combative or just
coming through hey
just pitch me bro
one of those guys
I'm in sales I get
it don't play their
game right first
off hey you know
maybe like one
technique we can
use here that I
like to employ is
just falling on our
sword which means
hey maybe I'm not
asking you know the
best questions here
right now they're
going to be like
okay dude they
almost start to feel
bad for you hey
maybe I'm not asking
the right questions
here but I guess
the reason why I'm
asking these questions
in the first place
is just to figure out
if we really can help
you or not and
based on different
clients we've talked
to different prospects
we've talked to you
know this is one of
those those key things
that you know we kind
of need to know so I
guess with that in
mind insert question
right we want to
always kind of follow
up with a question
because once again
the person who's
asking the question
is leading the call
they're the one in
control but if they
seem to be super
impatient let's let's
fall on our sword a
little bit even if
we're completely in the
right and they're in
the wrong hey my bad
man just just to give
you some context
on why I'm asking
these questions in
the first place
remind them that we're
helping them and then
follow up with another
question just get back
into it don't don't
hear hey just pitch me
dude and actually go
to the pitch don't
want to do that now
transition to pitch
we're done with
discovery getting into
the pitch phase here
once again this is
heavily modeled after
everything you've
already seen in this
part right here but
the expert perspective
this is one of those
things you guys are
just going to want to
write out that's
going to be very
tailored to what you
guys are doing but
just a quick sample
is like yeah based
on where so we
finished this up hey
just to recap what
I'm seeing here you
guys been struggling
with your lead
generation for the
better part of a
year currently
booking about like
five calls a month
and the goal is to
get to at least 10
calls a month so
you'd be looking for
outbound to bring
you guys another
five calls a month
is that a fair
assessment yeah is
there anything that I
haven't asked about
that you feel like I
should have no okay
cool well do you
mind if I show some
thoughts so let's put
this here
oh let's just cut
this actually yeah
do you mind if I
show some thoughts
cool and yeah just
to where just explain
where these thoughts
are coming from I've
helped this many
businesses if you
haven't helped any
businesses yet I've
studied XYZ business
let's say you're doing
email marketing for
econ brands I've
studied hundreds of
brands in their
email marketing
strategy and here's
why most businesses
struggle to generate
consistent revenue from
Clayville email
marketing right insert
the common pitfalls or
the common limiting
beliefs that you're
dealing with here
insert the expert
insight curious here
your thoughts on
that so in this
pitch video right
here I gave you
guys a couple
examples of what
that looks like so
I'd recommend going to
check that out if
you're still a little
bit confusing the
concept but once
again this is
something that
basically just takes
this person it's
basically a pre-pitch
and gets them
thinking about the
issue or gets them
over accommodating
limiting belief that
they may have about
your service so if
I'm here in terms of
the mindset and
they're here I get
them to move closer
to me so that way if
they're thinking more
so along the same
lines that I am the
solution introduction
the pitch everything
that comes after
this is going to
hit a lot harder
where if they have
some sort of core
limiting belief that's
going to prevent them
from thinking that
your service works
that's a big issue
obviously or if they
think for whatever
reason yeah they've
seen common pitfalls
or they haven't
they've struggled with
this a lot in the
past and they think
this is going to be
more of the same
like this part is
really really
important now the
solution introduction
after that becomes
pretty important and
this is going to be
pretty brief right
awesome so the way
that we solve for
reason most people
struggle or like you
know all this stuff
is by high level
overview of what you
do right so the
reason how we solve
for a problem or
the reason we help
people or the way
that we help our
clients avoid this
common pitfall is
by boom just like
quick elevator pitch of
what you do does not
need to be long like
we're talking in the
range of you know
10 to 30 seconds
here not a couple
minutes right then
we're going to get
into our proven
delivery system and
this is what it
looks like and at
this point we're
going to want to
screen share visual
representation of the
system this is where
you can go to a
diagram in your VSL
a slide deck if you
want to create one
for this specifically
so just to talk
about the visuals
Daniel does a good
job for our sales
team of giving us
something that we
can just screen
share on these
calls so we're not
like reading off the
VSL and screen
sharing through it
but usually there's
like a helpful
visual that we can
go back to but if
you don't have one
in your VSL for
whatever reason like
if your VSL was
all copy I would
not recommend going
to the VSL and
just reading the
copy I'd recommend
making a visual for
this and nowadays
with AI I mean it's
it's so stupid
simple it of course
takes work but it
is pretty straightforward
but you'd want to
have a diagram and
you know maybe from
your VSL maybe a
slide deck or maybe
examples of your
work but you want to
have visual here one
to ensure the
prospect understands
the nature of your
service the benefits
because like this is
the part where it's
like we're showing
them how we get
results we're showing
them how the sausage
is made so if they
don't understand this
part here confused
prospects don't buy as
I mentioned in a couple
previous videos and
two if they can see
something what you'll
what you'll notice is
if I if I say the
same thing just words
just me talking to the
guy on zoom versus
if I say something
while screen sharing
something if I do
the latter saying
something while
screen sharing
something it usually
generates more
questions which is a
good thing right this
is where we want to
welcome questions I'll
talk about that a
little bit more in a
second here but we
want to make sure
that there's absolute
clarity and you know
also excitement on how
this unique mechanism
that has three four
key components right
so your three pillar
pitch so at client
ascension forever we've
been using hey cool so
the way that we
actually get these
results is with the
three C's and we'll
break down what those
three C's are coaching
community content right
but and then we start
with coaching we have
a little written out
thing for that we go
into community we have
a little written out
thing for that we go
into content we have a
little bit of written
out thing for that but
it's basically like hey
this is what we do
which gives you this
benefit this is what we
do that gives you this
benefit and yeah the
system is specifically
designed to get
consistent results in
industry in time
frame what are your
thoughts on one to
three once again
because we want to
welcome and generate
questions here that's
why I'm asking what
are your thoughts on
one to three as
opposed to hey does
one to three make
sense so I did a
little note here
steps one two and
three can be a lot
longer than what I
just wrote out here
and if they are a lot
longer we can just
add this check-in
question as opposed
to just doing one
check-in question
after one two and
three we can just
add in small
questions between
these steps but
because we want to
generate questions
ideally we want to
stay away from those
yes or no questions
so for example what
are your questions on
X is better than any
questions on X here
very small different
difference but if I
ask what are your
questions somebody's
going to think they're
going to think of
something you know
maybe I don't have
any that's fine
because they at
least tried to think
of a question first
where if you go into
any questions on this
make sense you're
going to go through a
lot of pitches where
it feels like you're
just pitching to a
brick wall where
they're just like
yep yep make sense
make sense and we've
all had those sales
calls and they suck
and the reason why
they suck is because
you're kind of just
left in the dark it's
very difficult to gauge
where those prospects
are a lot of times
there like I always
recommend asking for
the sale but with
those calls where I'm
doing a bad job and
I'm just saying any
questions make sense
and they're just
saying no questions
make sense I'm I'm
really just like I
don't know this
person may be
disinterested or
like I don't even
know heading into the
asks there right so
really important we
generate questions at
this point now next
part we're also going
to want a visual for
this the immediate
roadmap and quick
wins so going into
the pitch outline
basically here's a
where we're at so
we had the proven
delivery system for
solving the issue
here sell the next
step not the entire
journey people don't
buy big transformations
this can work in
marketing they buy
clear pass forward
the analogy I like to
use if somebody was
trying to lose 100
pounds and we just
said yeah we can get
you from 300 pounds
to 200 pounds no
problem like the the
cool case studies may
get them on the call
and marketing but in
sales we want to show
them how they're going
to lose those first
10 pounds we're going
to show them how we
track calories we're
going to show them
what a beginning
workout plan looks
like for somebody
that hasn't worked
out in a while that
doesn't get them
injured right like we
want the quick wins
laid out which is
going to make make
sure that they're
excited to get
started and it's
also going to reduce
friction on them
actually making that
decision to get
started right so
we're going to want
to have a visual
representation of this
as well so in
terms of like most
important place to
have a visual
representation of
what we're doing
here like if you
didn't have it in
your VSL for
whatever reason and
I was making a
slide deck or just
making visuals on a
gambadoc to support
this the proven
delivery system and
the immediate roadmap
and quick wins is
where I'd focus my
effort the next would
be like having like a
pricing sheet that
could you know just
lay out and display
the prices especially
if there's some
nuances there but
once again we want
to have a visual
representation think
roadmap with
checkpoints once
again that are
valuable because we
want to showcase
quick wins so it's
not just all boring
shit I'll show you
what this would look
like in a second
think of a timeline
think of a flow
chart here that
highlights the
first 30 60 90
days whatever it
doesn't have to be
30 60 90 days guys
by the way it's
it's essentially just
mapping out whatever
the time to value
is with for your
service right
something like SEO
may have a lot
longer of a time to
value than paid
ads right so I may
do a 60 day roadmap
for a paid ads
offer I may do a
six month roadmap
for an SEO offer
but I want to show
them what the time
the value looks like
what the path looks
like there and then
also highlight the
quick wins so they're
not just expecting
pain and desperation
in those 60 days or
in those six months if
I was pitching SEO
because if we do that
what's it going to do
it's going to make the
first 60 days seem
like hell nobody
wants to jump in the
hell they're just not
going to sign up
right so what we do
here is we set these
expectations which is
helpful for not having
bad expectations
setting promises that
we can't deliver on
and just making sure
we're clear on there
too because guys
prospects are they're
pretty ridiculous
sometimes with their
expectations so if we
don't set them they're
going to make their
own expectations and
trust me they're going
to be pretty bad
expectations for you
they're going to be
completely unrealistic
but we do this while
also getting excited
about what happens
next this is tailored
to your offer slash
delivery so what I did
below as opposed to
like giving you guys
like sample
questions that you
can kind of mess
with and change
with quickly I just
wrote out something
here and you can
picture this with like
a roadmap that has
like little you know
so it's like a
roadmap and there's
like little graphics
here like a tick
going up that
highlights the win
right because when I
highlight those quick
wins but what this
could look like so
just picture I'm
saying this with a
visual in front of
me hey so the
starting point would
be the first
onboarding call and
this is a for
whatever reason I
just did a YouTube
content creation offer
for business owners hey
so the starting
point is on that
first onboarding
call which would
be to map out your
90 day content plan
and schedule and
typically we'll leave
that very first call
with 30 to 50 high
level ideas for your
weekly YouTube videos
and we'll turn around
and give you 20
fleshed out creative
briefs from which
you'll pick 12 in
just 24 hours and
that'll be enough for
three months doing
one video a week
then we'll have
another call and
once again it's
easier to kind of
bounce around and
not sound like you're
over talking or
doing like a crazy
run-on sentence when
you have a visual
because you can kind
of guide the cursor
and everything along
with it then we'll
have another call to
make sure you're all
set up from a
recording standpoint
and we get the
first session on
calendar ASAP by
week two clients have
their first video
film and we've
edited it and
published it by
week four after the
first two videos are
out we'll be able to
see what the initial
results look like so
we can see what the
initial audience looks
like so we'll start
to build in CTAs to
each video by week
eight we should see
over a hundred
percent subscriber
growth from week
four and once
again like these
are wins but I
also don't need to
over promise because
think about it
somebody who just
launched YouTube in
the first you know
two weeks they may
have a hundred
subscribers if I can
get them to 200
subscribers by week
eight that's a hundred
percent subscriber
growth right like I
had my goal there
right by week eight
we should see a hundred
percent subscriber
growth from week
four and most of
our clients start to
see leads trickle in
in the second month
and third month so
by week 12 we
should have closed
our first client from
YouTube right and I
could have a nice
graphic being like yeah
cool like cash like
right like these
things sound dumb in
elementary but like
they really are
important right and
you guys can just hear
me talking about this
and saying this you
can see how much more
valuable it would be if
I had a roadmap in
front of me which is
basically just proving
my point right so
after that we've
basically given them
the whole pitch guys
right we've talked
about how we deliver
results we've talked
about what the next
30 60 90 days is
basically like we've
laid out what the time
the value is here and
then the process
confirmation which
is essentially just
say hey before we go
any further how you
feeling about the
process specifically
any questions in the
process that I can
help with once again
going back into this
part here make sure
they're clear about
the process confused
prospects do not buy
allow space for dumb
questions I expand on
all that in this video
but super important
because we want to
segment this out if we
if we just said this
and then went right
into value stacking
and closing then
they may have one or
two dumb questions
about the process and
once again I just
keep using the term
dumb questions they're
not really dumb
questions they seem
dumb to us but they
are you know
obviously gnawing at
the prospect we want
to get those out of
the way so they have
a clear head they
have a clear
understanding going
into what I call
the closing phase
here so we're done
with that we go into
the value stacking
aspect which for most
you guys if you
don't already have
something that can
achieve this function
and I talk about
this in video four
exactly what this is
why it works so
darn well how to
apply it on a call
if you guys don't
have something set
up I would just
recommend building an
ROI calculator I
think it's the easiest
way to do it and you
can also use
quantifiable case
studies the best bet
is when you can
supplement these two
right ROI calculator
quantifiable case
studies some of the
other stuff that I
talked about in this
video here are
essentially price
anchoring offer
stacking once again
this would be if you
don't have and you
guys probably aren't
going to go through
this with Daniel's
content like he's so
good at making offers
these these are these
probably work better
for other offers than
what you guys are
running so I wouldn't
worry about it too
much anyways we
showcase the ROI as
we talked about here
you know we have
presented the evidence
now we ask them if
they believe that
they're going to get
those results which
is in this next
section here and
based on everything
you're seeing here
do you see any
reason why the
solution wouldn't get
you to blank goal
and then obviously we
may need to go in
the handling
objections at this
point but if not if
it's a certain yes
like I talked about
in here if it's a
certain yes lay out
the onboarding steps
and ask for the sale
a little bit more
hashed out here
investment presentation
basically just going
over the investment
itself and this is you
know if you have
multiple packages
recommend one
specifically so they're
not just getting like
you know analysis by
paralysis so they're
not like thinking too
much in between the
packages and that
within itself delays
them from being able
to close in the call
and if you have if
you have a nuanced
pricing structure and
even if you don't I
think it's helpful to
have like a visual
place where you guys
can present the
investment so they
can see it in writing
and they can
understand that but
this part like
investment presentation
and next steps and
first ask these with
clients often get the
most questions and
they don't really
need to they're
really straightforward
like the whole goal
here for investment
presentation and next
steps and first ask
is just have a cool
calm and collected
tonality and don't
overthink it I get
it's nervous when
you're asking somebody
to give you money
but you seriously
just gotta you know
if you haven't been
there before fake
it till you make it
and just act like you
have right but
here's here's exactly
what it would look
like hey cool so
based on where you're
at I'd recommend the
gold package you get
10 calls a month
consistently and
the investment for
that would be just
five thousand dollars
now I talked about
kind of the the
silence here say the
number and pause I
like to pause and
just add a little bit
of silence once again
you have to be
comfortable and they
need to see you being
comfortable sitting in
that silence but I
don't think you need
to stay silent forever
if they are silent
for a little bit too
long I would just
ask him like once
again like we don't
want to butt in and
act too finicky I
would just ask him
like hey cool
curious man this
this align with what
you're able to invest
in order to get to
this goal and if I
need to sit in a
little bit more
silence that's
perfectly fine after
that point like I
don't recommend a
ton of silence after
dropping the price but
if you ask a question
like that afterwards
and they're still
silent it's usually
because they're
thinking of something
at that point I
would just be silent
and let them
respond but all
goes well cool got
it makes sense
like sometimes
it's pretty sick
they'll just be like
yeah dude I'm ready
to get started and
I just lay out the
next steps and get
them signed up but
other times just like
cool yeah so don't
expect after you say
the price that
somebody's gonna be
like I'm in or
I'm out a lot of
times just like okay
yeah makes sense like
it's not a definitive
answer so we need to
know exactly what to
do after that which
is plainly lay out
the next steps after
they process the
investment so there's
less fear of the
unknown so in terms of
next steps this is
like up here
this is like
on board this is
more so like what
the actual relationship
looks like 30 69
days at 90 days in
what the time the
value looks like the
next steps here are
more so the
onboarding steps
themselves and you
still want to make
that seem valuable
but it's like what
happens immediately
after so it doesn't
seem weird that
you're asking for the
sale on the call
because once again
this is optimized to
collect cash on the
call then plainly ask
for the sale ready to
get started once again
that's another thing
people ask me a lot
like hey what do
you say in order
to close them I'm
like what do you
mean like what like
what do you actually
say in order to get
them to give you the
money and they're
expecting like some
fancy like real
smooth suave smooth
operator line it's not
that right you do all
this process correctly
it's just hey ready to
get started and your
tone should reflect that
you're expecting a
yes all right fake
till you make it but
between us you
shouldn't be surprised
at all if you don't
and that's why we have
the objection
handling content but
what this could look
like in reality cool
so what happens is
you'll process the
investment here with
me so our team can
get to work right
away once that's
done the onboarding
steps trigger right
away so you'll
receive a link to
book an onboarding
call plus the
onboarding form and
your agreement the
outlines we've talked
about today got it
cool makes sense
awesome man ready to
get started yep
awesome then I would
take a stripe link I
would drop it in the
chat a lot of people
ask about that as
well I don't love the
method of taking
taking credit card
numbers I feel like
that almost just
creates unnecessary
friction I've done it
before right I feel
like that was just
like the old Russell
Brunson way of doing
it but somebody says
yes that that cool
man let me grab that
stripe link for you
I'll send it over and
like I mentioned as
soon as that's paid
it'll trigger the
onboarding step so
you'll get an email
that'll have the
onboarding call link
onboarding form and
an agreement that
outlines everything that
we talked about just
drop that in the chat
are you seeing it
cool yeah and I'll
stay on with you to
make sure everything
goes through correctly
on our end then you
just wait right and a
lot of people also
over complicate this
hey what do you do
while they're paying
like it's kind of
like rapport be
natural don't be
weird just just let
them pay let them
know if it goes
through and then get
in the next steps the
onboarding call link
the onboarding form
whatever it may be
but that's it guys
hopefully this is
helpful like I said
it's not something
where you just take
it and share a
few words which is
why or change a few
words which is why
this is one of my
longer videos but
trust me you build
this out for your
offer I've seen it
immediately double
some clients close
rates that's no
bullshit that's also
with like more
mature businesses
who have been around
for a while so you
guys starting here a
lot of you massive
shortcut so excited
to hear your guys
feedback excited to
see some scripts and
of course if you guys
have questions on
this just let me
know