What's going on guys in this video
i'm going to be talking about how
to win on follow-ups which is
a topic that i personally nerd out
about just because in my opinion
is the separation between
a good salesperson and a great
salesperson and i've managed a lot
of sales reps i've coached a
lot of people on the sales side
and i can tell you a lot of times
i'm looking at the calls i'm
trying to figure out what's wrong
the discovery seems pretty good
the pitch seems pretty good
then all of a sudden they show me
their crm and i'm like that's
exactly why they're not collecting
as much cash as they should so
super super important video you
guys are going to see me go
in depth here and then at the end
i'm going to be going into a
pipeline automation example
inside of go high level if you
guys haven't watched those videos
yet completely fine i would just
circle
back to that after you have
watched those videos just so
everything makes a little bit more
sense but
obviously with the context on
following up and the crm which i'm
going to get into both in this
video
here that automation example is
going to make perfect sense
anyways the reason why i'm titling
this video
how to win on follow-ups because
closing a deal or beating out a
competitor primarily because of
your
follow-up not the sales call is
100 a possibility i've done it
many times before our job here and
what you have to keep in mind is
that we're here to seek decisions
not validation meaning the last
thing
we want is a bunch of people on
the fence or us being in the dark
with a bunch of people just
because
it becomes unmanageable right and
it's more importantly a symptom of
the problem which is you
have a flaw in your sales process
or your follow-up process or a lot
of times both that doesn't result
in us getting a decision from the
prospect that's a massive issue
and i even put here a no i'm
telling
us no i do not want to do this or
never contact me again is better
at scale than a bunch of people
leaving us in the dark just
because like i said if our job is
to seek decisions not validations
and we
can't do that at scale it shows
that there's a real flaw in our
process so started us off by just
saying the money's in the
follow-up you guys have probably
heard that before 100 times but
it's one
of those cliches that is actually
true the money is sitting inside
of your pipeline if you assign
deal
values to the opportunity cards
which i can show you how to do
inside of go high level and i
actually do
show you how to do that in a
different video you're going to be
able to see and look at your
pipeline
at any given moment and there will
be hundreds of thousands of
dollars sitting there now that
should
do two things it should get you
excited because you're like if i
can convert some of this that's
tens of thousands of dollars
entering my bank account and it
should also get you a little
pissed off you
should be a little sick in the
stomach looking at how much money
is just sitting in there so if you
want a way to actually convert
that pipeline value which doesn't
mean much if you're not doing with
anything with it and convert that
in actual cash in the bank account
this section is going to help you
with that process exactly now even
the best salesperson in the world
like i talked about
it's usually separation between
good and great here can take their
close rate to the next level
by having a killer follow-up
process and oftentimes it's a
differentiator between you and
your competitor
who's the last man standing i love
that concept because a lot of
times they're interviewing
multiple
paid ads agencies they're in a
situation here where they just
dedicated a week to taking sales
calls
but they weren't yet ready to make
a decision until a month later and
this prospect may seem
super analytical they may seem
like they have all these different
buying criterias that's super
important but a lot of times that
last man standing the one who's
still following up
gets the deal it's not a great
example to use um but it's kind of
just like the last person at the
bar
you're like all right i guess i'm
going home with you and it works
like that in real life it works
like that in sales and also who
seems to have a more professional
sales process because what you
guys have to realize is that your
sales process even if you're not
selling sales coaching or
anything related to sales it's a
reflection of how you operate as a
company the person who has a
better
more professional sales process a
lot of times it's going to be like
okay this just seems like a more
competent company right so these
things here who's last man
standing who seems to have a
better more
professional sales process that a
lot of times can sway things in
your favor and be the deciding
factor
from when that person or for when
that person is ready to actually
make a decision
save yourself time book the
follow-up call i'm a huge
proponent of booking follow-up
calls and that
may seem counterintuitive because
a lot of people are like why am i
going to book a follow-up call
this
guy said he's ready to go or this
person uh told me like yeah i
think this is uh you know
something
we want to do i'll let you know by
the end of the week why would
putting an extra 30 minutes or 15
minutes or 10 minutes on my
calendar save me time dan it's
simply because we're setting a
clear deadline
for us to for them to get back to
us so in the micro it seems like
you're dedicating another 10
minutes
or 20 minutes or 30 minutes on a
call when you feel like you're
going to hear back from this
person
anyways but in the macro with the
amount of time that people aren't
going to stick to those deadlines
and we're going to be endlessly
chasing them and sending them 10
emails and cold calling them 15
times and sending them texts it's
actually going to cost us more
time if we don't set that clear
deadline which a follow-up call is
going to be the most effective way
to keep that conversation going
and save you time because it is a
clear timeline that makes it less
likely that this falls through the
cracks for you or the prospect so
first things first you're going to
want to lock in that
follow-up call on the first call
before you guys hop off so if you
are booking in a follow-up call
the last thing that should happen
on that call obviously you know we
agree to a time we send over
that calendar invite they accept
the calendar invite that all
happens before we leave the
meeting
you're going to see me mention bam
fam a lot in the next section
which just stands for booking a
meeting from another meeting very
common sales concept and that's
because for warm and cold
prospects
if you didn't close the deal i'd
recommend setting a follow-up call
90 of the time even if it's a
couple
months out reason why because like
i said it's it's just a surefire
way to not let sing things slip
through the cracks and even if
it's two months out it's always
easier to move around an existing
meeting
rather than creating a new one
which means if i want to talk to
somebody it's august right now
when
i'm recording this in october and
i have a follow-up call on
calendar is it likely that both of
us are going
to still be free at that time in
october no but the very fact that
that is living on their calendar
and they see it
makes me more likely for them to
say hey actually i'm not
interested in this or hey dan can
we just
kick this one more week or hey can
we actually move it from two
o'clock to four o'clock as opposed
to if
nothing was on their calendar i'm
just another one of the thousands
of emails in their inbox that they
haven't gotten back to right now
it's also important to frame the
follow-up call correctly you want
this
to seem like a valuable low
pressure call where there's
perceived work going into it on
your end and
the reason why i put this in bold
is because i can break down each
section for you reason why you
might want to
make it seem valuable is so
they're excited for that next call
because in general a lot of follow
calls there's not much to discuss
of them making a decision but we
don't want to frame it that way we
want it to be something where
whether they make a decision
whether they go with us or not
they're
going to get value out of that
call when i say low pressure once
again we know that there's not
much
else to do other than discuss one
or two points and make a decision
but we always want to make it
seem like something where it's
super low pressure if they don't
make a decision that's completely
fine
because in the back of our head we
know if there's not much else to
discuss we're going to get to
decision making time on that
follow-up call the tough thing is
actually getting them to show up
to
that follow-up call and if it's a
high pressure thing like hey okay
cool we'll regroup on tuesday
at two o'clock and we'll make a
decision there and they don't have
a decision entering that meeting
guess what they're going to do
they're going to cancel the
meeting they're going to no show
the
meeting they're going to try to
kick it down another week whereas
if it's hey you know we'll talk
through
any thoughts questions concerns
that you guys have they're more
likely to show up which once again
the the hard part on those
follow-up calls oftentimes isn't
closing them it's just getting
them there in the first place and
now when i say whether it's
perceived work going into it on
your
end this is just going to make
them feel like more of an asshole
if they don't show up so these all
three things are just geared to
get them to show up to the
follow-up call because like i
mentioned
that's a difficult part so i'll
just do a quick framing of a bad
follow-up call frame and i'll do
a quick framing of a good
follow-up call frame so bad
follow-up call frame would be okay
cool man um
you think this over let's touch
base on friday and uh we'll make a
decision there
horrible right because it's not
valuable we're just gonna think it
over which is how they left
the call anyways and if they don't
have a decision by friday they're
just gonna kick it right or
they're
not going to show up now a good
framing would be like awesome man
on that next call what i'm going
to do i'm going to put together a
little plan for you guys so you
can see what the first 30 days
would
look like with all this context in
mind now that i really feel like i
understand your business and
what you guys are looking to
accomplish um i'll present that i
think it'll be super valuable for
you guys whether you decide to do
this or not and either way we'll
just talk through any thoughts
questions concerns how's that
sound so what i did was i made it
valuable i was putting together a
little
plan as i was just pulling that
out of my ass but that's perceived
work going into on my end
and it's a lower pressure because
once again i didn't preface that
they had to make a decision
on that call so all this stuff
super important follow-ups when
you're not speaking to the
decision
maker especially with larger
companies uh you're not always
going to be just speaking to the
decision
maker on call one it would be nice
if you could just be like hey man
i only speak to decision makers
and just ask for when that
decision maker is going to be
available that's oftentimes
wishful thinking
there's a lot of people in the
sales space who are just like hey
don't pitch people who aren't the
decision maker but once again it's
like how else am i going to get
the decision maker i need to get
this person on the call one over
or else they're not just going to
run this up the flagpole for me
and get that decision maker on a
call with me right so obviously
let's qualify them let's take them
through you know maybe a briefer
discovery and maybe a briefer
pitch but let's get them to the
point where they're excited about
this and then obviously the best
outcome here is going to be
to book in a follow-up call with
that decision maker but regardless
of whether you get that or not
if we tie down meaning like if we
get that person genuinely
interested that we're talking to
they're going to become a champion
for your offer to sell it
internally so they're going to be
more
likely to actually vouch for you
to try to get that guy on a sales
call they're going to be more
likely to actually give this
person and present the information
for you guys and i talk about this
a lot in the partner objection
because that's that's really kind
of like what this is here is
just the ultimate decision maker
is not on the phone so i talk
about it in the objection handling
video
but the same the same methodology
applies here now in cases where
you're not able to book in with
the follow-up decision uh with the
decision maker for a follow-up
call ask for that decision
maker's email and phone number now
the reason why this is important
is because one when you're sending
over follow-up material and
obviously this video is all about
how to have a great follow-up
process
so if we if we have a great
follow-up process yeah we're going
to want to go straight to the
source
and and this is you know a funny
thing that that works quite well
if that boss is tied in
on the email communication or i've
done this before grab the phone
number and just put these guys
in a group chat afterwards this
person who's not the decision
maker who you're talking to
they may not care as much about
this decision to work with you
guys on their paid ads funnels or
not
just because it's not their money
like they're not the ones choking
the check at the end of the day
so if they go to you it's like
it's not that big of a deal and
like the opportunity cost of them
not
hitting their goals once again
it's not their business it's not
that big of a deal but if you're
also while you're following up
blowing up their boss in an email
thread or blowing up their group
chat this
boss is going to make you know
dave who the fuck is this dan guy
that keeps messaging us right uh
which will just increase the
chances that they get back to you
once again even if it's a no we
would
rather have that than a bunch of
people just leaving us in the dark
now try to maintain frame when you
guys are following up with people
like we we still don't want to
seem overly needy that's still
that
message uh of whoever needs to
deal the least usually gets it
still applies here what we want to
be is
obnoxiously persistent without
seeming needy we're following up
because we're professionals
not because we need the client
what i mean by professionals and
i'll talk about this a little
bit later on i think i have it
right now people who are in sales
which almost all these guys if
they're
you know the owner or one of the
decision makers or like c-level
exec they're involved in sales
in some way at their company
they're going to respect a real
persistent salesperson 90 of the
time
right so like if we're following
up if we're dogging them it's not
going to be because
be because like we're the most
needy people in the world it's
just going to be like okay that's
that's part of the game they'll
understand and respect that but in
the spirit of not seeming super
needy just had a minute to follow
up here is a better way to open up
an email than hey just wanted to
check in are you guys still
looking for support to get you get
50k a month or should i close this
out is
better than i'd love to see if we
can help you hit 50k a month this
is very small things like that
but just keep it in mind as you're
writing these follow-up emails and
also try to avoid the corporate
jargon when possible as well it's
um it's one of those things where
like a pattern breaker is always
going to get through and anything
that's just circling back or
anything along those lines that
you just
hear in the corporate world like
that that shit is just it's so
common it's just in one or not the
other people are just desensitized
to it they read you know just
circling back just checking in all
these different things here and
there's gonna be okay this is
sales email i'm not gonna read the
rest
of it now just to give you guys a
basic example of what a follow-up
is going to look like that's
going to help after each call and
once again if these guys don't
close on the call which the
majority
of prospects won't that's kind of
just the name of the game this
type of email is going to work but
it's
super important like before just
getting into the email itself that
every single call that goes in the
follow-up gets an email that same
day you can't be lazy with the
stuff you can't be sending them
a follow-up email the next day you
can't forget to have to send over
an email to a prospect that's
in follow-up i see my reps do this
and i flip out on them because
it's it's the bare minimum to
seeing
success with your follow-up but
basic example is you know the key
information you went over maybe
that's
a slide deck maybe that's a link
to your vsl doc uh a link to the
call summary if you guys are using
a recorder which you should be you
should be recording every single
one of
your calls your confidence in
helping them conviction sells once
again social proof and
the next steps so the next steps
are going to depend on kind of
where you guys left the
conversation
off but for example hey tim thanks
again for the time today here's a
link to the call recording and
the roi calculator we went through
on today's call links right
excited to help you guys finally
get the
outbound help you need after the
agreement signed today so i just
kind of did an example of somebody
that's ready to sign we'll send
over an onboarding form and a link
to book an onboarding call so we
can
stand track to launch before the
end of the month talk soon dan
perfect example don't overthink it
now another thing we want to do
here is make sure we're hitting
prospects on all platforms a lot
of
people have come to me hey i've
sent this guy eight emails he
hasn't responded i'm like okay
like is he
responding over text calling him
and they're like oh well i haven't
i haven't thought to call or text
him
huge miss opportunity some
prospects prefer text some prefer
email some prefer phone calls we
just
need to take note of where they
seem to be the most responsive her
mosey's talked about this before
but
you said the sales rep reach out
to people on every single platform
before the call even happened
and know where they responded
which i think is a good idea like
you should always be sending
over an email you should always be
sending over text before the call
at the bare minimum if you want
to add in linkedin as well shoot
them a connection request that's
not going to hurt wherever they
respond they're basically showing
you they're that type of person so
if i sent somebody an email text
and a linkedin connection request
and they connected on linkedin but
they didn't respond to any of the
other stuff and they showed up to
the call they've kind of proven to
me already linkedin is their
platform same with texts if
they're texting me back and forth
but they didn't seem to open or
respond
to any of the emails like they've
proven to me that they're a
texting person now still i don't
want to focus all my energy on
just one platform even after the
call but i'm probably going to
have the best odds on whatever
platform that they responded to
and do not stop following up with
them like as i mentioned when
they're finally ready to pull the
trigger oftentimes they'll go with
the provider that still happens to
be following up with them be
creative um simply being a dog
and your follow-ups will get you
very far but eventually a lot of
prospects will get comfortable
ghosting you they've dehumanized
you in their minds and they're
starting to see your message
as any other marketing message
because what happens here is i
have a good call with them
i send them over an email i send
them over another email they're
like i probably should get back to
dan you know this is something
that we're looking into but for
whatever reason they get super
busy
life happens right they've got a
bunch of different priorities uh
and the reality is and why i
always
say time kills deals is when
they're on the call that's as
close to the top of the priority
list
as we're going to get unless we
kind of re-engage them and bring
them back through follow but
generally
if we're looking at the average
prospect on the call the
priorities here then it kind of
just dwindles
here so other thing takes up their
time takes up their importance and
whether it's after my fourth
message or third message you're
like oh shit i just got super busy
i haven't been responding to dan
and guess what the world's still
the same you know the business is
still fine nothing's blowing
up uh you know the sun still rises
and the sun still goes down so
it's like okay they're just
looking at it they're like it's
fine to dehumanize this person
it's just going to be a marketing
message
they have to deal with and just
look at for two seconds and ignore
there's not any real consequences
there so what we need to do is
find a way to stand out from all
the other marketing messages
that they're getting the way we do
that is with a pattern breaker so
send over a loom with
a gif on their website right i
mean you guys have all heard of
loom obviously that's what i'm
recording this on if you just
embed a gif and it starts the
video on their website they're
going to
see a video of a guy or a girl
talking with their website showing
and they're just naturally going
to
think what is this person saying
about my website because
everybody's so self-absorbed
they're going to be
be more likely to click on that
and you're also going to get a
notification when they do click on
it and how much they wash of it
text them a meme i remember one of
these clients that i close at our
cold email agency who was running
like a very big agency well-known
guy in the space and we had a
great call and he's just one of
those guys who's perpetually busy
because he's running like a legit
eight-figure company and i just
kept texting him and text him text
him and all of a sudden like i did
enough you know hey just had a
second to follow up with you or
have you had a chance to read the
agreement or you know is this
still something you guys are
looking to do i was just like you
know
what i got like a meme of super
mario throwing a fireball and i
just literally went on like
snapchat
and just put in like what was it
like ready to finally get calls
with cold email something like
that it wasn't even a great
message it was literally just the
fact that he saw that
and it broke the pattern and he
got back to me and he signed on
and became a client
that's the whole point right we
got to break the pattern
especially with these super busy
guys who
unfortunately a lot of the best
prospects in terms of like the
best businesses are those super
busy
guys so it's important stuff send
them a voice note um i love voice
notes uh it's it's one of those
things that it's most prospects or
most sales guys rather won't have
the balls to do that let's stand
out
these things will catch them off
guard simply because they aren't
used to saying seeing it and
that can get them to realize that
you are actually a human so we've
moved from the dehumanized
category
to back to being human and they're
like shit yeah i probably should
get back to dan who's taking the
effort to leave me a voice note to
send me a loom to make a meme for
me right and it's just a reminder
like okay there's a real human
behind these messages it's not
just a sequence so if this is dan
doing
this and he's seemingly never
going to stop let him get back to
me even if he tells me no once
again
that's still winning my book and
as long as they get back to you
that's all you want as i said the
goal is to get a decision whether
that's yes or no what we don't
want is a bunch of people who have
ghosted us and we're not sure why
now this is kind of counter
counterintuitive i just said be
creative
but i'm also going to say kiss
keep it simple stupid here are a
couple things that everybody loves
to see so if you're ever running
out of ideas you don't have a good
creative idea for a follow-up
go back to this numbers and social
proof you get numbers from your
roi calculator you get
social proof from your clients
fomo is very powerful and by
seeing that you can help them
with an issue they haven't fixed
yet or that your clients are
winning and they're not that
shit converts lastly you want to
leverage novelty people are
intrigued by things that are new
the way that we can do this is by
making them another offer so this
is a strategy i like to talk
about called the re-offer and
here's what that would look like
for the sake of the example let's
say you're testing a new guarantee
um hey dan wanted to reach out to
you specifically because we're
testing
something new this week that could
help you out with xyz like
whatever you guys are selling uh
with
less money down at no risk to you
mind if i send over more info at
this point like i need to leverage
something new this is probably a
colder prospect so i'm not trying
to get them on a call right away
i'm
just trying to get them back in
the conversation so that's why the
cta is very low friction similar
to
like sending out a cold email like
the good ones are pretty low
friction so this person sees this
i'm kind of dangling this new
novel thing over their head and
it's a super low friction cta so
it's
like yeah send it over right now
we've successfully presented
something new to them and made it
easy for
them to get back to us with a
simple yes send it over and we've
got another chance to share that
new
guarantee ask for another call to
see if the time is better and once
they're on another call we can
make
another ask for their business
more asks equals more sales and
guys this concept of just a
re-offer
of presenting something new and
saying mind if i send it over it
can be used in so many different
ways you don't actually have to
have a new guarantee you don't
actually have to have a new offer
you can
be willing to come down a couple
hundred dollars on your price and
call it an end-a-month promo
hey wanted to reach out to you
specifically because we're testing
something new this week
um that could help you out with
xyz with less money down at no
risk to you mind if i send it over
it's the
same thing i'm just not testing a
new guarantee i just have an
end-a-month promo right and the
concept of fast action bonuses are
really really helpful because it
kind of goes into the the whole
follow-up methodology with like
one of the most important things
here is just setting a clear
timeline and if we're setting a
clear timeline that's great if
these guys aren't abiding
by the timeline it's like okay we
need to kind of reinforce and
almost manufacture
a new timeline so having a random
end of month promo that can come
back or saying
that you know we'd be willing to
do this if they move forward by
the end of the week like that
stuff
really works i know over at our
other company we use fast action
bonuses all the time uh even on
the
calls themselves uh just because
we know that once people get off
the call they're much less likely
to
close so a lot of times we'll
throw in a hey if you move forward
by the end of the week we'll give
you 200 off setup we'll give you
300 off the setup just because we
know that at scale
that trade-off of i give you a
couple hundred dollars off or i
give you this extra deliverable
in exchange for you moving quicker
than you would otherwise it's
worth it trust me now bonus don't
worry about being an inconvenience
i can't tell you how many times
clients have hit me up asking me
like hey dan uh this person said
they were gonna pay on tuesday and
you know they haven't paid the
invoice yet and i sent them a
message on wednesday and now it's
thursday what do i do it's like
what
do you mean what do you do you
just hit him up again yeah i i
texted him two days ago like text
him again
call him this time that doesn't
seem like too much too over the
top like dude get that head trash
out
remember we're there to give them
the help that they need they're
also in sales as well most of
the time so they will understand
it 90 of the time like i can't
tell you how many times i've
gotten
the feedback of hey dan um respect
it respect the persistence i i've
gotten that probably a hundred
times not even joking with a guy
being like dude respect let me
actually get back to you this week
versus i can remember maybe two
times in my life somebody told me
to fuck off because i was
following up too much both the
times i had a shitty grade on my
face so it's like cool like i
found out
where the line is so i go right up
to that line and try not to cross
it but if if the ratio is a
hundred
to two that should all be
encouraging to you guys like do
not worry about being an
inconvenience this guy
we're here to help they get it
they'll respect it actually most
of the time um so yeah now
obviously
follow-up stuff is so important
but almost none of it's possible
if we don't have a crm so here's
how
to get the most out of your crm
first off not having crm in sales
is just gross negligence i'm not
saying
you need hubspot right off the bat
which we use for our companies
it's a little more expensive we'll
be showing you how to use go high
level obviously if you've seen
some of that content you already
know that but having a place to
keep track of where people are at
in your pipeline is an absolute
must
not doing this will guarantee that
your business makes thousands of
dollars less than it would
otherwise so if you guys want that
guarantee go ahead don't follow up
with people or don't use
a crm because it's you're just not
going to follow people as
effectively if you do want to make
thousands of dollars more listen
up as you know the goal is to
follow up with every single
prospect
until they are either won or lost
it's kind of the same thing that i
said earlier right it's just
getting decisions until then we
should strive to always have a
next step and you'll see inside of
go high level you'll see inside of
any crm in the world regardless of
what you're using there's
always a good place to just set a
next step to set a new task right
and even if it's not like
a clear task that me and the
prospect both know like let's say
they said to check in uh in a few
weeks which is super vague i'm
just going to put that task two
weeks from now to send them an
email
to give them a call right very
very important that we're always
having a next step for people
until
they're either in the close loss
or close one column now most of
the calls you take wind up in the
follow process before they close
that's just the name of the game
right so if you don't have a crm
your probability of closing the
majority of prospects you ever
speak to goes down once again guys
i know
all this stuff is obvious it's
cliches but there's a reason why
i'm saying it four or five times
it's
just because it's that important
here's some basic pipeline stages
and you guys can kind of see
what this looks like here because
i already set this up in this
video but schedule call no show
hot list contract scent follow up
holding nurturing close one close
loss just give you guys
context on what everything is
schedule call really doesn't need
any explanation they book a call
you have it connected to your uh
calendar which is also and go high
level so it automatically appears
in this column then depending on
what happens you move them into
one of these no show they don't
show
up these are the ones that we want
to focus on because these are the
ones that are not
close one or close loss yet and uh
you know they're still worth
following up with so hot list
contract sense keys on the end of
the call bam fam we talked about
this booking a meeting from
another
meeting isolating the objection
right we want to have like if
they're in the hot list contract
set
this is like the one yard line
guys right these are the verbal
commitments these are the people
that
owe us money so this is the if i'm
looking at my crm and looking at
the opportunities in a given day
and i only have a few minutes i'm
gonna focus most of my effort on
the hot list right because
these are the people that are
closest to closing at the moment
here so with that in mind those
people
that are very close to closing
keys to the end of the call i'd
still want to book follow-up
meeting
most of the time i want to isolate
that objection so it's not one or
two or three things that they
think about in order to get to the
sale maybe it's just that one case
study that they need to see
maybe it's literally just uh they
they want to do it um but they
just need to check in with their
co-founder to make sure they're on
the same page having a very clear
timeline guys what i mean by
clear timeline here if somebody
says like yeah i'll sign the
contract today i'd ask them like
cool when
do you think you'll have 15
minutes to do that so i'm getting
the time of the day they say four
o'clock
okay awesome the reason why you
just want them to verbalize that
is because i don't want to seem
like i'm i'm too needy once again
but if it's four o'clock was when
they told me and now it's five
o'clock i'm gonna check into them
hey i know you mentioned you'd be
reading this at four do you have
any questions on the agreement
easy follow-up getting that verbal
commitment on the call
itself um you know whether that's
to read the agreement whether
that's to sign up and the keys
for follow-up here is really just
brute force once again these are
the people that have given
you essentially a verbal
commitment um there's maybe just
one outstanding item they need to
do
so don't overthink it don't worry
about being an inconvenience the
cta here is moving forward
right text call email do whatever
we do uh obviously like you don't
have to be crazy over
the top if they told you yeah i'm
ready to do this tomorrow until
that deadline passes but that's
once again why it's so important
to have a very clear timeline but
once again hot list ctas focus
on moving forward follow-up keys
the end of the call um bam fam
once again want to book in a
follow-up meeting and the keys for
uh you know follow-up emails is
going to be to recap the first
meeting with that follow-up email
uh social proof in between meeting
one and meeting two so if i have
a call with somebody and i book in
a call for you know it's it's
thursday right now my time and i'm
booking a call with somebody on
monday i'm gonna send over a recap
email right after that call and
then
probably friday monday morning i'm
just going to send them more
social proof just quick check-in
confirm the appointment make sure
we're good to go here right and
also with those check-ins before
a follow-up call i don't really
want to ask to make sure they're
good to go i i want to
assumptively
close them on that time meaning i
don't want to give them an easy
out by asking if the time still
works for them i just want to say
looking forward to speaking to you
at two o'clock so it's more of a
reminder as opposed to confirming
the appointment i guess right um
reminding them of their struggles
and their goals that's important
too uh once again we don't want
them to lose sight of that because
a
lot of times it will between the
first and second call look forward
to helping you fix your outbound
strategies to get 100k a month by
the end of the year right problem
outbound strategy goal 100k a
month by the end of the year cta
here is focused on the next step
for people in the follow-up column
so this is essentially people that
have a clear follow-up within the
next 30 days or clear next
step in the 30 days so the cta is
focused on that next step now
holding nurturing is basically
anybody
this the coldest of the follow-up
pipeline dispositions is anybody
that has a next step that's
past 30 days um or you know we
failed to get a next step on the
call uh or they gave us like a
real
soft no like more of a not for now
than anything else or like a real
vague maybe we're we're kind
of going through this we don't
really have a clear timeline all
right keys to the end of the call
if
we can if it makes sense i would
still book another meeting in and
the keys for follow-ups social
proof
this is one of those things where
like with these guys they're more
so cold enough to the point where
we need to get them back into a
conversation whereas like for this
it's like we need to get
them to move forward in the hot
list and the follow-up we need to
get them focused on the next step
here it's like we just need to
re-engage them so it's almost like
we're remarketing this person
to get them back into a situation
where we can get them on a call
again where we can make an ask for
a sale more ask more sales but
social proof here um like numbers
social proof everybody loves that
sequences is on top of them
without burning out so sequences
is just automation and that's what
i'm
going to show you guys how to do
uh at the end of this video is
basically just showing you how to
set up a simple automation for
people who are in the holding
nurturing here and questions to
see if
they still have a need for this
right the cta is focused on
starting the conversation about
their
outbound problems again or in this
situation if you're selling paid
ads or whatever just get them
focused on their problems again so
they're ready to have the
conversation about that and once
they are
great cool get them on a call
we'll kind of restart from there
if you have time this week and
still
i've been able to generate those
10 qualified calls a week you were
looking for it'd be great
to catch up and share what our
cold email strategy would look
like for you do you have 10
minutes
this week so you can see how we're
kind of almost marketing to them
again now in terms of automation
sequences here in frequency in
which you should use it should go
one holding nurturing two follow
three hot list right so if you
have a general
case study or like some flow you
want to put people through
follow-ups in you can absolutely
do
that right i would just have it
almost look like a little bit
different so you have your primary
thread which is like you manually
sending out your message which is
a recap of the first meeting
i would still have that thread be
focused on the next steps for
questions whatever that may be but
if you want to also enroll them in
another sequence that just shares
basic social proof that's
completely fine it's like a nice
to have not a need to have here in
terms of where you need to have
it is in the holding nurturing
here because like i said want to
be able to stay on top of all
these
prospects without burning out so
if you don't have a sequence it's
really tough to look at somebody
on you know your pipeline that you
talked to three months ago and
have the energy or have the the
bandwidth to type up a super
manual message for those person so
it's a need to have for the
holding
nurturing guys it's nice to have
for follow up i wouldn't bother
with the hot list uh contract sent
people because here it's like more
could be less right we we just
want to keep them focused on that
one outstanding thing and if
there's only one thing they're on
that one yard line that's keeping
them from moving forward sending
them over a bunch of stuff and
having them lose sight of that
one thing can actually do us a
disservice so here it's like no
this is all manual this is brute
force
this is something where if you
have a nice sequence that you want
everybody to see you can
also do that would still have a
separate thread that kind of still
focuses manually on that next
step with this person and here's
where it's it's pretty much
necessary especially at scale and
you
can get by without setting this up
right away but as you guys have a
more mature pipeline where there's
prospects in there that are
multiple months old really the
only way to stay on top of these
guys without
burning out is by having a
sequence so with that being said
let's go into how to set up a
sequence
for people in holding nurturing so
one of the cool things about go
high level setting up an
automation
is is very very simple um once
again this is a tool that has a
lot of content out there about it
too
so you can go to youtube uh you
can ask chat gpt for questions
about how to set up a sequence but
i'm just going to show you real
quick how to set up a pretty basic
one so what i would do on this
left hand side is going to
automation go to create workflow
start from scratch
and i'm going to start this with
trigger the trigger would be
let's go to pipeline status
changed add filters here
so in pipeline sales pipeline
stage
for this example is holding
nurturing because like i said it's
most important to have sequences
and automation for these guys uh
save trigger so let's say after um
after our meetings we're always
sending over a recap email right
but let's say for these holding
nurturing people we want to wait a
few days until we kind of enroll
them into this marketing sequence
here so what i would do then go to
wait
three days
save action
email
uh let's go to from
get this thing out of here user
email or no
mess that up this is the first
name so this will be your first
name
user email there we go um yeah
let's let's do this one just
sharing some recent wins no
template
obviously if you have templates
you can use that just say hey uh
contacts
let's see first name
okay so hey name wanted to share a
few wins from this week um
brian added 10k a month
tim close a five thousand dollar
deal
so
now ideally you want to add things
with the question but i'm kind of
just doing this
fast for the sake of speed here uh
subject line
sharing some wins cool save action
all right now let's say a few days
later
wait let's go two days later
send email it'd be the same steps
above
um
so
all right
all right okay cool i'm just gonna
fill this stuff in real quick let
me just pause it
okay so you just see that threw in
some sample copy there
cool cool cool uh it should feel
before saving them
all right dope uh now let's say we
want to add in
one more wait period one day
and then bounce over to another
platform you can use sms here uh
so if you guys have a
twilio account connected here they
use through this if you guys are
just sending uh so you can
go through the integrations there
and set up the twilio number if
you want but let's say you're
just uh sending these messages
manually from your iphone
whichiphones will convert better
at the end of the day this is more
so going to be a manual action so
it's going to be a reminder
for you to send over this but once
again still works you'll just get
a reminder like hey
text greg on this day uh so hey
uh contact first name
all right then maybe a couple days
later
this email can maybe be um a
little bit more drawn out contacts
ask them uh if you know they're
still looking to launch paid ads
in q4 if they're ready to close
this out and then a couple days
later i can do another manual sms
message uh that kind of reiterates
the same thing so i'm hash out the
offer saying hey it looks like you
haven't been able to get back to
any of these emails
but one of those things where in
the sphere of not worrying about
being an inconvenience make this
literally as long as you guys want
it can be 10 emails it can be 10
emails and three text messages
right if you're spacing it out
it's not gonna be that big of a
deal and once again once they tell
you a no or yes uh either if it's
a no we close them out we move
them to close loss once again
that's
one of my book if they tell you a
yes a lot of times it's going to
be like a yes we're revisiting
this then but then we can move
them from holding nurturing into a
warmer disposition like follow
up like hot lists or hopefully we
can get them back on a call and
close them right away anyways um
before i do this let's just delete
this right here delete action
everything else is good uh going
over the settings real quick uh i
wouldn't allow re-entry just
because it's going to be a little
bit
awkward if somebody moves out of
there that moves back in if they
get enrolled into the same
sequence
so we're going to take that off um
allow multiple opportunities
allows contact with multiple
opportunities under the workflow
separate executions that's fine uh
stopping responses i would do this
just because a response is usually
going to be a yes where we can
move them into a different
disposition or no uh sender
details this is what you'd want to
do send your number once again
this
where you connect could connect it
for sms once you guys have this
ready um it's quite simple you
just
save it publish it save then you
go back to workflows you can go
into the opportunities tab
and then whenever i move somebody
from here to here
they're automatically enrolled in
that sequence so the first delay
is three days three days later
this
person is going to get that email
a couple days later next email a
couple days later you'll get
the reminder to send over an sms
but simple stuff like that guys
goes a long way because at scale
it really just does become
impossible to know who needs what
when that's exactly what the crm
is for
and when it comes to automations
holding your train is going to be
the main place you want to focus
then follow-ups and then lastly uh
hot list i would just kind of take
full control of those leads
just because they're really on the
one yard line and just brute force
these people through
hopefully this was helpful guys
hit me up with any questions wrap
it up there