What's going on, guys?
My name is Dan Crowley.
You're going to be seeing a lot
more of me
in the sales section here.
I'm one of the co-founders at
Client Ascension and ListKit,
lead the sales team at both
companies.
And this first video is going to
be all about
the foundation of how we're going
to get good at sales and have a
killer sales process,
which is the mindset of a
high-performing closer.
If you're like me, you probably
want to get into
the tactical stuff, which trust
me, we will.
But like I said, if things aren't
built on this
foundation, it's all going to
crumble.
And you may be thinking, I'm not
good at sales.
Well,
first off, you're not good at
sales yet.
That's what we're going to change
throughout
these next few videos.
If you're thinking I'm not the
type of person that could be good
at sales,
it's usually just a mindset issue,
or it almost always is just a
mindset issue.
I can tell you
my first sales gig, it was in an
office and you would see all
different types of personalities,
the outgoing jock type who seemed
like he was a stud athlete, the
guy who's super reserved in the
corner, the girl who's also super
reserved, the girl who's super
outgoing, wants to talk to
everybody
in the office.
And I can tell you that none of
those personality types were
actually indicative of
performance, right?
At the same time, if you're
thinking, I don't want to get good
at sales,
I don't like sales, I hate sales
and salespeople, that's usually
just another mindset issue.
Because what you're thinking of
when you're thinking of sales is a
greasy used car salesman who's
trying
to sell somebody a lemon that's
going to break down on the first
day.
We're like, of course,
you don't want to be that person.
That guy's kind of a crook.
But if you are selling somebody
something that's actually going to
help them, you can see sales for
what it is, which is a noble
profession when it's done right.
So we talked about the mindset
issues that could lead you not
being good at sales or want to be
good at sales.
Now let's talk about the mindset
that's actually
going to make you good at sales.
What I call it is the service
driven closer mindset.
It's not as
sexy as me telling you that you
need to be in the Wolf of Wall
Street mindset and me being like,
or you being like, I'm going to go
into every single call and I'm
going to close every single call
because that's just not realistic.
And after you take enough sales
call, you're going to be like,
thank God I didn't try to close
everybody or didn't close
everybody because some people are
going to be absolutely miserable
clients if you do sign them.
But this is both what works
and is sustainable.
And it's also very easy to
understand with three simple
rules.
So let's
just jump into it.
Number one, your only job is to
help the prospect.
The way that you help them
is by making them, because they
usually need a little convincing
and we'll get into why,
making them make the best decision
for themselves, their business,
whether that's to work with you or
not.
Your job is not to collect as much
cash as possible.
So don't treat sales as purely
transactional.
It's not if you're doing it right.
And a lot of people get burnt out
because of this.
They get
drained from sales calls or burnt
out entirely because they come
into each call thinking,
I need to take this person's
money.
Like I need to take this person's
money from their pocket
and put it in the mine, which it's
more sustainable, ethical, and
actually way more lucrative
long-term
going to each call thinking, I'm
going to help this person fix
their shit.
99% of the time, if they signed up
for a sales call, they have shit
that needs fixing.
If they didn't, they wouldn't be
on the call.
Right?
And if your service can help them,
great.
It's actually immoral not to sell
them.
Also, I put this here.
Don't believe people when they
tell you everything is fine,
because for
whatever reason, people have this
weird proclivity to just tell you
things aren't as bad as they are.
They know they need to help, so
they sign up for the sales call.
But then when they get to the
sales
call, they're like, ah, it's
actually things aren't that bad.
And the only reason is they think
that
admitting that they're in distress
is a poor reflection on them.
It makes them look like a
more incompetent business owner if
they're really in need.
We know they're in need.
They want to sign
up for the sales call if they
weren't.
We just have to do a little
digging and also get them to
realize
and verbally come to an agreement
that they also need help with X,
Y, Z, which is where you're
selling.
Now, we're just there to help
them.
At the same time, what's best for
the prospect is usually
outside of their comfort zone.
If they were already the person
that was capable for getting the
help
they need or doing the thing that
they need to do on their own, odds
are they would have already done
it, right?
Just think about that.
It's pretty much a universal law.
Even though they may know
they want to go from A to B, the
transformation from fat to skinny,
poor to rich, sad to happy,
they need to be sold on the thing
that gets them from A to B, which
is your service.
Because doing
a thing that gets them from A to B
is going to be outside of their
comfort zone.
Once again, if it was
inside of their comfort zone, they
would have already done it, but
it's outside of their comfort
zone,
which is why we need a sales call
in the first place.
Now, the third thing, these guys
are going
to fight to stay inside of their
comfort zone.
And most of the time, they'll
fight pretty hard.
This is why you shouldn't get
intimidated when somebody tells
you no on the sales call.
A lot
of times, that's just when the
sales call is beginning, right?
Why are they going to fight?
Like if somebody knows they want
to go from point A to point B,
why?
As I mentioned, they want to go
through some transformation, but
they're not yet the person on the
other side of that transformation.
In other words, because they have
not achieved the result, making
the decision needed to get the
result is going to feel foreign
and uncomfortable.
And I'll give you guys a super
common example,
because I've seen it time and time
again.
A lot of our clients want to grow
their business.
So they
join client Ascension.
Now, once they're in client
Ascension and they do grow their
business,
in hindsight, they'll see it as a
no brainer.
Like you'll see on testimonials
and case studies like,
dude, like it's one of the best
decisions I've ever made.
Right.
But, but the reason why they're
saying that, oh yeah, it was a no
brainer is because they're being
taught by coaches who have
already achieved what they're
looking to achieve.
We've got great testimonials about
how the program
is run, tons of case studies, and
one of the best communities out
there.
However, on the actual sales
call when they were the person at
point A, not the person at point
B, they likely had multiple
objections.
They were super nervous and they
needed to be closed.
Right.
And some people may call it
like hard closing techniques,
which we're not, we're not
treating or, you know, teaching
these high
pressure sales tactics, but like
there are times where people do
need to be closed.
And a lot of our best
case studies going back to one of
our guys who's absolutely crushing
it right now, running a multiple
six figure a month agency on that
first sales call, he just jumped
off when he got the agreement.
He just was literally right there
looking at, looking down the
barrel at a $10,000 investment
and just, just hopped off, closed
the zoom, ran away, came back in a
couple of months,
joined and then became a massive
case study.
And what's funny is he, like so
many of our other
clients have gone on to join other
programs because they already went
through the initial transformation
of someone who thinks in his mind,
like, ah, dude, I don't know yet.
Cause I haven't done it.
Maybe coaching doesn't work.
How do I know they know how to
help my business specifically?
Blah,
blah, blah to, okay.
Based off my experience with
client Ascension, like, yeah, next
time,
if the program seems legit, has
good results and helps with what I
need help with.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm capable of seeing an ROI.
I've already done it before.
Right.
So 90% of the time,
the former, this mindset right
here is where your prospects are
today.
So it's our moral obligation
to get them to the ladder.
And the reason why I'm saying
moral obligation is because
think of this person and we'll go
over frame.
Like you don't want to make them
your friend.
I mean,
if you do in the process, great,
but like that shouldn't be your
sole goal going into it,
but think of them as a friend.
If you were hearing a friend say
things that are just completely
unaligned with their goals, like,
would you push them a little bit?
Would you hold them accountable?
I hope you would, because that's
what a good friend would do.
That's what a good salesperson
would do.
Right.
So it's our moral obligation to
help them get to the ladder, which
is the person on
the other side of the
transformation that they told us
that they wanted to go through.
Right now,
three rules.
Like I said, super simple.
Your only job is to help the
prospect at the same time.
What's best for them is going to
be outside of the comfort zone.
And also they're going to fight
like hell to stay inside of the
comfort zone, right?
Which is where all these sales
techniques
are going to come in.
Now, even if you have a service
driven mindset, you still need
these three
things.
Number one, conviction, super,
super simple, but often a lot of
people are struggling
with sales.
They just simply don't have
conviction, right?
This is perhaps, and Daniel may
disagree.
He may say the offer.
He may say something else, but
I've seen it.
When a sales rep has conviction
in what they're selling, they
really believe in what they're
selling.
They can get away with a lot of
stuff.
When they don't, they can be a
great sales guy in all their areas
and super competent,
but their performance is just
going to fall off a cliff because
people can viscerally feel when
you
believe in what you're selling.
And if sales is a transfer, it's a
belief and you have none to
transfer, you're not going to do
very well in sales.
Pretty simple.
So believe in what you sell.
And
when you pitch, really pitch.
If you guys are here, you're
probably a fan of Alex Ramosi or
have
consumed some of this content.
He has talked in a couple of
videos about his worst ever live
pitch
performance when he was on stage.
And the reason why the pitch
didn't work out for him is because
he
was like, eh, you know, I got
really good stuff.
It's going to help these people.
I don't really need a
pitch.
I'm just going to kind of explain
what I do and say, yo, if you want
help, just meet me in the
back.
Nobody did.
Right.
And his takeaway, which is the
right takeaway is when you pitch,
you have to
really pitch.
Contrary to popular belief, people
want to be sold.
They only roll their eyes and zone
out when they don't see how it's
going to help them.
And we're going to go over how to
avoid that,
but just burn that into your
brain.
Like you actually have to believe
that you can get them
results.
And if you're sitting there
thinking like, well, then I
haven't actually gotten results
for
people.
So how do I know I can get them
results?
That's why you have a
performance-based offer.
That's why you have a guarantee in
your offer.
So you may not know for a fact,
you're going to get them
results, but you should believe
damn well in your offer being a
good offer for that person.
Maybe they don't hit the guarantee
and they do get their money back,
but with that guarantee in place
in lack of, or in lieu of a bunch
of case studies that you guys are
going to build up eventually,
you should still be at a point
where it's like, dude, I know I'm
going to put my best foot forward.
I know I'm going to do good work
for you.
I know that I fully believe, which
once again,
they can viscerally feel that I
can help you get to that goal.
And if you don't,
you would get your money back.
So it's a no brainer here, right?
So you can have conviction
in what you're selling, in what
you're doing, even when you don't
have case studies.
The issue is a lot of people are
just scared to sell because
they're not confident in what they
do,
which is like a meme on Twitter.
But like, yeah, that's, that's
quite literally a skill issue.
Go back through the other content,
talk to the other coaches, get
good enough to the point where
you're like, fuck yeah, I'm going
to help this person.
Because once again, they can feel
that
and they want to be pitched,
right?
They want to be sold.
Think about it.
If you guys were buying a
car, like if you were interested,
I don't know what type of cars you
guys like, but let's say you're
interested in a cyber truck, for
example, and you're pretty excited
about it.
If the sales guy's like,
yeah, cyber truck's pretty cool.
You know, can tow a lot, got a
good battery.
Looks, looks kind of cool.
You're like, what the fuck?
You're like actively talking me
out of it.
Or let's say you're looking at a
new apartment.
If the person's like, yo, these
amenities are sick.
This place has 12 foot ceilings.
You're going to love it.
The community's dope, this, that,
and the third.
Like, yeah.
Okay.
That's what
I want when I'm excited about
something.
Once again, they only don't want
to be sold.
They only don't
want to be pitched when they don't
see how it's going to help them,
which goes into a sales structure
issue, which once again, I'm going
to be on the next videos here.
Two, because a lot of you guys are
beginners, you're going to have
less experience than people.
And even as you grow your
business,
like hopefully you're working with
people that have money.
So you're going to continue to
encounter
a bunch of people that have way
more experience, way more money
than you, right?
You cannot treat
these people as your superior.
First off, their problems are
largely the same as everyone
else's.
And you're still just there to
help them with their problems.
Like don't overthink it.
These people
value their time even more than
other people.
So of course they wouldn't have
booked in a call if
they didn't need help.
They don't, you know, no business
owner gets to where he's at
because he
loves hopping on hundreds of sales
calls that are going to lead them
nowhere, right?
If anything,
these people are probably more
problem aware than the broke
prospects.
Now, even though this person
may be making a hundred times the
amount of money you are, I mean,
we've talked to businesses that
are
five, 10, 15 X bigger than us.
They still share a lot of the same
problems that a startup will.
So in other words, like there's
very few problems.
There's just varying levels of
them,
right?
I can't get leads from cold
traffic.
I can't find good sales reps.
I don't know how to
create content that converts.
A lot of it's just the same exact
problem at different scales.
So don't
treat it as a different problem.
It's the same one.
You just need to be talking about
a different
point A and a different point B.
Obviously the worst thing you can
do is treat them like their
problems are less consequential
than the next prospects because
they're making more money.
Oh, you know, you know, like you
guys, uh, hopefully we can help
you grow, but it sounds
like you guys are doing pretty
good.
No.
Right.
If you treat them like that, of
course, they're going
to be like, well, I don't want to
work with this person.
Cause it seems like they're just
way out of
their league and they don't know
how to help somebody at my size.
And I'm actually like a little bit
off-put because he doesn't have
the same urgency that I have when
it comes to fixing this issue.
People want to work with people
that understand their problems
better than they do and are of
similar or higher status in your
domain.
This is, this is capitalism.
This is business.
People don't
want to work with the young kid to
give them a shot or, uh, you know,
give you some money to, as,
as charity, to help your business
also grow.
Like cool.
Like if that shit was how things
worked,
like, I guess that could be nice
in some instances.
It's not though.
Right now you may be thinking this
person makes way more money than
me.
How can I be of similar or higher
status?
You don't have to be
with the scoreboard of just how
many dollars do I have my bank
account or how big is my business.
It's, it's just in your domain
specifically.
For example, this person may be a
billionaire,
but he doesn't know how to create
YouTube content.
So if he can see me as somebody
who understands
the problems of why most people
don't see success with YouTube and
I can be seen as similar or higher
status in him, when it comes to
YouTube growth, that's all you
need.
Same thing with cold email,
same thing with any other service
that you guys may be selling.
And lastly, the person who needs
the sale
the most usually doesn't get it.
In other words, the person who
needs the least typically gets
what
they want.
And this is one of those things
that you just have to constantly
remind yourself.
Because of course, like if
somebody is making way more money
than you, or you're just trying to
get
this off the ground, or maybe
you're having a bad month or
you're in a slump for whatever
reason,
you need to remind yourself of
this.
If you need the sale more than the
prospect,
they have all the leverage, which
means they're going to dictate the
terms.
You're going to get walked
all over.
And usually you're going to get
walked all over and they still
won't pay you, which really
fucking sucks.
If you've been through it a couple
of times, if they need your
solution more than you
need their business, even if it's
not true, if we can carry the
energy and get them to believe or
get
them on the other side of the
phone or zoom call thing and like,
yeah, okay.
I think we definitely
need this.
Right.
And we're going to talk about
establishing opportunity costs
and, you know,
building up the cost of an action
in their mind to make this a
reality.
But if they need your solution,
more than you need their business,
it's only natural that they will
become your client.
And you're not going to get walked
all over in terms of, you know,
what the terms of the contract
look like.
And I'm not, I'm not sitting here
telling you that you're never just
going to have to sling a
deal to make it happen.
And, you know, maybe give a little
bit of a discount here or get rid
of a
contract clause there.
But I could tell you over the
course of thousands of sales calls
I've taken,
thousands of sales calls.
I've watched with the 10, 15 sales
reps that I have right now between
centers and closers.
No one likes the smell of
commission breath.
So like, yeah, at certain
points, there's going to be times
where it's like, okay, shit.
Like, you know, we, we kind of
push and
we drag the deal across the finish
line, but over the course of your
sales career,
you will see that when this person
needs your solution more than you
seemingly, because once
again, I mean, it's kind of all a
game of optics here, need their
business.
They're
going to become your client.
The money is going to flow to the
person that needs the least,
right?
That's just how it works.
And like I said, it's not a
charity game.
Nobody likes to smell,
commission breath.
They're not there to quote
unquote, help you out.
So that's it.
I said,
again, things in the next video,
it's going to be a lot more
process oriented,
but hopefully you got some value
out of it.
Let me know if you have.