Yo, what's going on guys?
Super excited for this one because
we're going to be getting into the
million dollar pitch architecture.
And the reason why I call it that
is because I've used the same
pitch architecture to scale three
separate companies to over six
figures a month.
And
a pitch is something you're going
to work on continuously and change
unless you have the
perfect pitch and a super high
close rate, but you're going to be
changing it over and over again
based on customer feedback and how
these calls are going and where
your close rates at.
But
when you have a structure like
this, that iteration process
becomes so much easier because
you're
not just ripping it up from the
roots every single time you're
making a change, you're
building onto a process.
So when you have this pitch
architecture, not only is it
easier to
make improvements, but it's much
easier to reach a level of
consistency where it's like
most of these pitches are going
generally well, as opposed to one
pitch being a one out of 10,
then another pitch being a 10 out
of 10, then a seven out of 10.
Like if we can get this right,
most of these pitches should be
between an eight and 10 out of 10,
right?
So now with the million
dollar pitch architecture, I just
want to start this off with a
quick note.
And before I get into the
quick note, actually, let's just
go up to here to just start with
like the bare basics.
The goal of
the pitch is to sell this prospect
on what you do.
So of course, we're going to be
selling them on our
offer, our specific service, but
it's also important that they're
sold on the mechanism that you
use,
right?
If you're selling a cold email
offer, it's important that they're
sold on cold email
as a lead generation strategy.
If you're selling them on paid
ads, it's obviously important that
if
they want to work with a paid ads
agency, they're actually sold on
advertising on meta,
for example.
Then we want to tell them exactly
how we deliver our service to get
them to their goals,
right?
Talking about this in the last
video a lot.
We want to pitch our service as
the straightest
line from point A to point B, make
sure there's clarity and
excitement about the process,
about the next steps, help them
visualize ROI and build momentum
up until we ask for the sale.
And I'll just add another note.
When you pitch, really pitch.
Now, the reason why I'm saying
this
is because a lot of people will
just almost sleepwalk through the
pitch.
And I've talked about this in
previous videos before, like we're
leading these guys, whether we
like them or not, if we're not
excited about what we're selling,
how are they going to be excited?
If we don't have conviction,
if we're not just very like
clearly believing in what we sell,
how are we supposed to transfer
that belief?
And once again, I've probably
brought up this Ramozi video in a
previous story, but he
talks about how his worst pitch
was the one where he just really
didn't pitch at all.
He just tried
to casually walk through it, hope
people signed up and nobody did.
And if we do everything right in
the discovery and in this first
part here that I'm going to talk
about the expert perspective,
these guys are going to be wanting
to hear the pitch.
The only time you kind of
sleepwalk and like
pitches in one ear and out the
other is where you're not really
sure you need this and you're
not really sure that you want
this.
But if we build momentum properly
and follow this structure,
by the time we get into pitching,
they're already going to have some
urgency.
They're already going
to be sold on, you know, the
service, the concept of what we're
selling.
So when we're pitching
them that like, yeah, they're
going to want to be pitched.
Now with the million dollar pitch
architecture, uh, also just one
more quick note before I get into
it, studies suggest that 65%
of people are visual learners.
And I'd suggest that 99.9% of
people retain information better
when they
have a visual to support what
they're hearing.
The point one, I don't know, it's,
it's Helen Keller.
It's, it's blind people.
I don't know.
It's, it's everybody, right?
So you'll want to use visuals.
Easy ones for all of you to use.
If you're like, well, what visuals
am I going to need, Dan?
Like,
am I going to have to create like
these, this, this whole big
project is another thing.
No,
a lot of you guys can use parts of
your VSL.
I do that with a lot of our
pitches, actually
an ROI calculator and examples of
your work.
Super simple, right?
Even if you were to just start
with parts of your VSL screen
sharing it, when you're talking
about specific parts, and I'll
point
out where in an ROI calculator,
you're already, you know, 90% of
the way there, that extra 10% is
obviously where a lot of the gains
happen, but it's not too hard to
create those extra visuals,
especially if you have VSL, the
way that Daniel teaches.
And I also have the VSL doc up
here.
So I'm going to be able to show
you where this stuff actually has
some parallels.
You can also
make a slide deck.
Obviously people, people use pitch
decks.
I'm not married to one of the
other way,
but if you are having a slide
deck, use it in the same structure
that you're going to see below.
Anything can work so long as it is
evidence.
It's proof that your sales
argument is going to work for
them, that it's going to be the
straightest line from point A to
point B to get them to their
goals,
right?
Now, this first part usually
actually doesn't use a visual
because it's not really a pitch.
It's
much more of a pre-pitch, right?
And the goal here is to get them
to sold on the concept of your
service,
not necessarily your offer yet,
right?
So a lot of times when we're doing
this part, we're talking
about them.
It's, it's, we're almost
displacing them from the
conversation.
Um, when I said them,
I mean like a third party who's
not involved, not the prospect
that we're speaking to
specifically,
if you do this wrong, uh, it kind
of sounds a little preachy.
I guess like the closest
parallel in the VSL, once again, I
wouldn't use this scripted part
is, you know, this right here.
It's kind of like the intro to
your sales argument.
You see how we're selling cold
email as a service
and we're selling or cold email as
a concept.
And we're selling paid ads as a
concept before selling
our offer specifically.
That's because once again, we want
them to be sold on paid ads.
If they're looking at this, we
want them to be sold on cold email
if they're looking at this,
but the differences between the
marketing and the sales is once
again, the sales side of things,
we want this just to be like an
expert sharing their perspective
where the marketing, because it
can be
so direct, because there's no
two-way conversation.
If you were to just read off of
this, it'd feel a
little preachy.
So I'd recommend not having a
visual to support this part, but
here's the structure.
If you're selling organic content,
they need to be sold in the
concept of organic content for
their business.
If you're selling cold email, they
need to be sold on cold emails,
legion strategy for their
business.
We start off by asking, do you
mind if I share some thoughts?
So that literal talk track after
we summarize,
then this is very much like the
last question of discovery.
We summarize what we're hearing in
discovery,
doing a quick recap, making sure
that we're on the same page.
I think that's fair.
Asking them if there's anything
that we didn't ask about that we
should have asked about.
Cool.
Discovery is over.
My usual next question is, okay,
awesome, man.
And do you mind if I share some
thoughts?
Nobody's ever said no.
If you guys get somebody to say no
to that, like, no, I don't want to
hear your thoughts.
Let me know.
That'd be kind of funny just
because it's never happened across
thousands of calls.
So right after that, then we
proceed to tell them where these
thoughts are coming from while
status signaling, right?
And this only gets stronger, the
more credibility and case studies
and experience you have.
So for us, we're able to say,
yeah, and just to explain where
these thoughts are coming from,
we've scaled up our own cold email
agency to six figures a month and
helped over a thousand businesses
to date with their lead generation
strategy.
And then we'll get into what we
say next, right?
So they're like, okay, cool.
I mean, this person clearly knows
what he's talking about.
Let me listen.
Now, if you have some version of
that, great.
Once again, it's one of those
things that's only going to get
stronger the more you keep going.
Why this is a great opportunity or
we break down common limiting
beliefs or help them understand
why most people struggle to
achieve what you're saying you can
do or what you can help them
achieve.
Now, I know that sounds a little
convoluted and the way that I
wrote it out kind of is,
but basically what's the number
one limiting belief or what's the
number one thing your prospects
need
to believe in order for your pitch
to make sense, right?
If we can get them on the same
page,
if we can get them thinking the
same way about our service, about
our approach as we do,
then obviously our pitch is going
to make more sense.
So to give you a couple examples,
and I actually wrote out an
example below, but one that we've
used time and time again for our
cold
email setup offer is, Hey, do you
mind if I share some thoughts?
Yeah.
And just explain where these
thoughts are coming from.
We've scaled up our own cold email
agency to six figures a month.
We've
helped over a thousand B2B
businesses with their cold email
strategy, and we get five to 10
calls booked
per day with our own cold email
currently.
And what we've seen after working
with all these different
companies is this is the main
three reasons why people don't see
results with cold email.
And the reason why we attack that
is because there's so many people
that are jaded by cold email,
cold email doesn't work.
I never opened up cold emails.
I worked with an agency and I got
burned.
So like for that specific offer,
it makes sense to attack that.
And then we would go on to say,
number one, they're not doing
enough volume.
A lot of people come to the calls
telling us they reach
out to a thousand people a month
for six months.
And they're surprised that they
only got one or two calls.
For us, we work with a minimum of
where we reach out to a minimum of
5,000 prospects per month.
And even then that's the bare
minimum that you'd want.
If you want to see meaningful lead
flow.
Now, the second reason it doesn't
take a genius to tell you that
sales and numbers, again,
we need to be reaching out to more
people that people want to see
results is it, is it takes a
lot of technical expertise to
build the right infrastructure to
reach out to 5,000 plus people a
month and not burn your domains,
end up in spam and have the whole
system crash and burn.
Right?
So now, even if you are doing
enough volume and you do have the
right infrastructure,
the reason why most companies
still fail with cold email is a
strategy.
They're trying to write long
form copy.
They're putting in links and
attachments into their email and
they're wondering why it's not
going through.
When with cold email, you have to
realize that these people don't
know who you are.
And even though we may get 50 to
70% of the list to open up the
email, we're probably going to get
them to read that for three to
five seconds.
So we need to be short to the
point conversational.
Cool.
I guess I'm curious, what are your
thoughts on all that?
And usually there's just some like
weak because we've, we've
established ourselves as experts.
There's some like weak, you know,
Hey, I'll defer to you because
you're the expert.
Yeah, I agree.
That makes sense.
That sounds right.
Like, yeah, I can resonate with
that.
You know, previously we just, you
know, didn't do enough
following him.
And once again, that was super
messy.
I'm just pulling off an example
for you guys,
but going back to where I was at,
the important thing is that they
come out of this on the same
page as you.
Now, remember, we're not even
talking about them specifically.
We're just sharing how we
see things as an expert and seeing
if they agree.
And most of the time when people
aren't 100%
committed to think one way or the
other, they'll agree with the
experts.
And usually they will agree
just because if they were so jaded
about your service that they
really truly believed in their
bones that it
couldn't work, even if they do
have a high level of skepticism,
they wouldn't have booked in a
call.
Right.
So here's an example.
That's going to be a lot more
clean for you guys.
I wrote it out.
Do you mind if I share some
thoughts?
Yeah, cool.
And just to explain where these
thoughts are coming
from, I've helped over 30 local
businesses increase their revenue
from restaurants to roofers.
And the
reason most local business owners
never see success with organic
content is because of the
perceived time
investment, right?
They're running real businesses
and don't have time to become
influencers, but they don't
realize they don't need to be.
So they do nothing at all, which
typically doesn't do much, or they
go
for quicker marketing strategies
and they wonder why they can never
find consistency.
They're constantly
looking for a strategy to get them
consistent traffic that they
actually keep long-term without
needing to
invest all their time, without
realizing that organic content is
that strategy.
If it's done right.
Curious to hear your thoughts on
that.
Cool.
Like once again, if I'm selling
organic content and I'm dealing
with a lot of skeptical
prospects, I would start off by
saying something like this before
getting into the real pitch,
just because if I break down that
limiting belief, that organic
content can't work for local
business
owners.
That's very important.
If I don't do that, a lot of my
pitch is going to be in one ear
and out
the other.
To give you guys another example,
I was talking to a client quite
literally earlier today
that was, or that is selling
static ad creatives.
And a lot of the people will go
through the pitch.
They like what he says.
And they give him like some
veiled, yeah, I'll think about it.
Or,
you know, thanks.
Send over some more information.
And the key issue is a lot of
people just don't
believe static ad creatives
convert as well as video.
Right?
So I told him about this concept
of
having just a quick expert
perspective to, as opposed to
hoping that we can solve that at
the end of the
call or hoping that we could solve
that over email and follow-up,
since that's where a lot of these
calls are going, let's just solve
it right at the top of the pitch.
Hey man, cool.
Do you mind if I
share some thoughts?
Yeah, man, just explain where
these thoughts are coming from.
I've helped over
50 e-com brands scale with static
ads.
And the reason why most e-com
brand owners aren't
super excited or super sure that
static ads is going to work for
them is because they're trying to
compare static ads to video ads on
a one-to-one basis.
And if you film a static ad and
you film
one video ad, odds are that video
ad is going to perform better, but
that's not the use case for
static ads.
The use case for static ads is to
test with way more volume than you
ever could with video
ads.
So take you, for example, if
you're a e-com brand owner with 15
different products,
if you have the wherewithal and
the manpower and the marketing
team to be able to do a ton of
video
creative for all 15, by all means
do it.
Most people don't have those
resources.
What static ads is going
to allow you to do is test at such
a volume.
So you can test 10, 15, 20 plus
static ad creatives for
each one of your products, test
quicker, get market feedback, find
the winners, and then be able to
use
that winning message for each of
those products and double down
your resources on video ads for
those
products specifically with the
messaging already being, you know,
already knowing that it works and
delivered to you on a silver
platter because of the experience
with the static ad.
So it's really much
more of a testing mechanism than
anything else.
I'm curious to hear your thoughts
on that, right?
Once again, I'm kind of just
pulling this out left and right.
But once again, it's one of those
things
where we just need to attack that
main limiting belief or help them
understand if they're super
jaded, why most people are in the
same boat as them and haven't been
able to see results.
So they don't
feel alone.
And then just curious to hear your
thoughts on that, right?
Like we're not yet selling, but if
we've done this correctly,
everything else is so much easier
because then we can establish that
you solve
this need in the market and who
you specifically help best.
So going back to this example that
I wrote
out about local content.
Awesome.
And it goes out saying that
content like anything else takes a
proven strategy, volume and
consistency.
So the way we solve local business
owners content problems is by
coming up with a distribution
strategy that guarantees they post
twice a day on different platforms
with
a proven strategy without spending
more than one hour per month
recording content.
And typically we work
with busy entrepreneurs like
yourself who know they can use
content to grow their business,
have
expertise they want to share.
I mean, they're, they're tired of
seeing these unqualified gurus
getting all the views, but they
need to do it in a way that
doesn't take away from their day
to day
responsibilities.
It's like, cool.
Like this guy's going to be a
hundred percent on the same page
as me when I go into what the
actual service looks like, which
is what happens next.
And this is where
you're going to want to support it
with a diagram, with a visual,
with some sort of slide.
So once
again, I could give you guys a
number of different examples here,
but like even scrolling down
yeah, right here, like a
depiction, graphical
representation of what this looks
like, how this
works.
Daniel probably gives you a ton of
examples in a VSL of how this
looks here.
Let me see.
So this is the same diagram in our
VSL, but once again, if I'm
talking about the process
of somebody needing a cold email
system that can reach out to 5,000
plus people and explaining the
process that we go through of
setting up 15 domains and two
email accounts per domain and
doing the
DMARC, the DKIM, the SPF records,
it can all get pretty technical
pretty quickly.
But if they have
this visual to support, they're
going to retain that information
and understand it a lot better.
So going back into this, yeah, a
pretty clear and obvious point as
to where you're going to want them
to be able to see some sort of
visual to back it up.
And you're also going to want to
break it down
into a three or four point pitch
that talks about how we deliver
results, right?
And the reason why you
want to have a clear three or four
point pitch is because that's
going to naturally help them
retain
that information a lot better too.
So if you've ever pitched somebody
and you feel like they're
just not understanding, they're
not grasping it, they're kind of
like, yeah, this makes sense,
but can you send it over?
Like I didn't really get it.
And they seem genuinely confused.
Try it again with having a clear
three to four point pitch and a
diagram and some sort of visual
to back it up and support it.
I guarantee you, these guys are
actually going to understand your
service a lot better, which is
going to drastically increase your
chances of getting them to close
on the call because confused
prospects do not buy.
Right?
So now another thing, we're also
going to
want a visual to support this
part, sell the next step, not the
entire journey.
People don't buy big
transformations.
This, this can work in marketing.
They buy clear pass forward,
right?
Now I'm not saying
that we can't sell them on a big
transformation.
I'm saying that if we don't, if we
don't sell them on
the next steps that lead to that
big transformation, they're just
not going to believe it.
For instance,
if I was a weight loss coach and
I'm selling somebody on a weight
loss program that can get
them from 300 pounds to 200
pounds, that's a massive jump.
If I don't explain exactly what
the steps are
going to look like to get them the
first few wins, they're just not
going to believe it.
Right?
Once
again, that, that stuff can more
so work in marketing as opposed to
in sales.
When the next step is small
and logical, not a giant leap of
faith, it's a lot easier for them
to say yes.
So you want to lay out
the quick wins, which reduces
friction and basically check in to
make sure the next nine, 30 to 90
days,
whatever roadmap you have for
delivery seems like the logical
next step for their business,
where they'll
see value.
So super important that you
understand and can, and can
cleanly lay out what those next
steps, what those first 30 to 60
days would look like.
So, Hey, you know, first couple of
weeks are
onboarding.
We're gonna get the whole system
set up two weeks from now.
You're going to have a cold
email system that can reach out to
5,000 plus people per month.
The next month is going to be
a lot of testing.
So we set you up with professional
copy that's written by our own
in-house copywriters
with an A, B, C, and D test.
In that first month, we're going
to be able to gather a bunch of
data.
And then going into the second
half of month two, we're going to
be able to see which clear winners
we have so we can double down and
then start to dedicate more volume
to the winning angle that we have
at that
point.
Once again, just kind of coming up
with these on the fly, but you
guys get the point.
It needs to seem like a logical
next step for their business.
And you can even ask them if you
want
to check in, like, Hey, you know,
curious, man, does that 30, 60 day
roadmap make sense to you guys?
That seemed like a logical next
step based on where you guys are
at.
Cool.
Once, once again,
this is very important when you're
selling to a prospect that has a
number of different problems
because all the problems aren't
going to be solved at once.
And if you tell them they are,
they're just going to be like,
okay, this guy's selling snake
oil.
I just don't believe
it.
Where if we can sell them on that
first next step, if we can show
them those first quick wins,
that's when we can get them to
actually start thinking about
buying on the call.
Now, next, we're going to want to
make sure that they are clear
about the process.
Confused prospects don't buy.
I mentioned that earlier, right?
I tell my sales guys this
all the time.
So after pitching and before
closing, ask them if they have any
questions about the
process specifically.
And how they feel about the
Because they could believe that it
would work.
But if they don't believe that it
would work for them, it literally
doesn't matter.
And it's also important to allow
space for dumb questions.
Because once again, they're trying
to think of how it would work for
them.
They may have a dumb question or
two.
And I'm only calling
them dumb questions because
they're going to seem dumb to the
person that runs the offer.
That is a
cold email expert.
That is a Facebook ads expert.
But a lot of times it's just stuff
like,
hey, you know, why do we need to
set up extra domains again?
What are the domain names going to
look
like or for paid ads?
Like, okay, so wait, how do we
actually film the videos?
Do I need like a setup?
Do I need certain software?
Right?
It could seem insignificant or
like low stakes question.
But if
they can't get that out of the
back of their head, they're not
going to be able to visualize how
this
is actually going to work for
them.
And it's also just going to be
gnawing at them in the back of
their
head to the point where it will
actually prevent them from closing
if they don't get all of those
questions out.
Right?
So we check in on that.
Cool.
The next thing we want to do,
because at this point
they are sold on the concept, you
know, we kind of introduce
ourselves as a solution that
solves the
problem that we tell them exactly
how we actually solve the problem
with the three or four point pitch
that talks about how we deliver
these results, showing them the
diagram, kind of showing them
what the next steps look like and,
you know, lay out those quick wins
and reduce friction for the next
30 to 90 days, making sure that it
seems like a logical next step for
their business.
Then we make sure they're clear on
the process.
So they should be, let's say 80%
away there at this
point.
Now it's important because we've
been talking for 20, 25 minutes at
this point in the sales call
to make sure that they don't lose
sight of the fact that this is
going to get them to their goals.
Because a lot of information has
been shared.
You're probably talking a lot at
this point.
They're probably a little tired at
It's important that we kind of
zoom out a little
bit and go back to relating this
from, Hey, this is all to get you
from point A to point B.
And you guys need to have
something that can show them this,
right?
So common examples of just like
summarizing and value stacking, as
I call it, you guys can use an ROI
calculator.
So these things are
so stupid, easy to make now for
AI.
I was just messing around with
this a little bit ago, but this
was the
prompt that I gave it.
And this isn't a special prompt.
Once again, I just kind of drew
this up
before we started this video.
My offer is called email.
My packages allow customers to
send out 20,000
emails a month, 40,000 emails a
month, or 60,000 emails a month.
The cost is this for this, this
for
that, this for that.
Let's make the 20,000 emails a
month package called starter 40 K
email a month
package called pro in the 60 K
emails a month called expert in
terms of average results.
I kind of laid out
what the average client would see.
And once again, like plug in,
whatever your numbers are,
those are the leads, uh, those 20
positive replies, uh, of those
leads, the clients typically
convert
40% of them in the book calls.
So the client that gets 20 leads
usually gets eight book calls from
the eight calls booked.
I want the prospect, the person
using the calculator to enter in
the close
rate and LTV.
If the close rate is 25%, for
example, the client would get two
new clients.
If their LTV
is 10,000, then return, uh, on
that investment would be 20,000.
We need a calculator.
Uh, you know,
we need to calculate the ROI from
here.
Could you create this calculator?
Literally took me five
seconds.
Asked, you know, is that good to
go?
I said, yeah, perfect.
Let's build it.
And you can
already see this thing is built
right here.
So I click the starter package.
Let's say I have a 25%
close rate and a, you know, four
or five Oh LTV right away.
I'm going to be able to see, okay,
there's a 3.5 X on my investment.
Let's see if I could do this.
I go to the bigger package.
Guess
what?
I'm going to see a bigger one
because the pricing sales with
volume, right?
And you can ask
it and have it make quick
adjustments.
So like just real quick, um, it
kind of shows the breakdown
here, the conversion, the funnel
to net new clients.
Um, let's just say, can we also
show the
returns they would see in cash
value month over month for six
months.
And you can see, this is already
done.
I just re-entered the numbers.
25% close rate,
$4,500 lifetime value here.
Uh, they can see this look month
one, month two, month three,
month four, month five, month six.
Cool.
12,000 invested in the first six
months, 42,000 collected,
right?
Super, super easy.
It's, uh, it's crazy.
Anyways, um, going back to this,
once we do that, once we can paint
the ROI, obviously we're going to
have some
sort of interaction.
Hey, cool, man.
All this make it sense to you.
Yep.
Any questions on this,
on the calculator, on this?
And let's talk about other things
outside of the calculator.
You can just, at this point,
remind them of results-based
guarantee, a risk reversal price
anchoring.
A good example of this is like, if
you have a super deliverable heavy
offer,
let's say you're doing like video
production.
And with all the stuff that you
do, if they want to
hire in-house people for that, we
can essentially use a price anchor
of like, Hey, this would
typically,
if you wanted to have a
videographer or somebody to come
out and do this and that it would
cost you
usually anywhere from eight to 10
K a month, right?
We only charge three K a month,
right?
And here's what our clients see on
average in terms of views.
Here's what it translates into
dollars
and cents, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, right?
ROI calculator is going to be the
most obvious way
to use it.
But once again, you can use it in
a number of different ways.
After that, after we show
them the ROI, it's going to be
pretty clear that, you know, the
numbers point to them doing it,
but we
still don't know if they actually
believe that it would play out
that way.
So the next question is
typically just a no good reason
tie down as I call it, which is,
Hey, do you see any reason this
wouldn't
work out for you?
Right?
So if I'm showing this calculator
or this calculator right here,
Hey, do you
see any reason you want to be able
to see that 3.5 X that we're
projecting?
Do you see any reason
you want to be able to get those
10 new calls that you were looking
for each month, right?
Whatever
that goal is, do you see any
reason you want to be able to
achieve X, Y, Z goal?
If they can't think
of one, they're mentally going to
default to no, which is a yes,
right?
So let me change that real
quick.
No, which is a yes for us, right?
This is a powerful way to close
without pressure.
Obviously
the deal is not closed yet, but at
this point it makes sense to get
into the investment next steps and
then obviously make that first ask
for the sale.
So then once again, we're going to
want to relate
the investment, not the price back
to the end result and say the
number and then pause.
I'm not
a big proponent of pausing and
having a ton of awkward silence
that just builds up and make it
makes
it awkward.
So if there's a bit of awkward
silence, I just ask them, Hey, you
know, all right.
So let's
just go through this.
Um, okay, cool.
And for all that investments, just
$10,000 guys say sound.
Okay,
cool, man.
Yeah.
I'm curious to hear if this aligns
with what you're able to invest to
get to 20 calls
a month.
All right.
The reason why I like that, as
opposed to how are we feeling
about the investment?
Cause people could feel a number
of different ways.
Really what matters is, Hey, does
this align with
what they're able to invest to get
to X, Y, Z goal?
So once again, we're, we're, we're
using that term
investment as opposed to pay or
swing to get to their goal.
We want to constantly remind them
that
the goal of this investment is to
get them to their goal, because if
they're looking at it through
their
lens, obviously it's going to be a
lot more valuable.
And it's very important that you
are cool, calm, and
confident at this point.
Cause we just asked them for
money, right?
So they're naturally going to be a
little
weird and finicky and just like,
we want to be just like, we've
been there a hundred times before.
Right.
So when I go through this in
reality, it's yeah, it's just
$10,000.
Cool, man.
Yeah.
Curious to hear if this aligns
with what we're able to invest to
get to
50,000 followers on Instagram.
Once again, I'm not freaking out.
I'm not seeming needy because
then they're going to smell
commission, commission breath, and
nobody likes to smell commission
breath.
I'm just acting very calm and
casual at this point.
I'm not acting, even if it is a
big
number, I'm not acting like it is
a huge number.
Now, obviously if they also act
like it's a giant,
giant number, want to call that
out and be able to start that
conversation, that dialogue about
that.
But if they're all good, if it, if
it seems like it's making sense
for them,
I'm going to lay out the next
steps and then I'm going to make
my first S, right?
So cool,
man.
Typically what happens at this
point, you'll process the
investment with me.
I'll get you over
an onboarding form and a
scheduling link, and we'll be able
to get started in the process.
So we should
be able to have that system built
up for you in a couple of weeks.
Ready to get started.
And it's
just that easy, right?
A lot of people ask like, what's
your closing line?
What do you say?
Like,
don't overthink it.
Like if we've built up the pitch
up to this point, using the same
architecture,
all you need is ready to get
started.
And once again, tonality is super
important.
right here.
Like your tone should be
reflecting that you expect them to
say yes.
Right?
Like your tone should be like,
Hey, I'm so cool and calm.
And I'm just asking it in such a
casual matter of fact way, because
my service is so good that this is
just natural that people do at
this point.
I'm not being like, what do you
think?
You're ready to take a chance.
You're ready to go.
It's just like, ready to get
started.
Cool.
And then literally take payment
and go from there.
Right?
But, but, but between us, between
you and me, you should not be
surprised at all.
If they don't
say yes.
Right?
If every single person was a
frictionless, yes, we wouldn't
have sales calls.
We would just have a checkout
page.
Right?
So when they say no, we also don't
want to be rattled.
We want to still have that calm,
cool, collected tone.
We don't want to freak out.
We want to obviously dive into the
next steps, which is objection
handling.
And we go from there.
So hopefully this is value guys.
Uh, like I said, this is really
everything up until the first ask.
And then we're going to go to what
happens after that, right?
The, the objection handling,
how to continue to get back in the
sales conversation so we can make
more asks because
more asks equals more sales.
Pretty simple.
The best sales guys are the ones
who make the most
asks.
So if somebody doesn't go on the
first ask, let's figure out how to
get back to a point where
yeah, it feels natural to
obviously ask them for the sale
again, which is obviously going to
come
after some objection handling.
So hopefully you guys got some
value out of this.
Going to wrap it up here.