What's going on guys in this video
we're going to be talking about
something I call the perfect flow
Conversation method because if
you've ever had a sales call where
you feel like for whatever reason
you and the prospect are at odds
It's not super productive.
They're taking control of the
conversation or it's just not
Progressing in a direction that's
going to lead to a sale.
This is exactly where this tactic
can be deployed
a lot of it is simply returning
questions with a question because
as the sales guy we generally want
to be the one leading the question
and
There's a reason why in a lot of
famous courtroom movies the
lawyers like i'm the one asking
the questions here
And that's because the guy who's
asking the question is the one
who's in control at the end of the
day
And before I get into it
I want to shout out her mosey
because he has a great video on
this
And you could see a lot of the
comments are kind of like people
who are in my boat
I've been doing this for years.
My first sales job had another
term for this her mosey's
Term for this is the triple a
framework, which is acknowledge
associate and ask and i'm going to
break down exactly what that means
But what I highly recommend
checking out this video because
i've watched so much her mosey
content
This is probably my favorite video
When it comes to sales that he's
put out
Now this conversation method of
reframing questions is for when
prospects are being difficult or
asking a question that would move
them further away from the sale
Essentially, they're giving you
anything other than a yes, which
if you had sales calls happens
All the time
This will allow you to get back
into a productive not combative
conversation with the prospect so
that it makes sense to ask for the
sale
And the simple equation that I
talk about the simple equation
that her mosey talks about is more
asks
Equals more sales.
So it's getting us to a point
where it's natural to ask for the
sale because once again
More asks equals more sales.
So the perfect flow conversation
method.
What is it?
Oftentimes you got to realize that
prospects are just asking
questions because that's what they
think they're supposed to do on a
sales call
If that's the case if they're just
asking a question because they
feel like they're supposed to ask
a question at this point
Answering the question is
sometimes a lot of times a
thankless exercise
So don't be afraid to pause
And think for a second about what
type of answer they're looking for
in the first place
Because if there's no ideal answer
that they'd want to hear just
answer their question with a
question
Hey, i'm i'm curious.
Um, do you guys have this sock to
compliance?
Um
Not quite sure on that.
Do you mind if I ask why you're
asking?
Oh, I just you know, I've heard
about it from another company.
Is that something you guys
require?
Um, no
Okay, cool.
It was a useless question.
They just asked it because it
popped in their head
I don't need to answer it and go
on a long diatribe and try to, you
know
Get combative and overcome
whatever objection that they may
have or I think they have a lot of
times
I can just return the question
with a question now
Other times prospects are asking
questions or making a comment
because they're trying to put you
in a tough spot
Or politely tell you no for now
now what I mean by put you in a
tough spot is
a lot of people just naturally
have sales resistance
So they're trying to put them in a
situation where them at the end of
the call saying okay, i'm going to
think about it
I'm take the information just send
me over an email and make a
decision makes more sense, right?
Very natural that is okay.
It's just part of sales
If prospects didn't need to change
their perspective or be sold we
want to have sales calls in this
case though
Whenever this is what they're
doing right there
They're asking a question or
making a comment because they're
trying to put you in a tough spot
or politely tell you for now
Or no for now we want to implement
this perfect flow conversation
method.
So let's get into it
The first step is acknowledging
their question and lowering that
sales resistance, right?
Because that's kind of the impetus
for them having that question in
the first place
So a lot of people simply don't
want to make decisions on the call
because it's outside of their
comfort zone
And they don't like being hard
closed at the same time
No, one likes feeling like they're
being unreasonable
If you've ever had a girlfriend a
significant other you guys kind of
know if you treat their question
as they're being unreasonable
Even if it is an unreasonable
question, they're going to freak
out.
We don't want that prospects are
the same way
For example, if someone says can I
think about this instead of saying
no or
Why would you need to think about
this?
Which tonality is really
important, right?
Which would make you sound like a
dick or like they're not being
reasonable
You'd want to start by addressing
this or you'd want to start
addressing this by saying of
course
Totally normal to want to think
about it as much as you need to
make the best decision for your
business
And that's going to once again,
it's going to make them feel heard
Acknowledged and it's going to
lower that sales resistance,
right?
So instead of saying well, what do
you need to think about or no, you
can't think about it
We we want people to take action.
We want to make a decision on the
call
I can just lay back say yeah, of
course, man
It's totally normal to think about
it as much as you'd want to make
the best decision for your
business
And then we'll get into the rest.
But once again, it's a very
important step
and it also helps us
Because it doesn't make us seem
like we need them to close
Right the person who needs the
least usually gets what they want
So after we say something like
this to start it off to
acknowledge what they've said
The second step is relating them
or as her mozy talks about
associating them with somebody
that has already closed on this
offer previously
So a prospect will often say
things that'll make them sound
like they don't need you
But if we can relate their
situation to someone that has
worked with you and seen success
We've just taken a trap or an
objection and given them another
reason to buy
So a good example of this is let's
say
Selling
Personal tax strategy
And they have somebody who
Is an accountant that they've
worked with for a long time
They're like actually yeah, I mean
i've got an accountant and you
know, he kind of helps you with my
taxes
And I was to reframe that by
saying hey
No worries at all.
Sounds like you got a good
relationship with the guy
Once again lowering social
distance
I would say actually a lot of our
best clients
Already have an accountant that
they've worked with for a while
Just for the filing aspects.
It's pretty low cost where we
really come in and specialize
is
Blah blah blah, right?
So i'm already kind of associating
them with somebody else and we'll
get to the third part of that
Which is essentially just
attacking the frame of the
question
but
Continuing on the same example.
I wrote above if we were to add in
a lot of our best clients are the
ones who had the most questions
before getting started
So they were ready to hit the
ground running after they said I
need to think about it
Cool.
Now once again, i've just
associated them mr.
I need to think about it with our
best clients
So all of a sudden this trap they
laid
I've just taken that and turn it
into another reason that they
would want to buy
Right, so we've related them to
our best clients which would make
them question the fear or doubt
that they're feeling
That made them ask the question in
the first place
Right now, like I said a lot of
this is just returning a question
with a question
So it's not done yet.
This is the third and final step
which is really important
And that third and final step is
to ask them a question that
challenges the frame of their
question
Right, so her mosey says ask or
attack the frame of their question
Now the reason why we want to do
this
And finish with a question because
one people can't disagree with a
question
So we're not going to lose the
sale right then and there and then
two
It's a chance to get them to
change their perspective
Maybe they'll realize there's a
pointless question and three we
stay in control
By asking the question right so
continuing on that last example
If we added on what other
questions did you have to
determine if this is a fit?
Now we're back in the sale, right?
So I just took a guy who said
Can I think about this and instead
of saying well, what do you need
to think about or no?
You can't think about it and I
said yeah, of course totally
normal
I want to think about as much as
you need to make the best decision
for your business
I mean honestly a lot of our best
clients were the ones who had the
most questions before getting
started
So they're ready to hit the ground
running
I'm curious.
What other questions did you have
to determine if this was a fit?
Now we're back in the
conversation, right?
Maybe they ask a question that we
have a better answer to
Or maybe they tell you they want
to think about it off the call
Now we can start handling that
objection specifically
The best way to keep the prospect
from getting annoyed here is to
pay attention to our tonality
Right?
So this will save us in terms of
being able to stay into the
conversation
Get closer to a point where it
makes sense to ask for the close
But when we're doing this like I
talked about tonality is important
We want it to be upbeat and
curious
I think what her mosey says in the
video is you want to have
childlike curiosity
So that's really important because
I can say of course totally normal
want to think about it
A lot of our best clients were
they're honestly the ones who had
the most questions the sales
process man
I'm curious what other questions
do you have to determine if this
is a fit
Versus
Yeah, you could think about it
It's it's normal I guess
To want to think about it to make
the best decision for your
business
You know, I guess we've had other
clients that have asked questions
before what other questions do you
have man?
Like that's the latter tonality is
horrible, right?
The upbeat and curious that
childlike curiosity is going to be
super important for keeping
prospects to get annoyed
Because once again, we want to
seek to understand not to win
If we master any if we master all
of this any question or comment
that was designed to either delay
things
Or move them further from the sale
can be turned back on the prospect
to get us back on track to having
a productive conversation
So that we can ask for the sale by
doing this
It makes it less awkward when we
do ask for the sale and allows us
to make more asks and more asks
equals more sales
Simple as that.
So just recapping this real quick
first step is to acknowledge your
question and lower sales distance
The second step is relating them
with someone that has already
closed on this offer previously
Or if you guys haven't had any
clients relating them with
somebody that
Would see good results for this
offer
Right
So they they may think something
is a disqualifier when it's not
So that's a good situation where I
want to relate them
To somebody that would still be a
good fit
Like I said with the uh personal
taxes example, like it's okay
If you work
With an accountant, right?
And then the third and final step
is to ask them a question that
challenges the frame of the
question because
One people can't disagree with the
question.
So we're not going to lose sale
right then and there
Two it's a chance to get them to
change their perspective.
Maybe they'll realize it's a
pointless question and three
We stay in control by asking the
questions.
So a really easy framework shout
out her mosey once again is just
that triple a framework
acknowledge
associate
Ask that's pretty much what we're
talking about here.
I promise you it's something where
You need to work this muscle a
little bit, but the more and more
that you do it
Anything that just seems like
they're trying to throw at you
In order to put you in a difficult
spot so that they can go through
their buying process as opposed to
going through your sales process
This is a perfect method to deploy
so that they can go through our
sales process as opposed to their
buying process, right?
So
Acknowledge associate ask very
simple, but very very very useful
So hopefully you guys got some
value out of this once again would
recommend watching this video as
well
But as a concept, this is a 10 out
of 10 sales method in my opinion