What's going on, guys?
In this video, I want to talk
about effective pre-call
messaging.
I was
actually supposed to get into this
in the last video, but it crashed
on me.
So I figured it'd
be higher quality anyways if I
spent one video dedicated to this.
As I mentioned, we've done
so many different things to mess
with the show rate.
Some of them have worked, some of
them
haven't.
But the current process that we
have today has been leading to mid
60% on ice cold
traffic in terms of show rate.
That's through paid ads, primarily
through cold email.
It's even
higher.
And then through organic traffic,
it's been over 80%.
So that within itself, we've
seen across multiple offers.
If you can get your show rate
there, that won't be the issue
for your company scaling.
That won't be the reason your
sales process fails.
So if you want
to make sure that your show rate's
not shooting you guys in the foot
in terms of being able
to close as many deals as you
want, collect as much cash as
you'd want, this is a very
important video.
Now, note, these email sequences
should be set up in your CRM so
that they come
from the salesman's email that is
not on the calendar invite.
This will get more attention
from the prospect and make more
sense with the email copy
provided.
It also makes managing
pre-call conversations easier and
has more congruence in the sales
process since the follow-up emails
will be coming up from that same
email.
Now, this is really an important
note for people that
are using Calendly because if I'm
using Calendly, I'd want to set up
things separately inside of
my CRM and not lean too much on
Calendly for the reminders.
Like we use Calendly personally
and we
just use it for a 24-hour
reminder.
The email that goes out
immediately after booking, the
email that
goes out one hour before, that's
done through HubSpot, which is our
CRM.
And we go through the hassle of
making all these automations and
putting in all that work just
because number one, like I said,
it wants to, it should look and
feel like you're sitting there as
a sales guy, just sending them a
personal message because it's
going to get more attention.
And then also if they do respond,
it's
easier to handle that
conversation, et cetera, et
cetera.
But through Go High Level, it's
super easy.
You just click the reminder button
as I showed you guys additional
emails.
Like it's brain dead simple
inside of there because Go High
Level is your CRM.
So you guys are in luck there.
Now, this is a sample
copy, but the action that we want
them to take is what's important
that I think everybody should add
the
same.
So, Hey, just need a minute of
your time before our, whatever
your call name is.
Hi, Dan.
Thanks for booking in with us.
Just a couple of things I wanted
to make sure you received before
our
meeting the calendar invites.
Since Google policy changes, when
you book in through a third party
scheduling tool, the calendar
invite will not automatically
appear on your calendar unless you
have had previous contact with the
center myself.
So please make sure you add the
appointment to your
calendar using the calendar icon
below.
There's nothing here, but you can
see there's a little add
to calendar icon inside of there.
Once you do make sure you accept
it as well.
This way, you'll have
the time blocked off.
So you do not get double booked.
Uh, the Google meet zoom link, uh,
located
inside of the calendar invite.
If you're having trouble with
either, shoot me a message.
I'll help
out right away.
If you're all set, just respond to
this email saying, good to go.
The reason why this
is the first email that seems, and
this is pretty boilerplate
regardless of what company, but
this is
what I'd recommend that seems
pretty basic.
Um, is because it is let's, let's
not over-complicate it.
Number one, the calendar invite
and whether they accept that or
not is going to be the highest
indicator as to whether they show
up or not, especially the colder
traffic you get.
It's,
it's crazy how you can just look
at a slate of calls in the day.
And if four of six have accepted
the calendar invite, your, your
show rate is probably going to end
up being four out of six
for that day.
So let's just get them to take
that action.
So they have it on their calendar.
And then second, the call to
action of saying good to go is
important because, you know,
one, it's just getting some buy-in
from them.
It's, it's starting the
conversation sooner rather
than later, which is important.
But two, if they don't do it, it
kind of just, you know, sets off
that first alarm bell of like,
okay, we should be a little bit
more cautious with this prospect
in
terms of just reaching out to
them, make sure they get to the
call.
Email two, 24 hours before,
right?
So like for us, when we do the 24
hours before email, it's just a
general email that comes
from Calendly.
But if you're doing it from go
high level, this is just some more
sample copy.
Look forward to our meeting
tomorrow.
I'd recommend checking out this
video before the call.
So we
can hit the ground running VSL
link.
So you just, you know, plug that
link right there,
whatever that looks like for you
guys.
I'll just leave it.
Here's some recent client success
stories.
You know, you can plug another
link here.
Other than that, please make sure
you accept the calendar
invite.
So my assistant doesn't take that
off my calendar and we'll be
meeting on the blank.
Zoom link in there.
Guys, this is a really strong
frame that's worked well for me.
I don't even have
an assistant, but I'll just
consistently say that.
Hey, yeah, accept the calendar
invite.
So the
assistant doesn't take it off my
calendar because I don't want to
be a dick, but I do want them to
accept the calendar invite.
So I'm just going to act as if
like, Hey, you have to do it or
there could
be some consequences, right?
You're just adding a little stakes
into there.
Talk soon, Dan.
So pretty
simple.
You know, here's VSL.
Here's case studies.
If you have them, uh, make sure
you accept that
calendar invite.
So the system doesn't take it off
my calendar.
Um, one hour before this is where
it's
like, okay, they should have
already accepted the calendar
invite.
Even if they didn't, if they're
seeing this, they might not even
go in and accept that.
Like they see it in an hour,
they're either
going to show up or they won't.
Um, hi, Dan, looking forward to
our chat.
An hour from now,
we've personally helped insert
authority.
You know, obviously if, if we can
have, if we
have any type of credibility,
let's, let's put it right there so
that they listen to what
we say next, which is if you
haven't already, be sure to watch
this video explaining how we
blank.
Don't hesitate to reach out.
If you need anything else in our
room for the meeting,
look forward to it.
So the email side is pretty
simple.
Um, the text message side is
also relatively simple, but you
guys may be asking, Hey, shouldn't
I just automate this
through go high level?
Um, no, the short answer is you
want to be using an iPhone.
So for all of you guys that have
an iPhone, great for all of you
that don't have an iPhone.
Um,
I would recommend getting one.
I think you will just make more
money and come off as more serious
pre-call post-call having an
iPhone.
I'm sorry to all the Android guys
out there.
Um, and also
they, they just get really good
connection rates on cold calls and
things like that.
Obviously
you're not going to use it to do
hundreds of cold calls, but if
you're doing a small line,
it's a good idea.
Anyways, like I said, if your
callers and I have one, it's worth
using an
automated provider like send blue
or link.
Uh, and at scale, you're going to
want to automate this
right when you're dealing with
hundreds of calls.
Uh, so send blue link or two
different providers.
I'd prefer link.
This is the platform that I use
currently to automate things.
Uh, the text message
sequences that go out on our guys'
behalf.
So it looks like, and you know, it
feels like
everybody has their own dedicated
iPhone for us.
Um, so I need to update this now
because this said
we were only using it for two or
seven reps, but you know, we're
using it for all seven reps.
Uh,
but up until that point, you know,
as you can see here, everybody
else was just doing it manually
from their iPhone.
We saw an immediate boost though,
and successfully saving
reschedules when the text
went out that same day, the call
is booked for the appointments.
So, so let me put it this way,
guys.
Right after they book, if I'm on
my phone, I'm sending them one of
these texts immediately.
And the reason why we want to
start that conversation as soon as
possible is because
if we're, if we're looking at no
shows, um, let's say 60% of the
people that book an appointment,
so long as you're booking windows,
like three days out are going to
show up.
10% are
just never going to show up,
right?
They're, they're just weren't
serious people.
They're funnel
hacking, whatever.
Um, another 10% there, you know,
people that like kind of see, uh,
you know,
other alternatives and they, they
want to reschedule and whatnot,
but like 20% genuinely
do want to show up.
They're just bad at calendar
management.
Um, and they genuinely could have
gotten busy with something else.
Right.
So whatever you essentially what
I'm trying to say is 60% are
going to show up.
20% are jokers and 20% are people
that do want to show up that have
interest,
but they're bad at calendar
management.
They may get busy with something
else.
So probably
frame that pretty poorly.
The reason why it's important to
start the conversation as soon as
possible is because by doing that,
you're going to catch those
reschedules.
You're going to catch
the person that was like,
actually, it's, it's going to make
more sense for us next week.
Cause I haven't even talked to my
boss yet about what the budget is
for this, or actually it's going
to make more sense tomorrow.
Cause I forgot I have a doctor's
appointment today, or actually I
have
this as opposed to that.
If you catch the reschedules,
you're going to have such a higher
likelihood of actually getting
them back on calendar because for
whatever reason, if people
reschedule or if people miss the
appointment, even if it's for an
earnest reason, like a doctor's
appointment, they have like this
weird social anxiety about
reaching back out.
Cause they're
like, Oh fuck.
I kind of did this guy dirty.
Like I'm nervous to reach back out
to him.
So it's not
about these text messages and
starting a conversation as soon as
possible, being responsible for
all 80% of the
people that could show up.
It's like 60% probably would have
anyways, but we can increase that
show
rate from 60% to 80% just by
starting the conversation sooner
rather than later.
All right.
So text one and two, pretty
simple.
Hey name, Dan from client
Ascension here.
The reason I put send is like just
text like a human, you know, quick
message, send quick message, send
like people double text like that,
as opposed to just sending a long
text.
You see the zoom link inside of
the counter invite morning of the
call, essentially sharing this.
The reason why you want to say,
let me know if you have any
trouble with the link.
And you can also look at this.
Same thing.
Send pretty quick.
Do you see the zoom link inside of
the counter invite?
The reason why I'm not going to
say,
I'm just going for a quick
question here as opposed to trying
to get them over assets too
quickly is because with the new
iOS updates, if I send somebody
something that even if that's
iPhone, iPhone, and they haven't
had previous communication with
me, that link is not going to show
up as clickable.
The moment they respond.
The link then shows up as
clickable.
So, but before that it's plain
text.
So by having like a very clear
question, uh, do you see the zoom
link inside of the counter invite?
Yes.
Cool.
After that, I'm going to send them
over the VSL so they can respond.
Uh, and then if it's like, okay,
last chance, they haven't
responded to anything yet.
Morning of the call.
I'm still just going to say, let
me know if you have any trouble
with the link.
So maybe they copy and paste it,
or maybe they're like, yeah, this
link doesn't work.
But then as soon as they send that
text message, the link works.
Even if it was a previous text
message.
So it's a little bit of a cat and
mouse game where you're just
trying to get them to respond so
that you can send over things
because you're looking at this.
You're like, well, Dan, what does
this do aside from making sure you
see the counter invite?
It usually elicits a response,
which then allows us to send over
links, which will then be
clickable.
So let me know if you have any
questions on this.
Uh, only other thing I would add
is.
It's been night and day when our
sales guys shifted their mindset
from, I'm just going to talk to
this person on the call and see
how it goes to, I'm going to try
to talk to this person as soon as
they book.
And just be proactive about the
conversation.
Their calendar efficiency is way
better.
Meaning like they're catching
reschedules earlier.
Their show rate in general is
better.
And even their conversations are
better because usually these
people share a little bit of
context.
So make sure you're doing this and
make sure via text, you're really
making an effort to get to these
people as quickly as possible.
The last thing that I'll say is if
you have this email that has a
call to action.
Um, you have this email, you have
this email, um, yeah, the text,
they haven't opened any emails.
They haven't responded to any
emails.
text.
I would also recommend just giving
these guys a quick call in the
morning.
Uh, it just to remind them of the
appointment.
Once again, it's, it's, it's, it's
one of those situations where
either it's like, yep, cool.
I'm ready, man.
So no harm, no foul.
This person wasn't going to show
up.
Okay.
That's also cool.
I'd rather find that out now at
the beginning of my day, as
opposed to the end.
So I can get that off my calendar
and get something else more
productive in there, or it's a
reschedule.
We catch the reschedule.
So there's a lot of work.
There's a lot of stuff, um, that
goes on before the call.
So I'm happy that this is a
dedicated video of its own, but
let me know if you guys have any
questions on all this.
Of course, I'm going to link this
document as well.
Thanks guys.