What's going on guys pumped for
this video because it's going to
be an absolute game changer to
help
you guys increase your close rate
especially for those people who
feel like the discovery is going
well the pitch is going well but
we just can't get somebody to
commit on the call i can't
overstate
its importance especially in b2b
sales which is why even though a
lot of this is baked into the
script with the roi based closing
logic part i want to make a whole
video dedicated to it so you
guys know exactly how to present
on a call to the point where you
basically can't mess it up and
then
with the objection handling that's
where we clean up any of those
remaining concerns which listen
guys it's unavoidable there's
going to be objections that's part
of the game if there
weren't we would just have a vsl
and a checkout page but there's a
reason why people talk about
this so much because it genuinely
is important the good thing is i'm
going to teach you guys how to
handle objections and understand
it from first principles so you
don't you don't have to write
out or memorize 50 60 100
different canned objection
responses that don't work it's
going to teach you
guys the framework to handle any
objection because there's only a
select few of real objections but
they're framed a bunch of
different ways if you just use
canned comebacks they don't work
that well
if you understand the principles
behind it regardless of how the
prospect phrases it you're not
going to be
two-faced and it's going to take
reps like anything else but keep
coming back to this guide and i
promise
you you guys will get way way
better at objection handling so
let's just get into it i started
off with just
quick intro when selling to
business owners they're only going
to buy because they think the
service will make them more money
so showcasing roi to a prospect on
the call is crucial for getting
the prospect to buy on the call
pretty straightforward that said
most of the time there will be
objections
but don't panic we're going to
show you how to solve those two so
let's just talk about why using
roi-based closing logic works in
general it's because there's two
types of persuasion right and it's
going to help most with the
logical persuasion specifically
the logical persuasion helps the
prospect
justify the decision hey this
makes sense it's based on numbers
it's based on what type of return
am i going to see it's based on
comparison hey you guys are
currently spending this much when
you could
be spending this much or you guys
are only doing this amount of
outreach when you could be doing
this
amount of outreach and then facts
all right so that can come in a
bunch of different forms but it's
pretty hard to argue with facts
right then there's going to be
emotional persuasion and this is
going to
make your prospect want to act
this is based on pain fomo
opportunity costs relief trust
pain hey if you
guys let the situation continue on
for another six months how's that
going to impact the business
fomo hey this is a strategy every
big company in your space is using
how much money do you think
you're leaving on the table if you
guys don't try your hand at
content opportunity costs hey
right
now your guys churn rate is 30 if
you guys don't get that down in
the next three months like if you
could get it down to 10 and you
decide not to by using something
like this how much money are you
leaving on the table relief hey
what would you look like what
would your life look like if we
took
this much work off your plate so
you guys could just focus on
closing calls as opposed to
generating
no leads trust that's going to
come in a number of different
forms but obviously there needs to
be
trust in order for somebody to
check out and pay on the call
which is what we're optimizing for
whenever we're going through the
sales training in general you're
going to get the close when you
combine both so that they can one
justify the decision and two want
to do it right now which are two
distinct things right like i can
know that i should go to the gym
but a lot of times if i don't want
to
go to the gym i'm just not going
to do it now 10 of the people will
come to the call already wanting
to act those are the lay downs
those are the layups whatever you
want to call them as long as this
logically makes sense to them
those types of people will buy but
if you're shooting for a 30 40
close
rate wherever you guys need to be
at and cool thing is we're going
to help you guys track and know
your
numbers so you're going to be able
to see okay if my show rate is
this my close rate is this my
average cash collected is this you
guys are going to be able to make
your own solid targets for your
close rate the other 20 to 30
percent in this instance you're
going to need a close and they
will need the emotional persuasion
along with the justification once
again like it's one thing to
think yeah i should do this it's
another thing entirely to think i
should do this and i also want
to do this right now which like i
said we're going to have to use
some of this and once again we're
going to get to that in the latter
half of the video now some people
are more emotional buyers some
people are more logical buyers
when we're selling the business
owners though even the business
owners
that are more emotional buyers
want to seem like they're more
logical buyers just because for
whatever reason they think it's
going to make them seem more
competent but what that means is
if i'm
selling to emotional and logical
buyers and the logical buyers
really do need to see the roi
and the emotional buyers want to
act like they are logical buyers
in either case showcasing the roi
is going to help them close the
deal right it could just be a gut
feeling that they're operating off
of
it could be general trust but
you'll start to notice you
showcase that and they're like oh
okay cool
like the mr you know analytical
business owner who's really just
making decisions emotionally
if he sees that his emotions are
going to sway in our favor right
and for the sake of closing a deal
on the call it's super important
to show the numbers because if
you've ever heard we need to run
the numbers
or do our due diligence in what
scenario would we be better off
with them doing it off the call as
opposed to live on the call right
there with us almost never right
and even if somebody says like
hey we need to run the numbers we
need to do the diligence after
seeing this you can say hey mr
prospect here's here's my concern
if you don't mind if i share some
thoughts yeah go ahead dan
i've seen this go well and i've
seen this go poorly and usually
when it goes poorly is when i'm
not in
the room when that conversation is
happening because obviously you
guys are experts at your service
i'm an
expert at mine i know what type of
numbers we're seeing on average so
i'll be an open book super
transparent while you guys are
running the numbers i can help you
go through that right now we can
just
have an open honest conversation
to see if it makes sense to move
forward or not you want to
just do that now if you've got a
couple minutes like it's worth
pushing in order to run the
numbers
with them which we can do in a
number of different ways and just
honestly talk to them a lot of
times
on calls especially when we're
talking about budget i'll just
open up like a google doc with
them
and talk about okay considering
the roi because i'm in there to
add that piece you guys just tell
me
the numbers we're going to figure
out if this works or not but once
again we want to do this on the
call
so how do we do this on the call
number one first step show them
the numbers so you can do
this using roi calculator i talked
about that in a previous video
daniel's also talked about that
as well we can do this via price
anchoring i've talked about that
in a previous video once again
that's like hey typically if you
have a super deliverable heavy
offer it would cost you this much
let's say you're a content plus
video editing like everything
that's involved a to z you could
talk
about hey typically this would be
a ten thousand dollar a month
higher we do this for only three
thousand dollar a month offer
stacking you guys have seen this
with presentations like her mosey
hey this
typically costs 35 000 this costs
70 000 this costs 100 000 and you
get it for the low price of
5 000 social proof that shows real
quantifiable results once again if
you don't have this yet
just keep it in mind as a goal to
work towards what i mean by real
quantifiable results is in the
form
of clients revenue usd that's what
people want to see because we've
put out hundreds of case studies
sometimes we don't get those
things we've always noticed that
the case studies where people
actually
talk about how much more money
they made works exponentially
better than somebody talking about
hey i got
more views i got more leads i was
super satisfied this person's
great once again those things are
better than nothing but if we have
those quantifiable results we can
also use them because then it
becomes
an argument of hey billy was able
to add 15k a month in his revenue
tom was adding 10k a month
in his revenue jim was adding
twenty thousand dollars a month in
his revenue when they came to the
call
similar to you they've never tried
paid ads before so i guess if
you're working with the same team
and we're implementing the same
strategy do you see any reason you
wouldn't see similar results
and then we can get like next
level jujitsu closing if we're if
we're talking about uh
you know how we want to attack
kind of like the identity crisis
if somebody's like really worried
like i don't know if it worked for
my business specifically we can
talk about what the variable
is because the variable is not
their business model a lot of the
times because all three of those
guys
could add business models and if
they hadn't worked with you
beforehand then they wouldn't have
become case studies we can get
this guy to realize like hey he's
the variable so if they're ready
and
willing to put in the work and you
guys are doing the same thing then
they need to be comfortable
investing their business in order
to make that decision anyways that
was just like a quick little rant
and aside not the important thing
the important thing and the bonus
as i mentioned it here is we need
to build up an overwhelming amount
of evidence that this makes sense
for them so even the most
skeptical
buyers have a hard time
disagreeing for most of you guys
just starting out uh or even you
know just as
a starting point for basically
anybody i think the roi calculator
is probably the best way to do
this
and then start to sprinkle in
social proof with real
quantifiable results as you guys
start to gather
that because it's not one strategy
the other it's not an roi
calculator or case studies or
price
hankering or offer stacking it's
all of them like if we combine all
of them that's the best form of
this
right now obviously if you have
too much to the point where it's
taking 10 minutes yeah let's
trim it down a little bit and then
just throw an extra if we need to
as an objection handling mechanism
but the more the better here right
because it's like you are a lawyer
presenting your case the more
evidence the more solid the more
you're going to be closing deals
and collecting cash so step two
now
that you've presented the evidence
let's say you brought up the roi
calculator ask them if they
believe
that they're going to get those
results because showing somebody
the roi calculator them saying yep
that makes sense and then you just
ask them for the sale is a miss
that now i've talked about this at
the end of the pitch video we
always want to ask for the sale
but in this case we want to first
ask them if they believe they're
going to get those results because
somebody's saying yep
makes sense cool got it that that
doesn't yes they can understand
the numbers but if they don't
believe
that this is going to help them
get to their goals then it doesn't
matter right i can believe it
could
work for somebody but not believe
it'll work for myself and i'm
still not going to buy so the way
that you can ask that question
very simply is hey so based on
these numbers that we're seeing
here do you
see any reason we wouldn't be able
to work with you on this package
in order to get you to your goal
of 20 calls a month right and if
they think no i don't see any
reason they kind of mentally
default to
a yes right so now let's go into
step three which is all based on
the response to step two
if it's a certain yes lay out the
onboarding steps we kind of talked
about this as well
make them seem valuable with quick
wins that you want to highlight if
you can if you can paint the
onboarding as a valuable thing it
kills two birds with one stone one
it makes them want to do this
more because the next step is a
value to them but two laying out
the onboarding steps in general
gives them the clarity that they
need to move forward we don't want
to have our prospect have
any fear of the unknown because
that within itself can keep them
from closing so if it's a certain
yes
full conviction yeah dude i think
it's absolutely going to work lay
out the onboarding steps make
them seem valuable with quick wins
and ask for the sale if it's an
uncertain yes which trust me is
not
a yes it's almost always a no but
if it's an uncertain yes yeah i
mean i think this could work or
yeah uh yeah i could see this
possibly working once again if we
just take ourself out of the
sales conversation and we apply
this to any other area of life
let's say you're asking your
girlfriend
if you want to go get pizza and
she's like yeah i think i could
see myself getting pizza or yeah
you
know i think i think pizza could
be good you'd be like hey why
don't you why don't you want to
get
pizza right because that does not
mean a yes that's not how normal
people talk but for whatever
reason
and it's it's usually because
people are just hungry to close
the deal and they they want to
have an optimistic mindset to be
okay yes cool move on to the next
thing do not do that in this case
if it's an uncertain yes let's
challenge them back and say okay
why why do you think you want to
do
this they'll start to sell
themselves on the logical reasons
they'd want to do this hey you
know you guys
have good case studies um yeah
this is like way more volume than
we've ever done seems like you've
helped other similar people in the
space they're going to start to
sell themselves on the logical
reasons on the roi on the case
studies that you guys have the
facts the comparisons as i
mentioned
earlier now once we've established
the logical reasons now let's
gauge where they're at emotionally
okay cool so considering because
once again we're kind of just
repeating the rewards back to them
at this
point considering the fact that
you think this will that you'll
see you know an increase in calls
because of the fact that we're
doing way more volume right you'll
see x result for abc reasons
is there any reason you wouldn't
want to get started on this today
right just once again this is kind
of
like a soft ask for the sale but
the reason why we're doing this is
because even though i almost know
whenever it's an uncertain yes
that they're going to say no this
is where we can get the true
objection
which is great we're going to talk
about objection handling in a
minute here but if we get the real
objection we basically you know a
lot of times uh the biggest issue
is just isolating the objection
and a lot of times if they appeal
to the logical reason they'd want
to do this we've tackled that
uncertainty reasons so going on to
the objection i'm getting a little
bit ahead of myself it's probably
going to be fear timing partner or
money most of the time right once
again uncertainty would probably
be
the next thing i'm going to go
over where they just don't think
it's going to work but if this
person's uncertain yes and they
can actually articulate why they
would want to do this we
probably have the uncertainty once
solved so it's probably going to
be fear which goes hand in hand
with uncertainty but it's a little
bit different timing partner or
money there's not that many
objections in the world once again
this is why i teach people the
framework because they can frame
it a bunch of different ways but
it's typically just one of these
reasons here now if it's an i'll
think
about it we need to push past that
and isolate it like i'll think
about it as not a real objection
once again i'm going to dive
deeper into that in a minute here
if they respond to step two with
anything outside of yes or an
uncertain uneasy yes then we need
to call it out and that's one of
those
things that actually gets pretty
easy the longer you're in sales
but it's just a matter of kind of
like breaking the fourth wall and
just calling it up like hey man it
doesn't sound like you're super
certain and you're not gonna hurt
my feelings man i i get it you're
probably in sales as well it
sounds
like you're not 100 sure this is
going to help you fix your lead
generation issue to get you guys
more calls i guess my questions is
well you know what's coming up for
you that's giving you some doubt
once again we want to we want to
get that real objection out of it
we want to isolate the
objection because that's the first
step in solving any objection now
step four if we've done steps
one through three correctly you've
either a already closed the deal
great or b we need to isolate and
handle the objection itself right
and and you're you're probably
already made most of progress if
you're in this second category
here and actually isolating the
objection and then c you know this
is
where we you know we have to one
isolate it and then two solve it
so let's go into how i solve
objections i solve objections uh
and this is something that i came
up with called the xyz aside
method but if you've watched any
sales videos this is very similar
to a lot of the other stuff that
you've probably seen before um and
i'm going to dive deeper into why
that is and you know why these
principles are taught widely it's
it's usually because they work
quite well right isolate and
handle any
objection confidently without
having to remember canned
comebacks that don't actually work
that's the goal
with this xyz aside method so
let's just start off high level
the most common pitfalls when
handling
objections are one not sniffing
out smoke screens and two not
isolating the objection
right so not sniffing out smoke
screen an example of that would be
somebody says i need to think
about
it cool what do you need to think
about uh well if you can send me
over the email that'd be great
okay cool man send you over the
email when can i expect you to
hear back once again like we
didn't
we didn't sniff out that smoke
screen of the i'll think about it
we just accepted it at face value
we asked them what information
they wanted to see we sent it over
and we established some timeline
for a follow-up not a good idea
right so first off we need to
sniff out those smoke screens and
if
somebody says once again like an
uncertain yes yeah i think i think
i want to do this if we just take
that face value great when do you
think you want to do it oh we'll
get in touch with you next week
you're never going to hear back
from that person i promise you and
then if we do call out
things and we sniff out that smoke
screen then we need to isolate the
objection
two there are only four real
objections right and these these
are a little bit different but
i kind of grouped them together
here but it's partner finance
money as i called it earlier fear
uncertainty and timing right the
reason why these kind of go
together is uncertainty i'm not
sure if this
is going to work um fear is more
so just like even if i do think it
would work i'm just a little bit
scared to do it in timing right i
need to think about it is not a
real objection that's a smoke
screen if someone says i need to
think about it do not ask them
what they need to think about
they're
politely telling you no so asking
what they need to think about
makes no sense and fails to sniff
out
the smoke stream instead say
totally fair now before you go
away and think about it this is
really
important now before you go away
and think about it because if
somebody says i'll think about it
their guard's up i don't want to
get closed so i'll think about it
on my terms and i'll get back
to you that's what they're trying
to say really so that little line
of now before you go away and
think about it that's going to get
them to lower their guard and
lower their sales resistance
because
i've already prefaced that they
can go away and think about it so
it's like i'm not going to hold
you hostage on this call it's kind
of like i'm pointing the gun at
the guy it's like okay let's
lower the gun for a second here so
it first emphasizes with their
stance then lowers the
sales resistance by prefacing that
they can go away and think about
it we're not going to hold them
hostage on the call then say
before you go away and think about
it do you think this is something
that
can actually get you to their
goals because let's say they might
actually have something to think
about most of the time they don't
right it's just a polite way to
tell you no but even if they did
have something to think about if
they don't believe your service
this is a double negative so let
me
change that is something that's
going to work for them they're not
going to join anyways right even
if
they did legitimately have to
think about some logistics in
terms of how this would apply if
they don't
first think that this is going to
work there's no point ask them
what they need to think about
because if they don't think it's
going to work they're not going to
do it right however if they
think this can hit their goals
this can help them hit their goals
ask them why they think that once
again it's it's just kind of like
a quick return get them to start
appealing to like the emotional or
the logical reasons usually the
logical reasons that they want to
do it they'll start to sell
themselves and we can ask okay
cool so if you're confident that
you can this can help you achieve
this goal what's coming up for you
that makes you feel like you need
to think about it you can see
it's pretty similar to what we
already said up top then we can
handle the isolated issue right if
they
don't think that this can help
them hit their goals or they sound
uncertain let's call it out and
isolate
why right so at this point if they
don't think it's going to help
them hit their goals it's probably
an
uncertainty objection right so we
need to call that out so we're
going to get the uncertainty in a
second but
we're actually going to start with
a partner objection now once again
you'll notice the xyz
aside method because i'm almost
displacing the reason why they
tell me they're not going to buy
right
now and focus on the important
stuff which is do they think this
is going to work so if it's
partner
objection i need to talk to my
business first let's not just give
up and book follow-up call that's
lazy
let's first empathize with their
stance again but ask them if they
think this can help them hit
their goals so you could say
something like no worries i've got
a business partner myself so i
get it but before you go away and
talk with john i've got to ask in
your opinion specifically do you
think this is something that can
help you achieve xyz goal if
there's uncertainty once again
let's call
it out if they are confident great
now let's ask them what john's
objection may be awesome to hear
i know you're running lead
generation so if you're confident
that this is what you guys need
then i'm
curious is there any reason you
think john would be against this a
lot of times they'll just voice
their own objection that they were
too afraid to say because now it's
like i don't have the heart
to tell this guy but if it's not
me telling the guy it's my
business partner it may or may not
exist
once again we can ask about you
know different people in the
decision making party in the
discovery
so we don't get hit with these
people that don't exist at the end
of the call but once again even
if there is a real business
partner a lot of times they'll
just say their own objection
so they can displace the blame on
somebody else other times john the
business partner in this
scenario may actually have an
objection either way it's helpful
to solve it right so finally let's
say there's no reason john would
be against it mr prospect who
we're talking to is confident
this will work he just needs to
get john's sign off on the
investment itself then it becomes
a lot
easier if it's just a matter of
permission there's nothing else
which is super common
then it becomes a lot easier to
compress a follow-up timeline
which is super important because
time
kills deals like guys i tell my
guys this all the time especially
when it hits thursday friday those
are scary hours i'm like guys i'm
telling you push harder on these
days so that the deal gets wrapped
up this week because something
happens even when prospects that
genuinely wants to do it when
the weekend goes by they go out
they gamble or they they have a
big night at a dinner or a bar and
all
of a sudden they just kind of
forget like i spent a lot of money
this week i don't know if i'm in
the
mood to spend money on on monday
right so push these guys
especially you know when there's
that deadline
like a holiday or a weekend coming
up but once again if the person is
actually sold and it's just a
matter of
permission it becomes a lot easier
to get the sign off on the call or
as soon as possible which is key
because time feels kills deals
what you'll find is that you know
the reason why i want to displace
this
partner place a partner aside and
essentially say hey cool and
before you go away and talk to
your
partner i'm curious do you
specifically think this is what
you guys need because what you'll
find is a lot
of times you still end up going to
follow up but if you actually have
this person i'm talking to on
the call 100 sold your success
rate will be way higher because
they'll become a champion within
their company for you right and if
there's a follow-up call where
most of the time there should be a
follow-up call i may make a video
just called save yourself time
book the follow-up call because in
basically every scenario where
there's something that still needs
to be discussed and they're not
100 of the way there there should
be a follow-up call right if
nothing else it's just going to
place
a deadline for them to get back to
you which is super important if
you kind of let that go or you
just you know generally like hey
yeah get back to me by the end of
the week they don't do it
right but if this person i had on
the first call is 100 sold this
person is going to become my
teammate on the follow-up call
what i mean by they'll become
champions within the company if i
was
to run something by my business
partner daniel or andre or
christian if i come to them and i
say hey
i think this uh this you know
sales consulting program would be
pretty good helping my department
and they're like okay they're
always just going to ask how much
is it uh it's twenty thousand
dollars
so it's an expensive one if
they're like well you know do you
think it's a good move if i'm like
yeah i think it would work they're
like okay like we've got other
priorities let's focus on this but
if i'm a hundred percent sold and
i'm like guys no this is gonna be
game changer it's going to
increase
our close rate from twenty percent
to thirty percent you guys can
look at the numbers and see what
that would do to our company
they're gonna be like okay yeah
dude like we trust you go do it so
that's what i mean by champion
within your company which only
happens if you actually get that
commitment you actually sell the
person 100 on the call now on a
follow-up call they're your
teammate on that call and the
times when you don't have this
person 100 sold it's very
difficult
right because then i'm going into
the follow-up call and it's one v
two as opposed to two v one
follow-up calls are really easy
when it's me and the business
partner who are on the same team
because
that person's already sold
convincing another business
partner they're very very hard
when it's
me convincing two skeptical
parties there's a lot of dynamics
that go on there once again that
could
be a whole other video just
talking about how to make each
person heard and make sure there's
no
skeptical party or make no silent
party on the call just because
then it's it always ends up and
hey
we're going to discuss this
offline but trust me if it's one
of those situations where you talk
to
a business partner first then it's
a follow-up call with all the
business partners on there
it's a lot easier when it's two v
one versus one v two so that's the
partner objection with the
money objection i can't afford
this is what they're essentially
saying uh so we call the finance
up
here let's just change this to
money but same thing with the
money objection i can't afford
this
what i'm gonna respond is all good
if you can't don't worry man we
don't want to put anybody in a
situation of financial hardship
but i'm curious money aside is
this something you're 100
confident
would get you to xyz goal what i'm
doing here is i'm isolating the
money as the actual objection
because anything's too expensive
if i don't think it's gonna work
right if i don't if i don't think
something's gonna help my business
i'm gonna pay five dollars for it
let alone five thousand
so let's make sure money's
actually the problem if it's
confident yes
then i'm gonna say awesome so if
you're confident this can help you
achieve xyz goal
then would you be open to having
just like a quick honest
conversation about your finances
so i can see if we have an option
that works for you because i also
don't want to let you you guys
get the help you need even further
if we can help you out right and
they'll usually just be like yeah
okay that makes sense right if
we've already established that
this is going to get them to
this outcome if they're thinking
about the return as opposed to the
initial investment they're going
to
be open to having that real
conversation with you and then we
can kind of just break down what
numbers
look like right sometimes they
were looking at a smaller larger
package that can actually afford
a smaller package or sometimes
it's like they're actually pretty
close on budget and i'm like okay
dude i mean we talked about the
fact that you are confident that
this can help you guys out and
based on what i've seen for other
similar companies i am too is
there anywhere else on the
marketing or
sales side where you feel like
your budget isn't being used
effectively because we're only a
thousand
dollars off at this point like i
can get real into the nitty-gritty
i've talked to a lot of guys
about how much money is in their
bank account their business bank
account how much money they're
spending on all other vendors just
because before i did that i made
sure that money was actually the
problem and i just framed it this
way cool man like if we're
confident that it's going to get
you
result return then would you be
open to having just like a quick
honest conversation about your
finances
where they're at and they're
usually going to say yes if they
are actually sold on this and if
they're not
once again that goes to
uncertainty we call it out timing
objection this all looks great
but yeah we're not ready to move
on anything for a couple months no
worries at all once again lower
sales resistance you guys see the
common trends coming up in these
no worries at all but i'm curious
timing aside are you actually
confident that this can help you
achieve xyz if they are confident
yes then
once again i'm going to reiterate
my typical timeline to see results
and i'm being conservative
because if i'm being conservative
with my timeline to see results
let's say i'm uh
man i hate i hate that i keep
using cold email as an example for
you guys but let's say i'm selling
cold
email if i'm taking two weeks to
set up and launch and it's 10 days
to get up to full speed and then
it's initial testing i'm not going
to project that they'll get
results till the second half
of month two and a lot of times
people are saying hey i'm not
ready to start in this right now
but if
i remind them of our typical
timeline versus theirs i can ask
them like hey when you say a
couple months
are you guys looking to take on
sales calls in a couple months
months or just starting a new
initiative
in a couple months because we know
in our back pocket if they say
they're just looking to if they're
looking to get sales calls in a
couple months then they should be
getting started now right so it's
a
good chance to set proper
expectations while also being able
to make a good argument that they
should
get started sooner rather than
later if they seem to be delaying
for no good reason it's not a
timing
issue it's a priorities issue
right if this doesn't seem super
logical in terms of why they're
delaying
it's not a timing issue it's a
priority issue which typically
falls under fear and uncertainty
so we need to isolate and handle
that instead right and we can do
that in a number of different
ways hey i understand you're super
busy and it's probably never going
to sound like a good time
but you mentioned that your goal
is to get to fifty thousand
dollars a month in revenue
by the end of the year and just
based on our timeline those types
of results are going to take
four or five months based on the
growth you guys are looking to
achieve so it really makes sense
to
start looking into this sooner
rather than later i guess i'm
curious what are you guys
focusing your your bandwidth on
right now that would prevent you
guys from doing something that
would get you more calls on
calendar right once again now i'm
questioning their priorities as
opposed
to the timing of it because i've
already kind of gone the first
route which is make sure that
they're confident and then remind
them of our timeline to deliver
results versus their timeline in
terms of when they want to see
results right now finally uh
uncertainty and let me pause this
here
so getting into fear and
uncertainty the most difficult
part about handling uncertainty
objections
we'll start there is getting used
to calling out in the first place
talked about this a little bit
earlier but once we build that
muscle not being afraid to have
uncomfortable conversations
because
that's what we get paid to do
right and if you're not a closer
but you're doing founder-led sales
like
that is where all the gains come
from we need to welcome that we
need to get comfortable with it
trust me it is a huge huge payoff
if you do then it's pretty
straightforward once you do that
we need
to quantify their uncertainty
though which can be done because
uncertainty is is very qualitative
as
opposed to quantitative so
something that we can do here and
once again this is one of those
sales
tactics that you've probably seen
before is quantify their
uncertainty which can be done
through one
through ten time check and then
isolate why they're not 100
confident this will work for them
if we can
get them to a point where they
want to do it that's where fear is
going to come in but a quick
example
of a temp check is okay cool man
and i know that uh you know this
is something that you think you
may
want to do but it doesn't seem
like you're 100 of the way there i
guess on a scale of one to ten
zero being
gave me off this call i never want
to see dan again to ten being yes
this is absolutely the
decision that my business needs to
make where would you say you're at
a lot of times they're going to
give you a seven everybody likes a
seven okay cool well that's that's
not a zero um i guess why so high
is the seven uh you know you guys
do some good stuff i i like that
you're doing more volume than i've
ever done i like the fact that you
got some case studies with similar
businesses once again it's the
same
stuff right they're they're
appealing to the logical reason
that they'd want to do it then
let's attack
that gap okay cool i mean that i
would i would agree with all those
reasons so i guess if we can
get you extra salt and you
highlighted abc reasons which i
agree with i guess what's holding
you back
from being a ten and that's where
the real objection comes out right
so we can solve the objection from
there but if it's not one of these
objections it's just generally
fear we're still not able to do it
we
can just ask them like hey mr
prospect i gotta ask is it is it
the value or the price here
what's holding you back we'll make
this a yes right but if i ask them
what's if it's a value
or the price a lot of times people
are just going to say it's it's
the value okay well you know where
aren't you seeing the value here
we kind of talked about the return
or it's the price you know the
the price is usually what they
default to so sometimes they say
value or price but usually
even if you cover the value and
start to handle that objection but
then it comes down to the price
it's just they're fearful of
parting with the cash that's it
right so now it's fear that
they're right
at the edge but they don't want to
make that jump we can get into the
problem symptom dynamic which
is probably something that you may
have seen before or this is all
new to you guys but essentially
them being confident they'll see a
return on something and still
being fearful of it is
is doing it is not the problem
right the problem is they don't
have enough money
right so if we've covered the
value part and they're confident
that they're going to see a return
on
this and they're still fearful
that's not the problem it's a
symptom of the problem them not
making enough
money causing them to believe that
our price is too much that's the
problem them not making money
right so so that's it i i would
just typically open up this
conversation by asking them hey
man
i guess you know you seeing the
value in this and agreeing that
this will work for your business
to
get you guys to xyz gold but still
thinking this is too much or too
expensive i gotta ask do you think
that's the problem or the symptom
and they'll usually be pretty
confused it'll be like i guess
it's a
problem or symptom what are you
talking about hey do you mind if i
share some thoughts this is just
like
permission-based something you
mind if i share some thoughts on
that yeah just based on what i've
seen
working with a bunch of other
businesses if you think that this
is going to be a good fit for your
business if you think that it's
going to get you to the goal and
you see the return right because
this isn't going to be expensive
in comparison to this return that
we're both confident that you'd
get and you still not being able
to make that investment that's not
the problem the problem is
that you're not making enough
money or the problem is that
you've never done anything like
this before
so just fear is blocking it you
thinking that this is too much or
too expensive that's just a
symptom
of the problem would you agree
once again more permission-based
selling like i'm getting them to
buy
and they're starting to come to my
side of the table so the question
is how does someone become
the person that thinks your price
isn't too much it's by making the
commitment to do something like
this right and at this point we
want to acknowledge the fact that
hey this is scary i agree it's
it's a
little like i remember the first
time when i made an investment
like this it is scary you can even
talk
about making an investment in
client ascension if you want but
you also because it's our moral
and ethical
responsibility to get these guys
over the finish line if we both
agree that it can help them
we also want to be real with them
by letting them know that that
problem won't get solved unless
they
make a decision based on the
return that they think they'll see
right it's like in this scenario
the only
way to get from point a to point b
is to make that jump that they're
afraid of making right now and
it's never going to feel like the
right time this is where we get
real with them it's it's never
going to
feel like the right time to go
through that transformation
because the first time you do
anything even if you're a kid
riding a bike it's going to feel
foreign right so if we're real
with
them in that scenario we kind of
break down the problem symptom
dynamic and then we get into the
point where it's just like if we
both see the value in this is you
thinking that this is too much is
that
the problem or the symptom we
agree that it's a symptom okay so
i guess in this scenario if we
want to become the person that
sees something that will be a good
investment for the business and
they
see the return in it what do they
do in this scenario
right and i even wrote out a
question here what's the person
that makes investments that
are good for the business
regardless of if the number seems
to hire not doing the scenario
the person they do it okay what
person you want to be john that's
a little bit of like
an identity close and that's a
little bit more on the emotional
side but once again it works so
what's the person that makes
investments that are good for the
business regardless of
if the number seems too high in
the scenario do they do it right
i've closed a good amount of
people
with that one as well so let me
know if this makes sense uh all a
through z you guys are going to
get
this document of course but down
to have any questions because once
again i would rather you
guys understand this as opposed to
memorize hundreds of canned
objection comebacks because if you
understand this stuff from first
principle trust me you're going to
get really good at just
diagnosing and just figuring out
okay it's it's pretty
straightforward let's displace it
figure out
if these guys actually think they
can get the result okay they do
think they can get the result
great
now let's isolate that partner
objection now let's isolate that
timing objection now let's isolate
that fear objection and let's go
from there with these strategies
laid out below i'm gonna wrap
there
guys hit me up if you have any
questions of course but hopefully
you guys got some value in this
one peace