What's going on guys in this video
i'm going to be going over three
things one how to set up your
calendar inside to go high level
two how to create a basic
automation inside to go high level
keeping
the theme of the calendar for this
video i'm just going to show you
how to create an opportunity in
your pipeline when somebody books
in a meeting and then three and
most importantly where i want
to spend most of my time in this
video is talking about how to get
as many people who book in a call
to show up to the call as possible
with good pre-call messaging in
this messaging i'm showing
you it's going to be very similar
to the messaging that we've used
to get consistently mid 60 65 66
show rates from ice cold traffic
and get 80 plus show rates from
warm traffic so something that
we've
taught tried tested i've tinkered
with things so much to get the
show rate as high as possible and
this is essentially what we land
on now before i dive into the
calendar stuff and the automation
stuff i'm
going to run through that pretty
quickly just because you guys can
be resourceful i mean if
you're starting a business or
you're scaling a business you kind
of need to be resourceful
it's maybe the most important
skill especially in the beginning
uh so i don't want to over
complicate
something that's rather simple
anyways let's just go into the
settings here uh you can see if
you go to
my profile scroll down here you
should be able to connect your
google calendar um usually i think
when you
hit add new it's going to take you
to the integrations tab which is
right over here or where is this
thing
settings integrations right over
here connect your google calendar
pretty straightforward right so
mine's already connected um also
with the email services portion
here going back settings real
quick uh i typically would
recommend just setting up a
two-way sync which
you can see here uh you can turn
off enable reply tracking you just
put reply to the regular address
that you're sending from um and on
the my profile side where is it
right here is where the two-way
sync
would be now you don't want to use
this for email marketing in the
sense of like a newsletter you
also don't want to use this for
cold email because that's going to
put your primary domain at risk
so absolutely do not do that go
through the steps to set up a
separate separate domain for that
we're
going to be showing you how to run
super high level cold outreach
anyways completely outside of the
system and for email marketing
like i said uh we may be showing
you how to use something like
convert
kit or constant contact but if you
are going through go high level do
not use this setting
this is really just for one-to-one
personalized outreach i.e somebody
books in a call we're sending
them pre-call messaging or they're
in our pipeline so we're sending
out a sequence that's going to
drip
to them uh slowly as opposed to
massive email blast which once
again could mess up your domain so
do not
use this for that you can set up
both at the same time but know
what you're using for which now if
you're just kind of acting as a
salesperson trying to add some
automation into the one-to-one
communication that's where the
setting can be fine for you
anyways going into the calendar
portion
once you've got that all set up um
you go to calendar settings and i
was just messing around
creating a couple test calendars
anyways you're going to see
something in here uh if you want
to edit the
calendar meeting details you can
add a logo you make the calendar
name so you can have it like uh
you know cold email setup call you
know uh paid ads console whatever
you guys want to name it um
not super super important but you
know you get a little creative uh
you don't you don't want to go
with a virtual coffee chat or
strategy session here assign team
members do this right here um also
if
you guys want to just start from
scratch um and you're planning to
add multiple team members to one
i hate how this is uh not showing
me this thing here let me just go
back and
we'll just create a new calendar
for you guys if you plan to add
multiple team members to it you
can just start with a round robin
even if it's only you to begin if
you're planning to add a closer
pretty soon uh you can just use
yourself as this uh calendar name
you know dan sales calendar
three because i've been messing
around with it and wanted to be
unique anyways uh yeah we'll just
do dan sales
three uh meeting duration 30
minutes set your availability
there cool this is already going
to
check your conflicts uh check for
conflicts guys so you probably saw
on my profile page you can add
multiple calendars to check for
conflicts so if you use more than
one calendar for one job and
another or
multiple companies like i do it
will check on your google calendar
automatically uh so let's just go
into this one and look at the
settings now in terms of
availability i would recommend
having as much
availability as possible like i
said it's going to check for
conflicts so if you want to add a
block from 12 to 1 for lunch or
you're a morning workout person
you want to add a block from 7
to 9 a.m to do that it'll already
factor that in so nobody can book
in at those times um
in terms of slot interval i
typically recommend 30 minutes
here meeting duration 30 minutes
um even
if you typically are like more of
a 45 45 minute person i would just
keep it at 30 minutes um then
i would also just add a buffer
post buffer would be 15 minutes so
this means that if you can only
book
in every 30 minutes somebody books
in at three o'clock for 30 minutes
um since there's a 15 minute
post buffer they can't book in at
3 30 but they could book in at
four o'clock um date range the
chances
of somebody showing up if they
book out more than three four days
they're just going to drop off
precipitously so if you have good
availability if you have a lot of
time and open slots which like i
recommend i would recommend
showing people as many options as
possible i would just put that to
three
days uh minimum scheduling notice
um i would put this to one or two
hours just so they can book in on
that same day if they're a hot
lead let's talk to them but at the
same time i understand you may be
out
about want to be able to get back
into your computer maximum
bookings per day that is for wimps
so
don't do that just kidding if you
get super busy you can set it to
like six bookings per day max
booking
per slot one that's pretty typical
so all this stuff pretty
straightforward like i said uh
forms here
it's just going to collect their
first name last name email phone
and notes if you want to do
anything
else you can do that inside of the
steps here sites forms you just
plug that form instead um in
general
i want to add more friction you
could add less friction so if
you're not using the notes from
here
specifically if you're just
looking at their website for
example you could just add website
as a separate
question or you could just take
off the notes altogether if you're
not looking at them because like i
said
less friction the better consent
box turn that off uh thank you
page ideally i'd recommend
redirecting to a thank you page if
you have one uh to give you an
idea as to what our thank you page
looks like this is pretty high
level complex not something you
need uh if you're just getting
started but you can kind of see
what we're doing here we're we're
making it very stupid simple for
somebody to be like oh okay this
is how i add this to my calendar
here and then we're giving them
frequently asked questions videos
which once again this is not a
requirement but something that
like
it's it's obviously not going to
hurt and you know you guys can
view it for context anyways now we
have
this auto confirm new meetings
make sure this is on uh we don't
want to have to like screen
meetings in
that sense if you did want to
screen meetings to like qualify or
disqualify somebody do that before
they book in do it through a type
form now notifications um this is
something or this is where you're
going to be sending out the email
reminders we don't need this
because it's just going to get
auto confirmed so this is
irrelevant uh but once the
appointment is confirmed which it
will be
automatically you can send out
your first email for here so you
would just do this uh you can just
do
this goes to the context i mean
contact you can sign it you can
also assign it to yourself if you
also
want to see the emails but really
not relevant and you'll put the
copy in here like i said we're
going to
talk about the copy in a second i
actually like this add the
calendar button so i wanted to uh
take that out but i could show you
what we use for ours so click out
of that i don't know what's going
on guys with the not let me scroll
to the top but it's it's bugging
me uh and then also the reminders
so for this i'd recommend doing a
few reminders here so let's just
do email additional emails uh so
for the
contact i would want to send over
a reminder that is
typically let's say 24 hours
before the appointment starts if
they book it on the same day it's
just
not going to send to them and then
i would recommend doing an
additional email
that's going to be
one hour before it starts the
reason why i would want to do that
inside of here as opposed to just
adding
more is because i would want the
email copy to be different you
don't really need to play around
with this at all you just need to
add a subject line once again
we're going to talk about copy
a little bit more but pretty basic
stuff here uh you can customize it
in terms of what you want this
to look like but not much that you
really need to change around here
so pretty straightforward and then
at
the end of it go into calendars
let's click here the share
calendar buttons up here for
whatever reason it's
not allowing me to do that so okay
cool now i can share calendar copy
the link and this is what it's
going to look like
pretty straightforward somebody
can select the time boom name
email phone and i'll show you how
to
create an automation real quick so
that when somebody does book in a
call and opportunity gets
created so what does that look
like let's go into automation i've
already built this we're going to
go back automation i'm going to go
into meeting books create
opportunity it's really this
simple guys
like this is a really easy builder
tool i'm not a technical person by
the way at all if you guys
going to tell with me messing
around now in most these tutorials
videos but trigger customer book
deployment create contact assign
to user us create our update
opportunity add opportunity uh
add owner to the opportunity
pretty straightforward and like on
this stage for example you can see
uh create
update opportunity in this
pipeline in this stage meeting
booked opportunity i just named it
after the
first name opportunity value you
can give it one if you want status
open save all pretty
straightforward
as i was mentioning and you can
see i booked in a couple test
appointments here
and they're all showing up right
inside of here just as i want
right so then i have the meeting
or they
don't show up they can move into
one of these and hopefully we
close the deal moving in there
so now that's done all pretty
straightforward just over 10
minutes here