All right so let me break down the
difference real quick between an
abo or a cbo and which
one you should choose so an abo
is essentially called ad set
budget
optimization and these have
different names inside of the ads
manager but this is what
you're going to hear it referred
to all the time as and then cbo is
campaign
budget optimization
so if you're going to choose a cbo
which sometimes inside of the ad
manager it'll just say campaign
budget other times it'll say
advantage campaign budget
basically what you're telling meta
to do
is you know in any ad campaign
you're going to have the campaign
level
the ad set level where you choose
targeting and different placements
and stuff like that
and then the creative level or the
ad level right three different
levels okay with a cbo
you're placing your budget so
you're saying all right meta on
this campaign i want to spend
a hundred dollars per day on a cbo
you're placing your budget on the
campaign level and let's say you
have two different ad sets you
have ad set one you have ad set
two and then inside of these ad
sets you
have five ads here and you have
the same five ads here with cbo
meta will initially spend a little
bit
equal to both of these ad sets but
it's going to quickly bias
typically towards one so in the
first
hour it might spend equally
towards ad set one and ad set two
and then it's like all right cool
we know
that ad set one based upon all of
our data points on every single
user and by analyzing the ads and
the messaging and the placements
and the targeting options on this
ad set in this set of creatives
we know that ad set one is going
to win so we're going to start to
push the majority of spend towards
ad set one and not much towards ad
set two that's all cbo is is it's
basically you saying hey meta
here's my hundred dollars a day
budget i want you to allocate it
between these ad sets that you see
fit and you think and sit and
spend money on the one that you
think is going to get the most
results
for me as an advertiser so very
simple on that front you know
after five days you might see
literally 450 spent on ad set one
and 50 on ad set two you just have
to trust meta in that case
that's making the right decision i
personally like to default to
cbo's typically unless i'm trying
to
force spend on one ad set and one
set of you know creatives one set
of targeting options
again that's where an abo comes
into play but i usually default
towards cbo especially if i'm
testing different audiences and
i'm testing the same ads within
those ad sets so if i'm trying to
quickly test okay does this set of
messaging or these ads work well
with these different audiences
like which audience is the best
that's when i'll run a cbo now an
abo is
you do now with an abo you do not
place the budget on the campaign
level you place it on the ad set
level so say you have these same
two ad sets you then put fifty
dollars a day here fifty dollars a
day here and meta is going to
spend fifty dollars on ad set one
and spend fifty dollars on ad set
two
right so it's going to spend it
equally depending on how much
money you put here if you put
seventy
five dollars on ad set one it's
going to spend 75 bucks if you put
150 on ad set two it's going to
spend 150 on ad set two it's not
like cbo where it's going to
distribute it depending on how it
sees
fit on these ad sets you're
essentially telling it hey meta i
want you to spend this amount of
money
on these ad sets so this is what i
will do typically if i want to run
some sort of split
test on an account like if i'm
seeing weird behavior with the cbo
i'll test out an abo structure
um or if i have this proven set of
messaging this proven set of
creatives with this proven
audience
i would just ram spend onto that
and just ensure that you know
essentially this ad set gets the
right spend amount that i want
versus doing a cbo so all it is is
literally abo gives you more
control
and cbo gives you less control cbo
you're leaning more on meta abo
you're leaning more on yourself
that's
really it but overall doesn't
really matter um to be honest the
creative is going to win in either
setup or either structure if you
have good ads and a good funnel
and a good offer and a good
messaging
doesn't really matter if you're on
cbo or abo i just want to show you
guys the difference
if you have good ads good funnels
good offer you're going to win in
either setup so it doesn't really
matter