All right, let's talk about what
actually makes a good winning
funnel and really what separates a
winning funnel from a losing
funnel.
So first off, I just want to make
it very clear when I talk
about what a funnel is, is I talk
about everything from click to
close.
So most people look at funnels
like it's just a landing page.
You know, you'll talk to a client
like, yeah, we have a funnel.
And you know, they just pull up
like their main landing page and
stuff like that.
So
I look at a funnel as the entire
experience, pre-click and
post-click that somebody goes
through, right?
So from click to close, they see
your ad, then what happens next on
the funnel,
the landing page, all that stuff,
what happens in the sales process,
what happens after they book in
a call, everything from click to
close.
So that's what I look at in terms
of being a funnel.
So and
again, by being able to have eyes
on that entire thing and input on
that entire thing and influence
over that entire process from
click to close, you become more
valuable to your clients.
And you can
also get them better results
because you can find different
bottlenecks throughout that entire
funnel.
And you can actually get them
again, good results because you're
acting like a marketer.
You're not just some low level
media buyer who's pressing buttons
in the ads manager.
So anyways,
what makes a good funnel, right?
So from click to close, we have
the ad, then we have the landing
pages that we drive them to, which
essentially, you know, is quote
unquote, the funnel that a lot of
people refer to.
Then we have the backend systems.
So like think email flows, think
content remarketing,
stuff like that.
Then we have the sales process.
And then we got where you collect
that cash, that cheddar right on
the backend.
But pretty much from there, what
makes an actual
good funnel from a bad funnel?
So the first is congruency with
messaging.
So think about it this way.
If I
had an ad that said, Hey, I'm
going to help you fix your show
rates.
And then the landing page,
I drive you to says, Hey, we're
going to help you fix your close
rates in your sales process.
That's not too congruent, is it?
Right?
Let's even think of another
example.
Say you run an offer that
helps people stop smoking and say
the ad says something along the
lines of, Hey, look, you know,
you might just have some family
history of, you know, smoking
addictions and stuff like that.
But
you know, right now you're just
maybe enjoying one or two cigars a
month.
And you're like, I just want
to get a grip on this and ensure
that this doesn't turn into a big
nicotine addiction and a big
problem,
right?
Something very light like that on
the ad level.
And then say, you know, it drives
you over to
a landing page that has something
like, yeah, you're a chronic
smoker, you're a chain smoker,
you're going to die.
You have really terrible family
history and stuff like that,
right?
It's
too jarring and it's not congruent
messaging.
So you want to make sure that your
ad says one thing,
your landing page says the same
thing.
Then your backend systems, like
all your emails says the
same thing.
Then your sales process and what
the actual, you know, setters and
closers reach out
with in terms of messaging and
different trust assets and sales
assets says the same thing.
It's
fully congruent.
And then ideally on the sales call
to the initial discovery is about
that same thing
too.
And then from there, of course you
can branch off into other aspects
if it deems fit, but congruency
is huge.
I re I see some people's funnels
where the ads say one thing and
then the landing page says
another thing and they try to like
fit too many characteristics in
the copy on the landing page.
And
the VSL is like this whole big
thing, right?
It's the power of one.
That's a big thing that I like to
really focus on when we're writing
copy, making ads and funnels is
the power of one.
So what exactly is
that now the power of one means
I'm writing for one avatar.
I'm focusing on one message I'm
focusing on
one pain point and I'm focusing on
one solution.
I'll give you another example of
this.
So we had a client
who is running challenge funnels.
So they're selling three day
tickets to a live virtual workshop
where they teach
people how to invest in
multifamily real estate.
So initially when we brought them
on, they had a
offer where it was basically like
they're selling a ticket to this
workshop in this challenge where
they're going to help you invest
in multifamily real estate, plus
help you like drop your taxes with
those properties and everything
like that and show you some tax
strategies.
And it was just really like
convoluted, confusing and weird,
right?
It was like, Hey, we're going to
show you how to
find these multifamily buildings
and then use them to offset your
taxes and then show you these tax
strategies in the back half.
It's like too many things.
There's too many ideas.
There's not one
central through line, not one
central idea.
So what we did was we just slashed
the tax end because we
looked at their sales call
recordings and we looked at why
people were joining their program
in the first
place and ascending and why people
would show up to the event in the
first place.
And it was just
because they wanted to find their
first multifamily property.
That was it.
So all the messaging
was centered around this one idea
of saying, Hey, during this three
day workshop, we're going to
help you find your first
multifamily property that you can
get cash out that you can, that
you can
invest in and get passive monthly
cashflow on.
That was it.
That's the power of one, right?
It wasn't
this weird convoluted, double
ended sort of offer and messaging
and this confusing thing.
It was just
centered around one idea and now
it's just, it's just now centered
around one idea of helping you
find your first multifamily
property that you can buy and
invest in with little cash down.
So way easier
to write all the copy, the through
lines easier.
The ads say the same thing.
The landing page says the
same thing.
It just goes more in depth into it
and how they're going to help you
do it on the challenge.
The backend systems, same thing.
The sales process, same thing.
The workshop itself,
same thing.
They're not talking about taxes.
It's one thing.
It's going to help you a lot with
your
copy and making funnels win.
Because if you try to throw too
many things in there and too many
things
in your headline, your copy, your
VSL, your ads, all that, you're
just going to confuse a prospect
and
they're going to bounce.
Plus, if you have both of these
things here, if I'm talking about
taxes
and multifamily real estate, I
need to find somebody that wants
both of these things at the same
time
for them to convert, right?
They have to want to drop their
taxes and resonate with that.
And at the
same time, want to buy multifamily
real estate.
So my pool is smaller.
So that's the first thing is
congruency.
And the second thing is just
overall design.
I don't know why a lot of people
just don't put
effort into making their funnels
look and function well,
especially, you know, being
responsive on
mobile.
That's a huge thing.
And just making them nice and
custom branded.
Like most of the time I land
on some and I'm like, this
literally looks like I'm going to
get scammed.
I feel like, like you guys know
when you go on those weird, like
webs, how weird websites, let's
back it up here.
I'm not like that.
Anyways, those websites on like,
like stream East trying to like
find different, like UFC fights
for free and all that.
And I always pay for the fights.
I never, never pirate them.
But anyways,
you know, when you click on like
those videos, and it keeps popping
up with all this stuff.
And it's
like, Oh, you know, this near you
this gambling thing or this offer
for this app and all this stuff,
like most people's funnels in
landing pages, like look like
that.
So put the time and effort into
making it custom branded and also
making sure that it's mobile
optimized.
That's a huge thing.
The majority of traffic is going
to be mobile.
So ensure that is mobile
optimized.
Does everything
load nice?
Is all of the, on your landing
page, are you following best
practices, right?
Is your headline
here?
If you have a VSL here, you know,
your sub headline, is it clean to
read?
Is your button
above the fold, your CTA above the
fold, right?
You want to make sure all this
stuff on mobile is above
the fold, all the key elements,
and just make sure it doesn't look
again, scammy, confusing, blocky,
all this stuff.
You want to ensure that design is
very crisp and clean.
So that's something that a lot
of people overlook, but it really
can help the conversions a lot.
So, and the third thing in
making a winning funnel is making
sure that you pair the right
conversion mechanism
slash funnel type, which
essentially are the same thing
with the right offer.
Okay.
So if you have an
offer that needs a lot of
educating and it's not necessarily
something like super intuitive,
like a
staffing company or something like
that, like maybe it's this new
sort of business opportunity that
really not a lot of people have
heard about.
That's where I would do some sort
of funnel, like a webinar
funnel or some sort of funnel,
even like a challenge funnel.
Now, obviously challenges you
can't run
too, too continuously.
These are more like bi-monthly or
quarterly events, but that's where
I would pick
some sort of mechanism, like a
webinar funnel to where, Hey, I
need to spend more time educating
these
people on my process or this
opportunity in order for them to
convert.
And with the call funnel, I just
don't necessarily have that time.
Unless of course you have the
backend systems in place, but
that's
more advanced.
This is where you could experiment
with something like a webinar.
So I see some people
trying to just jam this
convoluted, crazy, confusing offer
through a call funnel without any
backend
education or backend sales
processes.
And if they just switched to a
webinar funnel, they would find
much
much more, uh, you know, just much
better results overall.
And on the flip side too, I see
some people
who are trying to run a webinar
funnel for a just straightforward
service that they don't
necessarily
need to run that type of
conversion mechanism with.
They can just switch to something
more simple,
like a call funnel, and then add
some backend processes like
content remarketing, good
education
manually in the sales process,
backend email flows to essentially
educate them, to essentially
educate the
prospect and why their specific
service in general, why they're
different, their process, why it's
different,
why they get results.
But instead, you know, they're
doing this like longer kind of
webinar, which look is
cool.
You can still make it work, but
sometimes you're, uh, just, but
sometimes you just have the wrong
essentially, but sometimes you're
just adding more friction and
you're running more of a, uh, more
taxing
funnel, like a webinar funnel when
you could just run a call funnel
on that point and be
perfectly fine.
So simple offers go for a call
funnel or something like that, a
much more lower friction
funnel.
And if you need something that
need, and if you have an offer
that needs a lot of educating
before the actual conversion
point, that's where you can
explore something like a webinar
funnel.
And then finally, number four, two
real quick is just having a good
offer and offer that cold traffic
once.
So that is the main thing.
It has to be cold traffic
optimized.
And of course, Mr.
Fazio talks
about this all the time.
So go through his training for
sure on the offer side, but having
a cold traffic
optimized offer, something that
cold traffic actually wants is
going to make your funnels convert
super,
super well.
So these are four things to keep
in mind when you're building these
funnels and just
implementing these four things
will get you to a point where you
can get good results through your
ads
and through your funnels.