All right so in another video we
launched a cbo campaign which a
cbo is basically you telling meta
hey i want you to distribute my
budget that i set on the campaign
level between the ad sets that
essentially you deem is the best
combination right so if you want
to bias towards ad set one
and put all the spend there
because you think it's going to
get the best results awesome if
you want
to do a little bit more of an
equal distribution perfect if you
want to bias towards ad set two
because you deem it'll get the
best results awesome no problem at
all an abo is the opposite so an
abo is
where we place the budget on the
ad set level and we're essentially
saying hey meta i have these three
ad sets i'm going to put 50 a day
on each ad set i want all of them
to get 50 a day spent on them
in a cbo you would say hey meta i
have these three ad sets i have
that total of 150 per day to spend
on
ads on this campaign so i'm going
to put the budget on the campaign
level and if you want to spend 20
dollars on ad set one 30 on ad set
two and a hundred on ad set three
totally cool you know best you can
bias the spend you can pick which
ad sets get the most spend based
upon what you deem is going to be
the best for me to get results
basically so an abo in this video
is what we're going to build um so
again if you're trying to get
leads do leads if you're trying to
get sales do sales so if you're
doing like a challenge funnel or
something like that or a low
ticket funnel we do sales the
majority of the
time i don't really touch any of
these other ones unless it's some
sort of like content remarketing
sequence that we do but let's go
leads i do manual leads campaign
then from here if we're in an
account i'll usually do like smo
uh that's our agency sell more
online
just so i know like what campaigns
are running i'll do cbo and i'll
do the objective of the campaign
let's just say we're optimizing
around the schedule standard event
and then i'll do i don't know um
you know fund one right the offer
whatever it is so i'm inside of an
account right now
where these guys raise money for
their different funds so you know
i'm saying say hey we're raising
for fund one right now on the
campaign level
we are going to go here and what
you'll see sometimes is you'll see
advantage campaign budget
you can turn it on or off now
advantage campaign budget and it
might look different in some other
accounts like let me go into
another account real fast here and
show you guys
especially if you if you do the
sales objective it's going to look
a lot different
similar verbiage but we'll go here
into the one of our accounts that
is running
a sales objective
so if you choose for example
create campaign sales continue
you'll see on the campaign level
campaign budget and ad set budget
campaign budget is cbo ad set
budget is abo right so it's going
to look different honestly on some
different ad accounts it looks
totally different too uh just know
that campaign budget or this
advantage campaign budget thing is
a cbo if you turn this off or on
the flip side you select ad set
budget that's an abo right so
we're
going to leave this toggled off
here we're going to make sure our
objective again is leads we're
doing
buying type auction i don't touch
any of these unless of course
you're in a special ad category
which you'll know if you are and
you can also just read here about
special i categories and see if
any
of these are fit for you then here
we'll do the audience so if we're
going broad we'll just do broad
and if you're doing instant forms
you click there most of the time
we're doing this though
website which is basically going
to pull the conversions from your
landing page
maximum number of conversions we
typically always select that then
we're going to pick the actual
pixel the conversion event that we
placed on the landing page
then sometimes we'll turn on
dynamic creative other times we
won't in the last video i showed
you dynamic creative in this case
we're going to leave it off so i
can show you individual ads as
well and then like i said we're
doing an abo so this is where we
place the budget on the ad set so
if we put a hundred dollars here
this ad set this broad ad set will
get a hundred dollars in spend
then we could schedule it then of
course if you want to switch your
audiences and you want to start
doing intro stacks and stuff like
that or put exclusions in or
custom audience you click this
here switch to original audience
options if you're doing broad you
can fiddle with the age here or
exclude custom audiences or change
the locations and then i always
like to turn this off i do manual
placements and i uncheck audience
network a little tip for y'all
then here is where we'll label our
dynamic creative test if we're
doing a dct but in this case we're
doing actual individual ads so
what we're going to do is maybe
we'll do you know batch one
add you know we'll do like hook
one body one right whatever
whatever that ad is you know if
it's batch
one we're launching for this
client with hook one and body one
we'll label it like that just so i
know
exactly you know what we're
launching right inside of this ad
then from here manual upload
single image
unless you're doing a carousel or
something like that we'll put the
actual landing page here make sure
to turn these browser add-ons off
and now this whole thing where
they do the setup creative now
this might change it changes quite
a
bit but make sure you turn off
these site links
let's just go into here and pick
you know a random image say you're
running an image ad
i usually do original on these
because you know if you click
something like this 9 by 16
unless you upload a actual 9 by 16
image you know this is an image ad
we're we're placing in here if
you hit replace here you can put
in a 9 by 16 image for this
stories and reels placements here
if not i just leave it as original
and it'll add some like nice
buffer up here so it wasn't like
all cut
off and weird text we're gonna do
you know body copy headline body
copy or sorry headline knows put
some random stuff description
click usually do learn more next i
like to turn all this junk off
personally
so i will turn all of these
sometimes i will leave this one on
i'll leave add overlays on because
that's
actually looking relatively okay
usually i'll turn this off too
i'll keep enhanced cta on
too sometimes but i'll turn off
text improvements so usually like
these are the only two that i
typically will turn on um but most
of the time i'll even like turn
this one off but other than that
all the other stuff like the music
the visual touch-ups um 3d
animations sometimes i will keep
the
visual touch-ups on but honestly
like i'll see a lot of times these
things get cropped
out and it just looks super super
ugly um like half the image will
be showing on the whole page
it's just a mess so keep those on
if you want you turn them all on
or turn them all off if you'd like
again we still don't want to max
out all of these so we can put up
to five primary texts and five
headlines and five descriptions i
only will do about two to three
pieces of primary text two to
three
headlines one to two descriptions
max unless even if i'm at a lower
spend level i'll just do like
one to two body copies one to two
headlines one description and
that's it so tracking if you're
using hyros or something you'll
put your url parameters here and
then if you want to duplicate out
the ad inside of the same ad set
do click duplicate and then all
right maybe we'll put
hook two body one right we'll go
in and again see it always tries
to get you to turn these browser
add-ons on make sure you click no
make sure every time you do a
thing sometimes it'll also turn on
these stupid site links you want
to turn that off too so then we'll
go in here we'll do edit media
pick another one go through the
whole wizard again
right even sometimes it for this
particular image uh yeah sometimes
it'll like turn random stuff on
just
like be careful with all that
stuff you could also go here and
look at the um previews of these
enhancements and you could turn
them off you think they look like
garbage so it's up to you
sometimes different images will
look worse in the previews uh so i
keep that in mind but meta is
really trying to push all their
whole their whole ai optimization
stuff and all these weird things
right and it's just odd so like
even this one here has like the
click to learn more like
for some reason there i don't know
why but i would you know get rid
of that so
then you put your url parameters
there again if you're using hyros
or something
quick duplicate same thing right
hook three and then if you want to
run a new ad set we'll do quick
duplicate of the ad set
and let's say we're doing like an
interest stack right
or we label the ad set
if we're building an interest
stack we'll go here use original
audience
and then we'll just start layering
on a bunch of different bunch of
different interests right
make sure that this is nice and
broad over here and you're good to
go but that's an abo