All right.
So going to break down a challenge
funnel that we had for a client.
So this is a paid
challenge funnel that we're
running and they essentially are
in the real estate niche.
So
they basically teach people to
invest in multifamily real estate
and this is a paid challenge.
So we're
selling tickets to a virtual
event.
This is a three-day virtual event.
These guys are super
hungry.
So they actually run these
bi-weekly.
Now that is very, I have really
never worked
with any other client running paid
challenges that runs them at this
frequency.
It's actually
crazy how they do this thing and
how they orchestrate it, but it
works for them.
It gets the ROAS.
Usually you run these on a, you
know, every other month cadence or
once a quarter even, but yeah,
this is absolutely crazy.
These guys are, these guys are
killers.
So anyways, we have our campaign
with our two ad sets here.
So we have been running, by the
way, on challenges.
We've been seeing
statics work really, really well
for challenge funnels across the
board.
This is currently in August of
2025.
So obviously things could change
tomorrow, but
on the majority of our accounts,
just keep in mind, statics are
doing really well for challenge
funnels.
It's very interesting, driving a
lot more clicks of the page and
our longer form
pages.
I'm going to show you in a sec
here is doing more of the selling
work.
So we have
tested videos, but statics have
been consistently driving a really
good cost per result for us.
They do burn quicker.
So we do have to spin them out
more, but just keep that in mind.
So we have
our CBO with our two interest
stacks.
If you are running statics right
now in August of 2025 too,
I would suggest, you know, this
one here is a individual ad set.
So, or sorry, we have individual
ads as not dynamic creative.
Meta has been doing some very
weird stuff with, um, dynamic
creative
sets with statics in particular.
Uh, just seeing a lot of weird
activity, a lot of things that are
getting like cut off and all this
weird stuff.
You, if you're using dynamic
creative, even with the AI
optimizations off.
So what we do if we're running
statics, um, for, uh, basically
statics heavily on an ad
set, uh, we will just do
individual ads like this instead
of dynamic creative.
So, uh, and then of
course, if you go into the ad
itself, just make sure to turn off
like this browser out on stuff,
turn off
all the site links and things like
that.
So we're doing an early bird.
This set was for an early bird
discount for them.
So we did make that apparent up
there.
If it's like a last minute deal,
we'll put last
minute or put challenge starting
Thursday event, starting Thursday.
I don't always like to call
this a challenge.
We usually call it a live virtual
workshop.
We call it a live event, um, stuff
like
that.
And if we're doing a sale, we'll
put this here.
If you're doing a sale for a
challenge funnel,
stay firm to it.
Don't flex it.
Like, don't just be, you know,
have a dead, I have a timeframe
for it.
Like if you're going to be running
70% off for an early bird until
Friday, jack the price up then
punish
people that don't take action
because people will see that ad
again.
And they think that your brand
is just flimsy.
They think your pricing is just
flimsy and that you're not
truthful to your word
in that sense.
So that's what we like to do.
Uh, we stick firm to that.
So yeah, we have, you know,
even like all of these things, I
like to turn all these off.
I honestly didn't even see that
these
were hot in this set.
So meta still gets you sometimes,
but I like to turn most of these
off.
Sometimes I'll keep overlays on.
Sometimes I'll keep visual
touch-ups on.
Um, I usually turn ad
music off and I turn all this junk
off, but they always try to get
you to, to basically, you know,
turn on their AI enhancements.
Same with this thing, this
suggested event.
I turned this thing off as
well.
And this is, of course they're
using Hyros.
So we have that in there, but, uh,
that's essentially
what we're doing for the, the ad
itself.
So now if we go over here into the
funnel, so this is actually
starting, uh, tomorrow.
So we have our countdown timer.
We have starting tomorrow, last
chance.
We typically do a VSL and this is
with Fidelytics.
So I love, uh, I've been loving
Fidelytics lately.
These guys have a money back
guarantee on their actual, um, on
their actual funnel itself too,
or sorry, on their paid event.
So we stress that there.
And then it's pretty much like
long form
copy for the rest of it, for the
page.
We do of course explain what
they're going to get each day.
We talked about the schedule.
We say, what's including your
ticket, why you need to do this
right now.
Like they're talking about the
big, beautiful bill that Trump
passed and everything.
So they're really leaning into
that.
We heat map these pages.
This is actually getting consumed
a lot, which is quite interesting.
And then we have, you know, start
tomorrow,
secure your discounted pricing.
We have general mission.
We always like to do a VIP
money back guarantee, meet your
host.
And just a lot like on these
challenge pages to cold traffic,
we have a lot of content on it.
We have a lot of different things,
explaining what they're getting,
explaining the methodology, what
they're going to be learning, the
expected results, the payoff,
everything like that.
Um, some things that, you know, I
definitely, as I scroll here, want
to change,
like, I don't really like this
red.
So just kind of keep that in mind.
It's a little jarring.
We're definitely going to change
that later, even up here, right?
Super jarring.
I don't know,
like that.
It's contrast up here.
So I'm very critical of our pages,
but you know, this one's
converting super well.
So might not change it too much,
but, um, you know, we're gonna,
we're gonna
keep it, keep it running.
So click here to get your ticket
now and have another countdown
timer
goes right to a checkout.
They can click here to order bump.
This is on GHL.
I prefer
building on click funnels, but
Hey, totally cool.
Um, right here you can upgrade
into that.
So this is a,
um, basically we split test two
different checkout pages by the
way.
And, uh, this is just one of the
dead ones.
It's not actually live at the
current moment, whatever dead
funnels, but anyways, um,
what you would do is have your
nice order bump down here.
You'd go name, phone number,
email.
This also does submit it.
So if they fill this out and they
do not, um, go ahead and purchase,
we can actually dial them there,
which is pretty cool.
Have the dates up top and some
reiterations
of what they get.
Talk about some of the VIP
exclusives on there.
So we can get a nice take
rate on the VIP upgrades, have
some social proof and some FAQs,
um, down here.
This one actually
gets opened a lot, which is quite
interesting.
The house is different from Nate's
free training
or online content.
Nate's the person holding it.
Then after this, after you would
purchase your ticket,
you get hit with a series of, uh,
OTOs.
So one-time orders, and those are
basically just, uh,
one-time upsells trying to raise
our AOV up.
And at the end of the funnel,
we have a calendar for them to
book on in.
Now, after they actually purchase
their,
their ticket and they're in the
system and everything, we hit them
with backend email
flows.
We hit them with organic content
remarketing as well, just to
pre-frame them
before the challenge.
Plus we like to pair them up with
a closer.
We call them an advisor sometimes.
And, uh, we don't call them a
closer.
We call them an advisor.
And from there, uh,
what we do is basically the
advisor and the prospect will
build a connection with each
other.
So the advisor can basically be
like, Hey, you didn't show up to
day one.
What's up?
Like,
here's the replay, like, you know,
or 15 minutes into day one, they
text them, Hey,
showing up, showing up, showing
up, um, stuff like that.
So they're really, we're really
leaning
on those salespeople to pull them
through the challenge and get them
to show up more pre-framed,
ready to buy.
Um, and then also get them the
necessary resources they need to
prioritize
showing up the challenge in the
first place.
And, uh, of course booking that
sales call with them on day
two, day three, whatever the
pitches and, uh, roll from there.
So that's the challenge funnel
structure from a high level and
let me know if you have any
questions.