So what are the day-to-day
operations and just the day-to-day
look like running a advertising
agency like I do?
So pretty much all as it is, is
you're either ideating new ads.
So you're
basically scripting some ads,
you're making tweaks to a funnel.
How'd you run that?
So we'll
kind of start it where, so we'll
kind of start at the beginning,
right?
So if you just bring on a
client, what are you going to have
to do?
Now, usually there's one of two
things.
One is if
they've never run ads before,
they're not currently running ads,
nothing like that, you're
essentially setting everything up
from scratch.
So we're not that type of agency
that's going
to be like, yeah, we only work on
the ads.
That's it.
We only run the ads.
We only touch
the ads manager.
We don't touch the funnel.
That's not how you're going to get
good results
for clients.
It's not how you're going to have
good LTV.
That's not how you can charge high
prices for what you do.
So we essentially sit down and we
will make the entire funnel for
them.
So that's all the landing pages.
We'll ideate the funnel for them
too.
Like, are we
doing a webinar funnel, a call
funnel, a low ticket product
funnel, a challenge funnel?
Like,
what are we doing for you exactly?
Depending.
And that all depends on their
offer, their current
situation, their budget too, is a
big thing.
So we'll sit down, make the funnel
for them.
That
means we're designing all the
landing pages totally bespoke to,
you know, we build on
ClickFunnels,
Webflow, GHL, whatever platform
really we do frame or two, but we
like to have our preferred list.
So we like to, so we like to
basically bias towards
ClickFunnels 2.0 initially.
That's just like what
we use and what we see good
results on.
But anyways, we'll sit down, build
their full funnel,
design all their landing pages,
write all of the copy.
And from there, we're going to
make their VSL
typically too, if it's a VSL
funnel.
So we're going to script it or
outline it for them, send it back
to
them.
And we handle all the editing too.
That's again, another thing we
like to be this full stack
in-house on the paid media side,
full stack team.
So we don't want them to have to
essentially like
look for other partners for video
editing, for funnel building, for
landing page design,
for copywriting, none of that.
We want to bring it all in-house.
So we know one, the messaging and
the
style is congruent through the
entire funnel so we can get them
the best results.
But then two,
it also makes our service way more
sticky because we're handling
everything, right?
If they churned or
they cancel, they're losing the
video editing team for the paid
media, their ad team, their funnel
team, their landing page team, all
this stuff, their copywriters,
even all the backend email flows,
right?
They're losing all of that.
So that's how we really like build
the hooks into their business.
And we can have such low churn.
Like we don't have, we have way
less than 10% churn.
We've had
actually one client all of 2025 so
far.
I'm filming this on August 10th.
We had one client churn and we
actually refunded them.
So he was a nightmare.
I didn't follow any of the best
practices that I
talked about of finding a good
client in the past module.
So we refunded him and yeah, so
you have
very low churn when you have all
this stuff that you can take care
of.
And I'll talk about team in a
sec here and what it looks like,
but you can still have a very lean
team with all of this.
So again,
new client, they had never run ads
before.
We're going to build their full
funnel for them.
We're also going to sit down and
ideate the actual ads.
So we're going to go through and
say,
okay, cool.
Here are a bunch of different ad
angles that we want to go after.
And we think
could work with your, and we think
it'd work with your offer could
resonate with your target
audience.
And also we'll look at their sales
calls.
If they have them ideally, even if
it's through like
cold outreach or something, if
they have sales calls or client
feedback forums, we'll look at
those
and say, okay, cool.
Why did people buy?
Why did they book a call?
Why were they interested?
What problems were they dealing
with?
What things do they want?
What dream states do they want?
And we'll reverse engineer those
into the ad script.
So we'll make the ad scripts.
Then we'll send it
back to them and they'll send it
to us.
We'll edit them.
And then from there, now we have
the ads
completed on the front end.
We have the full funnel completed.
And then after that, we're going
to start
to ideate some things like backend
email flows and content
remarketing and things along those
nature,
depending on the client itself.
If they have those in place, we'll
CRO them.
If they do not have them
in place, then we'll build them
out for them.
So yes, we're like writing emails
for them and stuff too,
because our job again, to make us
very valuable as an agency, we
don't just sit there in the ads
manager.
We get people to book in calls and
we really want to put in, and we
really want to put
marketing systems and automations
in place to help them get those
people to show up to the call and
buy
as well.
So we'll also consult on like the
sales process.
That's another thing too.
If I see the
sales team is just being super
lazy, they're sending very
generic, one-sided, selfish
follow-up.
They're not actually even
following up with leads or calling
them before the sales call in
general,
or sending them assets before the
call.
Then I will, you know, more than
happy.
I will sit down with
that sales team, light a fire in
their ass, or I'll tell the actual
client itself and say, Hey, look,
your sales process really needs
some help.
Here's some things that we should
work on over the next
few weeks.
So that right there, again, makes
us more valuable as an agency
because we're not just
pushing buttons in the ads
manager.
If you see anything, any theme
that I have in this course so
far, it's telling you to succeed
as an advertising agency, running
ads and making funnels for people.
It's to see other areas that you
can basically plug holes in the
business and give value to them
because that allows you to charge
higher prices.
Like we're charging 15 K a month
with a 10% net rev share component
on top of that as well.
Sometimes on top of it, sometimes
either or, but we're able to
charge those high prices because
again, we're coming in as this
almost
like fractional CMO ish on the, on
the actual paid side.
Like we're handling so much stuff
from
click to close.
We're just not taking the sales
calls.
So that's what I would do if you,
so that's
pretty much what we do.
If you have a new client that has
never run ads before, if you have
a client
who has ran ads or is currently
running ads, we'll sit there,
basically look at all the data
that
they have for the past seven days,
14 days, 30 days, plus we'll find
where the bottlenecks are.
Maybe we'll have to completely
change up the front end offer.
Maybe we'll just have to change
the
funnel up a little bit.
The funnel structure will make
them a new funnel.
Sometimes it's more just
like seeing what's wrong in that
sense and plugging holes.
So you can unlock scale there.
So we use data,
of course, to see like where the
actual bottleneck is.
So we'll look at all the key.
So we'll look at all the key KPIs
across the entire funnel,
everything from like click-through
rate
to CPMs to unique page visitors,
the application rate, book call
rate, cost per call, show rate,
close rate, AOV, ROAS, all this
stuff.
We'll see where the bottleneck is
and we'll, that's the,
and then that's the first thing
that we attack, right?
So that's, if you have a client
that's
already running ads, it's just a
little bit different positioning.
You're essentially still
installing your best practices
into their paid advertising
system, but it's not just
like totally building everything
from scratch.
They might have some things that
you just need
to optimize to unlock scale and
unlock growth.
But what does the day-to-day
actually look like?
So first off, you shouldn't be in
the heads of
manager for hours every single
day.
You, or if you have a media buyer
on your team, you should not be
doing that whatsoever.
Max, I spend on a given week about
five hours inside of the ad
accounts.
And we
manage like 20 plus accounts right
now on a done fee basis.
And I have eyes into about 30 plus
more
on top of that, uh, on our done
with you program.
So I don't spend more than five
hours inside of
the ad accounts.
So really your day-to-day is
looking at the performance of the
marketing system
as a whole.
So from a to Z.
So from click to close, I like to
gather metrics across all of our
client
accounts.
And then from there, I'm just
sitting down every day and saying,
all right, cool.
Where's the bottleneck on this
funnel?
Oh, the application rates low.
Okay, cool.
How are we
going to fix the application rate?
Okay.
We're going to do X, Y, and Z.
Awesome.
Then we go and do X,
Y, and Z, right?
Sometimes we'll need to make new
ads.
If we're hitting like ad fatigue,
for example,
that means if our current cost per
result that we see in the results
column on meta is increasing
and our result volume is
decreasing, that means we have ad
fatigue.
So therefore now we have to make
new ads.
So we'll either pull some that we
have from the vault that's sitting
like a Google drive
for one of our clients, or we'll
hit the client up and say, Hey, we
need you to film these ads for us.
When can you get them done for
eight hours?
Cool.
Awesome.
Send it back.
And we'll send it off to an
editor.
They edit, we relaunch the ads.
But the whole thing is running
this type of agency.
Again,
you're acting like a marketer.
Okay.
You're not sitting there just like
a media buyer working inside of
meta ads manager or whatever
platform you're working on.
You're not just like pushing
buttons in there all
day.
You're looking at these full
funnels and seeing where the
bottleneck is on the entire
funnel.
Is the click through rate super
high?
Is the show rate low?
Is the close rate low?
Is the application
rate low?
Like what's the actual bottleneck?
And then you need to be able to
identify what you need to do
to solve that bottleneck.
That's it.
That's all we do on a day to day
basis.
And from there, maybe I'm
managing like our video editors.
I'm seeing, okay, cool.
Why are you taking forever on this
one?
Hey,
can you quality check this one?
You know, I'm looking at different
funnel performances and I'm
like, okay, cool.
The application rates low on this
one.
So let's check the congruency with
the ads in
the funnel.
Oh, okay.
The ad is saying, we're going to
help you fix your show rates where
the funnel is
then saying, we're going to help
you fix your close rates.
There's pure incongruency.
Let's change up
the headline, right?
So it's just making minor tweaks.
Once you have the full system
installed,
and that's how you unlock scale.
It's analyzing data on a day to
day basis and then saying, cool,
this is the one thing that I need
to change in this funnel to unlock
scale and unlock growth.
And then you make a plan and you
go execute and attack that.
But again, it's coming from a full
level, high level marketing
standpoint.
You're not just saying, Ooh, I
need to get my click-through rate
up.
Ooh, I need to get my CPMs down.
Like none of that stuff, right?
You might have to do that at a
certain time if that's the
bottleneck, but you need it to be,
but in this position and in this
job and
running this agency, you need to
be able to take a step back from
the entire system, look at the
entire
system as a whole and say, okay,
cool.
These are the bottlenecks.
I need to go attack this one thing
this week.
Do I need to get the client to do
something like film ads?
Yes or no.
If no, cool.
I need to direct my team to do
something.
We need to change up this landing
page.
We need to redesign
this landing page, change up the
copy on this landing page.
We need to add some backend email
flows because the show rates low,
right?
Stuff like that.
So that's what your day-to-day
looks like.
There's no like set sort of things
that I personally do on a
day-to-day basis.
I still block off
half the day for us to actually be
able to focus on growing our
agency.
Then the other half is looking at
the current client campaigns,
current client data.
Like we have one
spec, like we have one team member
on, like we have one member on our
team that we call the data
scientist.
So all is she does is she sits
there and updates these metrics in
these spreadsheets for
our client campaigns and the
performance of it.
So I can look at a spreadsheet and
say, ah, okay,
the show rates low on this
account.
Cool.
What are we doing?
Oh, we don't have backend email
flows in
place.
All right, cool.
Copywriter.
Can you go write these in the next
72 hours?
And then we'll install
them into our HubSpot.
So they have automated workflows
and automated emails that are
firing up the
prospects before the call that
should raise our show rate or, oh,
okay, let me like go audit this,
this client sales process and see
what their setters are doing or
see what their closers are doing
pre
call.
Oh, they didn't even hit me up.
They just had Calendly
notifications getting sent out.
Cool.
I'm going to set up a call with
the sales team with this client
for next week, or I'm going to
send
them this document.
That's like a checklist of what to
do before the call to actually
rate show rates.
Like, Hey, you got to double dial
them, you know, twice a day for 72
hours, send them selfie videos,
send them different trust assets
and sales assets before the call.
Like all that stuff is what I'll
look in and do.
But again, it's more of a, it's
more of a gathering data and
analyzing data type role
that we do on a day-to-day basis.
And then seeing what the
bottleneck is and then directing
the team
from there or directing the client
from there on what to do.