All right, so I'm super excited
for this one.
This is going to be a little bit
lengthier of a video,
but we're going to talk about
every single funnel structure
that you can run for your clients
and what they look like and some
best practices on them.
So first off is our trusty VSL
call funnel, all right?
So the objective of a VSL call
funnel is, guess what?
If you're smart, you'll be able to
get this, ready?
To book calls.
So there's two different
structures you could run with a
VSL call funnel.
You can run it with an opt-in and
you can run it without an opt-in.
And what these look like are this.
You have, of course, the ad and
you drive with the opt-in.
We're on the with the opt-in side.
You drive traffic to a landing
page that basically you collect
name,
phone number, and email before
they go to this page over here.
With the VSL, the CTA, and, you
know, any other copy or FAQ
sections
or case study sections that you
have.
And then from there, they have
the, you know, application, right?
And they go after they schedule a
call through the application to a
confirm page.
And that's what it looks like with
an opt-in.
Now, without an opt-in, you
basically just bypass this page.
You basically just drive them
straight to a page right here.
That has a VSL, the CTA, copy, all
that fun stuff.
The scheduler and the application,
you know, embedded there.
And then the confirm page.
And real quick, we'll just talk
about the actual landing page best
practices for, you know, these
pages here.
Now, what we like to do on our
landers for a VSL call funnel is
we have our nice headline here.
Nice, concise, snappy.
We like to have our sub-headline.
Then, of course, we'll have our
VSL here, our video sales letter.
Then we'll have our call to action
right here.
Then below that call to action,
we'll have a couple different
sections of copy.
So, we'll basically sometimes
articulate in a section the
problem people are having,
our solution to that problem,
basically our service.
Then we'll have below that a bunch
of proof, so case studies.
And then we'll have a bunch of
text FAQs.
So, there's a big old bunch of
drop-down FAQs.
So, that's what we'll follow.
Sometimes we'll split test
removing this stuff.
Other times we'll actually expand.
So, we'll pick some parts of the
VSL that we want people to
consume, like different sections,
topics, stuff like that.
And we'll break them out as
sections further down the landing
page and everything.
But what you want to know at all
times is to, again, make sure it's
mobile optimized, the entire page.
But above the fold, so when you
first land on the page, all of
this here should be within view.
The CTA should be within view.
The VSL, the headline, the
sub-headline should all be nice,
clean, positioned above the fold
right when you land on the page.
So, just a quick blurb about, you
know, actually designing landing
pages and the structure of them
and what to put on them that
actually convert.
That's what we like to do.
So, that is a VSL call funnel.
And we usually run these pretty
much and usually run these about
80% of the time, 90% of the time
sometimes for our clients.
This is the funnel structure we
typically default to because we're
working with a lot of high-ticket
businesses that are trying to book
in calls.
Now, the key part is all the stuff
that happens after they book in a
call.
That's outside of the scope of
this video.
But, you know, hitting them with
the right value-based follow-up,
hitting them with content
remarketing, emails on the back
end, manual, actual good manual
sales processes and everything.
Like, good reach outs, good
engagement bait, you know, sending
them different assets and all
that.
That's going to get people to show
up to that actual sales call and
convert in the first place.
But, this right here is just a
front-end funnel structure and
what it would look like.
And from there, of course, you
make sure that you have proper
pixel conditioning in place.
So, if I have the page here with
the BSL and the application, and I
have the CTA here, and I click
that button, it pops up and has
the, you know, whole type form.
We ask them a bunch of questions,
and then they have the scheduler
there.
Based upon their questions, we
could send them down one of two
paths.
If they are qualified, we send
them down this path.
If they are disqualified, we send
So, essentially, if they just
don't meet a certain revenue
threshold, or don't meet some sort
of qualification set of questions
that you have on that application,
you want to send them down this DQ
path here.
And these both go to confirmation
pages, unless you just totally DQ
the disqualified leads in the
form, and, you know, just end the
type form or application there.
But, if you send them to a
confirmation page, make sure that
this one has no standard event
code on it.
So, it does not report back to the
ad platform, and just make sure
that the qualified side, you know,
has, like, the schedule code on
there, or the submit app.
So, it reports back to the ad
platform, we only want to optimize
and protect that pixel.
We only want to optimize around
qualified prospects, so we protect
that pixel, and only, again,
feedback qualified people into the
ad platform.
Because meta is a big AI machine,
so the data you put into it, and
the conversions you send back to
it, is exactly what you're going
to get out in the future.
So, the next type of funnel
structure is a low ticket
Ascension funnel.
So, what this looks like is you
have the ad here, you're driving
them over to a page that
essentially is trying to sell a
low ticket product.
Usually, we'll put a video on here
explaining the product, sometimes
we'll split test without it, but
then the rest of the copy on the
page is just explaining what the
product is, the benefits, what
they're getting, everything like
that.
And usually, this will be a
product anywhere from I've seen
stuff work at, like, $7, all the
way up to about $97, and on the
checkout page that you drive them
to, you can have different order
bumps.
So, you can have an order bump
here to add on some sort of
product or service for, you know,
like $100, $47, whatever pricing
strategy you want to use, $27.
But it can be a checkbox for them
that they can add this thing on to
increase the AOV, which is the
average order value of this
funnel.
But essentially, you have page
one, which is the sales page, page
two, which is the checkout page.
And then sometimes, we'll put a
series of OTOs, so one-time
orders, which are pages basically
pitching an additional product.
Like, hey, you bought this thing,
this thing is going to be a great
fit to essentially help you
amplify your results, whether it's
like an additional swipe file, an
additional, I don't know,
a software package, a community
access, a physical product, an
extra book, something like that.
You can have a series of OTOs,
which sometimes we'll do like one
to three OTOs, pages here.
And then after that sequence, and
on these pages too, they can click
a button that says, yes, I want
it.
Or they can click another button
that says, no, I don't want it.
And that just drives them to the
next OTO page.
Or you can select it to where,
hey, if they say no to the first
two, like just drive them to the
confirmation page.
But basically, after that whole
sequence, whether you do OTOs or
not, that's up to you.
You essentially have a page here
that is the confirm page, but also
allows them to book in an
implementation call,
which is essentially a back-end
sales call for your high-ticket
product or service.
And after that, they go to the
final confirmation page, which you
can put the schedule code if you
want to on there.
So that's what a low-ticket or
high-ticket attention does.
And then the key to making these
work is you need to get the people
to actually consume and use the
low-ticket product.
So that's why we like to drive
them into communities, for
example, there, or also have
setters or salespeople just reach
out to them,
making sure they're implementing
and using the product that they
just purchased.
And like I said, these products
can be swipe files, mini courses,
physical products.
You know, a book funnel is another
funnel here, which basically
you're just selling a physical
book here instead of, you know, a
digital product.
But it's helping them solve a
narrow problem.
And essentially, like, for
example, if I sell ads, it might
be, hey, here's a swipe file of
all of our top-performing static
ads
that you can just mix and match
and, like, replace with your
product or service or change the
copy around and stuff that'll help
you get some results.
You know, it's solving that narrow
problem.
And essentially from there, I'm
going to try to sell them.
I've done a few ad services or my,
you know, coaching program for ads
or something like that on the back
end, right?
But the key is to get them to
actually consume the low-ticket
product and use it and then try to
build a relationship with them
to get them on a back-end sales
call if they do not, of course,
book it here to sell them your
high-ticket thing.
So you get them to consume that
low-ticket product and then ascend
into that high-ticket thing.
And usually we like to try to do
that within 7 to 14 days.
But honestly, you'll see some
people that buy your low-ticket
product and they ascend in 4, 5,
6-plus months.
It's pretty crazy.
So that's a funnel structure we
like to do.
It's a little bit more complex.
But we will run that sometimes in
tandem with a VSL call funnel.
But usually we just default to a
call funnel.
In certain scenarios, though, it
does make sense to get a
low-ticket.
But like I said, typically, this
is a little bit higher of a
friction funnel.
This is where we're already, you
know, scaling and kind of hitting
a wall with a call funnel
and we'll layer this low-ticket
on.
Cool.
Now, the next one is a webinar
funnel.
You can do these evergreen or
live.
I like to use live webinar
funnels.
Evergreens are doing absolutely
terrible right now.
We're in 2025.
They are not performing well.
So I would not recommend an
evergreen webinar funnel.
An evergreen webinar is basically
where you just drive somebody to a
prerecorded webinar saying,
hey, it starts in 10 minutes and
they watch a recording.
It doesn't work nearly as well.
So webinar funnels, we like to do
live.
And this is essentially where you
have the ad here.
You drive them over to a page with
an opt-in.
So usually we'll click name, phone
number, email.
Potentially one other question
here if we want to determine if
they're an MQL or not.
If they're an MQL, we'll pass them
down one side.
Right?
If they're not an MQL, we'll pass
them down another side.
Usually we'll let them still
attend the webinar and sign up and
register and all that stuff.
But if you want to protect the
pixel, that's what you can do.
You can have a qualifier question
here.
But after that, we drive them over
to the confirmation page.
And we're hitting them with a
bunch of email flows and hype
around the webinar.
And then we hold a live webinar
for them where we try to pitch our
product or service.
And if you're doing kind of like a
done for you agency service, I
like to give a ton of value
inside of these.
So much value to where they're
like, yeah, I'm just going to pay
this guy to do this.
He knows what he's doing.
If you're selling like a coaching
program type thing, you
essentially still want to give
good value,
but you want to sell the
opportunity some more, especially
if it's like a biz off.
That's a big thing.
So that's a live webinar funnel
and we'll run these bi-weekly,
sometimes weekly.
Even, honestly, we have some
clients that are doing it two
times a week, which is pretty
sick.
Obviously, it depends on your
spend level and how fast you can
fill up these webinars.
But we love doing these.
Love doing them for different
offers that need a lot of
education before the actual sales
call occurs.
Or if you just have like a
straight week sales team, these
are great to do.
And typically, we're going to be
booking calls off of these.
Sometimes we'll do direct to
checkout if the actual ticket
price of the product is like 3K or
less.
But usually, I would default to
booking calls on this.
Then from there, another one we
have is a lead magnet funnel.
This is very simple.
This is where we have the ad.
We get them to opt in to receive
something for free.
So we usually do name, phone
number, email.
Sometimes that other qualifier
question too.
They get something for free.
And from there, we have setters
typically calling the people that
opted in.
Trying to set them for a back-end
sales call.
But again, this lead magnet, just
like the low-ticket product, has
to be something good.
And it has to solve a narrow
problem that essentially unlocks
further problems to the prospect
that your core offer or your
high-ticket service or product
solves.
That's the key thing.
And it has to be actually good.
If it's a bad lead magnet, it's
just fluff and garbage.
People are going to look at you
like, yeah, this guy just gives
out fluff and garbage.
His free stuff sucks.
So why would his paid be any good?
You want it to be the other way
around.
If you're like, damn, this guy's
free stuff is so good, his paid
stuff must be insane.
Same with the low-ticket thing.
If this $27 product here is
insane, then they're like, wow,
his high-ticket stuff must be even
better.
That's insane.
So that's a lead magnet funnel.
We usually don't default to this
one just because it does take a
really good sales team.
Right now, we'll run this if we
need to create some top-of-funnel
traffic.
And we're reaching some spend
caps.
And basically, we're just reaching
a wall on the amount of scale we
can have on some other funnels.
We'll weave this in there.
And then another one that you can
run is a challenge funnel.
Now, these are really, really
complex to run.
You can do in-person or you can do
virtual.
Most of the time, we do virtual.
But essentially here, a challenge
funnel is you have the ad.
You're getting people to purchase
tickets, right?
You have a sales page, just like
the low-ticket product funnel.
Checkout page.
You can have some order bumps on
there, too, where they plug a box
and it upgrades their order.
It's like a VIP ticket or just
adds on some bonuses or something
like that.
Sometimes, we'll have OTOs here as
well.
And then after that string, we'll
still have them book an
implementation call, which is
essentially a back-end sales call.
And sometimes, we're able to
actually get people to ascend into
a high-ticket product or service
before actually consuming the
challenge just on these sales
calls.
So, you'll find a lot of people
who are super in-market for that
thing will just ascend right then
and there, which is pretty cool.
Not a high volume, but definitely
cool to have.
That's why we have that scheduler
instead of just a blank
confirmation page.
Also, on this one, if they're not
essentially ready to ascend or
they're not qualified, we'll mark
them down as that on the CRM if
they're not qualified.
But if they are qualified and
they're essentially just not ready
to fully ascend at that point, we
just hype them up for the event
and make sure that they're super
ready for the event that's coming
up.
So, usually we'll do like a
three-day or a five-day workshop
where each day is a different
topic, helping them get started
doing the thing that you're
teaching, right?
So, if it's teaching them how to
start investing in multifamily
real estate like one of our
clients, day one is teaching them
the tactics, day two is helping
them implement more.
And then day three is essentially
helping them actually get started
on sourcing a property, reaching
out to sellers, stuff like that.
So, it's getting them in motion
doing the thing, and day two, we
have a pitch, day three, we have a
bigger pitch.
That's all it is.
You're just getting someone to
spend multiple days with you,
teaching them the process and all
this stuff before sending them
into your high-ticket product or
service.
So, we like to do these usually
like bimonthly as like big old
cash grabs and sweeps.
So, we'll like also hit the
organic audience with these two,
hit the email list, all that
stuff, or we'll do them quarterly
too.
So, not a too frequent of a
cadence, but these are like big,
big, big, big, big cash plays.