All right in this video real quick
i'm going to show you guys how to
place the pixel and standard
event code on your funnel so very
easy but basically we're going to
open up the events
manager just make sure you're in
you know the right ad account and
everything like that right
bm basically going to go to this
events manager you can also find
it under all tools if you click
that but events manager open it up
you could go to data sources pick
the pixel you're using
now if you have to create a new
pixel you do connect data and you
follow the setup wizard you
click web next and you can
essentially just create a new data
set and follow that whole wizard
to create
a new pixel but what you want to
do if you have an existing one is
click here or if you step into an
account with an existing one to
find the code you're just going to
go to add events add events and
new
integration metapixel setup
manually add code to your website
copy this code continue i always
like to turn on advanced matching
not sure actually why they don't
have country on there we go now
that you have this code copied
you're going to go to your funnel
building
platform go to settings and you're
going to paste it in the whole
head code of the website okay
you're just
going to paste it right there hit
update funnel
and ghl it's a very similar spot
to it's the full funnel level so
you don't have to go into each
page
and click header code and paste it
you just go on the full funnel
level funnel level usually it's in
you know settings or something
like that on the entire funnel and
you just paste it in there now
what you need to do to grab the
standard event code
and the standard event code will
fire off whatever conversion event
right so if you're trying to book
calls and do schedule the standard
event code will be schedule let me
go this is the unconfirmed
here we go we have two pages one
for qualified and one for
unqualified the qualified one is
the only
one here that has the standard
event code but basically all
you're going to do is paste the
code
like this the fbq track and then
whatever standard event code here
so this could be lead this could
be
complete registration this could
be submit application you can find
these on metas website too or just
ask
chat gbt hey can you give me the
standard event code for meta for
schedule event and the script
codes
um the script brackets as well in
between there and just give me the
simplified one because if not
it'll give you
this really long crazy one uh you
just want to give you this simple
one and all you do if you're using
click
funnels 2.0 you have to put this
in the footer the header does not
work all other platforms though
you put it in the header now this
is the header on the actual
confirmation page
after somebody purchases after
somebody fills out a form submits
an application or schedules a call
you
don't put this on the entire
website and you don't put this on
the initial landing page people
fill out
an application and schedule a call
then they land on this
confirmation page here that's why
i have
this code on here right because
when somebody lands here i want
them to report back to meta
as a scheduled call.
So that's why I put that there.
So that's all you got to do for
this.