All right hey guys so i just
wanted to go over a quick video on
like how we actually build up the
campaigns got some of you guys
asking me about this um so let's
go we're going to be building
this campaign for one of our
clients here and right now um it's
august 9th or august 8th 2025
and we are defaulting to our
typical cbo uh setup but we might
be changing this up um but anyways
we're going to build it up now and
it's just going to be like minor
tweaks like an abo with
individual ads potentially later
versus the cbo especially for
statics we're running statics
we're
probably going to be doing that
but anyways uh i'm just going to
start one from i'm not going to
start
one from like complete scratch i'm
just going to duplicate one out so
i'm going to duplicate this
one out here but i'll show you
guys what to do whenever we're
essentially making one so what we
do is if we're stepping into a
agency relationship with the
client we're going to do smo so we
just
want to tag our campaigns the
actual um campaign strategy so
we're doing cbo the event we're
optimizing around and then dct103
so what we do is we have these
tracking spreadsheets it's called
a
creative roadmap that basically
says okay cool this is going to be
the these set of ads inside of
this
dct this dynamic creative test so
essentially we're on test 103 so
batch 103 of ads for them
if you're just starting out it's
going to be batch 101 right and i
don't do batch number one two
three
because it doesn't like look as
clean so uh anyways we're going to
set the budget on their campaigns
so for these guys we're going to
launch this one at 500 bucks for
the day or per day and then we're
going to split between on interest
stack and broad for these guys in
particular we might do a lookalike
audience as well um i actually
might duplicate one of these out
and do a lookalike but anyways
we're
going to do interest stack website
max conversions we're going to
pick their pixel and we're going
to
choose the conversion event we're
doing schedule we're not doing any
cost per goal or anything we're
not
touching any of these down here
we're toggling dynamic creative on
right now and then in the audience
level we have our interest stack
here so this is the interest stack
we're using for them i actually
wanted
to domestic roof i think there's
like roof there's one other
targeting options that i wanted to
get on
here actually we already had it
domestic roof construction um on
this page
with interest stacks um i don't
really like to get too granular
with it all i literally do is just
slap
on as many different interests as
i can think of that will fit their
um essentially demographic
right i'm just like slapping
roofer building contractor general
contractor roofing domestic
roof construction roofing
contractor website business page
admins all right stuff like that
i'll be like small business owner
right there you go nice little
healthy size i usually like to get
this up towards like the seven
million 70 million plus but these
guys are only targeting roofing
contractors so you know 19 mil
is okay for the lower end and then
placements i'm going to go here
i'm going to turn off this piece
of shit audience network thing
because it just never gets any
good placements and then what i'm
going
to do here for these guys in
particular is we're going to add
in some of their new ads that we
have
for them so i'm actually going to
edit these and label them
i want to we basically change the
messaging in their ads to say
specifically like if you're using
this software called exactimate
so that's why i'm labeling them
just so in the actual library of
the ad account
and all the media i can see like
exactly what these are it just
keeps us very very uh
organized and then actually what
i'm going to do too is i'm going
to do dct one two three
all right keeps us super organized
it's the biggest thing when you're
launching ads to stay
organized because then you know
what's working you know it's not
working all that fun stuff
especially when you go in to
analyze the account
at later dates i've made the
mistake in the past of just
launching ads and not labeling
stuff you're like
like did i launch that one did i
not launch that one right let's be
able to let these upload and
then i'm going to show you guys
what we're doing on the copy side
so always make sure this is
checked
on optimize creative for each
person we have three pieces of
body copy we're not maxing it out
even
though these guys are at 500 a day
and spend on this respective
campaign we're not maxing out the
sets here we have five headlines
which honestly we could trim this
down i'm actually going to do some
right
so if we are going to do some
right now on using exact admit
we can get you paid more
for roofers who use exact admit
and of course we have our url
there we turned all these browser
add-ons on sometimes you're gonna
have like call and all this crap
added we usually just do learn
more this is our hyros code right
there
and some utms to pass through into
the crm
and yeah usually what we do here
is we have dct102 actually this
will be 103 because this is test
number three and then what i'm
going to do here once these upload
and all the copy is the same
what i'm going to do is what i'm
going to do is what i'm going to
do is just go into here
and once these are uploaded i'll
have those in there but what i'm
going to do is i'm going to
quick duplicate out this whole ad
set as well and we're going to do
the lookalike audience
that has performed relatively okay
in the account
it's the uh hubspot lookalike us
whoops so i don't want to layer on
the interest stack with it so i'm
just going to delete all these
so i only want to target the
lookalike audience with this one
there we go and in the interest
stack too we have advantage plus
on so we're using these as
suggestions right suggestions
because we want it to go beyond
these targeting options if we
choose
to do so you actually can't really
turn this on in most account or
turn this off in most accounts by
the
way anymore they're trying to push
you to more of a broad targeting
approach
we'll let that upload and then we
will launch these campaigns
so i'm going to pause it until we
launch all right cool now these
are in there we're just going to
select
these videos
if you want to edit the thumbnail
you can uh we don't really do that
too too much but if
it's something like this is a
thumbnail like obviously we're
going to probably want to switch
it to
something to where you know it's
like a human face
cool can i publish
and sometimes when you're on the
ad set or the ad level and you hit
publish it's only going to
publish like one of the actual ad
sets so you're going to want to go
to here
and i need to only do
publish a bunch of these but
it's bugging out a ton
these are all some old ads in
their account just trying to
unselect so
publish all those and we're going
to go