All right.
So the tech stack is pretty
straightforward for what we use on
a day-to-day
basis.
It's very lean too.
We don't have a ton of tech.
We leverage AI a ton now in our ad
creation process, editing,
everything like that.
But essentially here, the funnel
building
platforms that we like to use is
ClickFunnels.
So you can use 1.0 or 2.0.
We like 2.0 personally.
You can use Webflow if you'd like
to.
You can use GHL.
That's pretty much like 1.0.
ClickFunnels,
very similar.
Or you can use Framer.
Those are all the ones we've used.
I know Perspectives,
like another one that people are
using right now.
Just don't use something like a
weird HubSpot
builder where you can't actually
edit mobile independently from
desktop.
It's terrible.
So make sure you're using a decent
funnel building platform if you
want to have a nice responsive
funnel across multiple different
devices.
And it actually looks good and
performs well.
So those
are what you can use for that.
The CRMs, you can use HubSpot,
GHL, Close, Kit, if you're only
trying to use it for sending out
emails.
So if you have like another sales
specific CRM, like I see some
people who use Close, use Kit for
the kind of CRM and like that for
the backend, like marketing
automations, like emails and stuff
like that and newsletters.
And they use Close for just like
the
sales side.
So like this is a good combo.
These two, if you want everything
in one spot,
HubSpot is solid and GHL is solid
as well.
Just to make sure again, they have
the ability to create
pipelines and everything like that
to keep the sales side very nice
and concise and trackable.
And also just make sure that they
have backend email flows that you
can install.
And like I said,
if you want to keep everything
kind of in one spot, GHL is good.
HubSpot is pretty expensive and
their funnel builder sucks.
So don't try to build landing
pages and funnels on HubSpot.
It's terrible.
Now the different funnel elements.
So other softwares will use inside
of the funnel is Typeform for the
application.
I know there's like you form and
stuff like that, but to be honest,
Typeform is the best.
We use Typeform all the time
across all of our accounts.
We see the best cost per result,
best user
experience with Typeform.
And then also Calendly.
I know you can use like the GHL
calendar, HubSpot
calendar, all that stuff.
Again, Calendly gets us the best
cost per result.
So we like to use
Calendly there.
And we'd like to do the Typeform
and Calendly combo where the last
question after
somebody fills out the application
on Typeform is the Calendly.
Calendly, you can also use partial
submit too, which is huge.
And then from there, in terms of
attribution and tracking, we'd
like to
use Hyros.
If you're using a, if you're
working with like an e-commerce
company or something like
that, Triple Whale is fantastic
for companies that are in the
e-commerce space for proper
attribution
and tracking through your ads.
So for most of the, most of our
clients that we use Hyros.
And Wicked Reports is also another
one that you could use instead of
Hyros.
But again, personally,
Hyros to me is the easiest to work
with, the best support, best team,
and is the most accurate.
So
that's why we use that.
And then finally, for research,
you could use an app called
Foreplay,
which is really cool.
It's just basically the ad
library, but more organized and on
steroids.
You
could search by different topics,
competitors, stuff like that,
industries, niches to find
different
ads that are running.
And also some ads that are not
running anymore.
You'd save them to a nice folder
for yourself for ad ideation and
all that.
It's very cool.
Or you can just use the meta ad
library
to see what your competitors are
running and get some inspiration
that way.
I also just like to go
through Instagram and Facebook and
save ads.
I screen, I screen record them,
screenshot them,
save them to a little folder.
I'll DM them to people.
And you know, if I see an ad or
some sort
of messaging that I really like
that grabs my attention, I'll take
note of it, save it, ideate for
later.