All right.
So we're just going to dive into a
webinar funnel that we're running
right now for
a client just so you guys can kind
of see what exactly we got going
on with that.
So let me sift
through all of the fun, fun
campaigns we have.
So right here is a webinar funnel
we're running.
We have basically these campaigns.
We have some that we turned off,
some we turned back on.
And this set here is a new set
that we did.
We did launch it with some more
rigid messaging.
So
basically they're selling a TikTok
shop offer and we're trying to go
instead of helping people start
TikTok shop, they're trying to
help people just do it better.
So that's essentially this set
here,
same with these statics that we're
running.
So this is a static ad set.
As you can see,
it's doing really well.
And we're going to be scaling this
up here pretty aggressively here
soon.
But
anyways, if we look at the ad
campaign, we have our traditional
CBO set up here and we have
dynamic
creative on the ad level.
And if we go into here, we have
six videos with a couple of
different
pieces of ad copy.
Whenever it's like a free
masterclass or something, first
off a webinar,
we'd like to frame it like it's a
masterclass or a workshop or a
virtual event.
We don't call it a,
you know, we don't call it a
webinar like, Hey, show up to our
webinar.
Right.
Um, so we have one text, a piece
of body copy.
That's more selling me
opportunity.
Some more,
we have another one, uh, that
really just like slams what's
going, you know, going to be
covered
on the actual masterclass itself.
And usually I do like to do a call
out here on these.
I see these
types of copies do much better.
Whenever in the headline, you're
actually calling out like, Hey,
it's a free class.
Sign up, uh, headlines, same
thing.
Pretty step-by-step, uh, or pretty
straightforward on these.
So free live TikTok shop
masterclass, learn TikTok shop for
free,
right?
Stuff like that.
And then if we go over to the
actual page itself, we love having
again,
free TikTok shop masterclass.
We have a pretty catchy headline
here.
We've been rotating between
and we have the time and date.
We have a nice VSL.
Sometimes we'll have a VSL on
these pages.
Sometimes we won't.
And then about the masterclass,
here's what you're going to learn.
So we tell them
what they're going to learn.
We flex the instructor a bit or
who's actually teaching it.
Then we of
course go into some case studies
of like, Hey, people actually
using the system.
We're going to talk
about on the webinar and teach
you, um, here's some of the
results.
And then here's actually where he
taught his, uh, his grandma how to
run TikTok shop, which is kind of
cool.
Then I like to have a
session, a section of, you know,
what is the class again?
When is it?
Why should you attend?
And then some FAQs.
Then from there, we just have a
pop-up.
If you secure the spot,
then we have our confirmation
page, which these are just there
to essentially pre-frame some
more.
So they're there to, uh, break
down like, Hey, who you are, uh,
how much can I realistically make
with TikTok shop?
Do I have to make content or do I
use UGC creators?
I have no idea what TikTok
job is right.
That's if somebody obviously on
the front end of the ads, we're
not really targeting
this type of person, but if they
do slip through here, we at least
have a resource in a video for
them there.
So love this one too.
It's free.
So am I seriously going to learn
anything?
Uh,
what are you going to teach?
We also break that down there.
And then how fast can you see
results?
Is TikTok shop a quick fad or is
it dead?
And I love this one too.
This is why we made it super big,
but will you be pitching anything?
So I love having that.
I love framing people, right?
Be like, Hey,
we're going to give you a ton of
value, but to be transparent in
turn and, you know, in return for
this free value I'm giving you and
everything we're going to be
covering on the masterclass here,
I am going to have a pitch for
some of you that want to move
forward, uh, with just
accelerating
your results here and really
taking this thing seriously.
So, uh, then of course we got more
case studies and some FAQs on
there.
And then I like to have a button
here that actually confirms
the event on their Gmail, uh,
calendar if they do have Google.
So that is our confirmation page,
uh, there for the webinar series.
And on the backend for a webinar,
what we typically like to do
is we'll of course run them
through an email series.
Now, typically this is seven to 10
emails.
We also do some more that's manual
as we get closer to the webinar.
So about three days out,
we're going to start to send
manual newsletters and manual SMS
blasts, just reminding people,
giving value, like pre-framing
them a little bit more, talking
more about what's actually coming
up.
And, um, I also like doing a text
that is a little bit more on the,
uh, the interesting and kind of
cheeky side, but I like to send
out a text that says, Hey, this is
Kate.
Like for these guys,
his name's Cade.
So we did, Hey, this is Kate here.
Um, just finishing up the deck for
the master
class on Wednesday.
Just wanted to see if you had any
questions or anything you wanted
me to weave in
there, shoot me a reply back and
let me know.
That's super effective.
We get a lot of replies,
a lot of engagement, and it makes
it feel more personal.
And then also the high quality
leads too.
I love to have them, uh, dial some
of these leads.
If they have a great sales team or
a setting team,
I'll have the client dial the
opt-ins for the webinar, try to
make a connection with them.
And, um, that's if you got a
hungry sales team and one that
actually likes to do their,
do some dirty work and do their,
do their job properly.
So that's the webinar structure.
Um,
like I said, it's opt-in to
confirmation page.
We have backend email flows.
We also
will hit them with content
remarketing as well to pre-frame
them before the actual webinar
occurs.
And we try to get a lot of
questions.
They need answered about the
opportunity,
about the system, build up that
know, like, and trust build up
credibility before the actual
webinar occurs.
So when they show up, they're
essentially ready to get value,
but they're more primed for a
pitch and more prime to move
forward.
And then on the webinar,
we'll either go direct to
checkout, or we'll try to book
sales calls from the actual
webinar.
Usually if it's a higher price
product or service, we'll book
calls.
If it's like one,
two, three, $4,000, we'll
sometimes try a direct checkout,
especially if it's like a thousand
dollars or $500, we'll go straight
into a direct checkout.
And then we'll stay on there for
the
webinar, um, for about 30 minutes,
you know, towards the end, he's
like, Hey, the link is
in the description or the chat and
zoom here.
So if you have any questions now,
you know, let me know,
like, let's, let's answer these
live.
I'll pull you up on stage here.
You can ask your question live
and we'll break things down.
Um, you know, the opportunity is
limited to whatever, 10 spots,
15 spots.
And you know, we have a fast
action bonus where you get an
extra one-on-one call with me if
you buy here on the webinar.
So again, I'm going to stay on
here for 30 to 45 minutes with you
guys.
And we're just going to
essentially sit and I'll answer
your questions right there.
So
that's the structure of the
webinar funnel.
And let me know if you guys have
any questions.