So as an advertising agency you
have to be able to pick the right
clients to go after the right
types of clients the right niche
the right vertical and of course
like the right actual
characteristics of the actual
client itself you have to be able
to identify the right one
uh if not trust me it's going to
be a mess you're going to be
working with very broke people
poor people who don't have enough
money to spend on advertising so
you're sitting there like trying
to pull a rabbit out of a hat
every single month and trying to
make something work with a small
budget and you're taking meetings
all day long they're facetiming
you at midnight and all this
stuff and you don't want that okay
so we're going to talk about in
this quick video here what types
of clients what verticals niches
and characteristics of good
clients you should go after so
first off
the actual niches let's talk about
that because everyone loves that
okay um personally I like to
go after high ticket businesses so
that could be b2b that could be
you know different like agencies
that could be even sas companies
that have a high ticket front end
offer that could be info products
that could be coaches we even have
some like real estate funds and
syndications that we work with
too but anything on the front end
where they're selling something
expensive so usually like five
thousand dollars plus that they
get in their pocket per sale is
what we like to focus on now you
can
make it work with you know like
local businesses and stuff like
that there's a lot of people I
know that do
that um just make sure that it's
more of like a higher ticket local
business where it's something
like roofing or it's something
like HVAC where they're actually
like getting a higher ticket
thing it's not working with like
coffee shops or restaurants or
stuff as much as I would love to
tell
you to work with restaurants
because that was actually my first
you know client my parents
restaurant
when I started out advertising
that was the first one but look
their margins are too low their
average
ticket size is too low and you
just don't want to be working with
people like that so pretty much I
would focus on
something especially when you're
just starting out targeting a
niche or business that has high
ticket
prices and they're pocketing again
five thousand dollars plus and
ideally a ten thousand dollar plus
LTV
per sale per customer per client
that I get that's going to make
your life so much easier now in
terms of
the characteristics of a good
client I don't like to take
anybody on personally that can't
spend less than
two hundred fifty dollars per day
in ads why is that well if they
have less than two fifty they
usually
don't have a like decent marketing
budget and they're really in that
case and they're really at that
time
like pretty cash strapped so what
I mean by that is like if they
only have three thousand dollars
to spend
on ads and on a super tight budget
it's probably not a good idea for
you to take them on it's probably
not
even a good idea for them to run
ads right now because ads do take
a little bit of time to crack
it's not that whole thing where
it's like oh I gotta season the
pixel for 30 days no but look you
might
run ads you might launch a few ads
and not get any sales in for 14 21
days sometimes even look it could
be 30 days and stuff like that and
you need a business that ideally
is already running ads that you
can help
them do it better or they've
experimented with ads or they've
scaled to a point where they're at
like 30k 40k 50k plus per month
they have the good LTV they have
the good average ticket price
and from there you can just help
them say hey you're crushing it on
organic you're crushing it on cold
outreach you're crushing it on
whatever other channel um you can
take some of that budget now
you can now move what should I say
this you can now essentially just
run ads because you have that
fifty thousand dollar a month
revenue coming in you can put a
healthy 5 10k budget into ads
right now and
it's not your last dollar you're
not really they're not going to be
too worried right if you're
working
with a business that is doing 10
20k a month and you're asking them
to put 250 a day in the ads
even 200 or 150 they're probably
going to be super worried about
that budget and it's just gonna be
a
total nightmare working with them
and yet it's not what you want
whatsoever so uh at the same time
too i've seen some people go after
businesses that are you know very
low ticket size low LTV and they
don't have a big budget it's a
super easy sell but they churn
after a month or two and it's the
absolute
worst nightmare working with them
so again pick a niche that has
some sort of high LTV some sort of
offer that has a higher ticket
price and of course it's something
that people actually
want at this current point you get
bonus points if you're working
with a company that's in like a
space that the grand narrative is
really flowing with you like right
now ai right ai is everywhere
so if you're working with a high
ticket business that has a good
LTV and a good ticket price
and it's in the ai space and it's
in the ai space i mean that's
fantastic that's an absolute
recipe
for a winning offer for a winning
product and for winning ads
because a lot of people want that
thing you know if you're selling
like newspaper ads right now or
placements on magazines or
something
it's probably gonna be a little
tough even if your LTV is high and
even if your average ticket price
is
high you're gonna want to find
something that again people want
or morph it or morph that offer
into
something that or morph that offer
into something that people want so
those are the characteristics and
of
course i always like to vet the
actual clients that we work with
where i say hey is this person
you always selling something
ethical of course are they
actually nice to talk to because a
lot of this
time because a lot of times i've
worked with clients and i'm like
yeah this person just does not
like i don't really vibe with them
too much they seem pretty like
schizo all the time they're
bouncing around ideas and stuff
they can't just fixate on one
thing and you don't want to work
with that
you want to work with level-headed
people in this space especially
when you're handling their paid
traffic and you want to pre-frame
them to that hey this is not going
to be all rainbows and sunshine
all day long so you know we're
very good at analyzing bottlenecks
and fixing things when they go
wrong
but um you know you have to
understand that paid ads is a game
that you start right now and
you're
never going to end right so those
are the characteristics of what i
would look for in a client
make sure that they are easy to
work with they're very you know
for lack of better terms very
chill
um of course they have the healthy
budget to be able to spend on ads
and they're in that
sort of high ticket space that's
what i would go after