What's up, guys?
My name is Evan Siech.
I run an agency called Sell More
Online, where
we focus on basically helping
people make more money online
through advertising.
So
we focus on paid ads and funnels,
and that's our main bread and
butter.
So in this whole
course here, we're just going to
be going over from A to Z, what
it's like to run an
advertising agency, how to
actually do it successfully, what
clients you should look
for, what different types of
funnels are, what some different
types of ad examples are,
how to make winning ads, make
winning funnels, all this stuff
from A to Z, we're
going to be diving into it.
And of course, we got to start
right now with what the heck
is an advertising agency that
focuses on ads and funnels to
begin with.
So, you know, the
whole like digital marketing
agency or SMMA like sphere is
essentially just very, very
broad, right?
It's a very broad term.
I do social media marketing.
What we focus on
primarily is the paid ad side.
So really, we honestly just focus
on like YouTube and
meta ads right now.
We will touch like Google, TikTok,
you know, different platforms.
We
even do like LinkedIn and Snapchat
at times, but primarily we make
the most money for our
clients and us off of Facebook
ads.
So Facebook and Instagram as well.
So meta and YouTube.
But primarily what we focus on is
just driving leads, driving book
calls, driving purchases,
you know, depending on what type
of funnel we're doing through paid
ads.
That's our main thing.
And for us, you know, you'll
basically look at a lot of people
who are just like media buyers,
right?
The whole old school like media
buyer is dead.
Now, what media buyers essentially
are just
people that click buttons and buy
media.
So they buy space on these
different social platforms and
everything like that.
And that skill is just not needed
anymore.
What you need to do if you're
going
to run a advertising agency like I
do that focuses on ads and funnels
is to really become an expert
marketer from A to Z.
You have to be able to make good
ads, make good funnels, come up
with different
messaging buckets and ideas to
craft those ads around and craft
those funnels around.
You have to make
actual good offers on the front
end.
So people who don't know you don't
like you and don't trust you
yet see your ad and are like,
okay, cool.
That's an offer that I would like
to learn more about.
And of course you need to be able
to actually warm those leads up
through different marketing
methods
before they actually show up to a
sales call.
So you can actually sell them
properly.
So
that's essentially what it is.
So from A to Z, what you're going
to be doing on, you know,
a day to day basis, we're going to
get into it much more detail in a
little bit here, but essentially
you're helping people run ads
profitably.
You're going to be making landing
pages, making funnels.
You're going to be helping with
emails on the backend too.
Pretty much everything in the paid
acquisition system from click to
close besides taking sales calls.
If you actually want to do
this right, you should be focusing
on, you should be helping your
clients with, it shouldn't just be
you sitting down, looking at the
ads manager for a couple hours a
freaking day, clicking buttons and
all that stuff.
No, you're directing the creative.
You're directing the angles of the
ads.
You're directing
the copy on the landing page.
You're directing what type of
funnel, what the funnel looks
like.
You're making landing pages.
You're building backend email
flows and everything like that.
And you're seeing where the
bottlenecks are in the funnel and
in the paid acquisition system.
And you're going all hell bent on
that to fix that.
So that's what an advertising
agency is
in the modern day that focuses on
ads and funnels like we do.
So without further ado,
let's dive into some more modules.