So let's talk about what makes a
good ad in the first place.
So the first thing is, of course,
the messaging in the ad.
So what should your ad actually
talk about?
Your ad should be calling out
the real-time pain points,
desires, situations, and
circumstances
that your target prospect is
experiencing right now.
It has to be hyper-contextual to
what they're
experiencing right now.
It should be something like if
you're talking about wanting an
iPad,
that's where you want essentially
you to get served an ad with an
iPad.
So it's like you want
to be in that position.
We can run back that.
Your ads need to be
hyper-contextual to what the
prospect is dealing with right now
in real time.
So what I mean by that is, for
example,
if they're struggling with show
rates, you want to call that out.
You want to articulate that
problem
better than they can.
You want to call out, hey, are you
struggling with show rates?
Not stuff where
it's like, hey, are you struggling
with sales?
It's way too broad.
You want to get very specific
to these pain points in your copy
and in your messaging.
That's what's going to get ads
that hit.
So it's very crucial that in your
copy and when you're writing these
ads, you need to get very,
again, granular with these
problems people are experiencing
and these dream states that they
want to be in, these desires that
they have.
Nothing is too specific.
Not nothing.
You don't want to go
super broad.
You don't want to be very generic
like coaches, agencies, and
consultants.
I'm going to
help you four to five X your lead
flow by fixing your sales.
That doesn't work anymore.
The call
outs don't work anymore.
You need to articulate the pain
points, the desires, the real
situations that
your prospects are in right now
and the circumstances that they
find themselves in in your ads.
So the flow of a
good ad that I like to follow is
you have the hook, of course, hit
the body and you have the CTA.
Now
the hook is articulating that
problem.
So calling out the problem like,
hey, are you struggling to get
your show rates above 75% or, hey,
are you struggling to get
prospects to show up to your sales
calls actually
warm and ready to buy?
Because every time they show up,
shoot, if they do at all, they're
super cold guarded and just
thrown out objections.
You see how more specific that
hook is than something like, hey,
are you struggling to actually get
sales
through ads?
Terrible, right?
So the hook will call out the pain
points, the problem, or the desire
someone has.
Or it could also call out proof to
like one of the ones that we shot
over with list kit, or like one of
the ones we shot with
Christian over at list kit was, we
sent, you know, 150,000 cold
emails or something crazy like
that, generated x appointments, x
revenue, x sales
calls, all that stuff.
It was super proof led.
Also, some like case study ads do
really well with this logic too,
where you
basically call out, hey, we got
this person, this result, here's
how we did it.
And then the body supports that
and talks more about
that, right?
So then the body, what we like to
do is essentially give support to
the hook.
So if you talk about a pain
point, you want to talk about, you
know, why that occurs, like why
that pain point or problem is
occurring.
The solutions to it, which
essentially is guess what, your
product or service.
And then the outcome slash proof,
which is where you can weave in
some CTAs and also talk about the
outcome they're going to get of,
you know, using your product or
service as the solution.
And then we go into the CTA, which
the
CTA, we just want to be very
direct and tell people what to do
next.
And also what's on the next page.
So what I like to do for our CTA
is not click the learn more button
down below and you'll, you know,
go to a page and you book a call.
I like to say, click the, you
know, if this is interesting to
you
and you want to fix your show
rates, click the learn more button
down below.
You're going to be taken
to a quick page that has a five to
10 minute video on there that
explains everything about our
offer in
detail and how we can help you.
And then on that page too, you can
click a button, fill out a quick
application, schedule a call, and
you'll hop on a call with me to
see if this is a fit for you,
right?
I like to be very direct and tell
them what's going to be on the
next page and just make sure that
they're not
jarred when they get to there.
We want to pre-frame them before
they get to there.
And sometimes in the body too, if
you look at some of the ones with,
uh, Christian and Liskit,
like we just go right into the
offer.
So we love doing like the, here's
our offer to you, right?
That's a good one too.
Those are just more direct.
Um, I am defaulting lately to
having longer ads
that have more context and more, a
little bit more education in them,
but these do work pretty good
too.
Just a very direct one.
So that's essentially what you
want to follow.
Uh, when you're writing
ads is the hook needs to be very
articulate and needs to hit on
their pain points, their problems,
their desires, or show some really
hard proof.
And then the body should
essentially support
whatever you say in the hook and
expand upon that.
Or of course you can try the very
direct route as well.
And then the CTA should just be
very direct to tell them what's on
the next page,
what they got to do next.
And you'll be good to go on that
front.
And then number two of making good
ads are the visuals.
Now in terms of your visuals, your
environment
should match who you are and what
you sell.
And what I mean by that is, for
example, I look like
an info marketer right now.
I have a traditional book
background and all that.
I got these wood panels.
I have an all same shirt on like,
this is the whole info marketer
thing right here, right?
I look like somebody that runs ads
for info guys.
You know, if I was targeting real
estate funds and
syndications, guess what I'm doing
in my ads.
I'm wearing a polo shirt.
I'm slapping the watch on.
I'm looking a little bit more
professional, maybe changed up the
background a little bit and what's
behind
me.
But you need to match your
environment to what you're selling
essentially.
Another great example.
This is one of our clients.
He sells Google ads to
contractors.
So instead of sitting inside of a
studio like this with, you know,
wood panel background, looking
like an info marketer,
he put on a polo shirt with his
logo, went outside of a Home Depot
and had his big Chevy truck in the
background and shot at selfie
video or a selfie style.
So he had a truck in the
background, Home
Depot in the background, polo,
collared shirt on, looked very
professional.
And that resonated with
people more than him sitting in a
studio like this, looking like an
info marketer because all the
other
marketing agencies look like that,
rip them off, right?
So he's meeting the prospect where
they're at
and essentially fitting into that
mold of somebody that does what
they say they do.
And the environment
is key for that, right?
So if you're a CPA, for example,
you probably want to be in a
studio
that's nice and professional.
You don't want to be outside of a
Lambo or something like that,
or in a Miami, you know, penthouse
type thing, right?
So just make sure your environment
matches your
offer and who you're selling to
and will resonate with the people
that you're selling to.
And then also make sure you have
good camera quality, right?
That's a key, that's a key thing.
You know, if you have like an
Android, a lot of those things
look like garbage, you know,
we can film on the iPhone.
They do look pretty good, but if
you can get a camera,
awesome.
Just make sure the camera quality
is solid.
And same with the audio quality,
invest in a mic, like make sure
that when you're shooting ads,
people can actually hear you very
well.
The audio quality honestly is
almost more important than the
the camera quality.
Cause if you have an amazing
looking video, but the audio is a
little bit off
or the audio is like hard to hear,
or it's really grainy and cloudy,
people are going to swipe.
So just
make sure that that is dialed in.
And then also with the visuals,
just make sure that you're
presenting the
in a confident manner.
And also you can add some
different props.
Like we love using the whiteboard
in the, uh, the flip chart with
Christian and the ads for let's
get love them.
That visual aid does so
well.
It grabs attention.
It's different.
It's not just a direct talking
head.
So add some props in there
and some visual aids and some
visual disruptors, especially for
your hooks, that'll help you so
much to make your ads just pop out
and get that hook rate up.
So people stop scrolling and watch
what
you're essentially, uh, trying to
convey to them.
Trying to do anything else.
Yep.
So those are really
the best practices when filming
ads.
And of course we'd like to make
sure it's native to the platform.
So if we're running ads on meta,
we'll make them, you know, nine by
16.
So they look like reels
or we'll do, you know, four by
five sometimes too, but we just
like to make it very native to the
platform.
If we're doing YouTube, we'll do
16 by nines.
So we'll film it landscape, not
vertical.
Um, some people
I've seen run YouTube ads where
it's like, you know, the 16 by
nine and they filmed it nine by
16.
So the videos here and they just
add this like weird grainy
background over there.
I don't like doing that film
native to your platform that
you're running the ads on.
But that's really the main things
you need to look at whenever
you're actually making ads that
are
good is make sure the visuals are
strong and the environment's good.
The quality is good.
You're speaking very confidently
on camera.
Sometimes you can weave in some
awesome props,
make sure you're filming in an
aspect ratio or format that's
native to the platform and make
sure your
messaging is really hitting on
their real time pain points,
desires, situations, and
circumstances.
So you can, again, attract the
prospects because you're
articulating something that
they're
experiencing right now better than
they can.