What's up, guys?
Lucas here.
In this video, I'm going to be
showing you guys the Client
Ascension AI dashboard.
Now, I should note that some of
you will have access to this and
some of you may not.
If you just purchased the course
version of this whole program,
then you unfortunately will not
have access to this
because this costs time and money
to maintain and develop.
So unfortunately, you won't have
access.
Now, if you are on the standard
tier, you will have access.
If you'd like to upgrade to the
standard tier,
you can reach out to the SSC that
gave you your onboarding call
or you can email me directly at
Lucas at ClientAscension.com
to talk about upgrading and
getting access to the Client
Ascension AI dashboard.
So I'm going to explain what the
Client Ascension AI dashboard is,
what it does, and how you can use
it.
And then in a few other modules,
we're going through using it in
depth
and showing you exactly how to get
the most out of it.
So if you take a look here, as you
can see,
at the first section here, we have
quick actions
and then we have AI business
tools.
Quick actions are some of the most
popular features that we have
that people want access to
immediately.
And AI business tools is all the
features that we have
so that you can see everything
that's there.
But I'm going to start off by
going through
what I think is the most important
part of all of this,
which is the JSON context profile.
This will be used across all of
the other tools that you use.
And I'll be going into depth in
depth on that in a moment.
But for now, let's take a look at
the slide right here.
We've got dashboard, my content,
progress, CEO dashboard,
growth calculator, CRM, and
resources.
Now, I've been dashboard is
obviously just for me.
We won't be looking at that.
But essentially, the way that this
works
is that when you create content
using the dashboard,
you can save it to your my content
section
where you can review it later,
copy it, edit it,
and overall keep track of what
you've been working on.
The progress dashboard is actually
the entire client ascension course
broken down.
And you can use it to track your
progress through the course
as you complete modules and take
them off going down.
So if you go here, and if I click
that,
you can see we're in progress, two
of eight tasks, et cetera,
and I can mark the whole thing as
complete.
The CEO dashboard is something we
teach inside client ascension.
And it's a way to track all of
your metrics across your business
in order just for you to get a
good idea of where you're
currently at
and how close to your KPIs and
goals you currently are.
So you can choose the metrics you
want to track,
and that will actually build out
your dashboard.
So for now I'm just going to
select all of them.
And I fill these out.
I'm going to add a bunch of random
numbers now in a moment.
In the next step, we're going to
add a monthly target.
Just for a few of these, we'll do
all of them.
I'm just hitting random numbers
here.
All right.
So create dashboard.
You can see here now we've got all
of these different details here.
So when we want to track that
we've updated,
so let me say weekly, week one,
we've done 500,
save updates, week two,
for cash collected, that much.
And this helps us to track our
progress weekly.
We add new weekly entries each
time to see where we're currently
at.
So that's a really useful tool as
you're kind of building your
business,
keeping track of everything,
and you can generate reports from
this as well and save it for
later.
So let's take a look at our growth
calculator here.
This here is the client ascension
growth calculator.
This is where you define your
wildly important goal.
You'll see your core metrics, your
lead generation,
your sales conversions,
your scenarios,
and all of this will give you a
kind of outline of where you're
currently at
and what you need to do in the
next kind of a timeframe in order
to reach the goals that you've set
out.
So you can see that your target
MRR,
your current one,
your deadline.
It'll kind of tell you what you
need to do.
What is your realistic,
your aggressive,
your conservative kind of
estimates.
And afterwards,
you can save that to your content
as well.
We do have a CRM built in here
where you can actually track your
different deals throughout the
pipeline.
You can move these across and see
where you're currently at.
You can edit the different users.
You can actually call the leads or
send emails directly from the
dashboard here,
add notes,
things like that.
But let's start off with that
section I talked about,
the JSON context profile.
Now,
JSON context profile basically
provides information about your
business to every other module
that you're going to use
throughout the dashboard.
So if I click this here,
you'll see there's going to be a
form we fill out.
And this is going to be a 20
question form.
Where you're going to input what
is the name of your business.
For now,
I'm going to write tests and I'll
show you a real one afterwards.
Do you have a slogan or a tagline?
When was it founded?
These are all just interview
questions about your business.
These are clients internationally.
What does your business do?
What is your mission or big
picture goal?
All these sort of things
throughout here.
Now,
after you fill all this out,
you're going to end up with a
context profile similar to this.
And you essentially can copy this
and paste it into any one of the
other chats in order to give it
information and context about who
you are and what you do.
So each time that you're,
say,
you know,
creating a VSL script or you're
writing cold emails,
you don't have to remind the AI
every single time in detail what
you do.
You just go,
here's my business context
profile,
paste it in,
and then it knows exactly what you
do.
So that's the kind of initial
overview of the dashboard.
In the next video,
I'm going to be going through each
of the business tools
individually,
explaining what they are,
how they work,
and how you can get the most out
of them.
See you in the next one.
Peace.