What's up guys, Lucas here.
So the first thing I'm going to
show you in the AI dashboard is
going to be the AI clones
of Daniel Fazio and Andre Heichel
Jr.
Daniel is the go-to guy when it
comes to cold email, offers,
anything related to packaging
what you're selling.
Andre is the ops king.
Dude knows everything about
operations, fulfillment, team
management, everything like that.
So if you go to chat with Daniel,
we log in here, you're going to
see that it's going
to load a chat with Dan.
One thing you can actually do is
you can actually call Dan by
clicking the little call button
here and have a voice conversation
with him.
Even sounds just like him and you
can have a full conversation with
him.
But let's just start with like a
common sort of issue.
So I'm going to say like, hey Dan,
I'm running a lead generation
agency and I'm having trouble
signing clients.
What should I focus on?
We send this and we're going to
get a response from Dan.
These are trained actually on
everything Dan's ever said across
YouTube, across Slack, across
his Twitter, every source you
could possibly find for anything
Dan's ever said.
I believe it's over 2 million
words in total that it's actually
trained on.
But if you look here now, you can
see he says, all right, so you're
running a lead generation
agency and struggling to sign
clients.
You've got to focus on three core
things.
Your offer, your outreach, and
your volume.
Let's break it down.
Your offer needs to be
bulletproof.
Your outreach needs to be dialed
in.
Volume is the name of the game.
Define your sales process,
leverage case studies, and
results.
So it ends with what's your
current offer and outreach process
looking like?
Let's dig into that.
So say my current offer is sign 10
to 15 new clients in 30 days or
you don't pay.
And my outreach process is
primarily cold email, but I don't
have a particular niche or
industry
that I focus on.
All right, so your offer's solid
in theory.
It's bold and clear, and it's got
a reversal baked in.
But here's the issue.
That niche you're shooting in the
dark.
You're trying to be everything to
everyone.
It's a recipe for media of
results.
Let's fix that.
Niche down like yesterday.
You just pick a specific industry
or type of business to focus on.
So it gives you full solutions on
how you refine your cultural
process.
It even gives you kind of like
suggested personalization and kind
of like structure.
It talks about volume, case
studies, and social proof.
And then the answer is, here's
your game plan.
Pick a niche and territory or
offer to them.
Process your cold emails, scale
your outreach, build cases, back
up your claims, optimize
your online presence to build
trust.
What niche are you leading toward?
Let's figure that out and get you
moving.
So as you can see, this is like
very detailed.
You can talk to this all day and
get like a full AI consultant from
Dan right here, ready
to go.
But let's have a look at the Andre
one.
So same sort of deal.
We've got a chat with Andre,
trained also on all of Andre's
stuff.
So let's say, Andre, I'm having
trouble with motivating one of my
team members.
What can I do to get the best
results from them?
Andre Colon is going to think.
Happens to all of us.
Motivation use your breaks for one
of three reasons.
No clarity, no path, and no
stakes.
Here's the fast fix I use.
One, reset clarity.
Set every time this line on role,
top three responsibilities, and
two to three KPIs.
Find what great looks like weekly.
Ask directly, what are your career
goals for the next 12 months?
What do you want more of?
Money, responsibility, skills,
recognition, flexibility.
Build an essential plan.
Create near-term stakes.
Coach and hold the line.
Recognize wins publicly.
Tell me their role, current KPIs,
what's slipping, and what they
actually care about.
I'll draft the essential plan, the
scorecard language you use in your
next one-on-one.
So let's take a fake employee.
We're going to say they are an
email copywriter.
Currently, they have to write,
let's say, 10 scripts per week
that get a 3% reply rate.
But they're not finishing their
scripts on time.
And they have said that they care
about making more money.
Got it.
They don't have more money,
they're missing deadlines.
Type A to output timelines and
results.
These are structured used for an
email copywriter.
Com plan.
Base per script.
Paper deliverables on hours.
On-time bonus.
Late penalty.
Performance bonus.
Attention escalator examples.
You can paste.
10 scripts per week at X per
script.
First draft within five business
days of brief.
On-time bonus.
Plus $10 per script delivered on
time.
Late penalty.
Minus 50% of the script's pay per
late day down to zero.
Manage rhythm.
Weekly 15 minute 101.
One review scoreboard.
Remove blockers.
Confirm briefs are clear.
Public scoreboard.
Show scripts due to submit on time
after reply rate.
Two weeks reset.
The min's agreement is at a short
pit with daily check-ins.
Quick question.
So you can tell our numbers.
What's your current prescribed
rate?
Your SLI expectations in days.
And average will be volume per
client.
I'll plug exact figures that do a
clean one-pager to roll out.
So as you can see, any potential
issues you would have with your
business,
it can pretty much be answered by
Don or Andre here.
Super, super useful tool to have.
I guess, you know, these are
available 24-7.
If you're part of client
Ascension,
then obviously you can go to Don
and Andre's calls,
but they're only once per week for
an hour.
You can DM them as well, but, you
know, if they're human,
they need to sleep and they have
other responsibilities.
Whereas these are available on
demand 24-7.
You actually call them and chat to
them while you're out and about,
you know, on your AirPods, while
you're having a jog,
whatever you're doing.
So super useful tool.
And something that we spend a lot
of time building out
and developing to be as
comprehensive as possible.
So I think any of you that are
using the dashboard
should really rely on these two.
I think you get a lot of great
information out of them.
So see you in the next one.
Peace.