- What's up guys, so in this one,
I'm gonna show you our cold email
creator
inside the Client Ascension AI
dashboard.
Also going over the cold email
script reviewer,
but obviously first let's start
with actually writing our cold
email script.
Now, this one is super easy.
Like all the others, it's asked
for things
like your specific offer and
service,
your target audience, background
credibility markers,
and campaign preferences and
goals.
So for this, I'm gonna give it the
same information
that I gave the sales, or I think
I gave the VSL creator,
and we're just going to enter this
in here,
and it is going to create our cold
email sequence for us.
So as you can see, it's thinking,
and in a moment now, we're gonna
get our full email sequence.
So as you see, this is done,
and it actually gave us an eight
step email sequence.
So this is based on the training
that we provide
inside Client Ascension from
Christian Bonnier of ListKit,
and all of our cold email training
that we've got hundreds of hours
worth of
in there at this stage.
So see, obviously the more kind
of, you know,
the information you give this,
the better the scripts will be.
So for instance, this first email
is,
hey, first name, or the one in the
table,
their existing email subscribers
at company name.
We guarantee a 30% revenue
increase
from your marketing.
That means you don't pay a cent.
Just help with a $50 million
skincare brand
at 180K monthly for the existing
50K subscribers
through proper segmentation and
automation.
One of a set of a free audit
of your current email setup.
So obviously we didn't actually
help
with a $50 million skincare brand.
That's the information that,
when it asks us for kind of
credibility
and any kind of background
information
we want to provide for it.
So case studies and things are
important
to get in there too.
But still a very, very good start.
We go through eight emails in
total.
Finally finishing up with moving
on from company name.
Also reaching out with the email
marketing opportunity
for company name.
If you ever want to see how much
revenue
you might be missing from your
existing subscribers,
just apply to this email.
We'll be here when you're ready to
explore
a 3% increase guarantee.
So we get a full ASAP sequence
fully written for us
in seconds, just based off the
basic information
that we gave it.
So now if we go to the email
review bot,
we're going to paste the sequence
in here.
We're going to get a review of
this sequence
that hopefully will improve it
even further.
So need some context to give you
the most valuable feedback,
which target audience of the
sequence,
blah, blah, blah, all this stuff
here.
So already it says that the eight
emails
are actually too long.
Five emails maximum is good.
We're being too repetitive.
Subject lines are weak and
generic.
Don't proper personalizations.
Cut down these five emails with
four-day, three-day,
five-day, 21-day delays.
Fair your messaging and CTAs.
Make your subject lines puncture
and more specific.
Add real personalization.
Focus each email on one specific
angle
instead of repeating the same
guarantee.
It's strong, weird to beat people
over the head with it.
Use the strategy to give you three
emails, not all of them.
Once you give more context for
your audience and goals,
provide a specific right to the
proper five emails
so you can structurally perform
much better.
So what's your target market?
Let's say target market.
Ecom brands doing five to 20
million per year.
Current results, say like 4% open
rate, 1% reply rate.
So we're getting some actual
specific things, but not just the
cold emails themselves, but
deliverability.
Messaging problems, audience
mismatch.
Here's a new strategy.
Go to five emails, maximum proper
delays.
Show a bigger case.
Let me rewrite this as a proper
email sequence.
So we got a full sequence being
written for us here now.
Even tells us when to wait.
Let's focus on the iOS attribution
side of things.
So there we go.
So now we've got the key changes
made.
We've got spam, trigger words, and
guarantees from subject lines.
Use industry specific pain points.
Included bigger, more relevant
case studies.
Vary the CTAs.
Add a proper virtualization hooks
for their product launches.
Focus on problems specific to
their revenue range.
Cut from eight emails to five or
proper delays.
But each email serve a different
purpose instead of repeating the
same offer.
This has got much better
durability and response rates
because it sounds like industry
expertise
rather than generic marketing
pitches.
Now, most of those could have been
solved if I gave it more
information in the beginning
cold email sequence writing
section.
But again, I just kind of gave it
just a basic one I've been using
for a few of these.
So the more information you give
about your actual real offer, the
better results you're
going to get.
But as you can see, this is a
great job of fixing this up and
rewriting it even better.
And this is something that we can
customize even further and, you
know, kind of really
hone down and especially combined
with our mass personalizer
workflow that we have inside
later on in the course under the
lead gen agency section will
really create some great campaigns
that should do really well.
And of course, your client
extension, you will get three
different, I believe three, maybe
even four different cold email
calls every single week where with
experts that will just
go in detail on what's working
currently, the best methods to,
you know, get your emails
seen at the top of inboxes and how
to set up your campaigns for
maximum deliverability.
So just another quick insight into
client extension, AI dashboard,
and hope this was helpful and
see you in the next one.
Peace.