What's up guys so in this one
we're going to be going over the
vsl script creator and reviewer
uh to do this we're going to be
taking our previous offer that we
created using the offer
creation and offer review module
and we're going to add a little
bit more information in order to
get a decent vsl script so we're
going to do a new chat and we are
going to paste in the previous
offer that we got from our offer
creator but let's add a bit more
information so the promises
in there the problems in there uh
the desired situation uh say
desired situation is uh increased
revenue uh from uh let's see let's
just say from email plus
conversion rates uh what is the
usp and usp
details usp is uh our retention
revenue system usp details uh 90
day uh fast track to generating
more revenue from email lists
reasons to believe so strong case
studies last brand generated we'll
just say 150k extra revenue from
existing email list within 30 days
30 days and sales argument is just
uh we generate uh more money from
existing uh contacts without
any added effort on brand owners
part so i was going to hit send on
this and this is now going to
start
writing our vsl so it's going to
go to the whole vsl i will uh let
it run for a little bit and then
we're
going to go back and i will uh
just quickly run through what we
got out of it and then we'll
send it to our reviewer so scroll
up here it's actually a pretty
long vsl but if we take a look
and say uh if you're an e-commerce
brand owner sitting on an email
list of 10 000 subscribers or
more and you're not generating at
least 30 percent of your total
revenue from email you're
literally
leaving hundreds of thousand
dollars at the table every single
month listen i know you didn't
build
your business to watch money slip
through your fingers you're going
to create freedom security
the life you actually want there's
a brutal truth most email
marketing agencies won't tell you
your current email setup is
probably costing you more money
than it's making you i'm talking
to the
ambitious e-commerce owners who
are tired of being slaves of paid
traffic the ones who know there's
a
goal on seeing their emails
because i've figured out how to
extract it if you've got all these
subscribers you're ready to stop
throwing money at facebook and
google just to break even then
what
i'm about to share could be the
most profitable evidence you'll
ever spend
so that's beginning let's take
this now and we're just going to
copy and paste this to our
reviewer
so let's go over to vsl script
review chat we're going to paste
this in we're going to hit enter
and
we're going to see what uh we get
overall assessment the script is
strong bones with excellent pain
point identification a compelling
case study but it cuts off worth
crucial call to action and lacks
clear
pricing details script search for
review book analysis the opening
line if you're an e-commerce brand
owner
senior email list uh so it gives a
full analysis of each section of
it
and improvements to what we can do
give us an implementation
checklist conversion optimization
recommendations um and uh then
what we can do to make it better
next so it says conversion
optimization recommendation add
scarcity and urgency elements
throughout your screen reads like
the
offers always available which
reduces motivation doc now add
limited spots time set of bonuses
or
seasonal urgency specific pricing
and package details uh strength
unique mechanism add more social
proof
variety create stronger bridge to
the call to action and then
complete the call to action
section with
clear next steps application
process and booking instructions
actually three more brief case
studies insert pricing investment
uh information before the
guarantee section strengthen the
unique
mechanism name and explanation add
urgency almost throughout and as
finally as with the financial
script is solid with excellent
problem identification emotional
hooks focusing completing the
closed
adding this conversion almost to
trends to a high converting vsl so
you can see we've got the basis
or vsl written within seconds you
know that took us like literally
just pacing in our offer and we
got
out something really really solid
and uh now we can use this to go
forward and kind of actually
develop
this and add our own kind of you
know twists and our own uh
personalization to it based on
also the
the suggestions we're getting uh
here in the uh uh vsl script
reviewer so again this takes what
would you
you know usually be if a minimum a
two-hour process of writing vsl
down to literally about like you
know
15 minutes maybe max and you have
a vsl script ready to go uh this
is also trained off of nick verges
incredible training uh that he
provides inside client ascension
so you know it works nick has
written
vsl for some of the biggest uh
names out there in business and is
extremely good at what he does
so uh you know that the results
you're going to get from this are
going to be really really solid
so also nick will be happy to
review your vsl script on your vsl
on his vsl calls inside client
ascension so uh if you want to get
started asap definitely the
dashboard is the quickest way to
do
that hope you enjoyed this video
and i will see you in the next one
peace