What's up guys lucas here so in
this one i'm going to be showing
you the offer creation
offer review modules now you saw
in the previous video that we had
a chat with daniel and a digital
clone of daniel who definitely can
help you with your offer but this
is if you want to get more of
a structured output that gives you
your full uh offer details your
launch strategy kind of
everything involved so uh it
requires a bit of less going back
and forth answering questions with
ai dan so if we go to the offer
creation module here um i'll do a
new chat and uh we had previously
um made a json business context
profile uh so i've gone to my
content section i've copied that
i'm
just going to paste that in here
now with no other information
right so i'm going to put that in
and
click send and uh that is after
filling out the full json business
context profile form and uh now
it's
going to create a uh fully
detailed uh uh uh offer for me
it's going to call the problems it
might be
a little harsh at times um so it's
going to then end up writing the
whole thing for me so we're going
to run all the way through and
then we're going to go back and
look and see what the full output
is in
a moment okay so this is done so
we're going to go back up and see
this is problem one your offer is
boring ahead as hell retention
service email retainers sound like
every other email agency
on the planet the zero different
differentiation your selling
service not offers no quantifiable
results promise you say meaningful
uplift that's not an offer that's
wishful thinking
call traffic needs specific
numbers they won't even respond to
your outreach you're targeting the
wrong segment shopify brands doing
50 plus per month is way too broad
you need to get specific
about who within that range and
what's the problem you solve
here's what you do
make specific subnetions in
shopify brands create a demand
generation offer with a guarantee
and uh based on your services
here's what i recommend we
guarantee and decrease your own
revenue by at least 24 in 90 days
for our revenue retention revenue
system or you don't pay
what do you get complete clavier
flow rebuild zero audit
optimization 90 days of campaigns
company management optimization
difficulty auditing cleanup
stipulation for the guarantee most
of
at least 10k email subscribers
most event all recommended changes
in 30 days must maintain current
traffic levels must not change
pricing or product mix during test
period position is a hybrid offer
don't make this pure retainer make
it a 90-day intensive option to
continue monthly this removes the
subscription resistance i talk
about in my training pricing eight
thousand dollars for nine days and
two thousand dollars a month they
want to continue step four get
case studies immediately your
average
strategy is the dream 100 approach
find a hundred shopify brands in
your chosen niche doing 50 200k
per month send them a loom video
showing exactly what's wrong with
their current email setup and how
you'd
fix it even gives me a script
content strategy and uh your
current offers will get you maybe
five
ticket per month if you're lucky
this position gets you to 100k
plus because you have a bigger
problem
with a clear guarantee so very
detailed response right really
really good so let's take that
offer
section that uh it came up with
there so uh offer what you get and
simulations so actually we'll
include this
position as a hybrid offer and
let's go back to the offer review
module we're going to go here and
do a
new chat and we're going to paste
this in here we're going to see
what the offer review which is
also
trained on daniel's information
has to say about that this is
solid our foundation needs some
refinement
what's working your guarantee is
strong uh the hyperstructure is
exactly right what needs
improvement
your value proposition lacks a uh
so that component you're telling
them what to do but not why they
desperately need it your position
is better we guarantee increase
your own revenue by at least
24 in 90 days let's finish writing
out uh through a retention revenue
system so that you can reduce
your customer acquisition uh costs
and stop leading money on paid ads
and get more expensive every month
ideal client profile target
e-commerce brands 100k to 500k per
month uh talk after brands 150k a
month
gives you some lead magnet ideas a
launch strategy and positioning
improvement turn of offer
consideration this doesn't convert
well instead of having to email
revenue recovery specifically
targeting brands who had good
email revenue that dropped off
this creates more urgency and
demand
your offer strong bones the
guarantee price and structure
intervals are solid focus on
improving
the positioning of vibe
proposition then launch a dream
100 outreach using free audits to
do service
based the magnet so that's
essentially how this works you can
easily create both your offer and
then
review it using our offer review
uh of course you already have an
existing offer just go directly to
offer review but if you're just
starting out obviously go to offer
creation uh you don't
have to give it the json business
context profile although i do
recommend it you can just you know
talk to it back and forth and tell
it kind of what you want to do and
what you've been doing in the
past maybe or how you think you
could uh kind of get started on
something but overall uh you know
this is going to give you a
structured output for how you can
set up your offer and we'll help
you then with the rest of your uh
content creation such as your vsl
your sales checklist all that sort
of
stuff so this is just one of the
modules that we or two of the
modules say that we have in here
offer
review and offer creation and uh
both are service kind of the basis
of the rest of what you're going
to do throughout the course so uh
if you're using client extension
ai highly suggest you start with
the business context profile
followed by the offer creation
hope it's helpful and see you in
the next one peace