What's up guys in this one i'm
going to be showing you both our
landing page copywriter
and our hiring scorecard creator
so for this one it asks us for our
product service target audience
main competitors desired outcome
and call to action and price
points on any special offers
so again i've got some uh base
information here already ready to
go so i'm just going to paste
this in and we're going to send
this and we're going to get a
fully written landing page for us
it's going to write all the uh
copy we need for the landing page
so we've got the fully generated
copy here started off e-commerce
brands doing 2 million 50 million
in revenue we'll increase your
email revenue by 30 percent 90
days will work for free the only
email marketing edges are
guaranteed
results for e-commerce brands or
you don't pay a dime get your free
email revenue audit or book
strategy call first by two
e-commerce brands we've got a
testimonial uh then we go through
the pain
points problem one problem two
problem three uh explain our uh
system as the alternative and the
solution uh how do we guarantee 3%
more email revenues 90 days um
then what you get the uh
get your more cta see how much
revenue you're missing out get a
customer to capture it
uh how can we guarantee results
full faq written out here and then
some final ctas so this is
everything
you would need to actually get
started on uh creating your
landing page uh we've got a number
of templates and tutorials in
sidecline ascension uh for landing
pages across multiple different
web
builders and explain exactly how
to use this copy in order to uh
create a full landing page that is
ready to start converting clients
so um this is a very very quick
way to get started you know as you
can see
these are some things here that uh
maybe i would change but that's
because i gave it very basic
information to start with if i
gave it actual detailed
information about a real offer
that i was
actually running we get even
better results and of course i was
editing slightly as you go as well
but that is our landing page
copywriter again what would
usually take you maybe a few hours
now is
taking you seconds to do so uh
we're going to check out next the
scorecard creator for hiring new
employees so this is our scorecard
creator this is something that
andre teaches directly inside
client
ascension is when you're hiring
for a role creating a scorecard to
make the hiring process even
easier
and make sure you get the best
possible candidates uh when you're
doing your outreach
so again i've come up with a fake
job title and description here
just an email marketing manager
um giving some basic
responsibilities things like that
and so we're going to hit enter on
this
we're going to get our detailed
scorecard out of this
so we're finished so we go to the
top here you'll see uh the goes
with the mission for the email
marketing manager uh the outcomes
and kpis this is super helpful if
you actually don't know what
specific kpis that you want the
hire to actually have to hit so it
tells us that uh drive through
percent of revenue growth for each
client account with the 90 day
optimization periods
achieve minimum 50k additional
monthly revenue maintain 99% of
email deliverability
um building optimized comments of
automated email flow systems uh
has full breakdown exactly all the
responsibilities of the role the
different competencies that they
should have uh the time
that is expected of the uh the
role the compensation that they
will receive as part of the role
expected
earnings uh and what the work
environment is like so again do
you just put in the basic kind of
what you're looking for one-liners
kind of each of these sort of
things and you'll get out a
detailed hiring scorecard that now
you can use to not only use the
job posting but also when you're
hiring someone run through this
make sure they can hit all these
things here so uh then of course
you can take this you know to
andre's uh operations call where
he'll go through it even further
with
you um this is uh just an example
of a few things the client
extension dashboard can do it's
extremely
powerful and we're constantly
improving it to make it even
better and adding more features
and tools
um we've got a few already in
production that i think are going
to be really really helpful and
are
really going to make this the
number one place to manage your
entire agency
so again if you've not upgraded
and you're interested in uh
getting access to the dashboard
you can reach out to whoever
helped you with your onboarding
the ssc that onboard you as part
of the
course or email me directly at
lucas at client ascension.com
hope this is helpful and i will
see you in the next one peace