What's up guys so in this one i'm
going to be showing you our sales
checklist creator
as you can see here this is takes
the form of david jacob our sales
coach at client ascension
and helps create detailed sales
checklist checklist that you can
use in your sales calls
to close deals more consistently
we do this because we tend not to
teach using an actual
detailed sales script rather a
checklist of things you should
complete on the sales call
in order to increase your chances
of closing so i put together just
some basic answers
to these questions here based on
the offer we talked about earlier
and we're going to hit enter
on this and uh it will give us the
full sales checklist for
performance-based email marketing
pre-call preparation lead
qualification criteria gives us
the criteria for the lead the
mindset
and frame preparation the research
requirements the opening and
disqualification uh gives us kind
of the step-by-step of what we
should do on the call in order to
and things we should mention in
order to help to close the deal uh
as you see this goes on for quite
a bit so we're going to have this
run and then i'll go back through
it when it's finished
okay so as you can see this is
pretty detailed so as i said it
gives the lead qualification
criteria once it in frame
preparation position is the email
expert is not a service provider
maintain outcome independence
you're evaluating them too most of
your first privacy three
for 40 percent revenue on the
table of email you guarantee
results as you qualify for your
expertise uh then brief positive
results actually take the time
today and are running x million
first bank is too busy acknowledge
their growth and recent
achievements and discovering
research
before we dive in we go forward to
a new work with browns to at least
two million our process requires
full access to email platform
customer data we guarantee 32
revenue in nine days so that means
following our own our proven
process exactly
then you look at buying propensity
indicators we'll strive for you to
look at email marketing
improvements right now how much
current revenue comes from email
marketing authority identification
who else would be involved in a
decision like this when you made
marketing investments
100k plus annually before what's
the difficult decision process
then the pain point discovery
this is going to take by 15 to 20
minutes but for problem
identification revenue leakage
look at
your emails with ex-subscribers
what do you think each subscriber
should be worth monthly
uh implication questions revenue
impacts if you're leaving an extra
month at the table with email
what do you have different email
charges for customers to spend 50
just 500 these are all
detailed questions you're going to
ask in order to uh get the most
out of the sales call
finally we've got the three
pillars pitch which is about two
to three minutes long
uh pillar one is the revenue audit
and foundation the first thing we
do is conduct a
comprehensive revenue audio
recording email performance uh the
tie down is does having
that clear picture of your revenue
opportunities make sense as a
starting point
then they'll say yes you say
performance campaign execution
then we have our proven campaign
system
uh can you see how having those
systems running automatically
would free routine to time
while driving more revenue they'll
say yes finally we continuously
optimize performance using
advanced
analytics and testing scaling what
works and limiting what doesn't
tie down makes sense that
ongoing optimization would be
crucial for the same results right
they'll say yes
then we do some objection
prevention then we close with a
pre-priced
tie down price delivery approach
next step process the frame
management is how you're going to
conduct
yourself on the call the power
response they say we need to think
about it i understand
what specifically need to think
through the investment the process
the results
most successful brands make
decisions quickly when they see it
clear about the guarantee results
was holding you back uh if they
say it's not the right time i'm
curious but it would be the right
time to add excellent revenue to
your business quality frame
response they say we can find
cheaper options you're absolutely
right there are cheap email
services because they guarantee
the revenue increase in 90 days so
then you have the post call
actions the follow-up process
pipeline
management and some key reminders
for execution so you can see if
you were to follow this exactly
this
would you know be 100 perfect
before um uh getting you through
any sort of sales call and you do
this
before any of your you set this up
for any of your uh different
offers it'll be uh tailored
specifically to
whatever offer your uh you type in
here and you will get a perfect
kind of checklist to follow
through you give this up on the
screen beside you while you're on
the call and it's uh super super
helpful so the next we're going to
look at is going to be the sales
call review
the sales call review you just
paste in a sales call transcript
now i've gone and gotten
uh a sales call kind of a sales
discovery call uh transcript
already copied here i'm just going
to paste it in we're just going to
hit enter so now the ai is going
to analyze the sales call and
give us a detailed breakdown so
we're gonna let this run for a
second we're going to go back to
it
okay so we're done so we go
through here um overall call
assessment this is a technical
consultation call rather than a
traditional sales call like i said
i knew this was more of a
discovery
call than an actual sales call um
lucas did well in understanding
the technical requirements and
demonstrating capability however
from a sales perspective is
calling me several critical
opportunities to establish value
create urgency and secure
commitment beyond just saying a
proposal
oh well lucas quickly established
credibility uh good technical
understanding effective use of
screen sharing professional
rapport building collaborative
tone throughout clear next steps
established established uh key
areas with sales loft lost those
career of pain points who
looks never explored why trials
need the solution urgently uh how
this illness is impacting his
business whatever he's using by by
delays time and pressures for his
new photo launch
frustration levels of current
situation so there's a ton of
things i mean
improved upon there then we get
specific uh framework
recommendations and action items
for future
calls uh so you can see if you use
this repeatedly over and over as
you're doing sales calls
this will be super useful in
helping you to determine uh what
areas you're kind of consistently
missing
out on and where you can improve
going forward uh combine this with
the sales checklist
creator and your sales calls
should be an absolute breeze so uh
as you can see that's how we
conduct sales by the ai dashboard
super useful and of course we also
have our weekly sales calls with
david jacob our sales
here at ca uh who does our long
calls every week where he goes
through all this helps you develop
your
sales mindset uh it goes over kind
of different kind of sales
techniques and tactics and overall
uh gets
you trained up to be the best
salesman possible so i hope this
was useful and i will see you in
the next one
peace