All right, guys.
So in this one, we're going to go
over how to get a phone number and
how to get it approved.
You can start sending texts to
your leads, prospects, clients,
you know, whoever you want to
reach out to.
So you're going to go to settings.
Then here, go to phone numbers.
Right now here.
You get a chance to buy a phone
number.
What you want to do is click add
number up here.
So let me just move that out of
the way.
Add number, add a phone number.
And here we want to filter.
So here you want to put local, not
toll free.
And here you want to search the
first three digits of wherever you
are located or honestly, wherever
you want.
So I'm just going to put a pick a
random one.
Doesn't really matter.
So I'm going to take this one in
Nevada.
Proceed to buy.
And so what you're going to do
now, what you're going to have to
do now is get your ID verified.
So let me just do that and we'll
keep going.
All right.
So I verified my ID or my, uh,
yeah, my ID.
So I bought the phone number.
You could edit the name here.
So first is just X out of this.
And what you want to do is click
here.
You could keep it as is, you know,
Henry's number, know of that, but
a couple other things you want to
change is first of all, you want
to record every call you get.
And I would just stop playing the
record message unless you're going
to be used, like sending this out
to people or doing stuff like
that.
I just record the calls for myself
in case I need to review something
like during the call, like my
process or just getting some
details that happened on the call,
stuff like that.
So since it's internal, I prefer
just to avoid this message, but
you could also just say, just add
it.
It takes a second to, to say in
there.
Then you want to make sure that
whenever someone calls this
number, it rings your phone so you
don't miss on any leads.
And then you can remove this as
you grow.
And maybe have someone that's
specializes in the sales of the
business.
You can change the name and this
call connect feature, pretty much
what it means is that before you
connect, you have to press a key.
I prefer to remove it because it
just makes the person calling you
wait until you click that button.
I'd rather just go straight to, to
the call.
So you can click save and then we
can go into the A2P verification.
So A2P means automation to person.
Okay.
And because there's like a lot of
scams that you get a text from
Amazon or something that you got
to update a setting, I don't know,
just scams.
Now we have to pretty much pay a
fee and, and register our
businesses for every time we buy a
phone number.
So what you want to do is go to
the trust center and you want to
click start registering now.
Okay.
Now, if you followed my
instructions and you filled out
this information, uh, inside
business info, if you follow my
instructions and you fill this out
under business info, then this
will be already filled out for
you.
Okay.
So you're just going to go here,
continue.
Now I'm honestly, I don't need to
register my business again.
So I'm just going to put random
info here just to show you what it
looks like.
You're going to put the address.
As you can see, your address
should be already added and then
your name, email address.
So for the email address, you want
to use a domain email, not like a
Gmail account, just because it'll
ask you to verify again.
It's just, it's not ideal.
So I'm just going to put a domain
email.
phone number, just put your phone
number and your position.
Honestly, just put director
doesn't matter.
Then click continue.
And here you want to put a, Oh,
hold on.
Let me go back because yes, you
want to make sure you have an LLC,
like a tax ID.
Okay.
And then here you're going to put
business type, LLC, corporation,
wherever it is.
EIN here, you put a EIN, whatever
it is.
I like to put consumer here and
then your email, same thing.
And your website.
And wherever you serve, you
service people.
And then here we continue.
And here you want to select low
volume.
Most people need low volume.
You don't need to send 600
segments per day.
That's a lot.
You click the, you acknowledge the
fee of $24 for the registration.
You click continue.
And then here you want to add
essentially examples or explain
how leads will be messaged.
Okay.
So there's a way to do this where
you really just copy and paste
stuff.
So what I use is called A2P wizard
and it's free, which is great.
So you scroll down here, you click
get my free compliance kit.
And what you're going to do is you
put your name, so your email.
So whatever it is, the client, the
client name is going to be you
again.
So business name and then client
website, business website.com/book
or/contact us, something along
those lines.
And here it says use HTTPS.
Right.
And then just upload your, your
logo here.
So again, just select your logo.
Check this box off and submit.
And what I'll do is it'll just
process your information and give
you everything you need
to use just to copy and paste it
into those fields, which makes
your lives a thousand times
easier.
So wait for it to load.
Click here.
It may take an extra second to
load.
So just give it a bit.
It's just rendering images and
everything you need.
So it's very easy to get approved.
OK, so just wait for the images to
render.
OK, so as you can see, like it
just takes your logo and adds it
to forms that are already
compliant.
OK, so that way you really don't
have to do a lot of effort here.
So all you got to do is just click
copy.
So you can see here is use case
description.
You copy this.
You go back into root flow or
sorry, the go high level.
I just it's that's the the domain
I'm using.
But go high level.
You paste it in the under use case
description.
And then same thing.
Sample message one.
You go back to A2P wizard sample
message one.
Go back here and paste it.
Message two.
Copy the second message.
Paste it.
Continue.
Here you go back again.
Same thing.
Go to A2P wizard.
You can send copy.
Just copy that.
Paste it in here.
Opt in message.
Go right here.
Paste here and then you submit.
OK, so I'm not going to submit
because I don't really want to
submit.
Like I don't need to submit it.
But you submit and then you got to
wait until it's approved.
So for the brand approval.
So there's two applications I go
through.
First is the brand, which is to
make sure you your business is
real, that you are legit.
You actually have that LLC or EIN
or whatever.
And then once it's approved, they
go into the campaign.
So to make sure that the brand is
approved, you have to make sure
that the legal business
thing that you put in there is
actually your legal business name.
So if your legal name is XYZ Corp
LLC, you know, whatever it is, but
your actual name
that you use online is like Legion
Mastermind, you know, whatever it
is.
Don't put Legion Mastermind put in
the XYZ Corp LLC.
Like that is the legal name.
And that's the one you have to use
for the application.
If you use the wrong name, even if
it's if you forget to put like a
capitalized letter in there,
it'll get denied.
So it needs to be exactly the
same.
So whenever you you filed or you
you got your EIN number, there's
going to be a letter or a form
you filled out that pretty much
gives you that EIN.
And next to it is your legal name.
Just check that form out and
you'll see exactly the name you
need to use for this application.
And then once you do that, you
should be good to go.
So I have my applications have
never failed since using A2P
Wizard.
So expect it to go through.
And if it fails, if the brand
fails, usually means that the EIN
was wrong or the name of the
business
was wrong.
Okay.
Something along those lines.
All right.
So now the way it'll work when you
send the application is first,
you're going to go through
the brand.
Once the brand is approved, you're
going to get an email.
And then once you get that email,
you got to go back in here and
submit the campaign,
the campaign application, it will
already be filled out with
everything you added.
You just have to click submit one
more time and that's it.
Okay.
So that is it for this one.
I know it's kind of a lot of stuff
to send that application, but once
you do it,
you can buy more numbers for your
business without any issues.
And yeah, it's just a one-time
thing.
Okay.
See you in the next one.