What's up guys lucas here uh i'm
gonna run you guys through
something really cool so uh as you
know i've talked a lot about
building landing pages and how
awkward it can be a lot of you
been on my calls or been on
one-on-ones with you um it's
usually a long kind of annoying
process
and we've talked a bit in the past
about kind of ai uh website
builders but honestly none of them
have been very good until now so
uh webflow just launched their ai
website builder and today i'm
going to build a quick site with
you guys to show you what this can
look like so i'll put the url
to access this in uh the
description but basically just go
to the ai site builder here who
are you
building for for us obviously
we're building for a business i'm
going to use my own business going
to
say innovative i'm going to go
next they want some details right
who's our audience makes the
business
unique uh they have an example
there you know about it so i'm
just use chat gbt that knows a bit
of my
business to generate a basic
description so we're going to go
back here and we're going to paste
this
in right now it actually has to
put in 5 000 words which is a lot
so you can prompt this pretty
deeply
but uh let's go ahead with this
i'm going to let i'm just going to
choose clean a professional for
this one to like a light mode sort
of one brown tone of voice ai
suggested uh color range i like
blue so let's go with that we're
going to click generate now what's
cool is after you generate the
initial site you can actually
generate other sections for it
afterwards so even if you don't
like something or there's a
section missing or you need to add
more stuff no problem you can just
click generate choose from an
example and uh it'll it'll get
added so i'll show you guys this
now now
you'll probably still have to
write the copy yourself that's
something you're still gonna have
to do but you know this still gets
you the majority of the site done
it's mobile optimized too this is
super super handy and it's going
to speed up actually making a nice
looking website super super quick
it's
going to be great so um let's take
a look at this now see what this
does all right we're back for
reference that took i'd say
approximately 30 seconds to a
minute maybe max uh but we've got
the base of our site here now uh
again like i said this doesn't
follow the exact format that we
teach in c8 that's no problem so
i'm going to show you guys how
this works so uh there's tons of
you
can change you can change the
colors you can change on the
overall theme of the site um just
there you
click a button and it changes so
let's say i like this one actually
we're gonna go with this like
super like kind of gray and white
sort of sort of theme um let's
check this one out too and see
what this is like i actually kind
of like this one too all right
let's go with this one actually
this
is a nice little change up right
so we're gonna go with this um i
like these buttons a lot these
buttons are really nice um over
here you can change the typography
so you can change you know the the
fonts that you want you can give
it a different look whatever you
want to do um almost cool to me
uh you can change the colors of
the sections this is where you
change like i can see kind of like
the
layout so you can have like just
the top section this one kind of
changes up here uh you can just
show what it looks like yeah okay
let's go with this like this all
right uh you can do accent you can
think so i can do it like a color
if i want so i can do that you
know something on those lines um
but i kind of like the inverse
ones let's go with uh let's just
go with this i think this is kind
of a nice symbol thing you can
choose the images uh the different
kind of styles so let's go with a
nice cool dim lighting i think
that's a cool style and uh these
are all ai generated obviously um
i'm gonna check out the modern one
too actually i want to see what
this is like so let's see what
this does um it's just doing all
the images now there you go it is
very dark and moody let's go with
dramatic or dramatic light so let
that do that change the buttons
how you want them to i as i said
like the buttons as they are i
think well that's pretty sexy
let's check that one actually
let's
go to the other one do like that
all right we're gonna go with that
uh the forms the cards you can
change uh just how they kind of
look in general so so you want a
real poppy you know kind of like
a comic book-y sort of one um kind
of super clean uh i kind of just
like the basic one with a bit
of a shadow i think i don't want
to go super crazy with this uh
it's like it's kind of clean and
simple so let's just do that and
uh they can change the roundness
of the corners on on different
things you have it square you can
have it fully rounded but i like
it how it is so let's go so
now we're going to start building
now we're in the actual webflow
editor here's where we can change
things right uh you know text and
stuff but i want to talk about
adding new sections so you know as
we
mentioned like one of the first
things you want to do after your
hero section which obviously you
have like a vsl or something
instead of an image you also kind
of edit those sort of things but
uh
yeah let's say we want to replace
the hero section right we want to
do we need to deal with a video
we're going to click here we're
going to click this purple add a
section button
now it'll bring you to the bottom
of the page it's totally fine it's
going to accept the terms
and conditions here and you've got
different categories for different
layouts let's do hero
it's going to generate a few
wireframe options for us right so
as we mentioned we obviously want
one
like kind of a video option here
so that's where we put a video
into uh this looks like it could
work
what else would be good that
obviously could work again we're
going to add these a little bit
afterwards so it doesn't have to
be a hundred percent perfect we're
just looking for one that we think
is kind of nice and goes overall
uh with kind of what we're what
we're looking for um i would say
we're going to go with yeah i like
this one let's do this one right
so we're going to click this
and it's going to generate the
section down here there we go so
obviously you replace this with a
video box but let's just move this
up to the very top and we'll
delete this one so obviously here
you
can click it and change everything
how you want it to um you can
replace this with a video all that
sort of stuff then the next
section would be like you know a
uh a pain point section right so
let's say
do a pain point section obviously
there's not going to be a section
here titled pain points
but they will have something we
can repurpose so let's say
features features are usually
lists
or blocks or sect or kind of you
know multiple cards so let's look
through here and let's find
one that we can use uh yeah this
will work right so the three three
pain points let's choose this one
now again the copies are going to
be the exact copy you want you'll
obviously change that up but
that's really nice i really like
that so let's take that and put
that up underneath our hero
section
uh again you can reduce the
padding and stuff you can add a
headline everything you want to do
there
uh then let us go to okay
sometimes it does glitch out a
little bit as you saw there it
wasn't removing
the thing after i did it that's
totally fine i just clicked out of
it and then i hit escape and i hit
plus and i did back to the same
generator again so uh after that
we usually have a why choose us
so you know uh technically
something like this actually
already works let's move this
further up
um so after the pain points we'll
have the why choose us move us up
here uh actually before we do this
let's do a testimonial that's one
of the sections i actually have
here so add a section of ai let's
do
a testimonial
and let's go away from like these
kind of boxes a little bit we've
done a few of them so let's find a
nice layout that we like let's say
one of these big feature
testimonials right let's do that
let's use a few extra sections
here we can delete these too so
that's done so let's get rid of
that
and that and that and that that's
this further up the page to
i think it was here so we can
delete these two sections we don't
need these
all right now let's do a three
part this is another kind of basic
test so i don't like that
let's do a basic uh three part
book a call section right so we're
going to go add section uh if
click
show more you'll see there is more
different sections here you can
choose from uh i'm just
repurposing a lot of stuff because
i think it's like the easiest way
to do it but uh let's do
again features because again we
need kind of cards or boxes um so
again this is going to be the
three
part uh book a call section this
one actually has a ct already in
it so i'll show you what we'll do
here
let's choose this one
generating
and then all we have to do really
is
delete delete delete
great there we go done right so
this is our three part you know
uh yeah it's like probably the
headline actually not by headline
so all right so then we do a three
part book a call um let's take
this move further up here put the
faq let's move the faq right
yeah above the footer
all right so we got these are
three part book a call uh you know
then you do like a watch you get
that'll work for what you get
section you know you can explain
there in detail what they're going
to
get uh you could have a pricing
table you don't need to obviously
we don't usually do pricing tables
so you know just boom delete that
uh then we don't need to get in
touch or anything like that
uh let's do a like team section
section or about you or something
like that right so let's go to
team
let's see if we'll choose
let's look at different wireframes
and what ones we like
let's just go with
with this one so that'll do like a
basic team section
there you go
there it is again you're just the
uh you know the which got potting
is without yourself manually as i
explain in different tutorials and
our team faq and then obviously
you would add your colony as we've
kind of like talked about in the
past so like again uh or actually
let's do another one actually
well there's one there i like they
do stats so let's do a stats
section
go show more
do this one
perfect so we're gonna move this
up right below the hero section
so there it goes that's basically
it we've got the basically edit
the site done uh obviously i
haven't
done any editing on this just very
very minor so obviously you want
to go in and fix some things up
and change all the copy and update
everything but let's say you want
to change uh large things right
like you want to change the uh
typography you just click into the
typography and you can choose
the different uh styles and size
and change up the whole kind of
look and feel of the site so i
actually do like that one so let's
go with that right and they got
different ones here as well just
different uh headings and fonts
and types um and uh some creative
ones here
you know you can do whatever but
uh overall that's uh that's kind
of how this works you can change
up all the settings we saw at the
beginning over here even change
the colors for this the whole
section we can choose from
different palettes so we can
choose slightly kind of lighter
blue sort
of one choose a darker blue choose
a whole different uh like orange
and teal and stuff and we'll get
different colors throughout the
page uh so let's say let's change
let's choose this copilot one
and then let's change up the uh
section colors so let's do this so
there we go we've got a nice
different layout now for
everything uh and uh super easy to
do uh takes two seconds and
obviously this
gives you an amazing base now to
edit from again uh probably not
going to be a one shot where
you're
going to do this once and it's
going to be absolutely perfect but
it's going to give you a
way easier starting point and it
should be mobile optimized largely
as well you'll have to do a
little bit of editing but it's 10
times easier for anyone that's
designed in my flow can tell how
much
easier uh this seems than uh
having to do everything yourself
from scratch uh so i'm going to
work on some
prompts for this for you guys too
so if you're going to find a bit
more and get it closer to like a
one
shot but um for now i think this
is actually an incredible tool
again check the description in
the link below uh for a link to
the site where you can try this
out in webflow and uh i think this
is
going to be really handy for a lot
of you guys um this a lot of the
questions you get are like how do
i
make a nice looking site you know
i think this is definitely the
first step to that um you know
having a
side like that is going to be i
think also even does like
animations and stuff a little bit
uh
got it um yeah look at that see
that how nice that is and i didn't
do any of that no so like you know
like hover interactions and stuff
um you know overall this is
there's a little thing there too
you know
uh this is a an extremely i think
powerful way to uh get the start
of your site started and to uh get
you know most of the way there
with it 80 of the way or so and
mobile optimized things super easy
so
uh yeah please mess around with
this let me know how it's going
for you and try it out a bit and
uh
yeah just uh i'll be doing a lot
more training on this and you can
ask me any questions about this on
my landing page call on wednesdays
so see some of you guys there
peace