Has come to my attention that I
have not made a video on Microsoft
Clarity.
I may have mentioned
this in some of the others, but I
don't have a dedicated video on
it.
So today I'm going to walk
you guys through it.
So what is Microsoft Clarity?
Basically, it records every single
user that comes
to your website.
This allows you to see where
they're clicking, where they're
scrolling,
generate heat maps, basically
figure out what areas of your site
you need to improve.
If someone's
only scrolling down 30% of the way
of your landing page, now you can
see what's at that 30%.
That
means they're not continuing on,
they're not moving forward.
And what can you change there to
get
them to keep going further?
So Clarity works across basically
any platform.
The three popular web
builders I suggest for you guys
are Card, Webflow, and WordPress.
So I'm going to quickly walk you
through just the installation
steps for each of them.
So go to clarity.microsoft.com,
sign up for
free.
You can log in with Google or you
can log into Microsoft, whatever
you want to do.
You add a
new website.
All you put in is the URL of your
website and the name, then it'll
bring you to here
and you'll see this page.
So if you want to install
manually, which is what you want
to do for Webflow
and card, it'll give you a
tracking code.
So the code looks like this, copy
to your clipboard.
Then this is the CA test site.
I use this just to test a few
things and to show you guys how to
do
stuff.
So what you want to do is you want
to add a new embed.
Put this at the top here, name it,
anything you want, clarity,
whatever.
Style.
This is the important part.
Style, hidden.
You don't want
this actually show up.
Hidden and set it to head.
So these are the two main
important settings.
Style,
hidden and head.
And then you just paste your code
in there.
And I think that's basically it.
Yeah,
then you're done.
Just click done and publish.
And that will, that will show up
then on clarity,
right?
It'll take a few minutes maybe and
you'll start seeing data coming in
as people visit the site
and view it.
So same thing then in Webflow.
If I go to Webflow, I go to one of
the templates that we
have here.
You want to go to your site
settings to the bottom right hand
corner.
Custom code over here, head code,
paste in there, save, push, right?
So that's how you do that.
Let me
delete this.
And then the only one that has a
different installation is
WordPress.
So WordPress is
even easier.
You simply go to plug-ins, add
new, search, clarity.
Correct off clarity.
Install now.
It's installed.
Activate.
You'll then get clarity down here
on the left hand side.
Let load.
And from here, you can log in
directly.
I've already signed in.
Select your project or create a
new one, link it up and you're
good to go.
And what the data and clarity
looks like is something like this.
So let me just log in here.
Don't need a new project.
Let's take a look at my own
website.
So it'll give you some metrics and
details, scroll depth, things like
that.
It'll give you recordings of
everyone that visits the website.
So you can go on.
You can see how long they spent
here, how many
clicks there were.
You see here they're on mobile.
It'll hide some things.
That's just a setting they
have just to avoid things to do
with the privacy settings.
But basically you can see how
someone's
interacting with the page.
You can also see heat maps, see
where people are clicking on,
clicking off,
see what areas that they're
clicking on the most and using
that information.
Then you can
You can, uh, you can, you can, you
can set the, uh, the, the, the,
this is over the last three days.
I said it over the last 30 or give
you some more.
There you go.
So it gives you some more data on
where people are clicking, what
areas they're
clicking on, uh, the information
involved, and then you can just go
back and you can just watch entire
recordings of, uh, of people on
the website.
And it just gives you an idea of
how people are
interacting, what, what areas you
can improve, what you can do to,
uh, kind of generally get people
to
go to the final step, which is
booking a call with you.
So that's a, just a quick little
tip
that I highly suggest you guys do.
It is completely free.
It'll take you five minutes to set
up and
it will give you a ton of free
data you can use to improve your
landing page.
So hopefully some of you
guys will, uh, take this on board.
We'll, uh, we'll, we'll do this
and, uh, get a few better results
on your landing page in general,
and we'll help you to, um, improve
your overall performance.
And if you have any questions, any
trouble installing this, please
hit me up and I will
help you do it.
It's, uh, shouldn't take long.
And, uh, you can come to the
landing page call
on Wednesday if you want, and I'll
walk you through it there or book
a one-on-one of me
and we'll set it up.
So hope this helps you guys.
And if you have any problems, hit
me up.
See ya.