All right.
So in this section of the course,
you're going to be learning about
websites and
VSLs, but obviously you need to
first purchase a website.
Now, don't do this thing where
you're
going to like brand it to a
specific business model or like a
specific niche.
Just come up
with kind of like a broad type
name that could kind of apply to
anything else.
You get what I'm
saying?
Like, don't make it like, I don't
know, ecomscaler.com and then you
end up doing something
else.
You get what I'm saying?
Don't do that.
I'm just going to pick some random
things.
AI client ascension test.com.
And I'm just going to say that.
Just to show you how this
works.
So I like to use Squarespace.
AI client ascension test.com.
Check out.
Yep.
I'm going to do one year.
Um, you're not doing a website.
Don't, don't, don't do a website.
Um, okay.
Yeah, it is all fine.
Save and continue.
Um, confirm payment.
So it's $14 a year.
Okay, cool.
I have a website now.
So I'm going to click done.
I'm going to go to domains.
AI client.
I'm going to click on that domain.
And now here's what you need to
do.
Here's how
you get a business email address.
You're going to go to
workspace.google.com.
The links to all
this are going to be in the
description as well.
So workspace.google.com.
This is what you're
going to see.
Um, and all you need is a starter
plan.
So like what, when you see, like
there's
your name at your domain.com.
So like, what did we just buy?
We bought AI client ascension
test.com.
How do I make a Daniel at AI
client ascension test.com?
The answer is through Google
workspace.
This is how this works.
And then what happens is you have
like Google sheets, uh, Google
me, Google docs all through that
workspace.
So like for, I'm going to, so this
is how you do
it.
Um, so I'm just going to say, um,
AI client ascension test, just
you.
I'm in the United
States.
Next, Daniel Fazio, uh, a current
email address is like a backup.
Next, um, set up an existing
domain, continue with this method.
And this is my existing domain, AI
client ascension.com, uh,
next.
Okay.
So Daniel at a client says
test.com, um, come up with some
password.
Um, it's not
doing the suggest thing.
So I'm going to just put some
random, okay.
Um, flexible when a 40 month
business starter, um, try free for
14 days.
So you get a 14 day free trial.
Business starter.
Um, can I, can I not do that?
Payment method?
No, I guess I do.
I put it.
Okay.
I'm going to pause the video and
add a payment method real quick.
Okay.
I added that.
Green continue.
Okay.
Now, Daniel Fazio, Daniel,
dfazio85.gmail.com.
Oh, no, just to add, just to add
another user.
I don't need to add another user.
Nevermind.
You don't have to do that.
Okay.
So you can verify your own client
session, uh,
AI client ascension test.com and
then use Gmail with your domain.
Okay.
So get started.
So, so there is, there is a, is
it, there's an automatic thing
with Squarespace
that, that, that you can do,
right?
So I'll, I'm just going to do that
for now.
I'm going
to confirm it, but I need to also
explain to you what that's going
to do.
And I'll show you
in a second.
Okay, cool.
So what that just did is it added
DNS records.
What are DNS records?
So like,
okay, I'm going to refresh this
now.
DNS.
Okay.
So all this shit, it's hold on.
It just added this
right here.
It added this TXT record over here
and like a bunch of this shit
right here.
It just added
all of this, right?
That's how it connects to Google
workspace where it's like that.
That's
what like domain settings are just
DNS settings, right?
So that's what happened right
here.
So now
start using Gmail with your
domain.
We'll help you set up Gmail.
So it's probably going to make me
manually add DNS myself now.
So hold on.
Set up Gmail instead of receive
emails.
Okay.
Continue.
Danny Fazio.
Yes.
Me proceed with activation.
Okay.
I'm going to, I want to switch it
to manual
verification just so I can show
you.
Continue.
Okay.
So, so, so I'm going to show you
what adding
a DNS record does.
So it wants a MX record with this
data.
So I'm going to copy this priority
as one.
So I'm going to add a record.
Oh, fuck.
Hold on.
But you could have just did it
automatically.
I'm just showing you this just so
you know what DNS means
because you're going to like fuck
with DNS a lot in your, in your
life.
You're going to do this like
hella frequently.
So you just, you need to know
what's happening here.
Right?
So
MX.
MX record.
Priority is one.
This is the data.
It's actually there.
TTL.
4 hours, 30 minutes.
And then host is set to default
values.
I think you just put an ad.
Save.
Okay.
Cool.
Now.
Confirmed.
Cool.
Bam.
It worked.
All right.
So now, let me show you what
Google Workspace actually looks
like.
And the way you get to that is
with admin.google.com.
Okay.
Cool.
So admin.google.com.
And you log in with the email you
just made.
So I just logged in with Daniel at
AIclientessentialtest.com.
I understand.
So you'll, you'll get this thing.
Sign into new, uh, sign into a new
Chrome profile.
Hold on.
Let me move my fucking, you won't
see it.
Um, sign into a new Chrome
profile.
You should do that.
That's like, um, that's, you see
the top right.
You see a person and like you
could open another,
you can make like a new Chrome
profile for, um,
this like business.
You should do that.
I'm going to say no for now, but
you should do that.
Um, all right, cool.
So now here's, here's where
everything is.
So it's like, you have all your
shit here.
So like users, like what are my
users?
What do my users look like?
It's Daniel Fazio, right?
You also have apps.
So like, what kind of apps do we
have?
Google Workspace.
Um, all right.
I'll just go here.
Google Workspace.
Now I want to find Gmail.
Okay.
Gmail's on.
So what does that mean?
It means that if I go to
gmail.com, I can log in with
Daniel at client ascension,
AI client ascension test.com and
the password I set, and now I have
Gmail, right?
Okay.
So, so all of this shit you see
here.
So like, for instance, if you're
connecting a domain to, um, like
go high level or click
funnels, what it's going to do is
it's going to ask you to put in
DNS records and it'll
be manual at that point.
And, but all you do, all you need
to understand is that you have a
domain, you go to DNS settings,
you just add it in.
So like, for instance, um, you
know, you know, we just go to
custom records over here.
So you just, you just do add
record and it's always like some
shit.
It'll just say, add this TXT
record with this text or data,
right?
And normally you could just leave
host blank.
But if it's like a C name, for
instance, like a C name, what
that'll do is, um, you ever
notice how you'll see something
where it's like
www.clientascension.com?
That's, that's like a C name
record where it's like the host is
www.
Get what I'm saying?
Um, but if you do like go now and
go and you point it to a, a
specific IP address.
So like, for instance, um, like if
you were on ClickFunnels, like if
you, if you were
on go high level or ClickFunnels
and you're like, I want to publish
this domain on go.yourdomain.com,
what you would do is tell it, it
would give you a record that says,
okay, make a C name record
with the host go and send it to
this series of numbers.
And you would just like copy and
paste the numbers in here and
you'd save it.
And that's, that's all you do.
That's, that's all DNS record is.
You just fuck with it like that.
That's, that's pretty much all you
need to know.
But now this is all set up, uh,
you can fuck around in here if you
want.
Like if you have an employee and
they need to email, this is where
you do it.
Just admin.google.com and you just
click add user and then it's $8 a
month.
That's, that's how that works.
Um, yeah, but you're not, you're
not building a website in
Squarespace.
You're, you're going to, we're,
we're recommending you use go high
level because it has like a
fuck ton of shit for, for you to
use.
You'll see another video.
It's, it's all in this section.
You'll see it.
But yeah, that's it for this
video.
All right, peace.