All right, guys, in this one,
we're going to go over how to set
up your email service within Go
High Level.
This will allow you to pretty much
send emails to your list,
prospects, clients, or anybody
else.
So you want to go to settings
first, then email services.
Once you do that, you're going to
have this pop up.
OK, so this pop up is for setting
up your email with the lead
connector system, which is just
essentially Go High Levels email
system.
If you want to do that, just click
create dedicated domain.
And here you're going to put your
domain.
So let's say lc.company.com or
whatever it may be.
You're going to click add and
verify.
It's going to give you a few DNS
records to add into your domain
register.
OK, so you could click continue,
but that's going to have it think.
And then most likely you're going
to have to do it manually anyways.
So I would just click add record
manually.
And then you're going to take all
of these DNS records and put them
inside your domain registrar.
OK, so obviously make sure you
have you're selecting the right
record.
Right.
And that everything is copied and
pasted correctly.
If not, it won't work.
Once you paste all of these in
your registrar, just click verify
records and let it think for a
bit.
OK, and it'll be good to go.
Now, if you want to connect a
different email service like Gmail
or Yahoo or, you know, SendGrid,
we go back here.
And in this page, you can click
add service.
So here you click add service and
you select the one you want to
use.
So let's say it's Gmail here.
You want to put your email.
And then here below that, you
don't want to put your email's
password.
You want to put it what's called
an app password.
And there's a guide right here
that shows you how to do it.
So it's super simple.
All you got to do is you got to go
to your Google account.
They might have a link here for
you to just click on it and log
in.
So it takes you right there.
Then inside security, you're going
to click two-step verification and
then you're going to scroll all
the way down.
OK, then you're going to see app
passwords.
You're going to click there and
then you're going to create a new
app.
You're going to name it high level
or whatever you want to call it.
And you're going to click create.
Once you click create a password,
an app password is going to show
on the screen.
You're going to copy that and
paste it right back in this field.
OK, once you do that, click save
and it'll be connected.
OK, it's that simple.
So that's pretty much how you set
it up.
Again, should not take you more
than five minutes tops.
And yeah, you'll be good to go.
If you got any questions about
this, let me know.