All right, in this video, we're
going to go over the conversation
or inbox tab where you'll talk
and email and call every single
lead you guys have.
Okay.
So the way it works, just click
here.
It'll say conversations or inbox
in your account.
And here's pretty much where
you'll talk to every
lead.
So you can text them through SMS,
WhatsApp, you can get it
connected.
It just involves an
extra cost or you can email them.
Okay.
So for SMS, all you got to do is
just type your message.
And send it.
Okay.
Now, obviously, it's not going to
go through just because I have not
been
approved for A2P.
Okay.
But once you get approved for A2P,
you can send text and everything.
Now,
as you can see, it adds this thing
and this thing here.
The reason it does that is, again,
it's due to the texting issues.
You got to let people know they
can unsubscribe and all that
stuff.
You could edit this.
Okay.
So the way to edit this, I'll just
show you right now before I
forget.
You go to settings and you go to
business info, you scroll down and
let's see.
SMS compliance settings.
Okay.
So here, SMS compliance.
And here you can customize the
opt-out message.
So what I do is I just put,
if you want me to stop contacting
you,
just let me know or something
along those lines.
So the reason I do that, so it
contains the keyword
stop, but it's not so, um, direct
as in, Hey, you can just reply,
stop to unsubscribe.
Okay.
So
it includes a keyword, but if
people want to not talk to anyone,
they say, Hey, yeah, I'm not
interested
instead of saying stop, because if
they say stop, it's like a hit to
your reputation with the phone
number company.
And if you get too many opt-outs,
they'll just remove your ability
to get phone
numbers.
Okay.
Um, so yeah, that's pretty much
how that works.
I was going to keep it like this
if you
want.
Okay.
And then here center ID could be
your name pretty much.
Thanks Henry
or just something like that
and save.
All right.
That way it doesn't look so weird.
Feel, feels a little bit more
natural.
So if we go back to the inbox, let
me just show you what you can do
in here.
So here you got the
unread conversations, recents,
starred.
So if there's any like important
context or what I used
to do is I would just star every
client that I had that way it
would be easier to, to contact
them
and talk to them.
Um, now I kind of have just a
separate sub account for clients,
but, but yeah, you
could star people at the end of
the day by just clicking this, it
starts a conversation.
It shows up
here.
Okay.
Now, if you want to email them,
just click email.
You can write your subject line
here,
your email here.
You can add links, images, docs,
whatever you want.
Okay.
Now something else you could do.
So let's say you forgot the name
of the business of this person or
important detail.
You could go here and you have a
lot of custom fields, meaning
these things will
populate based on the information
to a specific client.
So appointments.
So if you want to say if they,
let's say they have an appointment
on Tuesday, you could say, see
you.
And then, oh, I don't know what
date exactly it is.
Just go here appointment.
And then you can click, let's see
where it is.
Start date.
Yes.
Start date, I think.
And then it'll just populate the
appointment date.
All right.
Um, or you could, you know,
business name, stuff like that, or
any custom fields we have.
Okay.
We'll show up here
and same thing with the email.
Now something else you could do,
you want to make sure you assign
it to
yourself, but something else you
could do is just, you could call
people from here.
So if you just click
this button, I'll start a call
with them and you can just call
them and see what's up.
Now here you could
also add notes about the contact.
What I used to do is whenever I
had a discovery call, um, I would
just
pretty much write the notes here
instead of my, now use a notebook,
but it's just do it there because
it was easier.
You create tasks for yourself.
Opportunity.
You could update the opportunity
right through here.
If you want to appointments, you
could book an appointment right
through here.
If you want to.
And then lastly, you got the
contact information.
Okay.
Now, if we click right
here on the contact details, you
can find all their information.
So you got contact info, lead
information, additional
information, right?
So that you could just come in
here and do whatever you
need to look at.
Then here you can add tags.
You can add them to specific
automations if needed.
You can update their
opportunities.
Um, and do not disturb.
So you could either, um, not let
them
reach out to you or if they ask
you to remove them from a list,
just remove them from the list
through here.
Okay.
Now here, this section right here.
So this is pretty cool because if
you're using
go high level for the websites and
landing pages, it'll actually keep
track of all their activities
within your business.
So you can see exactly when they
visit a
landing page, when they watch a
video, if you're tracking that,
when they will call, when they
become a customer, like
everything, whenever they pay,
it'll be in here and you can
scroll
through it.
If you're running ads, even you
can track that and see exactly
which ad they
came from.
So it's pretty cool.
And same idea, tasks, notes,
appointments.
Here you can add
documents specific to this person.
So contracts and things like that,
transactions and payments.
You can again, create a
subscription, invoice, manage
cards, create estimates, add a
card or charge them
now for something.
And here's just association.
So if you have like a company name
or other people
that work in the same company, you
could connect them with one
another, but you don't really need
to worry about that.
And yeah, that's pretty much what
you can do with the conversations
and inbox
section.
And another thing is internal
comments.
Okay.
So I don't use this a lot, but if
you want to add an
internal comment based on delete
itself, let's say you had, you
just had a call, you could just
add a
note, um, book a follow-up.
They are interested, but low on
funds, right?
So now you send that and
it'll be just for your eyes,
right?
So, but you know, the context of
what happened on the call before
having to go and listen to the
whole recording.
All right.
So, so yeah, if you got any
questions,
about anything else regarding
this, this section of go high
level, let me know, but yeah, see
you in
the next one.