All right so in this one we're
going to go over how to customize
your website and landing page
so first i want to start with the
landing page um so most of it
should be already done you're
gonna have to add a couple things
in there to make it yours so let's
dive into it so all you're gonna
do and just to go back here go to
sites then click on the landing
page template then hit edit
and a new page will open up to
edit the landing page now if you
follow the custom values
and pretty much fill those out
you're gonna see your logo here
and this button should be in your
business color now if they're not
to change them all you gotta do is
just scroll down here
and select the color that you want
to use okay now below you want to
change the ideal client section
or just delete it if you prefer to
remove it then the headline should
be something either
you know benefit based like we can
get you an extra or sorry outcome
based like we can get you an extra
outcome in time frame or get more
outcome without pain point okay
there's a two solid
frameworks for a headline and then
the sub headline just read
something that supports that
headline
okay then here you want to add a
vsl or like an explainer video so
people get an idea of of what you
do
and all these buttons by the way
there if someone clicks it it'll
automatically scroll down to this
section right here okay now here
you want to add some business
logos of clients you've worked
with
and here so what i add here is
just metrics that cannot give me
authority right that show that i'm
good at what i do for me it was ad
spend calls booked and revenue
generated for you maybe something
else
which is why i left it blank then
here this will populate your
business name or the name of the
sub account
and here you want to write five
reasons why people should work
with you and five pain points
working
with a traditional agency instead
of yours will bring them okay then
here you want to add pretty
much testimonials or client
interviews things like that if you
don't have like an interview or a
video
and you want to add an image all
you have to do is just click this
plus sign search for image
click on it and it'll pop and then
you can just delete this okay and
you add your image just click
here upload and select it okay let
me just switch this right back
then here you want to add an image
of
like a diagram of your system
because it'll show that what you
do isn't just a simple thing or
pushing
a couple buttons but rather show
that there's actually a process
involved in getting your clients a
result
and you want to put the name of
your system in here along with a
tagline or if you don't want to
if you don't want to add a tagline
just delete it here you can add
five things people will get five
benefits essentially that they get
from working with you and here
just faqs to edit this part just
click
on it scroll down and you see here
all the sections for faqs so let's
say the first one's this one
so once you click on it you'll be
able to you know write whatever
you want on it and here same thing
okay once you go to the next one
just click here you'll be able to
edit the next one and so on
now here you want to add some
results
to show that you know what you're
doing and lastly pretty much the
call to action section
where they can either fill out a
survey or you could just switch
this out for a calendar if you
want to switch it for a calendar
just click the plus sign look for
calendar select it pick the
calendar you want to use and it'll
populate in there okay and here
you want to change the name of
your system you want to add some
client photos and reviews and if
you don't have those you could
just delete this section all
together if you want and just
leave the calendar or the the
survey in
there okay then once it once you
finally um customize this for your
business you can just click
publish
and if you connected your domain
you can just select the man you
used and it'll go live okay now
the next
page is the book a call page so
here what you want to do is make
sure you have your calendar
selected which for some
reason it's not like populating
but it will and same thing here
you want to change the system name
and
whatever is going to happen on the
call add client photos and reviews
and they should be good to go
okay now once you publish this
page you want to take the link of
this page and add it to the custom
value that is called booking link
um that way what you can use it to
put it into text automations and
things and you know that you're
always going to be sending people
to the right booking link okay
and the last page is the call
confirmation so here you want to
switch this video out for
something
that just explains what's going to
happen on the call who you are
should take like a minute long so
there's no need to make it extra
long and you can embed from vimeo
wistia youtube
custom admin so if you use like
loom just in the share option
you'll have like a custom embed
and you
can just copy that text and or
that code and paste it here and
it'll show up then below we have
some
videos you want to add that pretty
much show your authority case
studies or educational videos
things
like that just show that you know
what you're talking about and here
what i did is just add my youtube
link
so people can just go and watch
more videos before our call okay
and that's it for the landing page
now the website i made it simple
because i don't think it makes
sense for you guys to just work a
ton on making a perfect website
because honestly you don't really
need it yet it's good to have a
website because it shows that
you're real business but you don't
need to have this incredible
website
off the bat landing page i think
is more important than the website
so the website looks like this is
super
simple okay so what you need to
change is again the sub headline
and the headline you want to add
your
explainer video here the metrics
similar as in the landing page and
this is similar thing as the
comparison as before the old way
so people what people are doing
wrong now and what you do
differently
or benefits of working with you
then here you want to add a
headline as well
you can keep this as is if it
applies to your business and then
a three-step breakdown of your
process step one we do this step
two we do that step three you get
outcome okay and here we have a
survey same as the same one that
we have the landing page and then
here just faqs which you can edit
the
same exact way as before okay now
we have other pages we have an
application page
let me just save that we have an
applications page where people
again it'll just be the
application
you can add more photos and videos
if you want but i think keeping it
simple works
then how it works again it's just
our explainer video with a call to
action to go and book a call that
will go to the booking page then
the booking page is just the page
with your calendar again you can
edit the headline here if you'd
like the call confirmation a video
same as in the landing page
version just the video explaining
what's going to happen here we
have some text just about you know
that we're excited for the call
you want to add results in here
and some youtube videos in here
and i mean the way to do that just
in case you don't know how to add
youtube videos just click
on it just change the link and
you're good to go then results you
want to make sure you have a page
with results on your website so
you just want to fill this out and
change the images okay just
explain
so outcome so what was the result
sub headline it could be the time
frame or what industry the client
is in and then the result details
just add a couple more details
about what happened where they
were
before before stuff like that and
lastly about us just save that and
the about us again you don't
honestly you don't need to have
this you could just put a photo of
yourself your name founder of the
business write some nice stuff
about yourself and that's pretty
much it okay now if we go back to
the
home page so if you want to see it
on mobile you click this mobile
mode right here and it'll show up
show you what it looks like in
mobile and make any changes if you
think they are needed okay
so really that's pretty much it
that's what the website looks like
if you want to add a new page
you can just click add a new page
name it the path and create it
and honestly high level also has
templates so if you click new
website you can go from templates
continue
and there are honestly a ton of
templates you could choose from so
if you want to look at one let's
say
this one you can click here and
you can check it out before using
it
all right so if you don't like the
one that i have right here you
could choose from all the
templates you guys have and same
thing for the funnels and the
landing pages new funnel you can
choose from templates and then
they have a ton of different
templates you could try out okay
so that's it for this video if you
got any questions let me know and
yeah have a good one