All right.
So in this video, we're going to
go over how to customize the
workflows for your
snapshot.
Okay.
So I wanted to keep this as simple
as possible and not overwhelm you
guys
with a lot of different workflows
and automations.
So these two are really the ones
you need when it
comes to starting up your agency
and starting to book some calls,
some demos.
So the first one is
going to be whenever a new lead
comes into the business.
Okay.
Whenever they fill out a survey
or a form or something like that.
Okay.
So pretty much first thing I want
to do is filter out the
triggers.
Okay.
So let me first explain how an
automation or a workflow is going
to set up,
and then we'll go into how to edit
everything.
So obviously there needs to be a
trigger to start off
the workflow.
Okay.
And once a trigger is triggered,
then everything will go into
place.
So first thing
you got to look at is the trigger
you're using.
So I added two, the form submitted
and the survey
submit it because there'll be
different ways you guys are
bringing in leads.
Okay.
But this may need
to be duplicated or changed
depending on what type of assets
you guys are giving out.
So here,
survey submitted, you want to make
sure you select the right survey.
Okay.
Or if you know for a fact,
you don't need to filter it, you
could remove this filter.
And every single time someone
submits a survey,
they'll get added into this
workflow.
Okay.
Same thing with forms, right?
Let's make sure you choose
the right form and, and you make
sure you get the right leads in
here.
If you want to add any new
triggers, there's like, honestly,
a lot of triggers, adding a tag,
note added, you know, it's a
birthday
coming up, call status, depending
on the call status.
There's so many things.
So I highly recommend you guys
look at this, but don't get
overwhelmed with all the things
you could do.
Okay.
Just keep it as simple
as possible, at least for now.
Now, once someone submits the
form, we get an opportunity.
If you
edit the pipeline or if you edited
the pipeline, make sure to update
this as needed, because this,
for example, if you change this,
it'll most likely be removed.
So you need to fill this out
again.
Okay.
You can also here select the
status, the value of opportunity
immediately.
So if I put 4,500,
every new opportunity that comes
in and every new lead that comes
in, their opportunity will have
the value.
Okay.
That I put in here.
Another thing you could do, how I
showed you with custom values
before is you can create a custom
value for the opportunity value.
So in case it's always changing,
instead of having to come in here
and change the workflow itself,
you could select a custom value
that you've created before.
Now this point, it'll be empty,
but pretty much you could select
any custom
values you have, or depending on
the content, you could fill
content specific custom fields.
Okay.
Now, once they opt in, you're
going to get the training access
email or, you know, whatever the
thing you're going to provide a
PDF access, you know, whatever it
is.
Location name is pretty much
your agency name is with the name
of the sub account itself.
Location email is going to be the
email
you use to create the sub account
and the subject line.
Self-explanatory is the subject
line of the
email.
Now here it says, hi, contact
name.
This is user first name with
location name.
So this will
translate to, let's say the lead
that comes in is named John.
Hey, John, this is, my name is
Penry
with, you know, client ascension,
for example, or go high level,
whatever the name of the business
is.
So the, the copy here, the email
here says good call on getting
access to our topic
training or topic PDF.
So you want to, you want to change
this out in case you didn't watch
it or you
going to receive it or, you know,
whatever it is.
Um, so actually let me, looks like
this is
duplicated.
My bad.
In case you didn't watch it,
here's the link, right?
So you provide the link.
If you have any questions about
how to, you know, get more quality
leads, book more calls, get more
sales, improve your closure, you
know, whatever it is.
If you respond to this email, I'll
get back to
you all the best username.
So this will be your name.
All right.
Now training access SMS, same,
same
idea.
Um, pretty much say, Hey, John,
this is Henry with business name.
Just, just saw you got access
to our topic training.
Let me know if there's any
questions I can answer on how to
achieve outcomes,
same ideas above on how to get
more leads on how to increase
your, your close rate on how to do
whatever you provide.
Okay.
Then here we're waiting for a
reply.
Okay.
What this means is
that the system is going to wait
one hour, see if they respond to
your SMS.
If they don't respond to
your SMS, they're going to follow
up, um, a day later, or sorry, an
hour later.
It's going to say,
what do you think of the training?
Think it's worth a quick convo or
is outcome not really a priority
right now?
Okay.
So here, let's say you offering
more leads and let's say the, the
outcome they want
release to grow their business or
scaling their business.
So think it's worth a quick convo
or
is growing the business, not
really a priority right now.
Okay.
Then same thing, wait two days.
We see if they responded to the
SMS.
Okay.
And second follow-up.
I don't know, just to check in
here,
are you still looking to get more
leads or better leads for the
business, which has helped a
client,
a client in, you know, location
could be Miami, you know,
California, whatever it is,
get result in timeframe with
something like that'd be a worth a
quick chat.
Okay.
So you're just trying
to get them back into, you know,
your loop to talk to you and
ideally book them in for a demo.
Now you could edit any part of
this workflow.
Okay.
So if you want to change the wait
time,
you can just change here to two
hours or three hours or five days,
whatever you want.
And this thing right here is
called an if else step.
Okay.
Or condition step.
So pretty much you want to ask
if something happened.
So here we do contact reply.
That's the action we're looking
to.
And it's either
true or false.
Okay.
If it's true, it means they
responded to the text.
If it's false or, you know,
nothing happened, it means it
didn't respond.
So if it's true, nothing's going
to happen.
You could add more
steps in here if you want.
Okay.
So you could automatically say,
cool, here's my booking link.
Talk about it.
I don't recommend you do that
because it's going to be different
responses with
different contexts to each one.
So you can maybe leverage AI
because here we have AI booking
bot
or chat GPT.
You could connect it in here,
which is pretty cool, but I want
to keep it simple for now.
Same thing here.
You could change this.
And this is pretty much the same
step as above.
All right.
So let's go back to the workflows.
And then we have the demo booked
or sales call booked workflow.
So here we have, I have two
triggers.
One, one at the lead themselves,
book a demo.
And whenever you or someone in
your team books a demo manually.
Okay.
So the way this works
is, let me just check something
here.
We'll just make sure we have the
right one.
Yeah.
Perfect.
So
as soon as someone books a demo is
going to be assigned to, to you
ideally.
So here is you're
going to have a random number or
code just to make up for my, uh,
contacts.
I'm not going to be in
your account.
So it's going to remove that, just
X out and select your own name.
And here we're going to add a tag
called demo call that we can tag
people whenever they book,
we can separate them or segment
them for emails and stuff like
that.
The opportunity is going to be
updated.
As you can see, it's going to move
to the demo booked stage.
And then here, I like to filter
out by booking method in case in
the future, we need to do
different
things, depending on how the
prospect came in, in case we send
different things, uh, depending on
the
source.
Right.
But here we wait one minute and
here we send the confirmation
text.
Hey, I have you booked for this
date of time.
Reply yes to confirm confirmation
email.
Okay.
And then we'll wait for business
hours.
Okay.
We want to make sure we continue
to send them texts or emails
during business hours.
So the way to do that is we pretty
much put a time delay advanced
window.
We select the business
hour days, 8 AM to 8 PM.
And that's it.
You don't have to, you can remove
this if you want.
I prefer
to keep it at business hours.
Okay.
Then you want to wait four hours
and we ask, did they confirm the
appointment or no?
Okay.
If there was no response to our
confirmation text.
Okay.
So as you can see,
the wait is for a contact reply.
Okay.
There's many things you could
choose.
I choose, I chose contact
reply.
And then we have SMS appointment
reserve, which is the, the text
name.
And we wait four hours.
Okay.
You could keep it at one or two up
to you.
And here we're going to ask, did
they reply true or false?
Okay.
If they replied, then awesome.
The appointment is confirmed and
we'll go into the,
you know, the fault, the
reminders.
Okay.
If they don't confirm, we're going
to send another text.
Just let them know, Hey, need to
confirm that you can make our
appointment on date and time.
Please reply yes to confirm.
Okay.
And then once we do that, we're
going to wait again and add them
to
the next step.
Now, what I like to do here is I
always like to ask on the
booking calendar if they're able
or willing to invest.
Okay.
If they say no, then I don't want
to waste my time with them on a
call.
So this step automatically filters
those people out and just
sends them this text thing.
Hey, notice, uh, just notice you
put down on with unwilling to
invest or
unable to invest on your
application.
If that's the case, I'll go ahead
and cancel the call.
Let me know if it was an accident.
Okay.
That way you don't waste time with
people that are not willing
to pay you money for your work.
And, and honestly, they don't
waste time, uh, any of their, of
their
time because they're not going to
get anything out of the call with
you.
Right.
And then wait one day
if they respond and maybe, so if
the response is just going to be
like, Hey, yeah, it was an
accident
or they may respond.
Um, okay.
Right.
Whatever it is at that point, you
can just go ahead and cancel
the call yourself.
But if they don't respond after
one day, it'll be automatically
canceled.
Okay.
For
you from here.
Okay.
We're going to wait two days
before the appointment.
And then we're going to
send them a reminder.
Hey, just a good reminder for the
appointment.
Then we're going to wait until
the day of the appointment.
Then remove the tag for demo
upcoming.
So I like to use these tags to
kind
of filter the contact list.
I'll show you how to create this
in a minute, but that way we can
keep
track of where each lead is at and
when you have like appointments
today or upcoming demos, stuff
like
that.
And we add the demo today tag.
All right.
Then we're going to wait three
hours before the
appointment.
Okay.
Just remember for a call today.
And then five minutes before we're
going to send
them the link.
Okay.
Actually it says I see you in
five.
Okay.
And after one hour, we'll remove
the tag
that says demo today.
And that's pretty much how the
workflow works.
And it looks complicated.
It really isn't.
It's just a bit overwhelming to
see all these, you know, things
and connections
or whatever, but it's very simple.
Nothing crazy.
Again, you guys had questions
about how to make some
changes to this.
Ask me, I'm more than happy to
help you guys out with this stuff.
Okay.
And yeah,
that's it for this one.
But before we leave, let me just
show you how to use those, you
know,
tags to filter out the leads in
the contact section, since I just
mentioned it.
So if you go out here to
contacts, you could create what's
called smart lists.
So here, more filters, you search
up tag.
So tag
is demo booked.
Should be sorry, demo today.
And it looks like it's not really
added into this, this account.
So let me just add it for you guys
right here.
I don't know why it didn't get
added.
So new tags in a V demo
coming and demo today.
By the way, you could also just
create the tags directly in the
workflows.
You don't need to come
into this page to do that.
I just found it to be easier.
But if you go to contacts, okay,
now we
have those tags created, you go to
more filters, you click on tag.
Here, you search is demo upcoming,
for example, or demo today.
You click apply, you can save as a
smart list.
So you could just name it upcoming
demos.
And whenever you go here and click
here, you'll see any lead that has
an upcoming demo with
you.
And same thing for demo today.
So if we change this to demo
today.
Remove this.
Save as new.
Today's demos.
You could have it right here.
So you just quickly see, okay,
what am I talking to
today?
You got a list who's coming up?
You got a list right here.
And again, you can make it even
better.
You know, appointment date is
right.
So demo upcoming and appointment
date is within three days,
like stuff like that.
There's a lot of options for
filtering the leads.
I won't go into all of that
here because it's just a lot of
stuff.
But yeah, this is definitely a
possibility.
So that's it for
this.
If you guys need help with
workflows or anything like that,
reach out to me and I'll help.
Bye.
Thank you.