Right.
In this one, we're going to go
over how to set up emails for your
newsletter and you can start
sending emails to your list.
OK, so something I want to go into
mention before we go into the
emails is that you could actually
have go.
It will be like a social planner
where it automatically just post
for you and your accounts.
If you want to use that, you got
to just connect the accounts and
then just create the post and
schedule them.
Super simple.
I don't really use it, but I
thought I mentioned it now to
create the emails is going to go
to marketing on the left hand side
and then emails up here.
And here you'll see different
campaigns.
So there's just made up data from
high level.
But if you want to create a new
campaign, you can click there.
So what I like to do is separate
them by, you know, year or topic.
So, for example, if you're sending
newsletters in 2025, you just
click newsletter.
2025, create in that way, you can
have all your emails in there.
OK, so we click here.
And if you want to create a new
campaign, a new email, just click
create campaign.
Blank is the ideal option, in my
opinion, just because it's just
simpler and less stuff.
But if you want to make like a
nice email, you can select the
design editor.
So I click select here in the
blank option or plain text option.
And here you can just write your
email.
Hi.
Again, contact.
Contact first name.
And then you go into your email.
Right.
And here you would click save.
You can name it whatever you want.
Email one or the topic.
And then you could click send or
schedule.
Let's say we schedule it.
You put in your email here.
Then send their name, your name,
subject line, whatever you want it
to be.
You can add a pre-header text.
So something that will show before
the actual text in the email.
So there's like a preview in the
email.
And then here you could select
individual context or you can
create a smart list just for
people in your email list.
Okay.
So the way that would work is
similar to the smart list that I
showed you before.
Right.
Where you would filter people by
attack.
So if we click here, we only have
these two smart lists, but we
create a new one that says email
list.
And I'll show you how to create
that one in a second.
And here you could select UTM
tracking.
What that means is that it'll
track if they make, if they click
on the email to whatever link you
have, it'll track exactly what
email they came from and all of
that.
Okay.
You can add tags based on certain
conditions if you want, but I
don't really use that.
I just turn on the UTM tracking
and that's it.
And then once the email is ready
to go, you click review and
schedule and it will schedule that
for whatever date you want it to
schedule it for.
Okay.
So now let's create the email
list, smart list.
So what you're going to do is go
to contacts.
You're going to go more filters.
You're going to search up tag is
email list.
Okay.
So the tag is in here.
So let's just create the tag like
last time.
We're going to go to settings,
tags, and we're going to call it
email list.
So once that is done, we're going
to go back to navigation and same
idea, filters, tag.
We're going to look for email
list.
Apply, save a smart list.
We click save right here.
And now the list is here.
So whenever a lead or a contact
has this tag, they'll be in your
email list.
Okay.
So now let's make sure that every
new lead that comes in has that
tag in here.
So what we're going to do is go
into the new lead workflow.
And right here, what we're going
to do is just add an action that
says tag, add a contact tag, and
we're going to add the email list
tag.
So I like to just mention what tag
we're adding in the action name so
that it's easy to know what's
going on.
And that is it.
So we just click save.
And that's it.
So now whenever you're going to
schedule your email, let's go back
into marketing, emails, campaigns,
newsletter, and email one.
So whenever we're going to
schedule it, we would go down
here, send to smart list, email
list.
Okay.
Make sure you select schedule.
And down here, advanced
conditions.
Here is just asking, should we
send the list to anyone else that
gets added here in the future or
only to the people that are
currently in the email list?
So you want to make sure that yes,
include anyone that gets added
into the account between now and
by the time the email is sent.
That way you never miss out on
sending it to new people.
Okay.
So from here, again, you just fill
this out.
Click save.
And you have your email scheduled.
Okay.
Now, another important thing is
that to make your life easier,
sometimes you may want to create
templates.
Okay.
So if you want to have templates
already made for you, you just
create a template.
You could design it.
You could, again, plain text and
just, you know, have the main
things that you always send
already in there.
So let's say you always have like
your offer at the end of the
email.
So you could just add it how I can
help you get an extra 25 to 30
qualified lead in 30 days.
Okay.
And then you put your link here,
for example.
So every time you create a new
email, just choose the template.
And this tool always kind of will
be sent out.
It's going to name an example
template.
So we click save template.
And here, if you ever want to
create a new one, you select your
templates.
And here you'll see example
template.
So now you'll be able to create a
new email with the template you
just created.
All right.
And that's pretty much it for the
emails and the newsletter setup.
If you have any questions about
how to set this up, something
wasn't clear, just reach out to me
and I'll help.