All right, in this video we're
going to go over how to sign up
for Google High Level.
So obviously the first thing
you're going to do is you're going
to click the link below this
video.
It's going to take you to this
page right here.
So all you have to do is click the
14-day free trial.
You're going to put your name,
email, phone number, and then your
card information for the trial
details.
So if we put our company name.
Okay, we go to step two.
Oh, let me just put a real email.
We go to step two.
And then you're just going to
select the 97 starter plan or the
297.
So the difference between these
two is the 97 starter plans is
going to give you three
subaccounts.
Okay, so a subaccount essentially
means that you have one account,
which is the main Go High Level
license.
And then under your Go High Level
account, you can have subaccounts
for yourself or clients or
anything like that.
So for starting out, I recommend
the $97 starter plan just because
you don't need really more than
three subaccounts.
And if you start using High Level
for your clients and you're
providing them with subaccounts,
then you can go ahead and go into
the 297 unlimited plan, which
gives you unlimited subaccounts.
Okay, so just put your card
information, accept these things,
and then just start the trial.
So in the next video, we're going
to go over how to import our
agency snapshots.
You can start using Go High Level
with a website landing page
automations already set up for
you.