All right, so in this video, we're
going to cover how to customize
your subaccount and your snapshot,
okay?
So if or when you go into your
subaccount, you're going to see
this thing right here, the
launchpad.
You don't really have to do
anything in this page.
It's just high-level trying to
kind of guide you on how to start
using all of their features, but
you don't need to worry about all
that.
To access your subaccount, if you
are not in it yet, just click here
on this section and select the
subaccount you want to use.
All right, now the first thing you
want to do is go to settings,
okay, and then business profile,
and you want to fill all of this
out, all right?
The reason you want to do it now
is because down the line, we're
going to do what's called A2P
registration, which is what will
allow you to send text messages to
other businesses and, you know,
anyone really through our
automations, all right?
And by doing it now, this is going
to save you a bunch of time.
So make sure to fill it out fully.
Just all of this is going to take
you at most five minutes.
And then once you do that, you
want to go down to integrations,
okay?
So in integrations, here you can
connect your Google Calendar,
Facebook, Instagram, Stripe,
Slack, anything you may use.
If you use Notion or ClickUp for
project management, Airtable, you
could do that in here as well,
okay?
But again, just make sure to
connect all of your accounts we're
going to be using for your
business.
Then what you want to do is
connect a domain, okay?
So I prefer to just buy it from
Squarespace or Porkbun or wherever
else.
But if you want, you can just
purchase it directly through High
Level.
So to connect it, you're going to
click there on Connect Domain and
then choose this option right
here, okay?
So you're going to put your
domain.
So I'm just going to get my stuff
in here.
Give me one second.
All right.
So we're going to use one of our,
or one of my, you know, secondary
domains.
So I'm just going to put a
subdomain here.
So let's call test.begin.
But this could be your main
domain.
I'm using a subdomain mainly
because I don't have like a fake
domain to connect.
But put your domain in there.
Click Continue.
And then you're going to select
Add Record Manually, usually
because what will happen if you
click Continue and set up and try
to do it automatically, it's going
to think for a bit.
And then it's going to ask you to
do it manually anyways.
So just click Add Record Manually
and then just copy the records it
gives you.
If you're connecting your main
domain, you're going to have two
records.
It's going to be an A record and a
C name.
Because I'm doing a subdomain,
it's going to give me the C name,
okay?
But it's the same exact process.
We're going to go to your domain
registrar.
Click on DNS.
Add a record here.
Okay.
It's asking me to verify, so give
me a second.
There we go.
You're going to put the host,
which it gives you right there.
Make sure to select the correct
record.
Then the required value.
And then save.
Okay.
So once you do that, you're going
to click here, verify records.
You're going to let it think for a
couple seconds.
I'm going to pause here while we
wait.
All right.
So once you finish connecting your
domain, it'll just automatically
send you to this page right here.
And here you can just link any
funnels with your domain.
So if you have a website built
out, you could click on Website.
Okay.
And then select any websites you
have, like this one.
Or if you prefer to connect
directly to a funnel, you can just
select Funnel and then click
whichever one you want to use.
So let's say we go with a website.
Okay.
Then you're going to select which
one is the homepage.
It's obviously home.
And then additional options.
If you want to have like an error
page created, you could add that
in here.
Or you could just go ahead and
select the homepage as well for
the agency.
Right.
And then you click Proceed to
Finish.
And again, it's going to think for
a little bit.
And then we're good to go.
Okay.
So we've got this one here.
If you ever want to edit
something, you click Manage and
you can connect a new thing,
right?
A new website funnel or set
another default page if you want.
Right.
So pretty easy to follow.
All right.
From there, we have the custom
values.
Okay.
So custom values, essentially a
value that is the same across the
full subaccount.
Okay.
And you can use it to customize
like your website landing pages in
a much easier way than having
to upload a new image or link or
whatever every single time.
Let me show you how I use it.
So to update a custom value.
So let's use the account logo, for
example.
Right.
So to edit it, you're going to
click here and then edit custom
value and put in the value
that you want to use.
Okay.
So for an account logo, right?
So let's say you want to use your
logo.
What you want to do is go to media
storage, upload, and then select
whatever logo you want to use.
Now I'm just going to pick any
random image here.
Let's say this one, get link.
Go back to settings, custom
values, and then edit the custom
value.
We're going to paste that link
here and update it.
So what this does then is if the
custom value is added inside the
funnel or website in the logo
field or in the image field for
the logo,
then it'll automatically update to
whatever we have in here.
So to add it into a website, you
would just click the custom value
key.
Then you would go into the sides.
And again, just to show you
quickly how custom values work.
And then assuming it's added in
here, if we open up the page,
you'll see it right here, right?
So let me go back to our other
page.
And just to quickly show you what
that looks like or where to put
that key.
So here's the image and here's the
image, you know, link would go
here.
So we just put a custom value
instead, right?
So whenever you put the custom
value or wherever you put the
custom value, it will populate
whatever value is in there, right?
It's inside the key or the code
here, okay?
So that's how they work.
And I have created three for you
guys to start with.
You can create as many as you
want.
But we have a logo, a booking page
link.
So whenever you create your
booking page, you just take the
link, click the three dots, edit,
and then paste the booking link
here.
That way, when you create
automations for yourself, right,
for follow-ups or whatever it may
be,
you just take this value and you
put it in there instead of having
to go and find the booking link
for your business, okay?
And same thing with colors is
similar to the account logo idea.
For the websites or landing pages,
you just pretty much in the color
selector thing, instead of a hex
code, just put the custom value
and it'll populate your actual
company color, okay?
So that's pretty much on how to
take the first couple steps in
setting up your snapshot, okay?
If you run into any issues, let me
know and I'll be happy to help.
Bye.