Yo guys how's it going lucas here
i'm the landing page coach and
client ascension
uh i've put together something for
you guys i think is going to maybe
be a great kind of
starting point going forward it is
a template in card for your agency
page now i'm not a huge fan
of card but i've noticed that a
lot of you guys use it and it is a
great way to get started
uh quickly easily cheaply so uh
this might just help you kind of
uh get the format and layout of
your page down now note this is
meant to be highly edited i i we
don't want to see everyone
with uh the exact same landing
page in client ascension so uh if
you do use this i would
highly suggest booking a
one-on-one with me i will
literally get on a call with you i
will go
through this template i will help
you edit it i'll uh take you know
your what your offer and your
brand
into uh consideration uh walk you
through the whole thing but we
just don't want to have everyone
the
exact same page so uh please book
a one-on-one i'm more than happy
to to help you out with this stuff
so uh basically i'm just going to
go through the layout of the page
so we're going to start here at
the top with a banner section this
is going to be a different color
to the rest of your branding
uh in uh in the in the page it's
going to be like a uh it could be
a green a pink uh you know a
purple
just something that's going to
stand out against whatever your
main branding color is
um here you can put either a
client review so you know uh five
stars from client name you can
reiterate your guarantee you know
we work for free until you're
happy something like that
then you're going to have your
company logo here then attention
icps this is going to be attention
and
then whoever you're targeting so
you know attention lawyers and
accountants attention dtc brands
attention e-com owners whoever it
is that you're targeting is going
to go there
uh we'll x your y and z your
guarantee this is a basic like
heading format you know we'll
double your
revenue in 30 days or you don't
pay uh something along those sort
of lines not everyone's offer is
going to fit into this um
especially like i've noticed like
a lot of like uh kind of data
analytics
offers don't really like fit
directly into this but please uh
send me your headlines or book a
one-on-one
and i'll go through that with you
we use unique mechanism uh to x or
y within z time frame or
guarantee so dan's talked a lot
about the unique mechanism you all
have to have some sort of one
so you know we use our patented uh
you know data analytic technology
to double your revenue in 30 days
uh or uh you don't pay whatever it
is something like that here you'll
have your vsl hopefully you're
all doing a steven trister style
vsl it'll help a ton uh i've just
put a video box embed here
with a youtube video on it it is a
rickroll uh but uh i've also done
a quick video today on how to
embed a wistia video so i will be
linking that in the um course
section here just in case you guys
have your video hosted on wistia
uh you can this is a kind of
optional you have a brief sentence
with
your offer here and how you do it
or you know uh you can add a
review here maybe if you wanted
uh then another section is a line
below it book a call or it's free
strategy session or consultation
big cta book a call you can change
that like i said to strategy
session consultation trusted
by this is where you put company
logos any companies you've worked
with put their logos in here
you may not have four companies
you may have more you can uh uh
always add more images here
uh i'll go through this again with
you if you book a call uh you can
remove them little trash
kind of icon uh whatever you need
to do but uh please um uh book
call if you've got any issues
with this stuff and i'll go
through with you first section
pain points are you currently
struggling
with and your pain points right so
this is just very simply you'll
know what the people in your
industry are dealing with you and
other problems they're having so
you want to highlight them here
uh you'll just have a heading of
the main pain point brief section
about it uh you can do uh two to
three paragraphs i would just
suggest making sure that if you do
say like two paragraphs here make
sure this is two paragraphs this
is two paragraphs it'll keep the
sizing of everything consistent
and
look nicer uh change the logo to
whatever you want i've got it set
to icons now card is number of
icons built into it you can choose
from uh you can of course replace
that with an image if you want
instead uh benefits and why choose
you so here you're going to go
over uh why you're different
than other agencies uh in your
niche uh how you use your unique
mechanism to achieve a certain
result
uh just list the benefits the
primary benefits of your main
service uh you don't you might not
have
six you might only have three or
four you can always delete these
uh or add more copy to that with
you on a call uh transformation
slash our process so you don't
want to name this transformation
that's just you know what this is
uh you also don't have to keep
these colors in this background
you could literally have a like
like a transparent container
background with a different color
uh
heading i just did this to
re-highlight the the the top part
of each section um you're here
you're
going to go through the three-step
process that you you use to
achieve the result uh like i say
here
focus on the result your client
gets so step one you onboard the
client we analyze your business
whatever it is you guys do step
two we begin using our unique
mechanism to achieve whatever
result
step three uh you know you get x
result that makes your life easier
or makes you more money
and we continue our ongoing
support and optimization something
along those sort of lines
testimonials go here uh here from
like x number of clients who have
achieved y result
uh we ensure the success of our
clients by doing x our clients
have a lifetime value of x thanks
for our ongoing customer service
support something like that this
is again all just as all it can
all
be edited uh this is just kind of
give you a basic idea of what to
do here i have a gallery section
to include images of testimonials
you may have text uh i can show
you how to uh put that in instead
um this is just uh i figure a lot
of people tend to have screenshots
you can also put videos i can
try to embed videos there no
problem book a call what's
included i like to productize the
service here
essentially you're just breaking
down the main things your client's
going to get you're showing
them exactly that when they sign
up with you what are the things
they're going to receive uh i find
that this just makes it your offer
a bit more tangible a bit easier
to understand so it could be
you know like i said if you're
doing data analytics it could be
uh you know our our top of the
line
seo services and you know i'll be
free thinking about your seo
service and what you do number two
number two could just be your
ongoing support and optimization
or whatever it is you guys offer
but
uh you can also just easily uh
duplicate these uh to make another
one if i move my little head here
uh uh move down if you got more
than than than two uh i would
suggest keeping this alternating
image
style it just breaks the page up a
bit so it's a big wall of texts
all along one side a bunch of
images makes it a bit easier to
read um more testimonials uh
change that to whatever you know
like like something else about why
your clients are so happy uh i've
got another gallery here can be
videos can be texts about us some
guys miss out on this you need
about us section to try and
humanize
your page uh humanize your brand
human it shows that there is
someone behind the brand and uh it
highlights uh how you learned how
to do what you do how you do it
why you do it why you enjoy it so
much
uh the sort of benefits your
customers get uh you only need
like you know two to three
paragraphs here
does not have to be super detailed
uh and a photo of yourself uh or
your team you maybe there's more
than one of you on the team uh you
can always uh you know duplicate
these undo uh
to take this section you can
always do uh you know hi i'm i'm
you know ryan you know uh this is
my
colleague alex you know and you
can move these over here um like
that uh but just something there
to
kind of you know show that there
is a real person behind the brand
of what you guys do
faq and book a call these can kind
of alternate it really depends on
the type of page you're doing
if you think there's a lot of
information that uh like i said
analytics based sort of things or
data
driven sort of things people are
gonna have questions so you can
move this faq section uh above you
just
drag and drop um up there and then
you have your book a call uh
whichever you think will work best
i again this is kind of case with
a case basis i'll go over this
with you on the one-on-one
um i have here a custom faq this
is going to take a little bit of
explaining right this is why i do
suggest you you book a call with
me uh this is a custom faq made by
uh i believe it's jason leo
uh plugins.card.co he's got a ton
here um he made this is a free
plugin uh it is a drop down faq
you
can't see because it's an embed
but i'll show you in the page
preview after um you just add an
embed
this is this is all here i'm going
to go through this text a little
bit here so here you can change
the font and the style and change
the size of it here it says font
size 14 pixels um here you can
change the background color i
suggest keeping this the same as
your current background so it's
set to
white um here you can do the width
uh 100 you can do the maximum
width so how large it's allowed to
go
uh let's see then when you want to
actually edit the text you'll
scroll down a good bit
and as you go you're going to get
to a section here's the uh yeah
here's a section here so
title which countries do you ship
to you're going to want to change
that to you know uh whatever it is
your faq is about uh how do you
generate results for clients
description you'll put in there uh
all the way down i think all this
section here is the description uh
how long does it take so then
these are where you're going to
edit this again this is like all
very awkward so i really would
suggest
that you book a call with me uh i
will go through all this with you
but that's how you edit it
then book call and then your
calendly so i'm going to show you
guys the preview now of this
this is what's going to look like
mine is the rick astley video uh
sections all down here
testimonials these are showing up
as blanks i haven't got any images
uploaded but this would
be where your testimonials are but
else uh this is showing up like
that because it's a preview page
and then the efficacy is what the
faq looks like so as you see click
down pops down like that
so that's the basics of it guys uh
again i'm going to there'll be a
link here with the kajabi on where
you can do to duplicate this page
in card uh you'll be able to edit
it from there uh you can give me
editor access if you want uh
message me and i will tell you how
to do that um you can book a
one-on-one
me and i will literally build this
page out with you again i really
want this really customized
because i don't want to see
everyone with the exact same sort
of page exact same colors exact
same you
know everything headlines so uh
yeah hopefully this will be
helpful for you guys that are just
getting
started out and have no idea where
to begin with your page uh and
then we can work together to make
something that looks really really
sick so uh hope you guys enjoy
this uh any problems please uh
either
submit a landing page review via
type form or book a one-on-one
with me and you can always just
message me
in slack whenever and i'll get
back to you asap so hope this
helps guys and good luck