- Yo guys, how's it going?
Lucas here, landing page coach at
Client Ascension.
Today I'm gonna be going over
just some of the new templates
that I've made.
One is in Card and one is in
WordPress.
I'm gonna show you how to import
that WordPress template in.
So starting off with Card,
this is an update to the previous
landing page I made.
This kind of follows a similar
sort of layout.
Takes a bit of inspiration
from Oliver Kenyon's framework
that he showed us recently on a
call.
As you can see, it starts off.
All the copy here is just to show
you what to type in there.
You throw in your own logo here,
your VSL details here,
going down, pain point section,
benefits, transformation,
what's included, about us,
testimonials, FAQ,
and book a call, right?
That'll be where you count on the
embed is.
This is the new WordPress
template.
Again, it follows very similar
layout, pain points, benefits,
transformation, features, about
us, testimonials, FAQ, right?
So we're briefly gonna go over how
to,
how to import this into WordPress.
So this was made in Elementor.
So you will need Elementor.
You may need Elementor Pro.
To be honest, I've been using
Elementor so long,
I'm not entirely sure if you need
it or not.
I have built out the template,
CSCA landing page one here.
And there will be a link to
download the template
in the Kajabi here.
So with that, you'll get a .json
file.
So once you have the file, once
you've downloaded it,
I wanna imagine you're in
WordPress
and you want to install this
template, right?
You would add a new page.
You would call something like
home.
I'm just gonna call it test.
Just publish it.
You would then go to edit with
Elementor.
Here is Elementor, right?
It's a, again, Elementor is a page
building plugin.
There is a free version.
This might work with the free
version.
I'm not entirely sure.
You'll have to check that out.
If not, I think Elementor Pro is
like 60 bucks a year
or something like that.
It's not hugely expensive.
When you're here at this page,
you just add a new page and open
in Elementor.
You're gonna wanna select the
little folder icon here, right?
And this is where they have a list
of their own templates
and pages and things.
But you're gonna wanna go to my
templates
and then click this little import
template button.
When you do that, your template
will appear here.
Once you've got it, you're gonna
click insert.
Click apply.
And it's gonna import the template
here.
Okay, let it reload for a sec.
So there we go.
Now you can edit all the elements
of this.
I can do a detailed kind of
WordPress editing video,
but I'm gonna assume that you kind
of know
the basics of WordPress.
For instance here, I think that
this video is too small.
That's because it's got margins on
both sides.
So I'm gonna bring these margins
down a bit.
There we go.
Bigger video.
Make the changes you want in this
section here.
This is too high up for instance.
It's got a minus 10 margin.
So bring it down to zero.
Better.
Make all the changes and things
you want in this section.
Click update.
Top left here.
Click exit again.
You can check a few things along
the side here.
Just like disable title, disable
featured image, or things like
that.
I'm just gonna save the primary
header and the footer.
Because we've got those built into
the Elementor one.
You can leave the featured image.
You can leave the title.
Update.
Now, if I go to, you can see here
is the permalink.
CA test dot site slash tests.
I go here.
Here's the page, right?
So now you've got this page on a,
you know, a sub domain or a
forward slash.
You want to make this your primary
homepage.
You're going to want to go down to
settings and reading.
And here your homepage displays.
You're going to set it to a static
page and choose the site you want.
So if I choose test now and I save
the changes.
When I go to CA test dot site.
This main page shows up.
So that's the basics of it.
Again, this follows the same sort
of layout as the card page.
It's got everything kind of neat
there.
You can edit any elements of it.
It should be pretty easy to do if
you've got a bit of WordPress
experience.
WordPress is also a lot cheaper to
host than most other kind of other
website builders.
I think I'm using Hostinger for
this.
And I got something like, you
know, three or four bucks a month
or something like that to host it.
So this is a really good
alternative.
If you want to spend a little bit
less, even if you factor in the
cost of Elementor Pro,
if you need it, please test it and
see if you need it or not.
Look for the free version first.
Then, yeah, it still works out
super cheap.
So that's the basics.
This is a super quick video.
I just really want to give you
guys a look into this and what it
looks like.
And to kind of show you some of
the kind of basics of importing it
and getting it set up.
But if you would like me to do a
more detailed WordPress editing
video, I can do that.
But I feel like if you're using
WordPress already and you've built
a site WordPress,
you kind of know the basics of
things like Elementor and building
sites and everything.
So if you want more info, let me
know.
Hit me up on the landing page
talk.
You can book a one on one.
And we will be switching to weekly
landing page calls soon.
So there'll be a group call where
you guys can join.
Looking forward to doing that and
getting to meet a few more of you.
So, yeah, I hope that helps.
Again, check for the download link
in the Kajabi for the template in
Elementor.
New page.
Edo Elementor.
Little folder icon.
My templates.
Import template.
Top right.
Apply.
Publish.
That's the basics of it.
Hope that helps.
Let me know what you guys think.
Good luck.