What's up guys, Lucas Siddett, the
landing page coach for Client
Ascension here.
Today we're going to be going over
the new Framer template that I've
developed for everyone in CA.
So some of you guys have brought
up Framer to me in the past or
mentioned interest in using it.
So you have asked me kind of
what's the best platform to get
started on.
I'm going to go to start off by
going over kind of the answering
that question,
essentially what I do think you
should start with and what should
be kind of the main one you use.
For simplicity and getting started
quickly, if you have a little web
design experience, then Card is
still the easiest.
But if you want a slightly nicer
looking website that's easier to
create than a Webflow site, then I
would suggest Framer.
Framer is slightly cheaper than
Webflow as well.
There's a few other benefits to
it, but you can make some really
nice sites on Framer.
So today I'm going to go through
the template that I've made for
you guys.
So all this is placeholder text.
This is just kind of general ideas
for what you should be putting on
the copy on your page.
We have a whole section in the
Kajabi module on creating your
line of page copy with ChatGPT.
So make sure you go through that.
But I've given you kind of
placeholders here for what should
be kind of included.
So it starts off with, you know,
your headline, your VSL, then the
companies you worked with.
These are all placeholders.
I'll be over these later and how
to replace them.
Your pain points will be here.
Then why they should choose you,
some benefits and things there.
Big button there.
Then a testimonial here.
The three-step process for working
with you.
What's included as part of your
service package.
More testimonials, what people are
saying.
Then this will be your kind of
about you section where you'll
talk a little bit about yourself
and kind of why you started the
company, etc.
And then your Calendly embed and
your FAQs down here.
And then at the bottom here, we
just have a footer where you can
either add links to other parts of
the page or you can link your
socials and everything here.
So I'm going to go to Framer now.
I'm just going to walk you guys
through this.
So when you log into Framer, this
is what it's going to look like.
You're going to have these three
screens.
As you can see, they're labeled
desktop, tablet, and phone.
So essentially, these are the
three kind of what's referred to
as a break point, right?
These are where you go to your
phone.
It's going to look like this.
On top of it, it'll look like
this.
Does desktop look like this?
Each section of the page is its
own component that has been edited
to work across all three.
So changes I make here to, say,
the hero section are going to show
up here as well.
I'm going to show you how you make
those changes.
So when you mouse over this,
you'll see a purple outline.
You double-click on this.
It'll bring you into what's called
a module.
So this module is like all the
components that are included in
that section.
So if I want to edit the text
here, so I double-click here.
You have two choices, actually.
You can either double-click on the
text or you can edit over here
where there's this content in the
bottom right-hand side here.
But if I double-click here, if I
just replace this with your money
back,
and I go up here to the top left
and go back to home, as you'll
see, that's changed across all
three.
And I'm going to do that.
Don't want to...
Actually, don't.
Sorry.
I'll just be back here.
Don't want to...
I want to keep that as a
guarantee.
There we go.
So editing...
You'll edit each section like
this.
So again, you want to change the
pain points.
You'll double-click in here.
You'll change the text.
You'll replace the images.
Things like that.
I'll go into more depth than that
in a second.
I'm just going to talk a bit about
the hero section again.
So there's some things you're
immediately going to want to edit
here, right?
So obviously, you're going to want
to put your VSL here.
Framer has a number of ways to
host videos.
I have determined that the easiest
way for you guys to do this is
simply to use a Vimeo link.
I think Vimeo is the easiest way
to host it.
Simply upload it to Vimeo, post
it, paste the link in here, and it
should show up here and work
perfectly as is.
There are other ways to do this.
Framer has a built-in video
hosting service, but I believe you
need to upgrade to a certain type
of plan in order to get access to
that.
And again, one of the benefits of
Framer is that it's generally
cheaper than Webflow, so no reason
to add extra costs.
Just host it on Vimeo, share the
link, and paste it in here.
As you can see on the left-hand
side here, we have layers.
This is going to show you what, as
you can see as I mess over, it's
selecting each individual element.
It's a list of the elements that
are here.
These modules also include, as you
can see, the tablet and mobile
versions, so you can make changes
to just one or the other.
But in general, you're going to
want to edit whatever's here, and
it should show up in the others
too.
So, for instance, you want to edit
the video, yeah, you'll click
that.
And make sure that on the
left-hand side here, make sure
frame isn't selected, the video
within that frame is selected, and
you will change the URL here.
Editing text, select on either
double-click to edit, or you can
select it and change this here on
the right-hand side.
I'm going to talk a bit about text
styles now to kind of go over this
as something that's important for
you guys to know.
So, when you select text, you can
see how this is like a, you know,
this is much larger than the
subheading text here, right?
If you look here, a text under
styles, if you click this, there
will be a number of styles to
choose from.
If I change this, it's going to
change throughout it.
It's going to change the size, the
weight of the text, things like
that.
I can make it smaller, make it
bigger.
These are all preset, making it
easier for you guys to change them
up.
Simple things like the alignment,
you can change individually.
So, you can just click middle
there, and it'll be center
aligned, right?
And it's the same for all the
text.
So, you can go through and you can
change styles how you want,
although I think the current
layout is pretty much set as it
is.
I think you need to make too many
edits there if you don't want to.
These buttons are linked to the
appropriate parts of the pages.
So, for instance, this get started
should send people, if you look in
the right here at link, it's going
to send them to a section at the
bottom that I made called
Calendly.
It'll always send them there when
they click it, even if you add
stuff before or after that.
When they click this, this button
is showing them directly to the
Calendly section.
For the learn more part, it should
bring them to the why choose you
section.
I've named that as the learn more
part.
So, that's kind of the benefits of
working with your company.
You can edit those.
You know, essentially, you will go
to the main part of the module,
and you would click scroll
section.
You would give it a name.
So, you know, pain points.
And then when you're editing a
button, like up here, you would
click there, click the link for
home, and then click pain points.
Let's try up there.
I'm going to click it, then it'll
bring them to that section.
I'm going to remove that, and yes,
that's the basic idea.
So, let's go section by section.
I'm going to go to this part here.
This is the scrolling ticker.
So, if you click this, you'll see
a number of photos here, and
you'll see a scrolling bar here.
And if you look on the right-hand
side, we've got what they call
children.
These are all linked to this.
These are all the different logos,
right?
So, the easiest way to add this or
replace this is you can delete all
these whenever you have your
company logos, and you can insert
an image.
I'm going to do that now.
So, if I just drag an image in,
I'm going to click this box.
I'm going to click fill.
I'm going to click image.
I'm going to click choose image,
and I'm going to select a random
image.
I'm just going to picture this ad
that I have here, right?
This isn't going to be the right
size or work properly, but, you
know, this is demonstration
purposes.
So, then when I click here again,
I've got children.
I can add a new item, which I've
added already, and I can choose
the name of this frame, which is
that one there.
That, as you can see here, is now
linked to this.
So, if I preview this, there you
go.
There's the, you know, image
cutoff.
It's not the right size, showing
up there.
So, that's how you're going to be
linking company logos.
I'm going to delete that for now.
And, yeah, so that gives you a
basic idea of how that works.
This might be a bit tricky.
If you guys have trouble with
this, please feel free to hit me
up on Slack, and I'll help you
out.
So, going back out of this, back
to the homepage, next section, the
pain points section.
So, the main thing you're going to
want to change here, obviously, is
the titles.
You know, double-click the text,
edit that.
You're going to want to change the
logo or image that you have here.
To do that, you're going to click
on the box.
You're going to click fill and
click image and choose a new image
to put in there.
Again, I'll use this as an
example.
That's updated.
So, that's how you're going to do
that throughout the page.
You're going to want to replace an
image.
It'll be the same process for this
part here.
And the rest of this is mainly
just editing text.
You know, it's just replacing
images, editing text.
For this section, this is your
three-part process section.
These are actually not images.
They're icons.
So, if you look at the right here,
you can see there's variant and
icon.
iTunes can just put a campaign in
there.
There's a list of icons here that
you can take advantage of that you
can use to update.
As you click that, it changes.
I change that to call.
There's a phone.
You know, so you lose that.
And you can change, like, things
like the background color, the
variant.
You can do a gradient.
You can do a flattened stroke,
large flattened stroke.
You can do a very small gradient.
There's a number of things you can
do with it.
I think it's just a slot.
There we go.
So, you can edit those right.
The same for all those images
across there.
This is, again, just the what's
included section.
It's going to be just the image
change on the text.
Now, again, this is the
testimonials.
This is very similar to what we
talked about before, the ticker
section.
So, if you click in here, you're
going to see all these sections
are linked.
It's very simply just edit the
text on these and the photos is
the easiest way to do it.
And then you can delete some if
you don't want them to be
included.
This is a scrolling ticker again.
It's got six linked things.
You can delete these as you feel
free or if you don't have enough
for it or if you want to add more.
And then the rest will be updated
as it goes.
But, again, to change the copy
here, just double click, edit how
you want, edit the photo by
choosing a new avatar image, and
edit the names and things like
that.
There you go.
This, again, just image and text.
Okay, the Calendly section.
Do not mess with this too much.
Here's the only thing you're going
to want to edit here.
Obviously, aside from the headline
and stuff, right?
You're going to select the
Calendly.
Again, check on the left side that
you've selected Calendly
underneath form wrapper.
And here, you're going to put in
your Calendly link.
Now, you're not going to put the
full Calendly link.
You're going to put what comes
after Calendly.com slash.
So, if I go to Calendly.com.
So, see, I've got Calendly.com
slash Copyright Media slash
Discovery Call.
You just want this part.
The part after the Calendly.com
slash.
So, Copyright Media slash
Discovery Call.
And then you will go back to
Framer.
You will paste that in.
Hit Enter.
And it'll update.
That's the only part you want to
change.
Don't mess with any of your stuff,
right?
The Framer embed is a bit awkward.
Or the Calendly embed in Framer is
a bit awkward.
I have it set up to look pretty
decent.
So, just go with that.
And then the FAQs.
To edit the FAQs.
Double-click in.
Select the FAQ.
You'll see Variant is open and
closed.
So, you can set it to whatever.
To edit the question.
It says question here.
Just edit this content here.
And then to edit the answer.
Click Edit Content.
And you'll see the answer to the
same question just here.
And you edit that as you see it.
And then the footer.
Here's links that you can place in
here.
So, you just click Link.
And you either link to another
part of the page.
Or to another website.
And same for these as well.
You can add a link here in the
bottom right under a social icon.
And link to your socials.
And then delete these as you are.
You want.
You know.
So, the other thing I'm going to
go over a bit is editing colors.
As you can see, the page is just
black and white.
It's actually two things.
I'm going to go over the logo
first.
And then the colors.
So, if you click on Pages here in
the top left.
You will see I've segmented these
things out.
So, we've got logos and
typography.
So, for logos.
Basically, you want to double
click.
This is a logo component.
Double click on this.
And then you're going to delete
this.
And add a new image.
Just do insert.
And then media and image.
Upload your image.
Image here.
Size it to be approximately the
same height as this.
Width can be longer.
But height as the current here.
Which is about 46 or 50.
As I will probably fit.
Then go back out.
In the top left logos.
You'll see it here.
As you can see, it's within this
little box here.
And whenever you change that.
When you go back to the homepage.
All your logos on the page will be
updated to match that.
Now, for colors.
Colors are where you're going to
really customize your site.
Right?
So, every one of these sections.
If I select this.
And if you look at the bottom
right here under styles.
It's got a fill.
Right?
And the fill.
It's set to neutral surface main.
You can edit that here.
But I was just editing it on the
main color page.
So, basically.
These are all different presets.
If you go back to the colors page.
If I go to home.
I go to pages.
Go to colors.
You can see here.
We've got neutral.
Primary slash brand.
Secondary.
Territory.
Success.
Warning.
Danger.
Text.
Alphas.
Right?
If you want to change the primary
color.
You can see it says main default
slash brand.
You can change the color of this
here.
If you want to change background
color.
Say, for instance.
You wanted.
I don't know.
A green background.
Very simply.
You can click here.
Neutral.
Surface main.
Change here.
Set it to a green.
As you can see.
The background there is changing.
Of this entire thing.
As the entire background is.
Was set to surface main.
So, you can edit that there.
As you would like.
And then, any other section that
is used.
That surface main.
As its main section.
Will be green.
As you can see.
Like, these boxes aren't affected.
But the main background is.
And you can go through.
And edit that then.
As you.
As you want to suit your brand.
Same with these.
You change the main default brand.
Color.
Stop doing that.
Just click this.
Primary slash main default.
Click edit.
Set to red.
Go back to the page.
Then, any sections I had.
To see those.
Those icons are now red.
These stars are now red.
Anything that you set.
To use.
That color bar.
If I double click on this.
And if I click on the icon.
You can see.
For the icon color.
It used that primary main default.
So, when you ever.
Edit that primary main default.
It'll change the color.
On the page.
This allows you.
Just to keep a very.
Kind of constant brand look.
Throughout.
It's set to gray and black.
Just for you guys.
To start off.
Again.
Like on the section.
Say you want to just have a white
page.
With a white background.
You will double click here.
Click fill.
And then.
You've got neutral surface main.
Neutral inverse surface main.
So, it's white.
And for the text.
You would click this.
And then.
You can edit the.
You can add the color.
So, you can do.
Text inverse main.
And same for the one below.
Color.
Text.
Inverse subtle maybe.
For instance.
And now it's a white version of
the page.
So, you just do that throughout
And edit the colors as you go.
That is kind of the main part of
this.
Most changes you make to these
sections should just update
directly over.
You shouldn't have to edit them
specifically.
If you look here.
If you actually.
If I click on this section.
Right.
So, the white shoes.
The edge.
Which is there.
There.
And there.
The.
This is set to the variant of
desktop.
Right.
If I click in the middle one here.
See that's set to tablet.
And then if I click this one here.
It's set to phone.
If I was to change these.
It would.
So, that's the tablet view.
I set it to desktop.
See it looks kind of wonky and
weird.
So, set it to tablet.
And it's fine.
Set it.
It's set to phone.
Set it to desktop.
Way too big.
Not going to work.
Set it to phone.
Perfect size.
When you double click on these
components.
You can see the.
Tablet and phone versions of each
of these here.
So, if you want to make changes to
just the phone version.
You can make the edit inside the
variant itself here.
And that'll show up in the phone
section.
So, that should give you an idea
generally how this works.
I imagine there's going to be some
questions about this.
I'm going to put the template
customization call calendar link.
In the description of this video.
So, if you have any problems.
You can book a call with me.
And I will go through this with
you one on one.
But, I'll also give you some
resources.
I think you should watch in
general on Framer.
If you want to get really into it.
One other thing I included
actually was some background
sections.
These are some number of images
and backgrounds.
You can use to spice things up.
And change things around a bit.
So, you can take a look at these.
And kind of copy and paste them
in.
And again, you click on the
layers.
So, each of the backgrounds is in
a stack.
Let's make it smaller.
I have to move my face out of the
way.
They're in a row.
So, they're inside a stack.
Inside a row.
So, that's the first one.
That's the second one.
That's the third one.
Like that thread.
And you can copy and paste those
to the main page.
In order to kind of, you know,
make things look a bit nicer.
And change things up a bit.
So, play around with those.
See how it goes.
Any major problems.
Again, book a call with me.
And I will walk you through it.
These are going to be slightly
more technical.
So, you can bring these questions
to the landing page call.
But you'll probably have more time
with me.
To go through it.
And make sure everything is
working correctly.
On the actual template
customization calls.
So, feel free to book that for
whatever suits you.
And yeah.
I think you guys are going to
really enjoy this.
It's going to make your sites look
even better.
It'll be a little bit of learning
for some of you guys.
So, keep that in mind.
This isn't going to be as simple
as card.
It might take you a bit longer to
do.
So, kind of set aside the time to
kind of invest in this.
But it should end up you guys
having some really, really sick
sites.
That are going to really help with
conversions.
And, you know, make your business
look even more kind of
professional and stuff.
So, hope this is helpful.
The link to copy this project will
be in the description.
Along with a link to the
customization call on me.
And some resources on Framer in
general.
That you guys can use to kind of
brush up and just learn a bit more
as you go.
So, any problems, feel free to
reach out to me.
And yeah.
Look good.
Thanks.