All right, in this module, we're
going to cover pipeline setup and
management.
So I created a pipeline for you
guys already in this snapshot.
It includes the newly discovery
book, demo book, no show,
canceled,
follow up, deal closed, and deal
lost.
Now, you can edit this if you
want.
If you want to edit it, you can
click here in pipelines.
You can actually create as many
new pipelines as you want it
in case you have multiple products
or things like that.
But to edit this pipeline, you're
going to click here on the pencil
icon.
And here you can change the name,
new lead, new prospect,
whatever you want to call it, and
remove any sections
that you don't feel like you need
or add new ones.
So just click add stage, and you
can add a new stage.
Then you click save, and all the
changes you make will be added.
Now, when it comes to managing the
leads and moving around,
so they'll automatically be moved
based on what happens with a lead.
So, for example, if they book a
discovery or a demo,
they'll get moved to that stage.
But afterwards, you need to update
it based on what happens.
So if they no show, just move them
here.
If they book a follow-up, move
them here.
If they close, move them here.
If you lose them, move them here.
Okay, pretty simple.
And if you want to add any notes
to the opportunity,
you can just click here and add
any notes that you want to add.
Okay.
Save it, and it'll be right there.
And if you want to add tasks, you
could also add tasks for each
lead.
Save it.
That'll be right there.
Okay.
You can also book appointments,
manage payments.
Okay.
You can create an estimate or
create an invoice if you want,
once you have Stripe connected.
And add any other details like
tags and stuff like that.
Okay.
We just click update.
And it'll get updated.
Now, if you want to edit what
shows up in the card itself,
let's see where the card went.
I'll just refresh.
Okay.
Got moved here.
I'll just keep it here for now.
But if you want to make any
changes to the card itself,
you can open it up.
Or sorry, not open it up, but go
here to manage fields.
And here you could change how the
card looks itself.
So you can see we have all of
these fields added,
the source, the value, the last
reason, right?
So whenever, as you update those
fields,
it'll show up in the card itself.
But if you feel like you only need
the business name,
the source, and the owner, right?
Or the name of the opportunity,
you can just remove these things.
As you can see, the card changes
and gets smaller.
Okay.
If you want to add more details,
create it on last status change,
stuff like that, or contact
details,
you could add those here.
Just select, you know, what you
want to add.
And it'll update it for you.
You can make a compact card if you
prefer,
unlabeled, where you don't really
have any type of,
you know, what's the word?
These things right here.
And yeah, if you want to edit
these,
that's how you do it.
Now, another thing you could do
is add custom opportunity fields.
So to do that, you go to settings,
you go to custom fields, okay?
And you can create add field
where let's say, for example,
it's going to be a dropdown.
Okay, so here it could be a
product, right?
See what product you're interested
in.
If you have multiple products you
sell,
so it could be done for you.
It could be a one-time setup,
or it could be consulting.
So to do this
and turn this into an opportunity
field,
just click here in object
and change it to opportunity.
Okay, you save it.
Oh, you're going to group it,
so opportunity details.
You save it,
and then once you go back to the
pipeline,
okay, you'll be able to see that
field right here,
and you can select, you know,
what the product they're
interested in
or a prospect for.
All right, and then if you go
here,
you could make sure it shows up.
So let's just find here.
So it's not showing up,
but it should.
Let me just refresh the page
again.
Sometimes high-level can be a
little bit buggy.
It's in here.
So if we've managed the fields.
Product.
Okay, so we click save.
Now we can see the product is done
for you.
Okay, so now you can have your
custom product in there.
Okay, if you prefer to see it as a
list,
you can click here,
and it'll just show up as a list
if it's easier for you guys.
And yeah,
if you guys want to add an
opportunity manually,
just click add opportunity,
fill out the details,
and it'll be created.
Okay, so that's pretty much
how you manage the pipeline
and go high-level.
Very simple and intuitive,
in my opinion.
But yeah,
if you guys have any questions
about this,
just reach out.
Okay.