Okay, so we're going to talk about
claims and guarantees.
So to close cold traffic, you need
a remarkability factor, right?
Because market share works
exponentially, right?
So the people with the best offers
take all of the business
and leave basically nothing for
you, right?
So your job is to make an offer so
good that you leave nothing for
anybody else, right?
So these are arbitrary numbers, by
the way.
But let's say you have somebody
with an offer strength of one.
They get fucking nothing, like
just zero.
The offer strength of two, it's
like a little bit.
It's a double one, but it's still
nothing.
And then three is double two, but
it's still nothing.
Four is double three, but it's
still nothing.
Five is double four, but now
you're starting to getting
somewhere.
Six is substantially more and
seven is also substantially more.
You know what I'm saying?
But like no one's making any money
or getting fucking rich at all
until six and seven.
Like it's just so fucking useless
to have an offer that's like one,
two, three, four, or five.
You might as well just fucking
quit the business and go get a job
and just stop doing this.
There's literally no point at all.
And now you're probably wondering
at this point, well, what
determines what is the strength of
an offer?
And the answer is the claim and
the guarantee that you have on it.
Now, I don't want to say that as
an absolute because you can have a
really good offer with no claim
and with no guarantee.
But the only situation that that
is ever going to be the case is if
you are selling something that is
truly, insanely fucking
remarkable.
And it's like, it's just, you
probably don't have that.
You just don't, right?
I mean like really like
revolutionary type like tech that
you, proprietary shit that you've
developed, right?
It's just, you probably just don't
have that, right?
So the answer for you is it's a
claim and a guarantee, right?
So if your offer in business is
not remarkable enough, you don't
get scraps.
You need every single one of all
the variables for amplified
returns.
If your offer is not absolutely
remarkable, pretty much zero
people buy it.
So how do I know if my offer is
working?
You will know, right?
You will be getting hello
responses.
So people will be getting on calls
with you.
It will be extremely obvious if
you have a good offer.
If it feels like you need to climb
a mountain and run three marathons
just to get a single person on the
phone, your offer is not good,
right?
Your offer needs to be better if
that is the case.
Just like how you ask the
question, does he or she like me?
Are they into me?
Brother, you will know if she's
into you.
Like if you're confused, she
doesn't.
Like you will know, right?
If you're getting mixed signals
from the market, the market isn't
into you, right?
And you need to change.
It's really that simple, right?
You'll fucking know if the offer
is working or not.
If you're not sure or if it
doesn't feel like it is, then your
offer isn't good.
You need to up the claim.
You need to up the guarantee if
you don't have a shit ton of case
studies, right?
So a formulation of an offer
contains three components.
Claim, what result will they get?
Guarantee, what if it doesn't
work?
What happens?
Evidence, who else has it worked
for, right?
And evidence is case studies.
So this is the logical flow that
prospects ask in that exact
sequence, right?
First they ask, what results will
I get?
And then they ask themselves,
well, what if I don't get the
result?
What happens?
And then they ask, well, who else
has it worked for?
That's literally in the exact
sequence of what happens in their
head.
So if you have no evidence, it is
required to have both a claim and
guarantee.
If you have evidence, and I mean
like extreme evidence, like you
have like a fucking shit ton of
case studies, you can remove the
guarantee, right?
So here's just an example of a
content agency of what I call the
claim timeline or like the results
timeline.
So you got to imagine what's
happening here is, is let's say
that you produce videos for people
and you have a left side of the
timeline and you have a right side
of the timeline, right?
On the left side of the timeline,
there's the actual deliverable,
like the thing that you give the
clients, which is the videos,
right?
That's the thing that technically
the thing they bought is the
videos, right?
But you got to ask yourself, why
do clients want a video?
What is the purpose of a video?
The purpose of a video is to get
views.
Well, what is the purpose of
views?
Why do you want views?
The purpose of that is to get
followers.
Well, why do I want followers?
What is the purpose of followers?
It's to get leads.
What is the purpose of leads?
It's to get sales calls.
What's the purpose of sales calls?
It's to get clients, right?
So if you're on the left side of
the timeline, you're a service.
So I will give you videos.
You're a service, right?
If you're on the right side of the
timeline, you are an offer.
I will give you X amount of views.
It's an offer.
I'll give you X amount of sales
calls.
I'll give you an offer.
I'll guarantee you sign X amount
of clients.
That's an offer, right?
You only sell your stuff to cold
traffic.
The only way to sell your stuff to
cold traffic is if you promise to
end result in any of the
dimensions listed above.
So you can take any one of these,
slap a specific number behind it,
slap a guarantee behind them
hitting that specific amount, and
then that's an offer.
You get what I'm saying?
But what you're going to do is
say, well, I'll guarantee them
views then because I can't
guarantee them clients.
Okay, well, now your offer's
shitty because more people will
guarantee views, and you have more
competition now, and it's not as
attractive of an offer.
So what does that mean?
It means that if you try to make
an offer and you're guaranteeing
views, it might be in your
specific offer that you're selling
to your specific niche that no
one's booking a call with you.
And you're like, well, Daniel, I
did what you said.
It's not working.
It's like, no, because you're
being a fucking pussy and not
laying your dick on the table.
It's like, the views aren't
fucking good enough, right?
So maybe you need to guarantee
leads.
Maybe you need to guarantee sales
calls.
Maybe you need to guarantee
clients.
Just guarantee clients, right?
Just guarantee clients and
guarantee calls.
Like, it's going to fucking work
better.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, there's this concept called
market sophistication where, like,
markets have been sold something.
Like, people have already been
promised views.
Maybe they've already been
promised leads.
They've been promised calls.
Like, if you promise them clients,
you book fucking so many more
calls.
Like, so fucking many more.
Like, a fucking retarded amount
more clients, right?
But now what you're asking is,
Daniel, well, what if the client
fucks up the sales calls and can't
close clients themselves?
Then I'm stuck giving them a
refund because they can't close
clients.
Yes, correct.
That's why we use what are called
stipulations inside of your
contract.
What does that mean?
If you're guaranteeing clients,
you stipulate that they are
closing the sales calls.
And if they aren't closing the
sales calls, they're not eligible
to request a refund.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, that's what you do.
You eliminate the possibility of
the client fucking it up.
That's what you do, right?
And we'll talk more about that
towards the end of this.
But let's continue on.
So the only way to sell is to have
a remarkability factor.
Remarkability can be interchanged
with, like, differentiation.
So let's take something happening
in the market right now at the
time this is filming, right?
You can now train an AI on your
voice and face to automatically
create hundreds of pieces of
content in an instant, right?
You do not need to memorize
scripts, get on camera, spend time
recording, or manage editors.
You can post two or three clips
per day without doing anything.
This is the definition of
remarkable and different, right?
So now if you approach a client
and you say some shit, like, hey,
I can produce three pieces of
short form content for you per day
and you never even have to get on
camera or memorize scripts or do
anything.
I can just train an AI to look
exactly like you and sound exactly
like you and mass produce clips
and post them for you.
They're like, yo, that's fucking
crazy.
That's insane.
Like, I didn't know you could do
that.
That's so wild, right?
And they're like, fuck, yeah, let
me hear more about it.
Okay.
But in two years from the time of
this filming, that's not going to
be the reaction anymore because
that is going to be a widely
fucking executed thing.
And shit tons of people will have
fucking sold that to them.
That's called market
sophistication, right?
So now what do you have to do at
that point?
That remarkability factor is gone.
So now what do you have to do?
You have to fucking promise them
the result.
It's the only way.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, it all loops back around to
promising the result, right?
So your mistake will be to assume
that you're solving, like, a super
fucking wildly huge problem.
And you're going to assume that
your deliverable is, like, super
remarkable.
Like, what you have is, like,
profoundly revolutionary.
I fucking promise you
99.99999999999% of you do not
fucking have a product that is
remarkable enough to not have a
guarantee.
I promise you that.
I absolutely promise you that.
So how do I make my offer
different?
Okay.
By having something that is
genuinely different, but you
probably aren't different because
not everybody can be different,
right?
So what 99% of you are selling
isn't different.
It's not remarkable.
Like, you're selling it like a
cold email lead gen agency.
Like, congratulations.
You're the fucking 10,000th person
to do that.
Or you're making an ad agency.
Congratulations.
You're the fucking 50,000th person
to do that.
Like, it's like, no.
Like, you're not fucking
different.
Like, you're not remarkable.
You know what I'm saying?
You have to have the guarantee.
You fucking have to.
It's the only way.
It's the only way that this is
going to work for you.
So you need to do it, right?
If you have something genuinely
remarkable, absolutely profound,
indisputably revolutionary, then
you wouldn't need to promise
results.
But you don't.
So you do need to promise results.
And the sooner you come to grips
with this, and just listen to what
I'm telling you to do, the faster
you're going to succeed in your
business, right?
I think I said this in the last
video, but this whole idea of,
like, me sitting here and, like,
trying to get you to understand
that you have to do this, you,
too, are going to have to do this
to your clients.
Because most of your clients are
going to have dog shit offers that
are not going to be able to be
sold unless they have a promise of
a result on it.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, that's what I'm trying to
get.
So, like, I'm being so forceful in
explaining this to you because you
need to understand it so
thoroughly that you, too, will be
able to teach it to other people.
You get what I'm saying?
So, like, all right, let's just
walk through some examples.
A million views guaranteed.
That's an offer.
10,000 new followers guaranteed.
1,000 new leads guaranteed.
That's an offer.
100 sales calls book guaranteed.
10 new clients guaranteed.
That's an offer, right?
And that's just going from this
little timeline over here.
So, which of these sounds more
attractive?
Okay, of these.
Which of these sounds more
attractive to you if I offered to
you right now?
Which would you personally have
the highest probability of buying?
If I gave you, right now, you
watching this video, fucking which
one of these would you buy?
Don't bullshit me.
Because the answer is obviously
this one.
It's the 10 new clients
guaranteed, right?
So, what makes you think that the
people you're selling to are
different than you?
Right?
There's this saying by this famous
copywriter.
He goes,
The prospect isn't stupid.
She's your mother.
What is he saying there?
Like, for you to assume the
prospect is so fucking dumb that
they are not in the market right
now actively choosing this offer
over this one or this one or this
one or this one.
That's like the equivalent of you
thinking your mom is a fucking
retard.
Like, the prospect is your mom.
Like, they're not fucking stupid.
They're the same as you.
Like, obviously, they would want
this one.
And, in fact, they're in the
market right now buying this offer
at 45 times the rate than your
offer, like, over here.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, they're already buying this
45 times more than they're buying
yours up here or here or here or
here.
Like, the guy selling this is
making a fucking shit ton more
money than you.
Like, a fucking lot, lot more
Right?
So, okay.
You need to promise a quantifiable
end result or have a
differentiating value proposition
genuinely, actually unique.
So, quantifiable end results.
What exactly am I getting when I
work with you?
What results are you claiming that
I'm able to get?
People are only concerned with
what they get.
Nobody buys video editing.
Nobody even buys videos.
They buy the result the videos are
intended to produce for them.
Nobody buys emails.
They buy the result the emails are
intended to get them, etc., etc.
The same exact thing for every
service you'll ever sell in your
life.
It's actually the same exact thing
for anything.
For anything at all in your life.
Like, if you buy a fucking banana
at the grocery store, you're not
buying a banana.
You're buying a cessation of
hunger and the ability to continue
surviving.
That's what you're buying.
That's why the most commonly sold
product on the entire planet is
water.
You know what I'm saying?
Because if you go two days without
it, you fucking die.
Like, and then the next commonly
sold product in the world is food.
Okay, cool.
What's next?
Housing.
Right?
Can't be homeless.
What's next?
Transportation.
Right?
It's like, because, like, do I buy
a plane ticket because I like
being on the plane?
Fuck no.
Fuck planes.
I would never step on a plane ever
again in my fucking life if it
wasn't transporting me to a
different spot.
Like, that's the whole fucking
point of the day.
Like, you know what I'm saying?
Like, everything has an end
result.
Nothing is ever bought beyond
getting to the end result.
That's why when an airline
advertises, they advertise the
destination, not the fucking
plane.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, when you're trying to sell
emails or fucking, or videos,
like, I do video editing, that's
the equivalent of being, like,
United Airlines and being, like,
this is our plane.
Look at the inside of our plane.
This is how fast the plane goes.
This is how high the plane goes.
This is the fuel efficiency of the
plane.
How, why the fuck does a consumer
give a shit about the fuel
efficiency of the plane?
No, they give a fuck about the
destination.
Is it Cancun?
Is it fucking London?
You get what I'm saying?
So, all right, cool.
Quantifiable end results come in
destinations.
So, for instance, let's say you're
a content agency.
You sell scripted and edited
content.
You need to ask yourself the
question, why would somebody buy
videos from me?
They would do so for any of these
reasons.
Views, followers, leads, sales
calls, books, and sales and
revenue, right?
So, to create a quantifiable end
result for your service, you pick
any of these dimensions.
You put a number on it.
Million views, 90 days guaranteed.
But, Daniel, I can't promise
somebody a million views.
Yes, you can if you do what is
required to get one million views.
And you contractually require the
client to do what is necessary to
get one million views in the first
place.
You use stipulations.
I will explain what these are
momentarily.
But, basically, you design
contracts in such a way that the
only way the result could ever be
fucked up is if it's your fault,
right?
You completely eliminate the
possibility that the client gets a
refund if it's their fault they
didn't get the result, right?
So, I'm going to go over this real
quick and then we're going to
start talking about stipulations.
So, the necessity of a guarantee
is inversely proportional with how
many case studies and how much
quantifiable social proof you
have.
So, I've got a little graph right
here.
You can zoom into it more if you
open the Gamma Doc.
The link is under this video.
But, the first question you ask
yourself is you're going to start
with a specific problem.
Are you solving a real problem for
a niche?
And, if the answer is no, then
nothing you do will ever work,
right?
Now, if the answer is yes, you
move on to the next question,
which is, are you using a
completely new and unheard of way
to solve it?
If the answer is yes, you don't
really need a guarantee, but
you're definitely going to do a
fuck ton better with it, right?
Okay, now let's say the answer is
no.
That means you go to the next
question.
Are you charging an abnormally low
amount of money, right?
If the answer is yes, you don't
really need one, but a guarantee
will help a fuck ton, right?
But, you shouldn't charge an
abnormally low amount of money
because then you don't fucking
make any money, right?
So, the answer to this question is
no, right?
Do you have quantifiable client
results?
Like a fuck ton of client results?
Like more than $500,000 of like
pure profit made for clients?
If yes, you can get away without a
guarantee, but you're going to
grow a fuck load faster with it,
right?
Now, if the answer is less than
$100,000 that you made for clients
or no, then you need a guarantee.
Like 100% of the time.
Does that make sense?
So, types of guarantees from least
risky to most risky.
So, you have a performance basis,
which means that like the client
pays as the result occurs.
So, there's zero risk of the
client.
So, that would mean like, hey, I'm
going to do 100% performance-based
lead generation for you
and you're going to only pay for
the calls that show up.
Like that would be a performance
basis type thing, right?
Then there's money back
guarantees.
So, that would mean the client
gets refunded if they don't get
the result.
So, this is like a risk to the
client that you might not refund,
right?
So, like you collect the money up
front and the result doesn't
occur, then the client requests
the refund and you have to give
the refund, right?
Okay.
So, now, however, let me walk
through just some examples because
it's not like cut and dry
like that.
You can mix and form different
things in different ways and you
can just fuck with anything and
any which way.
There's no rules.
You can do any fucking deal you
want with the client, right?
But, again, like going back to the
concept I've said before, like the
purpose of your headline
and your offer is to get them on
the phone.
That isn't actually what you end
up selling people.
Like what you end up selling
people ends up being super fucking
like custom to each individual
person.
That's what running an agency is.
You don't have like defined
products where I only charge this
amount of money.
That's what everyone pays.
That's literally never going to
fucking happen in your agency.
Don't do that, right?
So, every fucking deal is going to
be custom.
Like the contract terms are going
to be custom.
Like people will negotiate shit.
Sometimes they won't negotiate
shit.
You're going to quote different
prices to different people based
off what they're selling and what
kind of results you think are
possible as you get more
experience.
Like everything is all sorts of
different fuck all which different
ways.
You get what I'm saying?
So, we're going to walk through
just four examples of like a cold
email agency.
Okay.
So, it's all cold email agent.
Every person charges a monthly
tech fee of $500 a month.
Now, okay.
So, let's talk about agency owner
one.
They charge a $2,000 setup fee
plus $300 per call on top of the
$500 a month tech fee.
And they have zero guarantee.
Okay, cool.
Let's compare this to agency owner
number two.
They also have a $500 a month tech
fee.
There's a $2,000 setup plus $300
cost per call.
Right?
So, same as this.
But, if you don't sign $15,000 in
new business in the next 45 days,
you get the setup fee refunded and
can refund half the calls you took
and choose to keep working
together or not.
If you had to choose between
agency owner one.
You're on a sales call, by the
way.
So, imagine that all of these
people had the same headline on
their website.
It was like performance-based lead
generation.
Right?
Because even this guy can fucking
say he does performance-based lead
generation where you pay per call.
Right?
He could say that as his headline.
You know, yes, there's a $2,000
setup and a $500 a month tech fee.
It doesn't fucking matter.
He could still say, you could,
because this is what I'm getting
at.
Like, there's wordplay.
Like, you fuck with the words to
get people on the phone.
You have to get the people on the
phone.
Right?
So, you got to say what is
required to get people on the
phone.
And then what you sell them does
not have to be the exact literal
interpretation of what the fucking
words are on the headline.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, it's not the same.
You got to say what is required to
get them on the phone.
So, now, okay, you, you as a
business owner were proposed these
two different things on a sales
call.
Which one do you take?
Whose fucking deal do you take?
Assume they have the same amount
of experience in case studies.
The answer, fucking obviously, is
number two.
Like, it just fucking is.
Right?
Okay, now let's compare this to
this one.
A $500 a month tech fee on this
guy.
Then there's a $300 per call.
And you pay, like, when the call
is booked.
Which is the same, same for all,
all these.
Right?
Which, which do you pick?
Most people pick this one to
eliminate this.
That's, that's, that's literally,
that's literally what they fucking
do.
Right?
Because this says, this, you, but,
because what we're saying here is
that, yeah, we'll refund the setup
fee.
But this one, because there just
isn't a setup fee at all, they
still want that one because there
just is no setup fee.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, it's like fuckery like this.
Okay, so now, now this one is $500
a month.
And then there's $500 a month tech
fee.
And then it's just $3,000 a month.
And if you don't get 10, uh, 10
calls per month, you get a
proportional refund.
So, like, say it's, because it's
10 calls guaranteed for $3,000 per
month.
So, each call is there for $300.
You get what I'm saying?
But if we only book seven calls
for you, we'll, we'll, we'll
refund the remaining $900 on, on,
on this.
Right, okay, which one, which,
which one wins on, on the sales
call?
This one wins on the sales call.
Why?
Because, because it's performance.
It's, it's, it's, it's mostly
performance.
You get what I'm saying?
Because performance is less risky
than money back guarantee.
You get, you get what I'm saying?
But all of them can still fucking
say performance-based lead
generation.
Where you only pay for calls
booked.
All of them can say that.
You get what I'm saying?
And now, like, this guy, if he
doesn't say that, he isn't getting
a single fucking person to book a
call with him.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, like, when you're making
these offers to call traffic,
don't make the mistake of listing
out every single fucking
contingency.
Of, of, of, of the offer, right?
I've seen people do stupid shit.
Like, like, they'll make this
their headline.
They'll say, performance-based
lead generation where we'll book
you sales calls and only charge a
$500 tech fee and refund you all
the calls we couldn't get booked
for you.
It's like, bro, what, what the
fuck are you saying?
Like, why, why would you, why
would you say that?
That is not marketing.
There's a time and a place to get
into the details of your offer.
And it's not the very first
sentence the prospect sees, right?
All of the deal, all of the
details about an offer, an
arrangement you make with the
client occurs after they're on the
phone.
You need to say whatever it takes
to get the client on the phone.
That's the entire purpose of using
a guarantee is to get them on the
phone, right?
Your guarantee is, is a mechanism
to get people to book a call.
It's not a mechanism to close the
sale.
You know what I'm saying?
So like, hilariously, 99% of the
time, the prospect won't even
mention the guarantee once they're
on the phone with you, right?
They'll forget you even mentioned
it when they're finally on.
In every deal you ever do, in
every deal you ever do with your
first 30 to 50 clients is going to
be custom anyway.
What you're advertising on the
front end as your headline or
original cold outreach script is
not the exact offer that you're
selling
because every deal you make with
the client is going to be
different.
Get what I'm saying?
Everything's different.
It's all custom.
It's all dynamic.
That's what you're doing.
Like, everything is different in
the beginning.
Like, don't fucking box yourself
into this like arbitrarily made,
like, I have to charge this exact
much.
I only charge this much money.
Like, what you can guarantee for
one person is not what you can
guarantee for another.
And if you get caught thinking
about all these contingencies and
pulling your punches,
pull your punches from saying a
really, really good offer with the
biggest fuck numbers on the front
end,
nobody is going to get on the
phone with you.
90% of the time, if you're not
getting enough sales calls booked,
it's because you're pulling your
punches and using a genuinely very
good claim with really big numbers
that actually get people
interested at all.
You're pulling your punches on
this because you're thinking about
all of the contingencies
and getting too into your head
about the fact that you're, that
you, that, that you can't get that
result
for every single, every singular
person.
Stop doing that.
Because the people who can get
really good results, who are great
clients,
will not get on the phone with you
if you're not quoting high enough
and attractive enough results in
your headliner offer.
So, for instance, if you're one of
those lead gen offers up above
and you charge $500 a month tech
fee and a $3,000 a month retainer
worth of proportional refund,
then don't fucking say that,
right?
Just say it's performance-based
lead gen where you only pay for
qualified sales calls that show
up.
And then, the, the, the, the, the
mechanical workings of how that is
fucking laid out,
you talk about that on the fucking
sales call, right?
You don't talk about that in the
headline of your offer, right?
So, all the nuance about the
logistics of the offer and the
terms is a conversation
that happens one-on-one, not on
the headline of your website
or inside of your cold email
scripts.
You know what I'm saying?
All right, cool.
So, if you use a guarantee, don't
sign clients who can't get the
result, right?
But when using a guarantee, you
need to heavily qualify clients
to make sure it's possible to get
the result in the first place.
Because it is inherently the most
attractive offer possible,
the conversion rate will go up
substantially, right?
So, with a higher conversion rate,
you must increase your filtering
and accept only the most qualified
people who have a high likelihood
of achievement in the first place.
So, let's say you get on the phone
with a prospect who, for whatever
reason,
there's no way they're able to get
the result promised on your
landing page
or you said in a cold email to
them, whatever the fuck.
Then simply don't fucking give
them that guarantee.
Like, just fucking, like, you're
not contractually fucking legally
required
to fucking do the deal with the
person, right?
So, okay.
So, normally, just like what you
would say,
normally when we sign clients in
this offer,
it's because I'm absolutely
certain we can get that result for
them.
Based off what you have, and
because X, Y, and Z factor,
based off what you have, Mr.
Client,
because you don't have any client
case studies yourself,
and, like, you've never actually
sold this to cold traffic before,
like, I'm not confident in my
ability to sell this to cold
traffic,
and therefore, I wouldn't be able
to guarantee you this amount of
clients.
You know what I'm saying?
I do not believe we'd be able to
get you that result.
What I do think is possible for
you is X, right?
And if that's something you'd
still be interested in talking
about,
I'd be happy to continue the
conversation, but if not, no
worries, right?
Okay, everything is a negotiation.
Do not ever lock yourself into one
singular deliverable
for only one singular price and
only one singular result.
You've got to be dynamic,
sell everybody exactly what they
are willing to buy
until you're at $100K a month.
I always hear this a lot.
People are like,
Daniel, how much should I charge?
Or should I do a performance
basis?
Or can I start taking rev shares
plus retainers?
Like, should I do that?
Or, like, what should I do?
And the answer is that you sell
what you can.
You sell the most advantageous
deal for yourself
that you're possibly able to pull
off, right?
And if a client pushes back on it
and they don't want it,
then negotiate the fucking shit
down
until a point where you both reach
an agreement
where you're down to do it for
that specific price
with these specific logistics and
contract terms
and this specific guarantee or
whatever the fuck.
You get what I'm saying?
The answer to how much money you
should charge
is the maximum fucking amount
that you could possibly get on the
call
that you could possibly get the
client to talk about, right?
And don't do this stupid bullshit
where it's like,
well, you know, like, I really
want to,
I really want to make sure I'm not
taking too much money.
Like, no.
Fucking charge as much as you
possibly can.
You get what I'm saying?
So, all right, cool.
If you're scared of getting
results for clients
and getting screwed by refunds,
I constantly get this question
from people inside Client
Ascension
who are too scared to use a
guarantee.
They say, I want to position my
offer around getting results,
but I don't want to guarantee
results
because not all my clients get
results.
And I don't want to get stuck
giving refunds.
What do I do?
Okay, a couple of things you have
to understand here.
The reason a lot of your clients
don't get results
is because out of scarcity,
you're allowing yourself to sign
low quality clients
who are impossible to get results
for in the first place.
But of all the people who say
this,
it's because they signed a client
and they're,
okay, when I say the word client,
what you're thinking of is like
this like vague idea
of a business owner who has it all
figured out
and like who has a lot of money.
That's what you were thinking.
What you're failing to understand
is that all of the people who say
this signed a client,
but it's not that person.
It's a client who like doesn't
actually run a business
that makes any fucking money at
all.
And they have like no client case
studies.
They have, their offer is dog
shit.
It's, they've never sold it to
cold traffic before ever
in their fucking life.
Not even once.
Like that's who says stuff like
this.
Which I, none of my client,
my, all of my clients don't get
results.
The clients who don't get results
are this,
is this person who isn't even
running
a real fucking business, right?
And now how did, how did the
person who's saying this,
how did they arise into a
situation
where they, they decided to sign a
person
who makes no fucking money at all?
And I want to explain why, right?
So, so because they weren't
promising results,
they were not positioning
themselves
to be attractive enough to attract
good quality clients.
This means you sign less and less
good quality clients
who are easy to get results for.
Okay, so their, their claim of
like results
that a client can get, or like
their guarantee
was so of a low number, like so
shitty,
only shitty clients were willing
to get on the phone
for it at all, where it's like,
your next client guaranteed, or
some,
or like I'll guarantee you book
five sales calls,
some stupid fucking bullshit like
that.
Like, what, what does that do?
What it does is it gets the
people,
like you say five fucking sales
calls guaranteed,
it attracts the person who thinks
five sales calls is a lot, right?
And they're fucking poor people.
You get what I'm saying, right?
So a reason you don't get clients
is because your offer is not good
enough
to attract the, uh, attract the
quality clients
in the first place.
So you only, so the only people
you ever talk to
are low quality clients.
This means you rarely get them any
results,
which means you're scared to
promise results.
Okay, so this is, this is, this is
what this looks like.
You promise an underwhelming
result, right?
Which leads to you only attracting
low quality clients
who think that result is a lot.
Which means it's impossible to get
results
for those clients because they're
low quality clients
and they run shitty businesses,
right?
Which means you can't generate
case studies
because they're impossible to get
results for, right?
And because you can't generate
case studies,
it means you can't charge more
money
and consistently increase your
revenue.
And when you can't do that,
it means you become insecure and
unsure of yourself,
which leads to you continuing
to promise underwhelming results.
That's what the fuck is happening
here.
You get what I'm saying?
So like, however, if you made your
offer substantially better
by actually promising clear and
quantifiable results,
you would book two to four times
more calls
fucking immediately, right?
Which would mean you have more
exposure to people
who actually have great businesses
and who are easier to get results
for.
So what would that look like?
It means you start, this is where
you start,
by the way, this is step one,
right?
You make a high result claim in
large guarantees
in your front end copy.
Which means that you attract high
quality clients
who are only swayed by those high
numbers, right?
Which means high quality clients
are easy to get results for,
which means you generate tons of
case studies easily,
which means that you book more
calls,
booking more calls becomes
progressively easier
and you build authority more
quickly,
which means you can increase your
prices
and keep making more money.
You know what I'm saying?
That's how this shit works.
So it's like super fucking
integral that you understand.
So this is a quick graph of,
it's just sales calls booked,
assuming with versus without a
guarantee.
Okay, so quick visualization here.
So you'll probably book something
like
fucking five and a half, six times
more calls
using a guarantee versus without
when you're just getting started.
You don't have a bunch of case
studies, right?
Okay, so.
What this means is that
over a six month period,
you have booked 33 calls without a
guarantee.
You have booked 198 calls with a
So six calls a month versus 33
calls a month, right?
So like almost fucking six times
more.
So the main problem you'll have
in objecting to what I'm telling
you to do here
is that you're not appreciating
the degree
to which this actually impacts
your trajectory
when you're just starting, right?
You got to understand that you
cannot afford
to only get six sales calls
average per month for six months.
So without a guarantee over the
course of six months,
it's only 33 calls you booked.
That's a 15% close rate.
That means five clients signed
over six months, right?
Account for client.
Sure.
And you're living in complete
absolute fucking desolate poverty.
You need to have another job,
right?
You are not running a serious
business.
You're not being a serious person
at all.
With the guarantee, it's 198 total
calls booked
over the course of six months.
15% close rate means you close 30
clients.
Average of five per month.
That's a fucking shit ton of
revenue to work with, right?
It affords you the opportunity to
actually produce case studies.
And when you get case studies
made,
you book even more sales calls
and you're able to make more
content
and get more referrals
and generally make like way more
noise
that tremendously impacts your
inbound lead flow, right?
So we're going to revisit this
concept
so you fully understand it.
Okay.
So your offer is about getting
people on the phone, right?
If your offer is not strong
enough,
nobody will get on the phone with
you.
If an unqualified prospect happens
to get on the phone,
you don't need to go through
with the exact offer that was on
your landing page for them.
It's just called just not offering
somebody.
Your offer is for qualified
prospects only.
But when you have a bad offer,
that's not attractive.
You never get qualified prospects
on the phone in the first place
because people only,
because good prospects only buy
good offers, right?
So you go into the death loop of
my offer is bad
because I don't get any qualified
leads,
which means I make no money,
which means I can't afford to make
my offer better,
which means I continue to not get
any qualified leads.
So you need to switch this to my
offer is great,
which leads to me getting so many
calls booked.
I actually get to talk to some
qualified business owners now.
I signed some of those business
owners.
It's easy to get them results.
I get case studies and they're
happy.
And they're also really easy to
work with.
So they send me referrals, right?
So you understand,
like let's just simulate out some
refund math here.
If you did have a guarantee,
let's say you're selling a $3,000
a month service
and the average client stays for
four months.
It means you have an LTV of
$12,000.
Those five clients you signed in
the offer without a guarantee,
zero refunds, right?
Now, let's say your gross margin
to fulfill the clients is 70%.
So you make $60,000 times 0.7, so
$42,000.
So non-guarantee offer because of
return rate,
this is how much MRR is going to
be modeled out to, right?
So you'd probably hit like $12,000
a month in like month four.
It's actually not.
It's like, I see a lot of people
who fuck this up.
It's actually like a lot of them
just stay at fucking zero and
don't sign any, right?
But what I'm trying to do is just
compare this to like,
if you're doing the guarantee
offer,
even if you were assuming a
fucking 6% refund rate,
which is like super fucking high,
like you're never going to have a
fucking 6% refund rate.
Like you'll have like 2% or 1%,
right?
It's $357,000 compared to $71,000.
It's so much more fucking money
you make with the guarantee.
And this is after, this is after
the refund, after refunds.
You know what I'm saying?
Like it's like, it's so much more.
Like you really just don't
comprehend.
The degree to which having the
guarantee outperforms a
non-guarantee
is fucking completely absurd.
Like it's so much more.
So, okay.
Problems with the assumptions
you'll make around implementing
this
is that you'll say something like,
this extremely low impact
guarantee will work to drive the
sales up.
is if I guarantee they get leads,
it's going to also work as well as
guaranteeing clients or sales
calls.
So I'm going to guarantee the
leads.
No, right?
So I had this conversation with a
client of mine,
Josh Steinberg.
So I was asking him, how's his
business been?
Yo, Dan, it's been good.
Hovering around $8,000 to $10,000
a month right now.
Clients are super sticky for the
most part,
which has been great for cash
flow.
Just been a little slow on booking
calls recently.
I think at my current revenue case
level,
probably need to focus on ramming
a ton of Dream 100.
I have 50 email inboxes, so I'll
book it in $8,000 to $10,000 a
month.
I was booking $8,000 to $10,000 a
month from cold email on YouTube
before.
And it's just been bone dry
recently.
So I started asking, like, what
other companies are there, right?
So, well, I know one company doing
$270,000 a month,
and another doing $100,000 a month
in the med spa space,
which is the space he's into.
And then I said, can you figure
out their offer and their lead
gen?
He goes, absolutely.
The $270,000 a month company's
offer is close 5 to 10 new body
contour clients
every seven days, or you don't
pay, right?
So his competitor is guaranteeing
clients, right?
So I told him, I was like, okay,
so you got to copy that offer.
Like, you're at $10,000 a month.
They're at $270,000 a month.
You have to fucking copy that
offer, right?
That's clearly the one that's
working wildly better.
And then I followed up with him a
while back, a while later.
He said, sign three clients since
implementing your advice, by the
way, right?
Like, fucking, that's it.
Like, that's all it takes, right?
So market demand resulted in the
old guarantee no longer having
impact.
Josh is guaranteeing appointments.
His competitor is guaranteeing
clients.
Josh makes $10,000 a month.
The competitor makes $270,000 a
month, which is fucking 27 times
more than Josh.
So from guaranteeing appointments
to clients results in 27 times
more sales volume.
Like, dude, that's how important
this shit is.
So I have another client who runs
a cold email lead gen agency.
Standard offer and, like, pricing
structure over there is a monthly
tech fee plus cost per
lead or cost per call.
This guy's revenue was stagnating
around, like, $15,000 a month
doing that.
I said, fuck it, bro.
Just switch to guaranteeing
clients.
He rocketed it up to $45,000 per
month in a couple months.
So he was able to do this because
he put a call closing rate
stipulation in his contract.
So his clients have to close at
least 15% of the calls.
And if they don't, they're not
eligible for a refund.
Like, that's how that works,
right?
You screw this up by not having a
fundamental understanding of
exponential math.
Like, 27 times is fucking
astounding.
Like, you have to do this, right?
So, like, ListKit has a money-back
guarantee.
ClientSuch has a money-back
We hit $1.2 million a month.
Why do you think we can get away
with this?
Why do you think you can get away
with doing this and, like, even I
can't, right?
So, contract stipulation.
When using guarantees, you have to
protect yourself against
unjustified refund requests.
So stipulations are things that
the client is required to do in
order to be eligible for the
guarantee.
There are two types of
stipulations.
There's a state stipulation.
It means that the client must
already have something in order to
qualify for the guarantee.
And then there's an action
stipulation, which means the
client must do specific or
multiple action items in order to
qualify for the guarantee.
So, the stipulation should be
generated based off of what is
required to get the result anyway.
You get what I'm saying?
So, like, as an example, let's say
there's a content agency and the
offer is 10 clients signed per
month or your money-back.
Okay, so what are the
stipulations?
The client must stay subscribed to
the service for a minimum of three
months before he paid.
Non-payment that results in
cancellation of the service before
three months have elaps
automatically makes the money-back
guarantee null and void.
Client must film 90 video scripts
provided by the company and allow
us to post all of them in TikTok,
Instagram, LinkedIn, YouTube, and
X.
If the client's accounts are
banned or suspended, the client is
no longer eligible for the
guarantee.
Client must respond to at least
50% of the comments made in the
videos.
Clients must have a guarantee on
their own offer that they're
promoting in order to be eligible
for the money-back guarantee.
You don't have to put this.
You can remove this.
Client must maintain a minimum
sales call closing rate of 15% and
give company access to their call
scheduling software in order to
audit the amount of calls booked.
If a client fails to close at
least 15% of the total calls
booked within the 90-day period,
the money-back guarantee is null
and void.
This is to deter against the
situation where the project is
considered a failure when, in
fact, it is a sales problem which
the company has no control over.
If a client wishes to request a
refund, then it must provide all
recordings of all sales calls
booked inside the scheduling
platform in order for the company
to audit whether the clients were
closed or not.
Right?
This is what's required to get the
client a result fucking anyway.
Right?
So it's not unreasonable.
It's quite literally just what has
to be done for the result to
happen fucking anyway.
Like, how else are 10 clients
signed per month with content
beyond fucking getting the videos
filmed and actually posting the
videos?
Like, and closing the calls?
Like, how else does that happen?
In the end, it's that it fucking
doesn't.
Right?
So you can set, you can do other
shit.
Like, you can set the contract up
in a fashion where, like, if they
do request a refund, it's given on
a tiered system.
So, like, if they only close 25
clients total, then they get a
16.7% refund or some bullshit.
Right?
Like that.
So, like, adding stipulations
typically does not decrease
conversion rates if all the
stipulations are reasonable.
So that is why, so, because the
stipulations need to be what's
required in the first place.
Right?
You should expect to not exceed,
like, a 2% to 3% refund rate.
If your client communication is on
point and you give status updates,
like, three more times a week,
your refund rate would typically
be less than 1%.
So this is just my own experience,
given that every single offer I've
ever got past 100K a month has had
a money-back guarantee.
I've actually never gotten an
offer past 100K a month without a
money-back guarantee.
So watching over, like, 1,000
agency owners come through Client
Ascension, it typically works out
that the people with a guarantee
grow somewhere in the range of,
like, three to four times faster.
Right?
So to visualize this, this is the
difference between, like, starting
at 5K a month or reaching 50K a
month at two years versus reaching
50K a month at six months.
Right?
So let's talk about some quick
value propositions and
differentiation.
So, like, a value proposition
means it's, like, you're quite
literally proposing something of
high value and a differentiation
is you quite literally actually
are different.
Right?
So if you're ever confused, if
you're actually differentiated,
literally just ask, am I actually
different than all the people
selling what I'm selling?
So here's some examples of
differentiation.
One is using AI.
So, like, making hundreds of ad
creators extremely fast or
creating content without the
client needing to sit down and
film themselves.
Right?
One-time payment, like, setup
offers are literally saying
one-time payment increases cause
book 2 to 3x.
However, this requires you having
sales skills and back-end
infrastructure to properly work an
upsell process to get them onto
recurring services.
Three is results-based pricing.
Again, going back to guarantees,
you only pay when it works.
Performance-based is money-back
guarantee.
You get results or you don't pay.
Like, just fucking do this.
Just, this is your differentiator.
Daniel, how can I be different?
The answer is this.
Have a guarantee.
Like, that's it.
So, what else makes you different?
It's that the client has to do
less work than they would
ordinarily with their competitors.
So, that means you, the logistical
intensity thing, like, you capture
more logistical intensity.
Client will get results faster at
working with you and the client
incurs less risk working with you.
So, that's a guarantee, right?
Quick prompt here, if you want to
throw this into AI to help you
differentiate it.
You could take all of the text in
this document, throw it into AI,
or you can just talk to Daniel AI
to talk about this.
You get what I'm saying?
All right, that's it for the next
video.
Let's move on to the next one.
Peace.