All right, so let's talk about
demand capture versus demand
generation.
So you've got a spectrum here.
So every offer sits on a sliding
scale of demand capture versus
demand generation.
A demand capture offer is an offer
that somebody will only buy if
they're already looking for it.
And a demand generation offer is
an offer where you can create
demand for.
So like, let me give you some
examples of demand capture offers.
Website, you need to rent a bounce
house for a party.
In what situation are you, is
someone going to convince you to
rent a bounce house when you don't
have an immediate need for a
bounce house already?
Like, you can't like convince me
to fucking get a bounce house if I
wasn't already having a children's
house party.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, so IT services, you're a
real estate agent and want people
to get their home, to list their
homes with you.
Like, you're not going to convince
people to sell their fucking house
if they weren't already going to
sell their house.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, insurance, like you don't
buy car insurance unless you have,
unless you just purchased a car
and you're in immediate need for a
new car.
Recruiting, automations, build
outs, bookkeeping, inventory
management, code base, security
auditing, task management, data
entry, data extraction, credit
card process.
You get what I'm saying?
I'm just spewing random shit here
so you get the premise of like,
you can't just fucking create the
demand for it, right?
So examples of demand generation
offers where you can just spawn
demand for it is getting people
more leads to Facebook ads,
building funnels, converting more
free trial users with email
marketing, helping people get
leads and clients from Twitter,
LinkedIn automated outreach to
generate leads to clients, UGC ad
creatives, influencer marketing,
content production offers,
cold calling lead gen, cold email
lead gen, Facebook, Google, TikTok
ads, webinars.
You get what I'm saying?
So you can like convince people to
do this, right?
People only buy this if they have
already personally decided that's
what they're going to purchase.
So your offer falls on a scale.
It can exist at any point.
It can be like, it can be in the
center, right?
So like, I've seen some random
shit like this before.
Discord community creation.
I hope you grow your business by
creating a Discord community for
you.
That would be like somewhere in
the center.
Conversion rate optimization is
somewhere in the center.
Organic YouTube management would
be somewhere in the center.
But if you like, if you took this
and turn it into like a content
production offer with like a
quantifiable claim,
you're shifting it towards the
left to, I'm sorry, you're
shifting it towards the right in
demand generation.
SEO, public relations, ad writing,
and designing video production
without it being among a content
production system
intended to produce new clients.
So like when you start slapping
like quantifiable results and
guarantees, you're shifting it
towards demand gen.
So now let's talk about this real
quick is mechanisms.
So a demand capture mechanism is
something like Google ads.
So if you know, like Google search
ads, right?
So you get in front of people
actively searching for it.
It means you're quite literally
capturing demand.
Where it's like, if I have an AC
unit and my AC unit goes out and I
search up like HVAC repair Tampa,
what does that mean?
It means that like the people
buying Google ads on that search
term are capturing demand as it
flows, right?
Demand generation mechanism is
something like cold email or
Facebook ads or cold email or DMs.
You're interrupting somebody.
So you're quite literally trying
to generate the demand, not
capture it.
So if I get a cold email or a cold
DM from somebody, I've been
interrupted.
If I get a Facebook ad, I've been
Now, Facebook ads are a little
different nowadays because of
what's called advantage plus
targeting or just like AI
targeting where you can have a
demand capture offer and use
Facebook ads.
And it just like reads the ad and
finds people who are interested in
that right now.
It just does that automatically
now.
So it's kind of a demand
generation mechanism, kind of a
demand capture mechanism.
Facebook ads could be used as
demand gen or demand capture
because of their AI targeting.
No, don't get confused when I put
something like Google ads in here
as a mechanism when I already put
it as an offer.
So like when that was listed as an
offer, I mean Google ads as a
service.
In this mechanism section, it's
categorized as meaning like a
means of acquiring traffic.
So now sometimes you're selling a
demand capture offer with the
demand generation mechanism,
right?
So if you want to sell a demand
capture offer like web design with
the demand generation mechanism
like cold email, you can only do
three things.
And these three things only,
there's no other way to do this,
right?
So extremely high volume and in an
attempt to just by happenstance
find somebody who already needs
one, right?
So if you're trying to sell web
design with cold email, but web
design is a demand capture offer.
So you would just need to send a
fuck ton of cold email, like a
fucking insane amount of it,
right?
So second is positioning your
offer to be unique and therefore
more on the demand generation
side.
So it's just morphing it to demand
gen side.
Outreaching to prospects based off
demand capture indicators.
So like an example would be you're
trying to sell IT services and
you're somehow able to scrape data
that somebody just had a security
breach.
That would be like an indicator.
You get what I'm saying?
So if you're trying to sell a
demand capture offer using a
demand generation mechanism,
what you need to be doing in your
marketing is selling first the
concept of why they would want
your offer in the first place.
So like for instance, every
business owner on the planet wants
more clients.
If you're selling lead generation
services, you don't need to make
an ad that's trying to convince
somebody why they need to get more
clients for their business.
Like it's fucking
self-explanatory.
They already want that, right?
So if you're selling life
insurance and you're trying to do
it with a mechanism like content
marketing or Facebook ads,
which are demand generation
mechanisms,
you have to start by convincing
people why they need life
insurance in the first place
before selling them your life
insurance.
You get what I'm saying?
So this is often why you hear
about the difference between like
first mover's advantage and second
mover's advantage.
The first mover must convince the
market why they should buy into
the idea and why they should use
their solution for it.
The second mover only has to
convince the market their solution
is better than the first mover.
You get what I'm saying?
So earlier, like one of these
things that said extremely high
volume, what does that mean,
right?
So if you're selling a demand
generation offer with a
quantifiable promise and guarantee
in social work,
you can typically get around one
client for your 1,000 prospects
contacted via cold email.
Well, maybe like depending on some
other things like 1,000 to 3,000,
right?
Maybe like in probably every 50 or
so Dream 100 outreaches if your
scripts are good.
So if you're doing Dream 100 and
you do like 50 of them, it's like
there's a considerable bottom of a
follow-up.
It's not like, oh, I hit number
50.
Number 50 converts.
Like it's like some random person
within the 50 who you have
executed sufficient follow-up over
sufficient quantities of time will
probably convert, right?
So now if you're selling demand
capture, the numbers will hang
somewhere between like one client
for every 5,000 to 20,000
prospects.
So like here's just an example of
this.
So like Cameron Tarbell, yeah, it
looks like every 20K prospects was
a new client more or less.
I haven't ran cold in like four
months.
So I have deals closing from the
campaigns I ran from November to
March.
So like Cameron sells web design,
right?
So for every 20,000 people that
Cameron contacts is able to sell,
just a standard website, right?
Aaron Price or demand capture, and
I've been incorrectly stressing
we're not hitting one client per
1,000 emails.
We're around one client per 5,000
contacts, 20,000 emails, which
makes sense.
Just need to send more emails,
right?
So how do you position your demand
capture offer to be unique?
So this is point number two.
How do you position your demand
capture offer to be unique and
morphed towards demand generation?
Let's go to two examples.
So like web design as a for
instance.
One is like, I'll make you a
website.
All right, cool.
Well, something better would be,
I'll make you a website with
internal fraud monitoring software
to stop chargebacks.
That's one.
Even better would be, I guarantee
you'll increase your website
conversion rates or you get a
refund.
That's even better.
Best would be like, I'll build you
a VSL opt-in funnel, run cold
traffic to it, and guarantee you
may get your next $30,000 in sales
or you don't pay.
Right?
So this is like, this turns into a
completely different offer.
You're not a web design business
anymore.
You're a funnels business, right?
So recruiting is, I can recruit
software engineers for your
business.
Better would be, I can recruit a
software engineer for your
business who can create an AI
model based on your data, meaning
you can create internal tech that
can automate customer service.
Best would be, I'll create an AI
model based on all your customer
data that automates your entire
customer service division.
So it turns into, it's an entirely
different product.
It's not even recruiting anymore.
You get what I'm saying?
This would just work better on
cold traffic.
This would work better on cold
traffic.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, you have the ability to just
turn your offer into something
that is designed for cold traffic.
You don't have a business unless
you're able to sell to cold
traffic, right?
It's almost like being a guy and
like having the ability to just
become six foot four, right?
It's completely fucking retarded
for you to just, and like, I'm not
six foot four, right?
Like, I'm fucking five foot eight,
right?
There's, there's, it's completely
fucking retarded to like have this
ability to just morph your offer
into something that is better for
cold traffic.
And then actively choosing to not
do it.
It's just, it's just an advantage.
Like, yeah, you can get by without
doing it, but you're not getting
profoundly fucking rich.
It's just like completely fucking
stupid to not do that.
You get like, like, why are you
actively choosing to make things
more difficult for yourself?
It's kind of like, it's kind of
like where it's like, you always
want to use what you have, right?
So I'll give you, for instance,
like, um, there's this one
interview with Donald Trump where
it's like, oh yeah, my dad gave me
a small loan of a million dollars.
And like people started clowning
on him for like, oh, a small loan
for a million dollars.
You know what I mean?
Like, yeah, like I get it where
it's like, yeah, Donald, you had
this fucking privilege and you
could just do that.
Like people can't just do that.
Like, yes, which is true, but he
would be a complete fucking retard
to not take the small loan of a
million dollars.
Like, why would he not do that?
Like, use all of the advantages
that you could possibly muster for
yourself, regardless of how unfair
that is to the general public.
Who gives a fuck about the general
public?
They didn't go fuck themselves.
Like, you're the main character of
your business.
Like, use every advantage you can
possibly muster for yourself to
make your life as easy as possible
and increase your probability of
success to the highest degree
conceivable.
You get what I'm saying?
So, all right, cool.
So, next, that third point is how
do you outreach prospects based
off of demand capture indicators?
One would be like they're hiring
for a specific role, in which case
it might look something like an
outreach message.
It might say something like, I saw
you were hiring for customer
service roles.
Given that, I can create an AI
model based on every conversation
your CS team has ever had and
automate your entire customer
service division.
One, for instance, might be they
just installed a specific
technology.
So, you could say something like,
saw you guys were using Webflow
for your site.
Have you considered building out
VSL webinar funnels instead?
And then you could interject that
same claim right here, that same,
that thing.
Now, you might have another one
where it's like, if they're
following or interacting with
another company or person or
social media.
So, you might have something like,
saw you were interacting with
Hermosi's post, went to your
profile and figured this would
make sense.
I can build you a full VSL opt-in
funnel and guarantee you make your
next $30,000 in sales or you pay
nothing.
So, let's talk about traffic
generation versus traffic
conversion offers.
This kind of applies to marketing
offers only.
So, traffic generation is like
getting them traffic and traffic
conversion is converting the
traffic.
So, it's traffic generation.
It's everything to do with getting
you traffic in the first place.
So, that's like Facebook ads,
Google ads, YouTube ads, TikTok
ads, cold email, content
marketing, direct message
outreach.
So, just ads, content, outreach.
Those are the only ways to
generate traffic.
That's it.
There's no other way to do this,
like in existence at all.
It's ads, outreach, and content.
That's it.
Nothing else exists.
Traffic conversion is everything
to do with converting the traffic
you or your client already has.
So, that's like email marketing.
Like, okay, you got someone to opt
in to a VSL, book a call funnel
with your Facebook ads.
So, now you need to use email
marketing to convert a higher
percentage of them, right?
It's sales.
It's the actual sales call.
It's follow-up, conversion rate
optimization on pages,
copywriting, sales pages.
So, like I'm color coding this.
So, like traffic generation is
orange.
So, in order for your YouTube ads
to work, it's orange.
It's traffic generation.
In order for your traffic
generation slash YouTube ads to
work, you need your email
marketing, sales, follow-up, CRO,
and copywriting also to be, right?
So, your YouTube ads traffic won't
convert unless you have sufficient
email marketing, sales, follow-up,
CRO, and copywriting.
Okay.
But in order for your email
marketing to work, which is
traffic conversion, in order for
this to work, to be able to do
anything,
you need to be getting traffic
from your Facebook ads, Google
ads, YouTube ads, TikTok ads, cold
emails, and content marketing.
Like, your email marketing can't
do anything if there isn't traffic
being generated.
You get what I'm saying?
So, in order to take somebody from
zero to paying money, they must be
generated via traffic generation
and converted via traffic
conversion.
So, it's typically easier to sell
a traffic generation offer than a
traffic conversion offer because
most people don't have traffic.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, I've kind of said this and
you'll hear me say it a lot, but
most people running businesses are
fucking retarded.
Like, they don't have traffic,
right?
So, however, traffic conversion
offers typically see clients that
stay longer and have a higher LTV.
Why?
Because the only people who buy it
are people who have their shit
together.
Right?
And there exist less people on the
planet who have their shit
together versus who don't.
So, like, in exchange for it being
more, in exchange for it, for
this, in exchange for the client
LTV being higher on traffic
conversion offers, they're more
likely, they're more difficult to
come across because less of them
exist and they require a higher
level of authority to sell as the
nature of what you need access to
is more intimate.
Right?
So, like, it's not new money.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, I've talked about this
before, but, like, selling
somebody email list management is
not new money.
It's more difficult to sell the
cold traffic.
Selling someone's CRO is not new
money.
Selling them just copywriting
without, like, the creation of a
funnel, it's not new money.
Right?
You really, really, really want to
sell new money.
Like, it's fucking severely
advantageous for you to sell new
money.
And then traffic conversion
offers, where it's all this shit,
is better, it's substantially
better to sell as an upsell to
people who have already paid you
something else.
You get what I'm saying?
So, for offers within the
marketing arena, this is just kind
of, like, visualizing this.
So, like, a demand capture offer
that's traffic conversion would
be, like, websites, or I'll write
your emails.
A demand generation offer that's
traffic generation would be ads as
a service, cold email as a
service, cold DMs as a service,
cold calling as a service.
Demand generation offer that's
traffic conversion would be, like,
converting pretrial users with
email marketing.
When a market becomes sufficiently
sophisticated, so, like, means,
like, you get hella competitors or
saturated,
all demand generation offers
become demand capture offers.
So, like, for instance, I'll make
you a website.
In 2001, it was a demand
generation offer.
Now, it's a demand capture offer.
So, it's called offer decay.
It's what I call it.
It's, like, just as you get more
competitors and time elapses, all
demand generation offers become
demand capture offers, right?
So, this is effectively a battle
that will exist throughout your
entire life.
At any point in time, your offer
is always decaying towards demand
generation.
This is exactly what will happen
to AI automation, for instance.
So, like, right now, AI automation
is technically a demand generation
offer.
But as time goes on, it will be a
demand capture offer that is
profoundly fucking difficult to
sell.
So, this is why, this is literally
why I instruct everybody running
that business to instead sell
specific builds, not AI
automation, right?
Because specific builds can be
pitched with specific results,
therefore morphing it into a
demand generation offer, right?
So, like, expansion of service.
Say you're selling a traffic
generation offer.
So, it's, most people are only
selling one half of this equation.
I, like, and again, I'm
reiterating this is, like, kind of
for marketing offers only.
Demand, they're selling demand
generation, or they're selling,
I'm sorry, they're selling traffic
generation, or they're selling
traffic conversion, right?
So, most of the time, it's because
it's easier to get started,
simpler to sell, it's easier to
get results quickly, requires less
expertise in your own.
However, when selling one of the
equation, you're creating your own
customers to sell the other half
of the equation.
So, in this slinging deals video,
what I talked about was an example
of selling a webinar build-out
offer,
and how a component of that offer
could be email marketing, right?
Now, so, like, you sold the client
a webinar funnel build with ads.
So, that would be, like, a demand
generation slash traffic
generation offer.
And then, a recurring upsell to
that offer is email list
management.
So, email list management is a
traffic conversion offer.
It's not new money, so it's
difficult to sell to cold traffic,
but it's difficult to,
but it's not difficult to sell to
warm traffic, because people have
already paid you.
So, like, again, I kind of walked
you through, like, if you sold
them a webinar funnel,
but now there's, like, a shit ton
of people who registered to the
webinar.
You got, like, fucking 500 people
who registered the webinar, and
now, like, you got those emails,
and you could sell email list
management where you send sales
emails three to five times per
week for them.
And now, let's say the client
wants to run another webinar back,
and now it goes from the next
webinar,
it gets a fucking another 500
people.
Now, there's 1,000 people on the
list, and the list keeps growing.
You know what I'm saying?
And then, maybe, you upsell the
client of ESL opt-in funnel as
well.
So, like, now that opt-in funnel
is also building emails.
So, now the email list is, like,
progressively fucking more
massive,
and, like, it makes progressively
more sense for them to purchase
email marketing as a recurring
service from you.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, it's, like, you're
expanding.
It's expansion of service.
It's just, it's called expansion
revenue.
You get what I'm saying?
All right, cool.
That's it for this video.
Peace.