All right, so welcome to the
offers section of this training.
So we're going to talk about how
to transform your service into
marketable products.
This is insanely wildly important,
right?
Because this is actually, so many
people don't even know what an
offer is.
Like I want to visualize this for
you.
You're going to meet a lot of
clients in your life, right?
And they're going to have no
fucking clue what an offer even
is.
They'll have somehow stumbled
their way into like whatever the
fuck business that they're running
in.
They'll have never even heard of
any of the concepts inside of
here.
So what I'm about to teach you is
what works.
This is how you sell to cold
traffic.
Now, you're going to talk to a lot
of clients in your life who have
never sold to cold traffic in
their life.
And they sell whatever the fuck
bullshit, random, warm traffic
shit that would never work to cold
traffic at all ever, right?
Your job in this section is to
one, not only fully and
fundamentally understand what I'm
telling you
and really ingrain what the fuck
I'm saying into your mind,
but also to ingrain it so deeply
within you that you are able to
articulate the lessons to your
clients
so that they get results, right?
It's a requirement to everything
I'm telling you here to do with
your offer is a requirement also
for your clients to get results
with their offer and for them to
make money, right?
So all of the arguments that I'm
going to walk through here, that
all the shit that I'm going to
explain to you,
you have to be able to do this to
them as well, right?
So this is one of the most
important sections of this entire
training.
So this entire office training is
teaching the fundamentals of
packaging and creating offers.
Here are some components of this
you need to understand.
Your headline of what your offer
is, the deliverables of your
product, the pricing of your
product,
and the terms and contract terms
of the agreement with your client.
This whole training here is
focusing exclusively on this.
Yes, this entire offers training.
I'm saying all this shit just to
get you to understand everything
around this one point.
That's how fucking important it
is.
All of the other components will
be established for each specific
business model in their respective
section of this course.
So the word offer can sometimes be
confusing.
So if somebody asks you, for
instance, what's your offer?
What they're actually asking you
is what is the thing you're
selling?
What's your service?
But what I mean by offer in this
training is what is the
proposition you're proposing to
cold traffic
and how are you expressing it in a
headline or single sentence?
That's what I mean by offer.
So the literal entire training
here is specifically to teach you
how to express an offer in a
single sentence
because this single sentence is
what determines whether you'll get
any leads to get on the phone with
you
and show any interest at all.
Okay, I'm going to say this
throughout this training a lot.
You're going to see it a lot.
The entire purpose of an offer is
to get somebody on the phone.
It's not what you're selling them.
It's just what are you saying to
get people to show any interest at
all
and actually be willing to get on
the phone.
What your offer is is not what you
actually end up selling them.
Right?
Okay, so how to structure cold
traffic offers to actually get
sold.
What you're about to learn in this
section is integrity of selling to
cold traffic.
If your business is not growing as
fast as you want it to right now,
it's because of your offer.
You are not selling something that
people want to buy, specifically
cold traffic.
Making a good offer is like
becoming the hot girl on
Instagram.
Have you ever wondered what it
would be like to be the hottest
girl in the world?
Everybody wants to buy everything
for you, fly you out here, do this
for you, give you special
treatment.
Right?
Because that's what it's like for
them.
If you're a 10 out of 10 straight
model, this entire section is
about turning your offer into the
hot girl.
Right?
We want to make the market
ravagingly obsessed with you.
So what is a cold traffic
front-end offer?
It's an offer or packaging of your
service or product that is
specifically designed to work on
cold traffic.
What is cold traffic?
Cold traffic are people who don't
know you.
They've never heard of you.
They've never seen you before.
They've no semblance of your
existence whatsoever in any
capacity.
They don't know you.
Warm traffic are people who do
know you.
They're aware of you.
The only way you're going to get
rich is if you could sell to cold
traffic.
Why?
Because you're probably not
fucking famous.
Right?
You don't have 50,000 followers on
Instagram or 10,000 YouTube.
So you don't have that.
You have to sell to strangers.
And if you're going to sell to
strangers, you need to have your
offer be constructed as a
front-end cold traffic offer.
Dope.
All right.
Cool.
So let's keep going.
So imagine two complete strangers
approach you.
Right?
They're not people you know.
You've never heard of either of
them.
Right?
They give each of you a different
proposition.
I'll set up an automated content
system for your business and
guarantee you sign your next three
clients in six weeks.
Okay.
The other guy says, I'll help you
set up a content system for your
business.
Which of these people are you
going to entertain?
You personally.
Right?
Fucking clearly, it's number one.
It's number one.
It just fucking is.
All right.
So I have to actually add this
manually.
But story of the guy trying to
sell data analysis.
Okay, I had this guy one time and
he was on one of my coaching calls
and he was coming to me.
It was like some fucking, he
wanted to make some fucking, it
was like some data analysis offer
where it's like, I'll help you
make good decisions with your
data.
I'm like, bro, what the fuck does
that mean?
What does it mean I'll make good
decisions with my data?
That's not a cold traffic offer.
What is the result I will get from
the offer?
Okay.
So what's the differentiation
between these two?
This one has a result.
Sign your next clients in three
weeks.
I'm going to guarantee it.
With a guarantee, you sign your
next clients, your next three
clients in six weeks.
What is that?
That is a, there's a quantifiable
promise with a guarantee.
What does this not have?
A quantifiable promise with a
guarantee.
Okay.
So what can we deduce?
That a cold traffic front end
offer is an offer with a
quantifiable promise with a
guarantee or some kind of risk
reversal.
That's what a front end cold
traffic offer is.
So I was talking to this guy and
he's trying to fucking come up
with this like random data
analysis offer.
I'm like, bro, this doesn't make
any sense.
You can't, this is not a front end
cold traffic offer.
And he goes, but this is because
he was working a job at an agency
and he's like, but I do this at my
current agency.
People buy this.
And I'm like, no, they fucking
don't.
I was like, stop lying to me.
Stop bullshitting me right now.
I was like, stop.
I was like, I was like, I was
like, cut the bullshit.
I was like, what's your agency?
Who do you work for?
And we look, we on this fucking
call, we look it up and what they
were selling clients were webinar
funnel buildouts.
That was their front end cold
traffic offer.
It was to build a webinar funnel
for a client and they had a
quantifiable promise with a
guarantee on it.
That's how they were selling to
cold traffic.
Hey, we'll build you a webinar
funnel and guarantee it makes you
$30,000 in profit in the next 30
days.
Some bullshit like that, right?
He was just on the data team where
he did data analysis to help the
webinars convert better over time
so they can make optimizations
around the webinar.
I was like, bro, like fucking,
like stop bullshitting me.
This is not a front end cold
traffic offer.
You know, it's not a front end
cold traffic offer.
Like, you know, your company is
selling fucking webinar buildouts
with a quantifiable promise with a
guarantee on it.
Stop fucking with me, right?
Okay.
Why did I give you this aside?
Because you need to understand
when you're fucking trying to
delude yourself.
Like, it's, this is just the
reality.
This is the fact.
Like, I wish it didn't have to be
like this either.
But if you are not famous and you
don't have a shit ton of
authority, you don't have a shit
ton of referrals, whatever, you
have to sell a quantifiable
promise with a guarantee, right?
Now, the rest of this training is
going to be me teaching you how to
do this.
Without getting fucked.
That's what, that's literally what
this entire training is.
All of it, right?
So does this sound familiar?
Right now, you're watching people
who run the same business as you
or a similar business and they
make a hundred, ten times to a
hundred times more money than you.
But they're doing the exact same
thing as you.
They're doing outreach.
They're making content.
They're running ads, whatever.
You're also doing that.
But somehow, they're making shit
tons more money than you.
And you spent however many
hundreds of hours trying to figure
out how this is.
And if you're like me, this either
made you angry, upset, confused.
And when you keep thinking about
it, it makes you demotivated and
want to quit, right?
How is it functionally possible
that these people selling
literally the exact same thing as
you or making so much more money
than you while doing the exact
same things you're doing?
Why is it that it works for them
and it doesn't work for you,
right?
This is the problem we're going to
solve in this little class today.
So I want to make it so that you
never feel that feeling again.
I want you to know why this is
happening and how to solve it once
and forever, right?
That's what this is.
So understanding why people buy
anything ever.
There are only three reasons
anybody buys anything.
Health, right?
Buying this will make me feel
better, look better, live longer,
and avoid physical pain, right?
Love, buying this will result in
me getting more dates,
getting married and procreating
and having sex, right?
Well, buying this will deliver a
return on investment that results
in me being richer than I was
before.
All right, cool.
But because we're all B2B and all
of our clients are prospects,
we're going to fall under the
wealth category.
What can we deduce from that?
That the only reason a client will
buy from you is if they believe
that your service will make them
richer.
So in order to make a good offer,
we must do the following.
Promise a specific result.
Then make the prospect confident
we can actually get them the
result.
That's fucking it.
You're selling more money.
There is all of you.
Every single, there's not a single
exception of anyone, anybody
watching this video right now.
Your prospect has to make more
money via buying your shit.
That's it.
By buying your thing, they have to
make more money.
So what does that mean?
What if you're sitting here
thinking, you're like, wow, my
thing like kind of doesn't make
them more money.
Like there's got to be a way that
I can like kind of scoot this
around.
No, stop fucking selling that and
sell something that makes them
more money.
It has to make them more money,
right?
And if we went a layer deeper than
this, you could split that in
half.
Where there's like things that
like help people make more money.
You can like help them make more
money from a system they already
have versus like building them
something new.
Building a new system for them
does even fucking better, right?
Okay, you have to understand this.
Nobody ever is buying your shit if
it is not extremely abundantly
clear that it is going to make
them more money.
Nothing, nothing for no other
reason fucking at all ever.
Are they purchasing from you?
This needs to be so, you need to
fucking, I don't care what it
takes for you to understand this.
We got to write it down 30 times.
Make them more money.
Make them, they don't buy unless
it is to make more fucking money.
Why did you buy this from me?
You fucking paid whatever amount
of money to have this product
right now.
Why?
Because you want to make money.
No fucking shit, right?
You got to stop beating around the
bush because,
Because everybody beats around the
bush.
You know what I'm saying?
Like all the people,
All the other people running
businesses and they might say
like,
Oh, our company is this big.
But they're all, they're actually
fucking poor, right?
All of the people actually making
real fucking big boy bucks, like
real fucking shit tons of money
are not scooting around the fact
that what we're fucking selling is
getting the clients rich.
That's fucking it.
We're getting them rich.
And if you scoot around this fact,
they're not going to fucking buy
from you.
They're going to buy from somebody
who is telling them that they can
get rich.
You understand, right?
You have to, you have to get this
because if you don't, you're
fucked.
You're so fucked, right?
All right, cool.
Value propositions, clear outcomes
to clear niches.
So the most successful business
owners we work with 100% of the
time have a clear type of person
that they work with.
They promise a clear outcome and
they achieve that outcome in a
clear way, right?
So the offer is what the prospect
gets.
The service is what you do, right?
You got to, you got to understand
the differentiation between these
two.
What the prospect gets is the
result, right?
The result, the offer is a result.
The service is how you get the
result, right?
The officer, the offer focuses on
the result the client gets as a
result of the deliverable.
The service is the deliverable
itself, right?
1 million views guaranteed is an
offer.
Video editing is a service.
We help you sign 5 to 10 clients
per month with cold email as an
offer.
Done for you, cold email as a
service.
Done for you, ads and funnels,
sign 10 to 20 clients per month
where you don't pay as an offer.
Done for you, ads and funnels as a
service.
You do not get cold traffic to buy
services.
They will never give you money.
Cold traffic doesn't buy services.
They buy offers.
Does that make sense?
So this is how you can deduce the
differentiation between when
someone is selling to cold traffic
versus warm traffic.
If you're only selling to warm
traffic, you're never really going
to get rich.
You have to be able to sell to
cold traffic.
You know it's cold traffic offer
when it's promising a result.
When someone says something like,
oh yeah, we do Google ads or like
we're professional Google ads or
whatever the fuck.
What does that mean?
What it means is that they're
selling a warm traffic offer.
They're not selling to cold
traffic.
Cold traffic is not buying for
them.
You can, I bet a million fucking
dollars cold traffic is not buying
for them if there's not a result,
right?
So you must be absolutely clear
about the result the prospect
gets.
So the next section out of the
first one, you'll understand how
to actually design an offer.
So everything in this section is
about fundamentals.
So what not to do.
Okay.
We do email marketing and Google
ads and Facebook ads and LinkedIn
ads and website building.
Okay.
Successful business owners,
today's market are not glorified
e-commerce.
They're not a glorified e-commerce
store where you put a bunch of
services in a fucking shopping
cart and you take a pic.
That's not how this shit works,
right?
This only works if it's warm
traffic or it's referrals, right?
If you're doing this right now,
you are probably thinking if I add
a bunch of services into the
packages, it will make it more
valuable.
I'm value stacking.
This will get people, more people
to buy.
No, wrong.
Doesn't work like that.
The primary result, there's a
primary result of misunderstanding
that it is more difficult to get
somebody on the phone than it is
to get them to give you thousands
of dollars once they're already on
the phone.
Okay, the entire reason of why
we're building an offer that
promises a result is because we
need to get people on the phone.
You can sell whatever you want on
the phone.
It doesn't matter.
You can sell them whatever the
fuck.
It can be completely different
than what you've got them on the
phone with.
It's just that when you're
positioning yourself as a service
instead of an offer, nobody gets
on the phone with you.
It's very important you understand
this, right?
I don't want this to be one of
those points where you kind of
just blow it off to the side.
You have to understand it is more
difficult to get somebody on the
phone than it is to get them to
buy, right?
In everything we're doing around
positioning your offer
specifically to get them on the
phone, it's 80% of the battle.
It's literally fucking all of the
battle, right?
Adding a bunch of services to your
packages will not get you more
calls booked.
Promising results will get you
more calls booked.
You have to promise results in the
offer, right?
So let's talk about unique selling
propositions.
A unique selling proposition is
the one clear specific reason why
customers should buy from you
instead of competitors.
So it answers the question, why
should I choose you?
It's not flaw for generic claims
like, we care or we're the best,
right?
It's bullshit.
That shit doesn't work.
A real USP, unique selling
proposition, highlights what makes
your offer different and better in
a way that your market actually
values.
Okay, so strong USPs do one or the
following.
They promise a specific result,
right?
Lose 30 pounds in 10 days, lose 10
pounds in 30 days worth free.
Guaranteed reduced risk, no
results, no pay, or highlight a
feature nobody else has.
The only CRM that writes your
emails for you or whatever the
fuck.
I just made that up.
Bad USPs.
We care about our customers.
We're professionals, great
customer service, high quality
work, right?
It's all fucking bullshit, right?
It's, it's, it's, it's, but it
just, this doesn't work.
This is like, this is like random
marketing lingo that like a, like
a, like a, like a, like a woman
college professor taught, but
she's like never actually sold
anything in her life.
It's just, it's just fucking
nonsense.
It's fake.
It's just fake bullshit, right?
It just is, right?
If, if your competitor can say the
same thing, it's not a USP, right?
This, this is the kind of shit
that people say who've never made
any money in their life, right?
It's just fucking nonsense.
So, so examples.
You tell me if each of these is an
offer or if it's a service and
whether it has a unique selling
proposition.
So we help real estate agents with
Google ads, not an offer, right?
We help, we help real estate
agents get more leads with Google
ads, not an offer.
We help real estate agents get 30
leads per month with Google ads.
Okay.
Now we're getting there.
It's an offer, but it's not really
a good offer.
Oh, 30 leads.
Now, now, okay.
So this is a, this is like a, like
a bypass point where it's easy for
you to kind of just like gloss
over this and like take what I
just said as definitive.
It's like 30 leads per month.
Oh, that, that's a thing that
someone said before, or like,
that's a thing that people sell.
Well, okay.
You, you, you, you, you gotta
fucking like think like many
orders of magnitude.
You gotta, you gotta think like
down multiple surface levels of
what the fuck is occurring in
front of your eyes, right?
Right.
So like, so, okay.
If there's a real estate agent,
what, what, what is a real estate
agent considering a lead, right?
Because here's what you
understand, like you understand
your market, because if you say
the word lead to a real estate
agent, what does that mean to
them?
They're thinking of like shared
lead platforms of like, oh, like a
Zillow lead where you gotta like
pay $50 for a lead, but they sold
the lead to like seven other
people.
And it's like, not actually like
someone who was individually
contacted, who was actually
interested in how.
So like, what, what does that
mean?
It means that if you fucking just
started saying this, like 30 leads
per month, and then it didn't
work, you'd be like, oh, Daniel
promising leads doesn't work.
It's like, no, because they
fucking think leads are that, and
you aren't, you aren't delineating
what exactly the thing is.
Like I was just in a conversation
with someone yesterday, he was
talking about how he's going to
sell a lead gen to financial
advisors.
And he was saying like, uh, he was
saying, I'm going to guarantee
them 10 qualified meetings a
month.
I was like, have you ever spoken
to a financial advisor in your
life?
And he's like, oh yeah, like my
parents do all that.
Like that's what kind of why, kind
of why I chose it.
So I'm kind of like familiar with
that industry.
I was like, okay, do financial
advisors use this specific
phrasing qualified meetings?
And he goes, no, he says, it's
more, it's more so like meetings
with high net, high net worth
individuals.
I'm like, okay, so then make it 10
meetings with high net worth
individuals guaranteed per month,
or you don't pay.
He's like, oh, okay.
You get what I'm saying?
But there's the problem, the
problem with me trying to like
teach a program like this is that
there are fucking thousands of
little nuance,
little bullshits like that, that
it's completely impossible for me
to accurately explain every single
one of them.
You get what I'm saying?
Like there's no fucking way that I
could give you every single little
intricate tiny step of exactly
what the fuck you personally are.
It's completely fucking
impossible.
There's so much different shit
that could occur.
So this is what I'm saying like in
the intro video when I was talking
about like use your brain.
Like you have to use your fucking
brain and like take nuance with
everything that, everything that
you're told.
Like you, you, you got to have
some like independent nicking
ability here, right?
So, okay.
So next one, we help real estate
agents get five new listings per
month with Google ads.
Okay.
So that's an offer, right?
We, we, we guarantee real estate
agents five new listings per month
with Google ads or you don't pay
us, right?
Okay, cool.
Yeah, that's much better that like
this.
Like you tell me what you're a
real estate agent.
We hope you, we hope real estate
agents get five new listings per
month with Google ads.
Okay, someone said that to you and
they said, we guarantee you five
new listings per month with Google
ads or you don't pay me.
Which fucking one are you buying?
It's, it's obviously this one.
Like don't, don't be a fucking
dickhead about it.
Like when you're making your
offer, like fucking clearly, this
is the one getting purchased,
right?
We do email marketing for
e-commerce brands.
That's just a service.
That's shitty.
That's not selling to cold
traffic.
We write and design marketing
emails for e-commerce brands.
Not, not, not going to do well.
We, we, we write, we write and
design emails for e-commerce
brands that drive more sales
without ad spend.
Eh, you're getting there.
But, probably won't work.
We write and design emails for
e-commerce brands that drive
$50,000 per month with initial
sales without any ad spend.
Meh, it's getting there.
Got some specificity there, but
there's no guarantee on it.
We write and design emails for
e-commerce brands to guarantee you
make $50,000 in additional sales
without any ad spend.
Oh yeah, that would work.
We implement AI individualized
email marketing for e-commerce
brands.
All emails are automatically
triggered based off of user
behavior.
We guarantee you a minimum of
$50,000 in new sales after
implementing it or you pay
nothing.
This would fucking annihilate.
Like, you, like, like, like, like
really.
Like, just think of the difference
between this and this.
It's like the essence of this.
It's, there's like life and aura
to this one.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, you gotta do this when you
have the offer.
Like, stop being such a fucking
pussy about it.
Like, make it like this.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, like, you, you, you, like, I
can't even explain what this, what
this is.
But you know what it is.
Like, it fucking, it, it is a
fucking oomph behind it.
You, you know what I'm saying?
Like, do that.
All right, cool.
We send cold emails for agency
owners.
Ooh, cool.
That's, no one's buying that shit.
We, we, we send 30,000 automated
cold emails per month for agency
owners.
Cool.
You're getting a little more
specific.
We manually send personalized cold
emails to 100 prospects per month
for your agency.
All right, so now this is a,
that's, this, this is a unique
selling proposition.
We send personalized cold emails
to 100 prospects per month for
your agency.
So that, that's like actual
differentiation.
No one does that.
We manually send, right?
You get what I'm saying?
We do performance-based lead gen
for agency owners where, where you
only pay if we get
results.
Good risk reversal there.
We do call you our agency owners
and guarantee you save five
clients every month.
See what I mean?
You got to fuck with it, right?
All right, cool.
Transfer of logistical intensity.
So let's imagine two situations.
Situation one, you are a roofing
marketing company, right?
We're just saying that you run ads
for roofers or whatever the fuck,
right?
But you do not qualify the leads
for your clients, right?
So you got to imagine, so like
what's happening?
Here's like, they're probably
running like meta ads.
If you're a homeowner and you need
new roof, yada, yada, yada, where
the fuck?
Now, they're probably using lead
forms and like people submit their
information and then you
have to call them to actually like
schedule a quote.
Like, hey, are you actually like a
serious person about getting a
roof?
Because like, again, most people
are completely fucking retarded.
So like what happens is like you
get a bunch of people submitting
leads and they're like,
I didn't, I didn't submit your, my
info.
And like, they're, they're
literally so fucking retarded that
they don't remember submitting
their info like eight minutes ago.
That, that, that's the vast
majority of the population, right?
So, so it's, it's sifting through
that.
That's what I mean by that.
Is that qualifying the leads, like
sifting through the retards, like
a little, like a, like a little
sand sifter.
You're like, you're doing that.
Now, situation two, you're a
roofing marketing company and you
do qualify the leads for the
client, right?
Okay.
Why is this important?
Because nobody else does that.
Nobody else wants to do that,
right?
So because you do that, now you
are differentiated.
Does that make sense?
Because it's, it's a piece of
logistical intensity that must be
executed in, in, in the service,
in, in, on the pathway to the
client getting results.
So there's like, you, you, you
make the ads, you set up the ad
account, you, you, you run the
ads, ads start running, right?
And now you got to do the retard
sifting, right?
The, the, the lead qualifying,
right?
Nobody wants to do that.
Most roofing marketing companies
are not going to do that.
They're going to make the fucking
roofer do it.
So what does that mean?
Now the roofer needs to either do
it himself or he needs to fucking
hire someone to do it.
And that's logistically intense to
do that.
It's, it's, it's logistical
intensity, right?
So now you're like, no, I do that.
Now he's like, oh fuck.
Wow.
This is way better of a product
because all the other fuckers make
me do that, but you do it for him.
Right?
So now, okay.
So when people, you got, what do
you have to understand?
When people buy services, what
they are purchasing is a transfer
of logistical intensity.
The more logistical intensity you
can allocate to yourself, the more
somebody will pay.
Right?
And I touch, I touch again in this
on the, in the video about how to
sell high ticket offers,
but you might, you might become
confused about what you can add to
your offer that will make
it more valuable.
And the answer is always just the
thing that nobody else wants to
do.
It's the thing that's a fucking
pain in the ass, right?
Both you and your competitors and
your clients don't want to do it.
Okay.
What does that mean though?
If nobody wants to do it, it means
that by definition, the supply is
low.
And when the supply is low, you
could charge higher prices.
You could charge a fuck ton of
money to do it.
And ideally, like maybe you could
automate a shit ton of it with AI.
You know what I'm saying?
So having a competitive advantage
simply means being able to do the
things that require logistical
intensity.
Does that make sense?
So like, for instance, Amazon
Prime guarantees you one day
shipping because they own the
planes,
the trucks, and the shipping
network.
That offer is impossible to have
unless they own the entire
shipping infrastructure with
distribution centers across every
state.
They overtook the single most
logistically intense process that
exists on the planet and
therefore were able to become a
multiple trillion dollar company,
right?
Okay.
So what you got to do is just
define the intensity points,
right?
So take a random fucking random
service, right?
Like your client wants to land
three to four podcast episodes a
week to promote their new book.
Obstacles.
How to find the right podcast, how
to reach out to those podcasts,
what to say in the podcast,
so you just create your offer
based off of how much logistical
intensity you capture.
Okay.
So what are all the intensity
points involved with getting a
client on a podcast?
So you've got to create the list
of the relevant podcasts in the
first place.
You've got to write the email
scripts to get them on the
podcast.
You've got to find the email
addresses of the podcast host, and
then you've got to send
the emails, and you've got to
schedule the podcast, and then
you've got to make the talking
points of the podcast.
So the more of these intensity
points you capture on your end,
the more you're able to charge.
Does that make sense?
Right?
So like building value is not
about stacking different services
on top of one another.
It's about capturing more
logistical intensity of a singular
service, right?
It's better to offer lead
generation all the way down to
getting the meeting scheduled on
their calendar versus offering
five different ways of generating
leads, right?
But the client has to do all the
response handling, the booking,
the lead qualification.
You know what I'm saying?
That's what differentiation is.
That's what it is, right?
That's what you got to understand.
All right.
Let's move on to the next video,
and I hope you enjoyed this one.
Peace.