Okay, so this is how to sell
high-ticket offers.
So this is a comprehensive guide
to collecting substantially more
money per client project
that you engage yourselves in.
And I see too profuse of a problem
with many of you guys with either
of these two problems.
So you're either failing to close
any deals and absolutely fucking
your sales calls up
because you lack the skills or
confidence to properly convey
value and explain in clear
English exactly what you do in a
logical argument as to why the
person should buy it.
Right?
Second, you're stuck in the
constant cycle of never being able
to raise your prices
because every time you do so, you
face progressively more resistance
and you don't know exactly what to
do to begin stepping up the ladder
of how much you charge.
Right?
So the objective of this video is
the following.
We're going to explain why people
pay more money.
We're going to explain exactly how
you're failing to raise your
prices.
I'm going to call you out on the
bullshit objections you'll give me
across the screen
before they even come up and then
the assets and exact things you
need to do right now
and begin implementing immediately
because it's extremely important
that you don't get stuck
in the cycle of charging no money
at all.
You have to be able to sign higher
ticket deals.
You have to do this because when
you properly convey the value of
what you're selling,
you're able to both increase the
close rates and charge more money
at the same time.
And if you fail to do this, then
you get the opposite of what I
just said.
Your close rate goes down and you
charge less money.
You know what I'm saying?
That's not what you want because
then you get stuck in this death
spiral cascade
and never being able to get rich.
So literally the purpose of what
you're building this business for
is to get rich.
You know what I'm saying?
So to get rich, you have to charge
more money.
You have to get people to pay you
more.
In order to get people to pay you
more, they got to understand the
value of what you're selling.
So that's what this video is
about.
So why do people pay more?
So the problem people have with
selling offers is that when
they're talking to potential
clients,
they're not making the clients
understand the actual impact of
how much of a financial impact
your service will make.
Right?
If a client fails to understand
how much of a financial impact you
make,
they're not going to be interested
in buying.
It's really that simple.
The only thing they're concerned
with is how much money will this
make them.
Right?
Everything else is bullshit.
95% of people will not explicitly
state this because they're too
much of a pussy to talk about it
or they're too scared to talk
about money.
99% of your competitors will not
talk about this because they're
too much of a pussy to talk about
money.
But every single person running
any agency or B2B offer that is
successful in any capacity
whatsoever is not afraid to talk
about money.
This is not something that you
need to stop concealing this.
The reason why people buy is
because that they believe that the
thing that they're going to
purchase from you is going to make
them more money.
That's it.
That's the only reason.
There's zero other reason why
anyone buys ever.
Right?
You can't not talk about this.
So here's the problem.
There's two ways to make a client
understand how impactful the
financial result is.
So by using ROI calculators and by
using client case studies.
Right?
There's also explaining the
logistical intensity.
Three ways.
So another important note is that
you as a beginner will say some
stupid shit.
Like I can't promise clients
results because I'm scared and I
don't think I can get them the
result.
Okay.
Well, here's my argument to you.
You better learn to stop that line
of thinking right now because if
you're going to pull your punches
talking about results and not lead
people to logical conclusions that
they're going to make money with
you, then you aren't going to sign
fucking anybody.
You know what I'm saying?
And you'll come to me and you'll
say, Daniel, I can't close any
deals.
And I'll say it's because none of
the people you're talking to are
confident in your ability to make
the money because you're too much
of a pussy to talk about actual
numbers and project results.
You have to stop doing this.
You have to talk about results.
You have to talk about the money.
Right?
So I cannot tell you how many
times I see this shit over and
over again.
I have coached thousands of
people, literally thousands of
you.
Do you want to know what stops
them from signing any deals or
making any substantially more
quantities of money?
It's they're not talking about
results and breaking down the math
with clients.
They're being vague about what
could potentially happen in the
engagement.
They say shit like, I can't
promise results because I'm not
confident I can get those crazy
results.
Okay.
Be poor then.
Right?
So this is like saying, I can't go
up and talk to that pretty girl.
How do you know?
You've never tried it.
I can't lose 30 pounds and build
muscle.
How do you know?
You've never tried it.
I can't start that business and be
successful.
How do you know?
You've never tried it.
I can't get these crazy results
for clients.
How do you know?
You've never tried it.
You don't know.
You just made this shit up.
You literally, you literally sat
here and you said, I can't get the
client's results.
You fucking made it up.
You literally made the shit up,
right?
You, you, with like zero evidence.
In fact, you, you just, you just
determined, you sat here and
determined.
That you're going to steer your
life towards the maximum
probability of pessimism.
Not even give yourself a chance to
get rich.
That's literally what you did.
Right?
So I want to make this abundantly
clear.
If you ever come to me with some
bullshit talking about how you're
not going to talk
about numbers or use ROI
calculators to project results or
use your client case studies when
you have them, or that you're not
comfortable talking about results
or promised results.
I'm going to tell you this
straight to your face in front of
everybody that your probability
of being a failure is extremely
high.
I get this a lot.
A lot of people say, they come to
me and they say, Daniel, you, you
like what they'll
join client ascension or Olympia.
They'll join anything.
They'll say, Daniel, what, what,
what, what are the traits of the
people who actually get
results in here?
Cause I want, I want to be one of
the best students.
Like what, like, what do I have to
do to be one of those guys?
The answer is a rational
confidence and confidence in
yourself and just thinking, yes, I
can do
it.
I can get the client's results.
I can do it.
That's, that's the separator.
People who don't do that.
Those are the people who don't get
results.
You know what I'm saying?
It's so important that you follow
this.
So of course, not all of your
clients are going to get results.
Are you going to do your very best
job to get them results?
Of course you are.
Right.
But unless you talk about results
and lead them to believe that
they'll get results, there
is zero situation where you close
anybody.
You, you will, you'll never even
get the opportunity.
So let me give you two examples of
clients I'm coaching.
So client number one, one of
these, one of these guys runs,
runs a lead gen agency for
PR firms, right?
So previously he wasn't able to
close many deals and the deals he
did close were very low
ticket.
So not getting paid much money at
all.
So now after coaching him for
three months, cause he's listening
to what I'm saying, he's
closing four to eight K and one
deals for Cody, my lead gen.
What changed how, how, how exactly
did this app?
So we made sales assets for him to
share on calls that show two
things.
So first is that there's an ROI
calculator that breaks down the
math of the possible results.
So it takes into account the email
sent reply rate, call booking
rates, and therefore how
many calls we booked based on
volume call closing rate that the
client says that they can achieve
how much the client charges, the
profit margin the client operates
at, and then takes into
account how much he charges and
calculates a projected amount of
profit over the next year
for the client.
If those numbers hold true.
So the numbers here regularly
point to an ROI of 10 to 50 X, not
three X high, absolutely
extreme returns because we're
taking into account LTV of the
client.
We're, we're, we're doing this
with optimism.
The client says that they can
close this amount.
Okay, Mr.
Client, you said that you can
close this amount and you charge
this much.
And this is your problem.
This is how much you would make.
We did the math and this is how
much I would charge to, to do that
on a monthly basis.
So let's calculate this, this ROI
that you're going to get.
It's basic, simple math, right?
So what does this do?
If the return only calculates for
the client and it shows them
making like a three to five
X return, it's muscle.
It's much less exciting, right?
So he's talking to proper large
companies, right?
So like 10 calls booked or three
client sign is not an impressive
or eye turning result.
Why would anybody give a fuck
about signing three clients or
booking 10 calls?
I signed 10 to 15 clients per day,
book 40 to 50 calls per day.
Why the fuck would I even bother
having a conversation with you for
three clients signed or 10 calls
booked?
When you say these numbers, it
only gets low level clients who
think that's a lot excited.
You need to quote higher numbers,
even if you've never done it
before.
Why?
Because you need to shoot so much
higher.
You need to not be a fucking pussy
about it, right?
So nobody who is capable of
spending any significant amount of
money is going to be willing to do
so unless you are saying numbers
that are within paying attention
distance to them.
You're selling to people who are
millionaires saying pussy little
results gets you ignored.
If you tell me, Daniel, I'll
guarantee you signed three
clients.
It doesn't matter.
That's it's not even worth the
time it takes to talk to you.
And I'm the kind of person you
want to, I can afford to pay
$10,000 per month.
I can do that.
Get what I'm saying?
So second, his client case
studies, which breaks down how
much money was made, money, right?
So of course you don't start out
with this, right?
But two things are important here.
You need to be completely fucking
obsessed with collecting these
things, right?
So specifically showing how much
money was made.
It has to show the money.
You need to know contract signed,
cash collected, et cetera.
If you can't get that, get the
next best quantifiable result.
If you can't get any quantifiable
results, it's useless.
I don't care if you have to pay
for it, right?
So I had, I had another guy tell
me he's been gradually upping his
prices.
So once he reached 4k a month, he
started facing some resistance and
I asked him to show
me a sales deck and the results he
had on the sales deck showed one
person who got actual
dollar results.
So the rest of them were pipeline
generated.
You got to stop with this
bullshit, right?
So nobody gives a fuck about
pipeline generated.
Everybody knows this means you
made no money.
That's what it means.
If you have one case study that
shows dollars and then all, and
you got like fucking six of
them that say pipeline generated,
pipeline generated, pipeline
generated.
That's code word for I didn't make
them any fucking money.
Everyone knows this.
It's not just this.
You're like, you're not tricking
people.
They're not retarded, right?
So they, they know that's what it
fucking means.
It's better to not even put the
shit there.
If you're going to say pipeline
generated, how much money cash
collected was fucking made.
Well, did you make money or did
you not make money?
You need to be abundantly fucking
clear about this.
And if you can't get that, it's
completely useless case study.
And if you can't, you need to at
least get qualified sales calls
booked.
And even that is not magnificent
enough, right?
You see, nobody gives a shit about
pipeline, right?
So stop making excuses and do
whatever you need to do to get it,
right?
Because you really do not seem to
understand how exactly important
getting the quantifiable
dollar value case studies are,
right?
Completely leave the pipeline
bullshit out and just say
qualified sales calls booked if
you
can't get that.
So not opportunities or whatever
other dumb shit or leads.
It's calls booked or cash
collected.
That's it.
Anything else literally is
useless.
It actually counter sells.
If you, if you scoot around it,
like, Oh, I did this person got
this many opportunities.
It's like, it's a, it's a dumb as
fuck way to try to explain that
you're getting, everybody
knows it means that you didn't
make money.
So I used to give away consulting
calls, lead lists and PayPal's to
get some of my first students
to post quantifiable results on
Twitter so that I could retweet
the tweets that they posted.
It had to show how many clients I
signed and how much money they
made.
If it didn't include that, it was
fucking worth it.
It was literally completely worth
it.
So here's our quantifiable case
studies and results posted.
So, uh, let's get, for instance,
this is a playlist of let's get
here's people make it.
It's money.
It's showing how much money was
made.
You know what I'm saying?
Client ascension, this is my
YouTube.
What's here?
It's fucking money.
30K a month, 50K a month, 100K a
month, 500K a month, 200K a month,
132K a month, 150K a
month, 70K a month, 32K a month,
45K a month, 23K a month, 80K a
month, 40K a month, 44K a
month.
Some of these could be refreshed
because these people have made
like a substantially shit ton
more money.
Um, the same Andre has the same
thing.
It's money.
It's the only thing that matters.
It's fucking money.
Everything else is bullshit.
So, so, so what did I have this
guy do?
So we had to take all of his case
studies, throw them in a document
with, with screenshots,
proving the results, and then
share the document on sales calls
and, and a VSL and in pre-call
assets.
Oh, you got a call booked, but
send this fucking document with
all the case studies on it.
Like, here's some results that we
got from clients.
So of course you can close people
without this, but not if you're
quoting tiny little pussy
results, right?
So here's all the objections.
This, this client gave me over a
time working together.
He goes, all my clients have a
hard time closing the deal.
So I feel like a fraud when
they're not getting deals closed.
Okay.
So here's what I explained to him.
The vast majority of clients, 90%
plus in any industry or niche, no
matter what they or
you are selling are going to have
a hard time closing deals.
Every client you ever sell for the
rest of your life will be terrible
at sales.
All of them, the rest of your
life, no matter what you sell to
every single one of your clients,
it can be dog shit at sales.
Why?
Because every human on the planet
running any business has both a
dog shit offer and
is dog shit at sales.
10% of clients make 90% of
results.
This is not a unique issue to you.
This is everybody in existence.
All of your clients will be shitty
at sales.
You have to coach them through it,
right?
You got to explain to them.
So because only your clients that
understand that the reason they
make any sales is because
they are showing their prospects
quotes of potential results that
are within paying attention
distance.
So this is always going to be the
case.
Not every client is going to get
results.
That's why it's your job to help
them get better if they're having
this issue.
The same lessons I'm giving you
now, you have to give to them.
You have to be their coach, even
if you're not selling a coaching
program.
So what happens when you coach
them through this concept that
they need to be talking about
results?
And the only way they'll ever make
any sales is if the prospects
believe they'll get a return
on an investment, you're going to
get pushback from the clients in
exactly the same fashion
that you're going to fucking say
this bullshit pushback to me, but
your clients aren't going
to get results without doing this.
And you're not going to get
results without doing this.
Fucking nobody's getting results
without doing this.
You know what I'm saying?
So you have a responsibility to
implement this yourself and quote
big paying attention distance
numbers, and then also get your
clients to do the same thing so
they can get results,
right?
You know, what if they still
refuse to do this?
Then it's their fault.
They're not getting results.
And you tell them this to their
face if they're going to complain
about it, right?
You made it abundantly clear to
them when you started the
engagement.
Like, yeah, if you want to sign
these bigger ticket deals, you're
going to need these case
studies.
You're going to need this ROI
calculator.
You're going to start quoting like
substantially bigger results,
right?
Just as exactly as I'm doing to
you right now.
If you made the same mistake, if
you come to me and talk about how
you can't close any
deals and I investigate the
situation to see that you're
talking about little tiny baby
pussy results, and you start
giving me these same objections
I've talked about in this
video, guess what I'm going to
say?
I want to say that you're not
listening to me and your failure
is your own fault because
you're not doing what I'm telling
you to do.
No, Daniel, I'm not getting
results.
It's a gap because you're not
fucking listening to me.
That's the same frame you need to
have with your clients if they
complain about getting
results.
Get what I'm saying?
This works.
If you don't do it, then you will
not succeed.
I'm telling you this and I'm so
adamant about this and I'm so
fucking flared up about this
because it's the truth.
This is how this shit is, right?
So the same applies to your
clients.
You must take this same exact
frame I have with you and say the
same thing to them if it
happens, right?
So here's another objection he's
giving me.
My clients are saying the leads
are unqualified.
Okay, the client is saying this
because the leads didn't close,
right?
And they go, the leads are saying
to them, I have to think about it,
right?
All my leads are coming to me and
they're saying that the leads I
give them or all my clients
are coming to me and they're
saying that the leads I give them
are saying I have to think
about it.
So they're saying that the leads
aren't qualified.
Okay, why do their leads have to
think about it?
Because the offer isn't enticing
enough.
The quoted results are not there.
They have to think about what they
have to think about is because the
value proposition
or quoted results is so
insignificantly small that they
don't give a fuck about it at all.
Right?
If this client is on the phone
trying to charge $5,000 or $10,000
and there's no talk about
financial return or payback
periods, of course they need to
think about it.
Because what they're thinking
about is what the possible
financial return and payback
period
is because fucking you didn't talk
about it.
That's what they're thinking
about.
So now the client is going to go
make some shit up by themselves
because you didn't talk
about it and they're going to be
pessimistic and then they're going
to come to the conclusion
that this is a waste of time and
money because the return isn't
there.
And why did they conclude that the
return isn't there?
Because you didn't guide their
thinking to what the possible
return could fucking be.
So they're automatically going to
default to the most pessimistic
option because everybody
in the world is a big fat fucking
pussy.
That's why.
So you need to guide these people.
You need to move them to the
understanding.
Working with you is going to
generate this return because this
is how the numbers work out.
They work like this, this, this,
this, this, this, this, this.
If you let the client do that shit
by themselves, it's always going
to be pessimistic and they're
going to go think about it, but
they're going to think about some
fucking bullshit that
isn't true.
You need to guide their thinking.
You can't let them just do this by
themselves, right?
So you know what would have saved
this?
If you used an ROI calculator and
quoted the results yourself and
you quoted big results,
right?
So I had to give the same exact
talk to my students.
I just give the same exact talk to
my students that he needs to give
these same lessons to
his clients and that this is going
to persist forever.
You're never going to escape this
with clients.
This is always how it's going to
be for the rest of your life.
Everybody's going to be like this.
This is not something that's
unique to you.
It's always going to be like this.
So unless you take the lessons I'm
teaching you right now, not only
are you going to suffer
from these problems in your own
business, you're also going to
suffer in the form that any
clients
who do manage to sign are going to
bitch and complain about it.
So about if you can't make them
understand how reality works, this
is how reality works.
You know what I'm saying?
Okay, cool.
So client number two, this guy in
my initial conversations with him
was also running a lead
gen agency.
So the business was going fine.
His problem upon me investigating
was actually a mindset issue.
So he was scared of getting client
results.
So he regularly signs clients,
sends like a thousand cold emails
per day, gets deals closed,
but was operating under the same
mental blocker that wouldn't allow
him to scale past that.
So what was that mental blocker?
It's he was scared of signing more
clients because that means having
to deliver for more clients
and having to deliver for more
clients means more possibility
that some clients don't get
results
and get mad at him, right?
Okay.
Well, yes, he might have a
justification for why he's scared
of this.
It might be happening to him right
now.
A majority of his clients might
not be getting results, but do you
want to know why his clients
might not be getting results?
Because he was quoting low as fuck
results, complete pussy numbers.
It wasn't doing enough volume for
his clients to get results in the
first place.
I'm talking 5,000 emails per month
total.
Why, what, why was he only doing
this much?
Why was he only sending 5,000
emails per month for his clients?
Right?
So, because, because, like, what
do you think would happen to this
client if he sends 50,000
emails per month per client?
Well, yeah, the results of, say
he's got 10 clients and he's
sending 5,000 emails per month
for each client.
And now instead of 5,000 a month,
he starts sending 50,000 per
month.
What do you think would happen?
The results would be 10 times
better.
Do you think his clients would be
happier with 10 times more
results?
Of course they would.
But then he says, but then he says
to me, but that would cost more
money to do.
It would cost more money to send
50,000 emails instead of 5,000.
No fucking shit.
Charge the client more money to
compensate for the extra amount of
money it takes to fucking
send 10 times more results.
Right?
So, this solves two things at the
same time.
It allows you to quote higher
results in your ROI calculator
because the input is 10 times
larger and it increases the
probability of clients getting
results because also your input is
10 times higher.
Right?
So, now you get to make more money
and at the same time get better
results because you
started quoting higher results.
Right?
So, this is the problem when
you're okay with little pussy
numbers because you don't want
to say a big number to the client.
Because you charge so little, you
can't do what is required to get
them really good results.
And if you can't do what is
required to get them really good
results, you don't get good
results for them.
And that is when your clients get
mad or get frustrated or like
fucking ask for their money
back because you didn't fucking
produce shit for them because you
didn't charge them enough
money to warrant getting them
results in the first place.
That's what happens when you
charge so little money.
You fucking can't get them
results.
It's completely impossible.
You know what I'm saying?
So, your projected results you're
giving are too small.
Right?
The amount of money, this is the
problem when you're okay with
pussy numbers.
Everything gets worse.
Right?
So, this is all fear-based.
You need to stop being fearful.
So, like, here's an ROI
calculator.
Right?
So, this is an example of an ROI
calculator at Liskit for cold
email.
And you can make this shit
yourself.
Right?
You can do it in Bolt.
Maybe we'll make a tutorial on how
to do it.
But you can do it in Google
Sheets.
It's just breaking down the simple
math of this.
And I'll be honest with you.
I don't want to be like a dickhead
saying this.
But if you can't logically
conclude the components that are
involved in getting results,
for somebody, like, you're kind of
fucking retarded.
Like, this is not some, like,
wildly complex thing to create in
Google Sheets.
It's literally just like, you know
how to do math.
Right?
Like, you took eighth grade
algebra.
It's not hard.
Right?
So, let's say we're on the gold
plan over here.
We get the average reply rate,
which is 1.5%.
And then we have these things
called offer variables.
Right?
So, there's case studies, social
presence, specific measurable
claim, and a guarantee.
The more of these offer variables
you have, the better the response
rates.
I'm sorry.
The better the conversion rates.
Right?
So, if you have three offer
variables, it goes up.
If you have four offer variables,
it goes up.
Let's say somebody has three.
Right?
So, they have case studies, social
presence, and a specific
measurable return.
Right?
So, they got three offer
variables.
They're on the gold plan.
Say their call booking percent is
20%.
20% of their positive responses
book a call.
Their close rate on the calls is
20%.
Their average client LTV is
15,000.
What does this mean?
He said they're going to have five
meetings a month.
They're going to close one deal a
month.
Their customer acquisition cost is
going to be $1,800.
And they're going to get a 13.9x
return.
Okay.
So, what if we sent 210,000 emails
instead?
Like, oh, magically, you're making
fucking $90,000 instead.
And your customer acquisition cost
is $1,000 to 15x ROI.
You're getting 32 meetings and
closing six deals instead of
fucking one.
Hey, do you want to close one deal
per month with my cold email
system?
What the fuck?
What do you fucking mean?
One deal.
Who gives a shit about one deal?
Do you want to fucking close six
deals and make $90,000 every month
with my cold email system?
Fuck yeah, I do.
Do you want 158 leads?
Yeah.
Do you want 30 sales calls?
Fuck yeah, I do.
Do you get what I'm saying?
Like, oh, let's double it again.
Like, fucking, let's send 500,000
cold emails a month.
Do you want to make 195 grand at
32x ROI?
This is the shit I'm talking
about.
Like, you need to project these,
you need to show these people, you
need to guide them, right?
And then you ask them, like,
what's your close rate?
How much are you making per
client?
You might have a client and their
LTV is like $25,000.
Now, now, now this gets completely
absurd.
They're going to get 25x.
Now, you might have a client who
always says, oh, the LTV is only
$4,000.
What's it?
Yeah, you're not going to make
much money with a $4,000 LTV.
That's when you would disqualify a
client.
You know what I'm saying?
Well, you need to sell more
expensive stuff.
And now the client's disqualified.
But you get somebody who has a
$15,000 LTV.
Yeah, they can make it 15x ROI.
Now, it's in paying attention
distance.
Now, people give a fuck.
Because you visually showed this
to them.
They don't know what the reply
rate is.
They don't know what these offer
variables are.
They don't know what a conversion,
what a good conversion rate is for
this offer.
They don't know what a good call
booking percent.
But if you don't tell them,
they're just going to lead to the
conclusion themselves
of the most pessimistic possible
situation.
You need to lead them to the
light.
You get what I'm saying?
So, you talk about transferring
logistical intensity.
Okay, so let's say you're on a
call with a client
and you've walked them through an
ROI projection of what's possible.
And now we want to talk about the
deliverables of what's included in
your offer.
So, why is this important?
Because if you fail to explain
everything that's included in
getting results,
then people don't believe that
it's possible, right?
They got to understand how
extensive this is.
So, you want to make what you do
seem as complicated as possible.
So, if you only show you're going
to do a small amount of things,
people cannot make the
justification that what you're
doing is actually capable
of getting the high-quoted results
you're giving them, right?
Again, people aren't fucking
retarded, right?
They're retarded and not retarded
at the same time.
So, however, if you show you're
going to do a ton of shit,
the justification of high-quoted
results begins to make more sense.
So, let's walk through an actual
sales deck.
So, like a sales deck is also just
a VSL deck.
When I film VSLs, I do it just as
a screen share over these decks.
So, I literally just film over it,
right?
And when I'm on calls, I use the
same exact deck.
It's the same thing.
You see what I mean?
So, this is one we made for a list
kit.
The VSL is over the stock.
And if I'm on a call selling this
offer,
I'm literally just screen sharing
this fucking thing that was
already on the VSL.
Why?
Because all the relevant
information is on the deck
already.
You know what I'm saying?
It's profoundly simple shit.
So, what am I doing here?
I'm saying, what you said,
$100,000 to $250,000 code units
per month.
So, it's like an offer and get
every single one in the main
inbox.
It's like a value proposition.
It's a good headline here.
And I'll just say, if you're...
So, what I'm immediately doing
here is saying it includes this.
It includes a dedicated separate
domain for your organization,
email inboxes, private
infrastructure, the automation
setting platform,
a CRM, and triple verified data.
So, I'm saying it includes all of
this stuff, right?
It's not just like the sending
where you need to get the inboxes
yourself,
or it's not just the lead.
It includes everything.
You get what I'm saying?
It's not what I go into.
Because I'm going to tell them the
expected results, and I give them
case studies.
Then I'm going to explain how the
coding system works.
Then I'm going to explain what is
included in the offer.
And then this specific offer, I
give pricing.
But you don't...
You have to...
You give price ranges, right?
So, what I'm doing here is I'm
trying to get them to understand
the gravity of how well this
works.
Because what I'm saying is, like,
if I'm going to be charging them
$3,000 to $10,000,
then they need to say...
They need to see that other people
make fucking substantially more
than $3,000 to $10,000.
So, this lady, fucking 20 mil,
$65,000 in one month, 16 deals in
a single month, 10 clients in
three weeks, 100 clients signed,
$40,000 in two weeks, 40 sales
calls, $97,500 made, 170 sales
calls, $20,000 in the first 30
days.
Okay, so here's...
And then I show examples of
campaigns we ran.
So, I'm like, 494,000 emails, 685
calls booked, 108,000 MRR.
Now, they're like, holy shit.
These are fucking substantial
results.
Then I start showing individual
campaigns.
This one campaign, 88 leads, 58,
63, 333.
Then I start...
Then I have this little section
that goes,
So, the average client under a
custom enterprise plan receives
this meeting book rate, books 33
calls, closes 22.8% as the LTV,
15,431, closes eight new deals a
month, and receives a 20.6X ROI
based on what they pay us.
And I say, that's the average
custom enterprise client.
And I show them the results.
And now, all these fucking numbers
have just been firehose spewed
into their fucking head.
And they're like, holy shit.
These people make a fuck ton of
money.
So, what did I just do here?
What's going through their head as
they're thinking this?
They're like, yo, I think I just
found something fucking crazy.
Now, they're like, holy shit.
It's appealing to their greed.
They're greedy now.
They're like, fuck, I need that.
I need to do that right now.
I need this before other people
find out about this.
That's what they're saying.
That's what extreme results do.
They get greedy as fuck.
They're like, I need that.
Right?
So, now, I just explain
graphically, visually how this
system works.
And then, I go through an argument
of why it needs to be set up like
this.
And I'm basically saying, if you
don't set up like this, the shit
gets burned.
You waste a ton of money.
None of your shit gets to the
inbox.
So, you end up losing thousands of
dollars.
And what's going to happen?
If you do it with someone else,
they're going to fuck it up.
Because they don't know this is
actually how you're supposed to do
that.
And I know this is the case
because here's our bounce rate.
And the average bounce rate is
like 4%.
And I'm just making an argument
here is why it needs to be like
this.
And why, if they don't do it
through us, it's going to be
fucked up.
Right?
So, now, here's what I'm doing.
What you get with this and how the
handoff works.
This is where I'm stacking the
logistical intensity.
Where I'm showing really just how
much shit is involved in this
offer.
It's like super fucking
complicated.
Right?
So, we set the domains up.
We create the sending inboxes.
We integrate those onto dedicated
IPs.
We set up SPF, DKM, and DMARC on
each of the domains.
We're going to connect those
sending accounts to the automated
sending tool.
We're going to warm it up for you.
We're going to give you the leads
for your campaign.
We're going to write your cold
email scripts.
We're going to load everything up.
Once you be ready, all you need to
do is hit the start button.
We're going to sign you a personal
cold email expert into your
account.
And you're going to have a central
inbox where all the replies and
leads land.
That's a ton of fucking shit that
we do over here.
Right?
And then, I just show them the
timeline of how this is going to
work.
Then, I go to the pricing.
I just give them a range.
It's going to be between $2,400
and $10,000 a month.
And then, over here, what I'm
doing is this is like a price
comparison comparing if they
did it themselves versus if they
did it through us.
And I show them that it's cheaper
doing it through us.
Now, this isn't always going to be
the case where it's like, you
know, if you're like
an agency service, it might not be
a price comparison because like
the alternative,
it might not be doing it
themselves.
You're going to say, so I'm going
to show you another example.
I go through, if they're on this
plan, this is the price comparison
if they did it themselves.
And then, common objection we get
is that they said, well, another
company said they can do
it cheaper.
How do you compare?
Then I say, okay, well, have you
made sure it includes all this?
It doesn't.
Then I break down the exact time
investment, how long it would take
if they did it themselves,
right?
Because that is their alternative
here.
And I answer some questions.
Okay, so this one's for Olympia.
And this is following the same
presence.
It's still a deck.
So it's like, okay, got a
headline.
What I'm doing here is, so this
wasn't a case.
This wasn't operating off of
client case studies here.
This was operating off of personal
results.
So I'm just showing proof of the
personal results over here.
I'm building some credibility for
myself.
This works for these people,
outline, right?
Show some more results.
I'm basically explaining, going
through my argument of this is how
it works and this is why it works.
You know what I'm saying?
So then I walk through like the
offer economics and how to do
that.
I just made this like little
Google sheet for them to go
through.
Then I just explained how the
process works and the components
of each process, right?
And both of these decks are going
to be in the description, by the
way.
So you'll be able to see it.
So I'm walking through each stuff
here.
And then what I'm doing is I'm
walking them through the
deliverables of what's included in
Olympia.
So it's offer creation, funnel
setup, ad scripts, VSL, GammaDoc,
video editing, initial ad campaign
launch,
emo sequences and tech sequences,
automations to build out, SDR, and
set of recruitment,
closed recruitment, fulfillment,
team recruitment, campaign
scaling, daily ads management,
and then I give them the price,
right?
And I say, what else is included?
One-on-one calls, I write your ad
scripts, weekly coaching calls,
four in-person events per year,
done for you, Fahoma team
recruiting, course videos, weekly
walkthrough of my ad accounts,
one-on-one review of all your
materials, unlimited texting with
me and all my co-founders, right?
So what I just do, I'm stacking
the logistical intensity.
I'm saying, I'm going to do this
for you, this, this, this, this,
this, this.
I'm explaining what is involved to
get a specific result, right?
So I'm showing what is involved,
getting a specific result, and
then I'm saying, I'm going to do
fucking all of it for you.
Done for you, done with you,
whatever.
So it's just showing, it's just
stacking all of the shit that is
required, and that's how you build
value.
Because you show, because now they
understand what actually is
involved in getting results,
right?
So if you just, if you didn't know
what the fuck you were talking
about, you wouldn't be able to
articulate and explain what
exactly is involved with all the
results.
But when you do, and then you also
say, and I do all this for you,
now, your logical mind, after
you've quoted fucking insane
results like this,
and like extremely high numbers,
you're like, okay, I understand
now how the quoted results could
be this high,
because there's so much shit that
goes into this, and you're going
to do all of it for me,
so I don't have to do any of it,
fucking yeah, now I understand,
right?
So what if you don't have case
studies to put inside a deck?
Okay, so first off, don't steal
case studies, but find results
from other companies that do the
exact same thing you do,
and explain that you're going to
copy the strategy for the client.
So obviously don't use misleading
language that would lead somebody
to believe you generated those
results.
The best policy is always honesty,
right?
So the premise you need to
understand is that you at least
need evidence that the concept of
what you're selling works.
If you're selling content, then
you need to find somebody whose
content strategy you're copying,
show the client the results this
strategy generated, and then
explain that you're going to do,
you're going to be doing exactly
the same strategy for them, right?
If you're selling a specific type
of funnel build out, then you need
to go find examples of funnels
that scale to a certain level,
explain that you funnel hacked the
entire thing, and that you're
going to replicate it for them,
and show numbers, right?
You need to sell the concept of
what you're doing to them.
You need to show big, dense, fat
numbers, even if they're not
generated by you.
You need to get people excited
about the opportunity, right?
So there's two sales that are
occurring.
It's the sale of the opportunity.
So like if you're selling cold
email, you have to sell the
concept of cold email, for
instance, right?
And then there's the sale of you
being the person to facilitate it.
So you have to sell the
opportunity, and you have to sell
you.
But if your argument on the first
point is sufficiently good enough,
it makes people forget about point
two.
But only if your argument and
evidence on point one is strong
enough to appeal to their greed.
You need to appeal to their greed.
If you're showing them people who
are making fucking astronomically
high, disgusting amounts of money,
it's appealing to their greed.
And now they're excited, and
they're like, fucking, yeah, just
do it for me.
Nobody is excited to hear that you
can book them 10 calls.
They're excited to see that this
guy over here made $1.7 million in
three months,
$1.7 million profit in three
months of this type of funnel,
and that you're going to copy the
entire thing for the client and
run up the same exact strategy
because you got a back-end look
into the operations or some shit,
right?
Which really means that you just
funnel hacked them, or you bought
consulting from them,
or did whatever the fuck.
You know what I'm saying?
So if I were to make an agency
right now,
it would be an advertising agency
where I charge,
if I were to make a new agency
right now,
it would be an advertising agency
where I charge $10,000 per month
plus 10% net rev share.
Why?
Because I've made a fucking shit
ton of money in advertising and
can actively show I booked
thousands
of calls, had over 930 clients
sign up through a funnel I made
with ads I wrote in emails I
created,
right?
And if I didn't have that, I'd
find somebody else who did and
explain what they did in extremely
explanative detail
going through every single aspect
of exactly what they did and then
explain that we're going to
exactly copy this funnel, right?
I'm not going to use this person
as a case study of me.
I'm going to use them as a case
study of the concept of the thing
I'm selling.
Do you know what I'm saying?
So I'm going to do, and I just
explained it, that I'm going to do
every single component of this
offer
and replicate it one by one,
exactly what this person did.
And I'd write out every single
deliverable that would be involved
with this exactly like it's listed
in the cold email setup talk or
the Olympia doc, right?
So something like this, let's take
this for instance.
Okay, deliverables, complete
technical build out of the funnel
in all pages, opt-in page, VSL
page,
thank you page, automations to
capture the emails, phone numbers,
applications, and calls booked,
all copywriting for all pages,
email flows, opt-in email flow,
application abandoned flow,
post-booking flow, ad scripts, 40
hooks, five bodies, 200 total ads,
VSL script,
ad and VSL video editing,
follow-up sales assets, ad account
and pixel setup,
full product launch strategy, all
social posts, Instagram stories,
three YouTube videos,
15 tweets, all broadcast emails.
Okay, so now that I've just listed
all this shit out, how much do you
think that is worth?
Just take a second and just think
of a number of how much do you
think all of this fucking shit is
worth?
What do you think the going rate
for a build-out of this is, of all
of this shit?
Okay, now let's look at another,
right?
I'll fully build your funnel for
you to launch a high-ticket offer
and guarantee you make at least
$50,000.
I'll build the entire funnel and
help you launch it A to Z.
Like, okay, so, so, so, and then
someone goes to this guy, they're
like, okay, well, what are the
deliverables involved?
It was, oh, well, I'll just build
the funnel.
Like, I'll make the pages and,
like, uh, and I'll do, I'll write
some emails and some ads.
And now they're like, and now
what, what is the client thinking
when you're not extremely fucking
explicit with what is involved?
They're thinking, well, well, what
if there's, like, the automation
stuff and, like, uh, well, I mean,
there's going to be filming and,
like, who's going to do the video
editing?
And, like, okay, well, I don't
know how to run ads myself or,
like, set up a pixel or, like,
like, well, what, what, like, what
if the calls aren't closing?
What's going to happen then?
Like, if they're, like, like, are
there things needed to close the
calls?
All this shit, they're thinking
it's all missing because you're
not being explanative in detail
about what the fuck is included.
So, how much do you, which of
these offers do you think is more
valuable?
This one with all this shit or
this one where you just say, where
you just say, I'll build the
entire funnel for you.
This is, like, a, this, this is,
like, a fucking $25,000 build-out.
Like, look at this, this is, you
could, you could sell this shit,
like, I could personally sell this
for probably 50 grand.
Maybe you with, like, way less
client results or just, like, just
straight off fucking cold with no
credibility.
You'd probably be able to sell it
for, like, 10.
But this, no the fuck you're not.
Like, you get what I'm saying?
You need to, you need to show and
explain all of the logistical
intensity that is involved.
That is what, that's the
justification of your price.
It's a justification of the highly
quoted results that you're giving
these people, right?
So, what's the difference between
these two?
Nothing.
They're the exact same thing.
But the first one fully explains
the transfer of logistical
intensity.
It was clear what exactly they
were getting.
It conveys how extensive this is
to be successful.
They hear numbers like $50,000,
$100,000, or $250,000 as a quoted
result.
And this now makes sense to them.
Because now they know, like,
you're not just bullshitting about
a $50,000, or $100,000, or
$250,000 number.
You're showing them how much
fucking shit is involved in doing
this.
It's like a lot of fucking shit to
do.
Now they're like, oh, now I
understand why it would, like, a
$50,000, or $100,000, or $250,000
result would be conceivably
possible.
Because there's hell of fucking
shit that's involved in it, right?
So, previously, they had no idea
what was involved.
They didn't know what the fuck was
involved in this, right?
They thought you were just a
bullshitter and just, like, just
spewing random numbers on the
table like a dickhead, right?
So, now when they go and they get
off the call, they have to think
about it.
That's what they're thinking
about.
They're thinking about, is this
guy a fucking bullshitter?
Like, well, what exactly is
included?
Like, I'm not sure what's involved
in this because you didn't
explicitly fucking explain this
shit to them.
You know what I'm saying?
So, nobody who's a bullshitter
would understand that there's this
much that goes into it.
So, prospects aren't stupid,
right?
If you don't know what you're
talking about, they're going to
sense it.
And even if you do know what
you're talking about, but you fail
to fully explain every single
thing to them
and complete and minute, fine,
expletive fucking detail, then
you've made the same mistake.
If you don't do that, they're
going to think you're a
bullshitter.
So, you're effectively the same as
the person who knows nothing and
actually is bullshitting.
So, take whatever you're selling
and fully explain every single
thing that is involved in fine
detail inside of a sales deck.
Show what is involved in it,
right?
Make them understand how wildly
extensive the shit you do is.
That is what gets people to pay
$10,000 instead of $2,000.
This is the difference between a
$2,000 per month service and a
$7,000 per month service.
It has more shit.
It's that you're failing to
explain all of the shit that
actually is required.
That's why they're not willing to
pay more money because they think
you're not fucking doing anything.
You know what I'm saying?
A $2,000 a month offer doesn't
include much.
A $7,000 a month offer is deep.
It's dense.
It's well thought out and fully
explains how intricate of a
process getting results for them
is, right?
Only when you pitch an offer like
this does a prospect fully respect
what it is you're doing and
understand the true value of it.
If you do not communicate this
properly, they simply never know.
That's when you get shit like,
I'll think about it, or this is
too expensive.
How could it be too expensive?
Why would somebody say, this is
too expensive?
It's because they don't fucking
believe that the shit you're
selling them is going to make them
astronomically more amounts of
money.
And how do we get people to
believe that it's going to make
them astronomically more amounts
of money?
You quote higher results.
You use an ROI calculator.
You show case studies if you have
them with fucking quantifiable
results.
And if you can't get that
yourself, then you go find a case
study to sell the opportunity of
the thing and show average results
in the opportunity.
And then you show all the
logistical intensity that's
involved with getting results.
So much logistical intensity to be
enough to justify a high quoted
result.
Because if you're not showing that
you're doing enough shit, they're
going to think this isn't enough
to get a result like this.
But when that shit is extensive
and dense and long as fuck, you're
like, wow.
And they really sit there and they
think that is a lot of shit that
you are about to do for me.
Magically, it's not expensive
anymore because they believe that
if you do that much shit,
it really fucking might actually
be believable that I make a
quarter million dollars doing this
shit with you, right?
So when they see everything they
get, it's magically not expensive
anymore.
It's not expensive anymore because
the logic of why it's expensive is
justified.
It makes a clear and logical sense
why it needs to be this much.
When you attempt to lower prices,
when you lower your prices, you
have to remove components of your
offer.
And when you have to remove
components of your offer, it's no
longer enough logistical intensity
to be enough to justify a high
quoted result.
You're fucking everyone when
you're charging these little baby
ass prices.
So when you attempt to lower your
prices and remove components of
your offer, all this does is
decrease the probability the
client gets a result,
decreases how much money you make,
and decreases how many case
studies you produce over time.
You need to sell higher packages
with more stuff to get better
results.
You need to charge more money, not
just for you, but also for the
client.
Because if you don't charge them
enough, they're not going to get
results.
They literally have to spend more
to get results.
If you don't charge the client
enough money, it won't be enough
for you to do all the shit that's
required to get them results.
So by charging them less money,
they get shittier results because
you're not willing to do all the
deep, extensive required shit it
fucking takes to get them results.
You have to charge them more money
in order to do the shit that is
required, right?
And if you keep getting stuck in
the cycle of selling little pussy
number packages,
then it's completely economically
impossible for you to get rich.
If you want to get rich, you need
to sell expensive shit.
Imagine how much easier it is to
make $100,000 per month the profit
if all your clients pay at least
$7,000 per month.
Why haven't you been able to do
this yet?
You don't have an ROI calculator
and you don't walk through
clients' actual numbers, right?
You're scared to ask for more
money because you're not confident
in your ability to get results.
You're not confident in your
ability to get results because you
don't charge clients enough money
in order to warrant you doing more
stuff for them, right?
Because you don't get enough
results for clients, you don't get
good case studies.
Due to your lack of case studies,
you continue to not sell high
value clients and you continue
begging and scraping away for low
ticket baby clients.
Here's what you need to do
immediately.
You need to make an ROI
calculator.
You can make a simple one in
Google Sheets and have ChatGPT
guide you on how to do it.
You can also make one in Lovable
or Bolt.
We'll likely post a tutorial on
how to do this at some point.
When I do, it'll be linked below.
But make a sales deck in exactly
the same fashion as a cold email
setup one.
It'll be linked down below.
And then map out all the points of
logistical intensity that are
involved in your offer.
Map them out in a fashion where
you're assuming you're getting
paid $10,000 to do it.
Do not leave anything out.
Write down every single thing
you'd be doing if somebody gave
you $10,000 to absolutely maximize
the probability that they would
get extremely good results.
Assume you just got paid $10,000
to do the thing that you do for
clients.
What's everything that you would
do for $10,000 in comparison to
$2,000?
That's your fucking offer now.
That's the offer.
And if you get on a call with a
client and you map out this whole
giant shit, this whole giant
package of what's included,
and you quote them a high price
like $5,000, $6,000, $7,000 a
month,
and for whatever the fuck reason
they can't afford that and they
want to pay less money,
just remove some of the components
on the offer.
What I'm saying is that they're
only going to get excited when you
show them the offer with all of
the components,
and they're only going to get the
best results when you show them
the offer with all of the
components.
The more expensive thing.
You have to do this.
It's completely fucking required
for you to do this in order for
you to get rich.
Don't be a pussy about it.
You have to do this.
I want you to get rich.
Fucking listen to me.
All right.
I love you.
Peace.