All right.
Let's talk about product market
fit.
So there is zero situation where
you should ever
just make something up, right?
This is extremely important to
understand because every single
business you ever run should
exclusively be derived because you
saw or figured out
that somebody else was making
money doing it.
Okay.
This isn't like a massive
misconception
with how to get profoundly fucking
rich.
Everybody thinks you need to make
like
the next Facebook or some, the
next Uber or some bullshit like
that.
This is, this is so wildly
wrong because you have to think
there there's of the millions and
tens of millions of people who try
to make these little startup
companies that make something new,
fucking one of them works.
So it's
just, it's like a 0.00000001%
chance of working.
It's so like, yeah, you're more
probable to win
the Powerball lottery.
And like, you're more probable to
be struck by lightning like 14
fucking times in
your life.
You get, you know what I'm saying?
Like it's what you need to do is
if you just copied the
shit that already works, that
already actively sells in the
market, your probability of making
money,
like substantial fucking life
changing amounts of money
massively increases.
Like what do you have
to understand is, is like, if I
say something like $100,000 per
month, um, or, or like a million a
year profit, like you think like,
wow, that's a fuck ton of money,
but there's fucking trillions of
dollars that exist.
It's like, it's, it's so, it's so
wildly small of an amount.
The United States
government considers a company
that makes less than $50 million
per year, a small business,
1 million per year is fucking one
50th that it's one 50th of a small
company.
You really don't
understand how fucking many
dollars there are to be made.
Right?
So what I'm trying to say is,
is you need to copy things.
Like the concept of saturation is,
it's, it's, it's, it's, it's a
signal that people are buying the
fucking thing.
Like you, you want something to be
saturated.
You
want other people to be selling it
because if they're not, you're
fucked.
You're like so completely
Right?
So like, let's, let's get into
this real quick.
So offer, because we, we need to
distinguish like what I mean when
I'm saying these two different
things.
So offer is the positioning of how
you convey your offer to cold
traffic and a single headliner
sentence and product is the actual
problem you're solving via a set
of deliverables.
So like, um, for instance, my
product was like,
you bought this, uh, AI assisted
agency.
The product is like, is a coaching
program that teaches you
how to launch and scale an AI
assisted agency.
That's what it is.
Um, a list kit, the cold email
setup offer is it's, it's, it's,
it's a done for you setup of a
cold email system, right?
That that's
what the product is right now.
Sometimes you can have an offer
that follows all the guidelines,
like big number claim, big
guarantee.
They'll hit those numbers, but it
still won't sell.
Why?
Because it lacks product market
fit.
It's just not something that the
market wants.
It just
fucking isn't right.
So, um, I give you a, for
instance, if we were trying to
sell the cold email
setup offer to like, I don't know,
fucking private schools to, I, I,
I don't even know.
Cause the cold
email should actually work very
well, but it might be like, okay,
so say we start trying to sell
cold
email to like D to C brands.
We're like, Hey, you can make
sales with, with automating a
bunch of cold
email or, or, or whatnot.
They'll probably think like, no,
that's like random spam.
I'm not, I'm not trying
to do that, but then you can make
another angle of it's B2B cold
email.
We can get you in retail
stores.
Then it would work.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, well, sometimes, sometimes
you're
just trying to sell something that
doesn't fucking work.
That's not the best example to
give you,
but sometimes you're trying to
sell a product to a specific
market and they just don't want to
buy it.
It's just not something they're
ever going to buy.
Right?
So how, so this is important
because
you, if you start selling
something that has no product
market fit and you just made the
shit up
and it doesn't work, you just
wasted so much fucking time and
effort.
Cause think about all the shit
you have to do here, right?
You got, you got to fucking, you
got to make a website.
You got to make
a VSL.
You got to get a list of a bunch
of people to outreach to, and you
got it.
You got to write
your fucking, write your fucking
emails to do that.
You got to set up all the tech
behind that.
And then
you got to start sending the
emails and like, it's a, it's a
whole fucking set of shit to do.
And if,
if this is your first time doing
it too, it's like, it's like 10
times more effort than it would
take
me because like you have to deeply
think about everything you're
doing.
It's a, it's like a colossal
fucking pain in the ass.
Right.
And now imagine you did all of
this and then you're selling the
shit and you spend like, I don't
know, six weeks fucking with it.
And nobody's getting on the call
with you.
Nobody gives a fuck about the
thing that you're selling at all.
Right.
And then,
and then you just figure out like,
Oh, this has no product market
fit.
And you just waste a
fuck ton of time.
It's like, that's so, that's so
shitty.
Like that you don't fucking do
that.
Don't fucking make something up.
That's, that's what I'm trying to
get out here.
Because
if you fuck that up and you just
make an offer up cause you feel
like selling it and you didn't
actually find if there was product
market fit for it, you're going to
get pissed off in like
six weeks from now or whatever,
eight weeks from now, you'll be
like, Whoa, Daniel, this isn't
working.
And like what you teach in here
doesn't work.
It's like, no, you didn't follow
the
fucking direction to sell
something that actually has
product market fit.
Don't, don't do this
fucking retard shit, but only sell
something that actively already
sells.
Right.
This is the whole
reason why that I designed this,
this whole offer.
It's called AI assisted agency.
It's not the dumb
ass business model, AI arbitrage,
not the stupid bullshit.
It's AI assisted agency.
And the entire
purpose of that is so that you
sell products and offers with
already existing active market
demand.
Why?
Because I know if I tell you, so
tell you, teach you some fucking
retard business model
that just made up in my fucking
head, it's not going to work.
You're not going to get results,
right?
That's, this is literally the
whole reason why I made the whole
program like this
is specifically for this concept
of product market fit.
Only sell shit that already
fucking
works.
This is, this is wild, this is
wildly more important than you
think it is.
Right.
So,
um, two methods to do this, uh,
like finding things that have
product market fit.
Right.
Okay.
So
first is noticing, right?
So there's a concept of, of
noticing, right?
So see the ads are getting
served, actually watch them go
through their funnels.
I, I listen like a specifically on
Instagram,
Facebook or YouTube.
I watch and read every ad.
I click the ads to go to the
landing page.
I watch people's VSLs.
I do this all of the fucking time.
I'm, I'm always doing this.
I'm
always noticing, right?
I'm an, I'm a noticer, right?
I'll get, I'll get this into a
second where
it's like, you need to stop being
a consumer and being a subject of
propaganda and start being a
purveyor and noticer of
propaganda.
You get what I'm saying?
I'll get this in a second, but
you got to get on Twitter and
watch what people are posting
about.
People like to brag about how
much money they make, uh,
particularly on Twitter.
Um, if you don't know who to
follow, just go to
my profile, the Daniel Fazio and
just follow who I'm following.
Um, you know, also see who's
making
money inside of client ascension.
Check the wins channel and my case
studies and see, see what
they're selling.
Like see what people are making
money with in client ascension.
And like when you're
on the calls and shit, like show
up to fucking calls and like talk
to people.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, like people talk about what
they're doing and what's working
like all the fucking time.
Like notice, read, show up, like
be a noticer, right?
Okay.
So see, become a noticer.
See,
see the competing programs like
client ascension and see if any of
their students are getting
results.
Find out what they're selling.
Be, but, but part of being a
noticer is understanding when
you're
being subjected to propaganda.
So I'm going to, I'm going to give
you one example here.
There, there's,
there's one marketer I'm friends
with and a while ago he started
posting about how the info market
is cooked.
Everybody's selling courses going
broke, right?
Okay.
Then one guy in client ascension
was selling a course, right?
And that was kind of like his,
his, his business model.
And he started
sending messages to me, like
freaking out, asking if he should
pivot his business model because
course
sellers going broke.
He's like, I've been seeing a lot
of people posting about like how
course
sellers are going broke.
It isn't working anymore.
Like I'm really trying to like,
like, should I pivot my business
model and start doing something
else?
I'm like, bro,
fucking like, you're not a
noticer.
And so, so I was like, this is
obviously not true.
It's
fucking propaganda.
And I noticed this because I'm a
noticer, but, but he wasn't a
noticer.
So I was
like, I told him, of course, the
fucking course sellers are not
going broke.
I'm like, this guy
who's posting that is just about
to launch an offer to info product
owners who he just scared the
shit out of.
IEU.
Stop being dumb.
Fucking notice.
You know what I'm saying?
Like you need to, to
understand what, you need to
understand like these fucking
psyops that are being executed in,
in
pervade or in, in, in, in forced
upon you.
Like you have to see, you're going
to see what the fuck is
happening here.
You get what I'm saying?
Like you, you have to fucking
notice, like this isn't, this
isn't real.
Like what it's not fucking real.
It's a psyop, right?
You have to be a noticer of
marketing, of propaganda.
You can't just like blindly
fucking accept the shit that
everyone's saying
this.
So therefore it's true.
It's, it's fucking not.
That's like literally like, it's
literally
propaganda 101.
Like just repeat something over
and over and over and over again
and everybody
will believe it.
So like as a term, as, as, as, as,
as a marketer, like what do I do
when, when I want
to fucking like really sell some
shit or sell against it?
I, I fucking repeat it all the
time.
This is wrong.
You get what I'm saying?
Like that, that's what you do.
That's what was happening here.
That's what happened to this guy.
Like be a noticer, my guy.
Right?
So, all right.
Notice the lack of things as well.
So we have one
competitor who competes against
us.
Um, but he exclusively uses case
studies from a different
business model that he used to
teach.
Right?
So this is because all of his
current students do not
to get results.
Right?
Yet he still touts the old case
studies as if it's the new
business model he's
teaching.
And he talks about how the new
model is so much better, but I
know because I'm a noticer,
I'm like all of these.
And if you just fucking actually
read the case study and listen to
the
case study, he's saying it's for
this business model, but they're
talking about, it's a different
business model.
So it's like, well, I'm, I'm
fucking sitting here like, well, I
noticed this.
You need to notice this shit, bro.
Like you have, you have, you have
to fucking, you have
to see what is occurring.
Not only things happening to you,
but the lack of things happening
from
somebody.
You know what I'm saying?
So this is obviously him just,
just trend happening.
For instance.
So why do you think I launched an
AI program that's specifically AI
assisted
agency and not fucking AI
arbitrage or AI automation
exclusively?
Why do you think I did that?
Right.
Because it is my genuine belief
and actually objectively true
reality that those models are
retarded compared to just selling
standard agency services fulfilled
via AI, right?
Even, even my
execution and like, like the way
I'm instructing you to do AI
automation, it's selling specific
builds.
That's what it is.
It's specific builds because
that's what fucking works, right?
When other people tell
you AI automation agency, they're
like, they're like, well, yeah,
you get on the phone with the
business owner.
And, uh, what you do is you figure
out their problems and like, okay,
okay.
Stop right
here because you don't just
fucking get people on the phone
with you.
Like the people don't just get on
the fucking phone.
Like you need an offer to get them
on the phone.
You get what I'm saying?
So you
as a consumer actually will get
shitty results and have a
profoundly low probability of
making money.
If the only thing you learned was
an AI automation agency, even if
that's the model that you're
learning in here, technically, you
should still watch all the other
ones, right?
This is proven by the
fact that in the next section here
that I'm about to go to right now,
that there's a massive overlap
between AI automation services and
the actual standard agency
services in terms of what has
product market fit and is actively
selling right now.
There's no, this is what you got
to understand,
like AI arbitrage or AI automation
has no straight demand.
There's no demand because it's not
an offer,
right?
Specific builds have demand.
Like if somebody wants to automate
their content production
to get results, that's an offer,
right?
That's an offer that can be
constructed.
Or if somebody wants
like a customer service AI bot
that handles shit tons of requests
from people, that's a specific
offer.
There's a specific product that
can be sold, right?
AI automation is not a product.
To be sold.
It's a vehicle.
You get what I'm saying?
It's like, it's like selling.
It's like,
it's like fucking literally going
up to someone and it was like 1998
and you're like, hey, I can help
you with the internet with your
business.
It's like, what the fuck does that
mean?
What, what does that
Like, like I can sell you, I sell
internet, bro.
What the fuck are you saying?
That's what,
that's what saying I sell AI
automation means.
I sell internet.
It doesn't make any fucking sense.
Like, what are you selling?
Is it a website?
Is it like a fucking, is it an
email system for your,
for your shit?
Is it a video conferencing
software?
What the fuck internet shit are
you selling?
You know what I'm saying?
That's what it means.
So that's, that's the best way to
have me help you
visualize it.
So, okay.
The second way to find what has
product market fit is by using AI
deep
research.
So I just made this prompt out of
nowhere.
Like literally like, literally
like an hour ago.
So I'm running an AI automation
agency.
Please conduct research about what
specific builds
or automation specific companies
are actively buying.
I'm specifically looking for
products
that have active market, that have
product market fit.
Don't make random services or
builds up.
I only
want to know things that are
actively being sold, that have
active market demand, work as a
front end
call traffic offer, and have true
product market fit.
The purpose of me asking you this
question is in
order to find products or services
I can promote that I know for a
fact that product market fits,
so I don't waste a bunch of time
and money trying to sell something
that isn't even going to end up
working.
Okay.
So I put this prompt, the GPT-5,
CLAWD 4.1 deep research, and
Manus, right?
So I'm going
to open this up, right?
So, okay.
What did GPT-5 say?
E-commerce and DTC, UGC to ads,
auto editor.
I'm not
going to go through all of these.
It'll take a long time, but the
links to them, like you could
pause
this video right now.
The link to this Gamma Doc is
here, and then just open these up,
and then go
there, right?
Local services, lead to book job,
SMS agent, SDR email, LinkedIn
agent.
So like, okay.
So
like, you get what I'm saying
here?
What's like, SDR email to LinkedIn
agent.
It's like, well, that would
fall under being a lead gen
agency.
Like, lead to book job, SMS agent.
That would also kind of fall under
being a lead gen agency.
UGC to ads, auto editor.
Like this, this would, this would
fall under being
like a, like an advertising
agency, right?
You got to say, like, there's,
there's a considerable amount
of overlap that occurs with AI
automation versus just like actual
fucking normal agency business
models.
You get what I'm saying?
So let me open the, let me open
what Claude said.
Customer service chatbots,
sales automation tools, content
generation.
Okay.
So this is a fucking content
agency.
This is a lead gen agency.
This is just customer service.
That's kind of a lead gen agency.
Not
really, but workflow automation,
consulting.
Well, consulting would only occur
if you have
inbound traffic, but let me go to
Manus.
Manus gave me like a lot of like
enterprise level type
stuff.
Uh, hold on.
Workflow automation, you know, AI
powered development tools, uh, uh,
customer service
automation, sales and marketing
automation, uh, operations to
process.
You get, you get what I'm
saying?
So, um, okay.
So then I gave it another prompt.
I was like, what, okay.
What about simple
agency services that a beginner
can sell?
And that's what this second tab is
over here.
So like in Manus,
they gave me some stuff over here,
SEO automation, uh, workflow
automation, marketing automation,
uh, Claude gave me AI chatbots for
small business, cold email
automation, AI content automation,
database reactivation campaigns.
This, this is actually fucking
like not really a good, so I kind
of
touched on this.
Um, and I've told this to people
before.
I, I had a guy one time, uh, he
was in one
of our get clients challenges a
while back and, um, he told me he
paid a hundred thousand dollars
in order to learn how to sell AI
and make an AI business.
And the guy had him, this was the,
this was the offer that the guy
made for him, a database
reactivation campaign.
What does that
mean?
Like, imagine, imagine there's a
company who has like 20,000 leads
or like 40,000 leads
order that they have a shit ton of
people in their CRM or their
salespeople aren't really hitting
up.
So what, what, what a database
reactivation campaign would do is
send emails and send outreach or
whatever the fuck to all these
people, maybe like call and text
them, um, as a, as, as a way to
get
them like back into a sales
conversation.
Now that theoretically sounds like
a good idea to you,
right?
Because it's, and it could be, but
because you, well, you could, you
could put like a fat
fucking number claim on this and
like a guarantee on it.
But if you remember in the last
video,
something I said was that you need
to sell new money, like new
system.
What does this mean?
Database reactivation.
It means, it means it's a database
they already have.
It's their CRM that they
already have.
So what does that mean?
It means that the entire idea of
the offer is scalping,
is scalping revenue off of
something they already have.
And that's their conception of it
where it's
like, no, thanks.
I don't need you to go into my CRM
for me.
So this guy, I was talking to him
and
like, he's like, I've sent tens of
thousands of cold emails.
I haven't gotten anyone interested
in
this at all.
It's been months.
I haven't made any money.
I've wasted a hundred thousand
dollars on
this.
And what's so fucking funny, the
guy spent a hundred thousand
dollars on it.
This, like this, you don't even
need fucking AI to do this.
Like it's complete, like where's
the AI
here?
Like you don't need AI.
Like you can send SMS
reactivation, email list, you
know,
multi-channel reactivation with
fucking zero AI in any capacity at
all.
Like, like where's the AI?
And the answer is that there's
fucking none.
So this guy got scammed out of a
hundred
fucking grand with the shitty
offer that is not a front end cold
traffic offer.
Right?
So again,
the second component, another
component of a cold traffic front
end offer is, is, is it's new
money.
It's new money, right?
Okay.
What do I mean by new money?
Like, okay.
AI content automation.
What this would mean is like you
build a content system for a
business that doesn't fucking do
content
yet.
What does that mean?
It means that you made something
new for them.
It's new money, right?
So
what is this?
Like if you build a cold email
automation system for a business,
right?
What does
that mean?
If they don't do cold email, it's
new money.
You created something.
You, you, you spawned
it from the fucking ether, right?
So AI chatbot for small business,
right?
Right.
It's, it's this,
this is kind of like, it's not
really revenue per se.
It's more so like maybe it is,
there can be some
sales component to it, but it's
actually just helping them like
save money as a, like, like
efficiency and shit.
But this, this is not new money.
It's not new money, right?
So it's, it's
difficult to sell as a front end
cold traffic offer.
I'm not saying it couldn't work.
There are
situations where it could work.
But what I'm saying is that if you
were fucking selling a database
reactivation offer, like that's
not a fucking business, bro, this
is like a random offer.
It's
a random fucking product that
should ideally exclusively be sold
to warm traffic.
You know
what I'm saying?
Like, like if you were doing this,
I would tell you, this is
something that
you sell to clients you already
have, that you already sold
something else.
For instance, you run
an ads agency, right?
And you help people build funnels
and make a fuck ton of money from,
from,
from funnels you make them, right?
Fucking, and this is like a random
thing you do for them,
right?
This is not a front end cold
traffic offer, right?
So again, this comes back to being
like a
noticer, like a, like you got to
be a noticer.
So like, for instance, this guy
got so fucking
psyoped into like, yeah, I'm going
to help you build an AI business.
And he learned how to build
a database reactivation business
and fucking, now what would I have
asked is, is find me anybody
who's fucking any human at all who
sells database reactivation as
their front end cold traffic
offer.
I want to find one fucking person
who consistently converts cold
traffic on this
offer, right?
And the guy would have been like,
we stumbled over the fucking words
like a retard
because it doesn't exist.
It's not fucking real, right?
You need, you need to be a
noticer,
right?
All right, cool.
So you can, you can click these on
your own.
Um, but let me go over this
now.
So what you might be asking, what
if there's an offer automation or
deliverable
that has active market demand that
isn't taught inside of here,
Daniel?
Okay.
Well,
our goal with this product is to
have an astoundingly massive
library of automations and guides
and how
to build pretty much everything
that, that everybody comes up with
ever at all, right?
So if you come
across something that you don't
know how to build or you want to
help, then just tell us.
So like
ideally submit it to Lucas and
we'll, we'll probably make some
kind of like way for you to like
submit it or, or some bullshit
like that, but just, just, just
tell us.
So, uh, and then we'll
probably just build it inside of
client sense and AI, but as far as
conscientiousness and figure it
the fuck out ability goes is you
have full range to just go onto
YouTube and figure out how to do
shit yourself before we get to it,
right?
Because that's ultimately what we
would do anyway, right?
If you came to me and you're like,
Daniel, how do I do this?
And I didn't know how to do it.
The
first thing I'm doing is going on
YouTube and be like, who has done
this?
Or just, I would type the
thing in and then I'd just fucking
watch videos, right?
So that's the first step of the
research
process.
Okay.
Let's see who else has done this
and what info I can find about it.
And we will
start from there, right?
So once you have that info, we
combine it with what we already
know,
then just try to build it out by
playing around in like N8N or
whatever.
Okay.
You probably heard
this before.
You can just do things, which is
true.
You can just do things, right?
So, so you get used
to just doing things without
permission or express instruction
for people.
So that, that's like a
degree of kind.
So it's called, it's called, it's
called having high agency, right?
Having, having,
what's called high agency is, is
you can just figure things out
yourself and just do things
without needing to be specifically
instructed on how to do so or
given permission to do so.
This is, this, this is a very
important quality to have.
You have to have high agency.
You need to be a
high agency person, right?
There, there, you can do anything
you want.
You can do any, you gotta,
you gotta understand like what I
am to you and what everyone in
this program is to you is a
consultant.
And we are like, in terms of your
life, cause you're the main
character of your life.
You are, we are a tool in your
tool belt right now as you are in
this program, right?
And you might use this as a tool
for a very long time.
Cause you're like, wow, this is
super fucking useful tool, right?
Now, now, if, if you don't use the
tool and you don't get results
from the tool, that's your fucking
fault for not using the tool.
Like, like a hammer, a hammer
fucking hammer screws, a
screwdriver screws screws, right?
But a hammer, hammers nails, a
screwdriver screws fucking, you
get what I'm saying?
Like the tool, the tool does what
the fucking tool does.
If you don't use the tool, if you
don't have like, like, you know
what I'm saying?
Use the tool, right?
Have high agency.
Like you, you, you, you, you can
just do things, right?
And be a noticer, like notice
things.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, this is like, like, don't be
a subject of propaganda, right?
It's like, it's like, it's like,
it's like, you gotta imagine
there's like a, I remember being
like way younger.
I was maybe like 19 or 20 or
something.
And I'm like, I'm like just
starting to get into this.
And, and like, I was, I, I, I, I
bought hella shit and programs and
courses and shit.
Like, just like you have,
obviously.
And, um, what I remember thinking,
like, I remember there's always
like this veil as, as, as I
learned more information and like
people told me specific things.
things.
It felt like the, there was like
this veil that would like slowly
was like lifted and I could see, I
could finally see.
And I just, I finally understood,
right?
That that's what this is over
here.
Like being a noticer, right?
You, you, you just, you notice
things.
You see, you, you observe what is
occurring to you that is
happening.
Like what people are trying to do
to you.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, like,
there's just this like second,
third order level of lifting that
like, it just, it just like peers.
You, you, you, you have, you have
to facilitate this.
You have to notice this.
You have to be a noticer.
All right, cool.
Let's go to the next video.