All right, so this is probably one
of the most important concepts
that I've seen.
Like, you could ask anybody in
Client Central.
This is like single-handedly one
of the most important things that
you need to execute at all.
It's literally like a
life-changing concept that you
need to follow.
This in particular is like what
drives you up to like your first
30, 50,
even fucking sometimes like
$100,000 a month.
It's by shifting your framing to
this, right?
So it's basically, it's called
slinging deals, and it's how to
close 100% of sales calls.
So everything about trying to like
jujitsu your sales calls into
manipulating somebody to purchase
is completely fucking stupid,
right?
So like your sole and only
function on call is to determine
what their problems are
and offer a solution that will
maximize them achieving their end
goal
because that's the only thing that
a prospect is concerned with is
achieving their own selfish wants,
right?
So that means that you have to
stop being selfish and everybody
you're talking to has goals,
and they're only going to buy if
they believe that what you have
will help them hit their goal
at a higher rate than whatever
alternative that they have access
to at that moment.
So might elapse, say some shit
like this.
Thanks for coming to the call
today.
Name, I'm going to operate under
deception.
Do you want to grow your company?
Yeah, yes.
Okay, cool.
So what's your problem right now?
Why am I going to be able to do
that?
And that would lead you into
discovery, right?
So you're going to proceed to be
relayed all the things that
they've tried and didn't work.
You're going to learn what their
frustrations are,
what the exact reason that they
haven't been able to grow their
company so far.
Now, you start talking about your
product, right?
So let's say that then go, well, I
don't know about that.
Simply ask, well, what do you
want?
So like, say you just pitched your
shit, right?
And you just say, well, I don't
know if I want that.
You can just say, well, what do
you want?
What makes the most sense to you,
right?
Now, they quite literally tell you
exactly what they want.
So say you're selling a
done-for-you offer.
Now, this video is important.
So make sure you watch the whole
thing.
So I'm going to like visualize
this more towards the end.
So say you're selling a
done-for-you offer, right?
And they tell you that they want
to learn how to do it themselves.
But because you've labored
yourself as an agency and only
sell done-for-you,
you just tell them, well, I don't
do that.
Which is dumb.
It doesn't make any sense.
Because you would sell them a
consulting offer for the right
price.
So just tell them, just sell them
consulting calls and swipe files
of stuff you've made.
So what I'm trying to get at here
before we get into the better
visualization of this is that
you will always hit your all-time
high revenue months when you are
slinging deals all month, right?
You got to understand that like
what's happening is every week
starts at zero.
Every day starts at zero.
You reset every single day.
You need to get deals over the
line all week and every day.
Each deal might be custom for a
custom deliverable and for a
custom price.
You are not locked into a singular
deliverable and a singular price
and that's it.
You need to be dynamic.
The problem with people below
$100K a month is they always say
shit like that won't scale.
If you're below $100K a month,
don't worry about scale.
Get to $100K a month first, right?
And you get to $100K a month by
slinging deals and getting the
maximum amount of customers
possible, right?
So, okay.
So let's revisit logistical
intensity here.
Inside of the how to sell high
ticket offers video,
I talked about stacking
deliverables and showing all the
deliverables involved in working
together.
So I'm going to take an example
offer from the ads and funnels
agency and help you understand
this better, right?
So we're going to take an example
offer of it's a webinar funnel
build out for high ticket coaching
clients, right?
So the client is conducting the
webinar that will pitch an offer
at the end
and drive those registrants to a
sales call to purchase that upsell
offer.
The upsell offer is $10,000.
That's why the webinar drives to a
sales call instead of the
self-checkout on the webinar page.
Okay, so now, these are going back
to what I said earlier in the
offer section.
These are the logistical intensity
points involved in conducting a
webinar funnel, a successful
webinar funnel.
You know what I'm saying?
So the logistical intensity points
that are required to have a
successful webinar are the
deliverables of your offer, right?
So, like, okay, so now we could
break this up into a very simple,
like, comparison chart between
what I do and what you do.
So this would be, like, what the
client does and this is what you
do.
So, like, you would literally
have, like, a fucking chart like
this.
Like, you'll see this more in the
VSL section where it's, like, the
actual presentation of it.
It's just, like, deliverable
stacking.
So, you would literally tell the
client, like, okay, well, I'll do
the funnel build-out, the landing
page, design, landing page, copy,
VSL scripting, VSL editing, ad
scripting, ad video editing, post
registration, emails, the webinar
script, the slides creation, the
thank you page, VSL scripting, the
editing, the post-webinar emails,
all the automations, connect
everything together, ad pixel
setup, ads management, media
buying, and the post-webinar email
flows of 30 days.
What you do is actually conduct
the webinar and then take the
sales calls that are booked from
it and close those deals, right?
Okay, so now let's say you just
pitched it.
Let's say you just pitched this.
So, if you pitch this offer at
$8,000 build-out plus 10% gross
revenue, and they say some shit,
like, oh, that's too much.
Okay, backtrack the conversation
with them and see if they're
actually sold on the concept of
the webinar in the first place and
whether they really, really,
really want to do a webinar right
now.
Okay, say you do that and they're,
like, sold.
Like, yes, I want to do a webinar.
I think, like, we need to do a
webinar.
I'm sold on the concept of a
Like, this is the thing that we
have to do.
Okay, now.
Here's what you can do to proceed
forward.
Offer to remove specific elements
of it for less money.
Like, if their objection is really
money and they literally fucking
can't afford that, just offer to
remove specific elements of it for
less money, right?
So, allocate some of the
logistical intensity towards them
in order to get the deal over the
line for less money and less work
in your end.
That's one available option.
Like, you could just take some of
this shit and move it over to
them.
Where it's like, well, I can't
afford this.
Well, you could tell them, like,
okay, listen, I could do it for
less money, but that means less
work on my end.
So, like, which of these do you
want me to move over to your
responsibility?
Like, what do you want me to do
exactly?
You get what I'm saying?
And, like, you could be screen
sharing with them, literally
fucking showing them this so,
like, they understand what's
happening, right?
Now, say they're not sold on the
concept of webinars.
So, you could offer to create a
different kind of funnel for them,
like a low-ticket product
essential funnel or a BSL funnel
that is requiring them to actually
conduct a live webinar, right?
So, the premise I'm trying to
convey is that there's always a
reason why somebody isn't moving
forward to somebody, which always
presents us an opportunity to
either upsell or downsell.
So, for instance, let's say they
said some shit, like, I just don't
want to actually do a webinar.
I'm nervous.
It's too much work.
I don't like presenting live,
yada, yada, yada, whatever the
fuck, right?
Here's what you could do with
that.
You could offer an upsell and say,
I'll personally conduct the
webinar for you.
And that might be, like, $5,000
extra plus an additional 10%
collected that you charge them,
right?
That's one available option.
Or, you could cross-sell them
where it's like, I'll build you a
different kind of funnel where you
don't have to conduct a webinar,
like a BSL funnel or a low-ticket
product funnel, right?
Now, they also might say something
like, I just want to do this
myself and don't want to give
control to somebody else, right?
Well, you could cross-sell them
into a done-with-you offer where
we get on a call once per week and
build out everything together.
And then you might charge, like,
$6,000 to $12,000 for that or some
shit.
It doesn't matter, right?
The idea that your packages and
prices will be clean and
established is wrong.
This is the wrong way to go about
building a business.
You need to sell.
I always find this interesting.
Someone will ask me, you know, how
much should I charge for this?
And the answer is the maximum
amount that you can pull off.
That's what the proper amount to
charge somebody is.
Now, obviously, you want to see
some examples of what have other
people charged.
Then you start with some, like,
arbitrary fucking number that
results in you making a lot of
profit.
And then maybe there's, like, a
back and forth with it.
And then over time, as you get
more clients and you're more
confident in your ability, maybe
you have more case studies,
you just gradually increase the
price based on the level of demand
that you're able to facilitate,
right?
So your goal is to collect cash.
As much of it as you can by any
means and no matter how unclear of
a sequence it results in.
This is a result of consultative
sales.
You're not actually selling
somebody.
You're just making recommendations
based on what they say because you
have shit tons of different
products and iterations to sell
them.
Okay, so, like, let me give you an
example.
If you have ADHD and, like, your
doctor recommends you Vyvanse, but
then you try Vyvanse and it lasts
too long to where you can't sleep.
And then you go to the doctor,
you're like, hey, like, I don't
really like this too much.
Like, it lasts too long.
Like, it fucks with my sleep.
So what he does then is he
prescribes you extended release
Adderall.
And then you take that, you're
like, hey, I actually kind of
don't like this at all.
Like, this also kind of lasts too
long and I kind of want it to come
down around, like, 7 p.m.
or whatever the fuck.
I don't know.
So he gives you instant release
Adderall.
But then you tell him, hey, like,
I'm taking, like, this instant
release Adderall and it's, like,
kind of intense when I first take
it.
Like, I kind of really don't like
it too much.
Okay, so then what does he tell
you to do?
He tells you to take the pill and
cut it in a quarter and only take
one quarter of it at a time,
right?
Okay, so what happened here?
He cross-sold you into a new
product from Vyvanse to Adderall.
Then down-sold you into less
volume of that new product based
on your particular situation.
This is how this works, right?
You are always a consultant simply
recommending what makes logical
sense for every individual you
speak to.
There is nothing clear-cut.
Do this exactly.
It has to be exactly like this.
There is nothing clear-cut about
this business, right?
This is, like, this is kind of,
like, a veil you might have in
that, like, there's a saying where
it's, like, you can just do
things, right?
Like, I'll give you a for
instance.
If there's, like, a long line to,
like, an event venue or, like, a
bar or some bullshit like that, I
will go up to the person at the
front of the line and I will very
discreetly take a $20 or $50 or
$100 bill and bribe them to skip
the line.
And it works, like, 99% of the
fucking time.
Like, it just does, right?
The premise is that you can just
do things.
Like, there's no rules.
Like, there's, like, just because
you're a done-for-you agency and
this is your offer doesn't mean,
like, that's what you actually
fucking sell.
Like, you just sell other shit,
right?
It's kind of, like, going back to
this concept I've spoken about in
this offer section where it's,
like, just get them on the phone,
right?
Like, so you could have some offer
with some, like, quantifiable
claim and, like, a guarantee or
whatever the fuck and all it's
doing is getting people on the
phone.
But it could literally be the case
that you have never sold that
offer that you have as, like, your
headline on your landing page or
the thing that you're saying in
the cold emails.
It could literally be, like,
you've signed 10 clients and
you've never fucking even sold
that offer once.
Like, literally fucking not even
one time.
It's, you just do, you sling
deals.
You just sell what you can.
Get what I'm saying?
Like, that's how this business,
that's how you do this.
All of the people who grow the
fastest just fucking do this and
you sell all sorts of iterations
and sets of fuckery and, like,
that's how this shit works.
You get what I'm saying?
This is why it's important for you
to understand, like, it really
ingrained in this concept of the
offer, like, the headline, what
you're saying in your cold email
script and shit or your cold DM
script is, like, just make the
offer so fucking ballsy that they
just get on the phone.
Because it, like, isn't even what
you end up fucking selling them at
all.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, in 90% of the cases, I don't
know, it might range, it might be,
like, 40 to 90%, who fucking
knows?
But it's, it's, everyone's
different.
But just, you can just do things.
You just, just sling fucking
deals, bro.
Like, that's, that's it.
Like, you, you, you, you, bro,
even if, even if it's, like, you
just collect $500 for making one
fucking landing page design for
them.
Like, just, just get something.
Just get on the phone and fucking
close them on something.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, because what you're trying
to do is, like, you just want as
many humans who have given you
money as possible.
And I'm, I'm, I'm going to
actually write this down.
Main goal.
Get as many humans to give you any
amount of money as possible.
Maximize the amount of humans who
have paid you any amount of,
maximize the amount of humans on
the planet who have paid you any
amount of money ever.
Right?
Why?
Because this increases your
customer base.
The moment somebody, the moment
somebody pays you any amount of
money, it increases the
probability they continue to pay
you more money by about 1000x.
Right?
Okay.
I'll, I'll, I, I, I, I, I, I, I,
I, I'll try to keep this as PC as
possible.
But, um, like, if you're a guy and
you want to take a girl out on a
date, the girl, or you want to
take a girl out or, like, do other
things with the girl.
The pro, if, if, if, if, if you
ask a girl who's already done that
with you, the probability that it
works is fucking 1000 times
higher.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, it's the same thing with
customers.
Like, if you pick somebody to pay
you money for an offer and you do
it to somebody who's already paid
you even fucking $5, like, it's
gonna work better with them than
somebody who hasn't paid you.
That's why you're trying to do
this.
That's why you need to sling
deals.
You need to fucking sell somebody
something.
Get any, any amount of money
because you need to maximize the
amount of humans who have paid you
any amount of money at all.
Alright, that's it for this video.
Peace.