All right what's going on guys in
this video i want to show you how
to expand your list kit
search based on job titles so you
have a bigger total addressable
market and more prospects to
reach out to for example let's say
i'm reaching out to marketing and
advertising companies and
i'm targeting um you know media
keywords right this is going to
give us a huge list that looks
great on paper but then when we go
over here to job title and we only
do cmos all of a sudden we
only have a thousand people to
reach out to um and a lot of
people will come to us at list kit
and be
like i only want to work with one
specific job title i only want to
reach out to one job title
and i'm showing you right here why
that's not the best idea because
you're going to run out of
addressable market in like a week
right so in the case of um only
having 1300 people based on cmo
job
titles the easiest way to expand
your search is to add in different
job titles so vp of marketing
head of marketing marketing
director
okay so we already 9x the search
results from 1300 to 9 000 and
this is going to give you more
addressable market to reach out to
with your campaigns and you're
probably saying well i only
like speaking to cmos that's
completely fine you can add in a
step in your cold email sequence
that says
who might be the best person at um
top 10 media to discuss marketing
with and they're more than likely
going to say my cmoivan is the
best person right so even if you
don't have a list of strictly the
job
titles you want to reach out to
you can still get in touch with
the right person by proxy of
reaching
out to a different job title at
that company does that make sense
if you only work with cmos you can
still
reach out to other marketing job
titles at a company and they will
direct you to the cmo by asking in
your cold email script who might
be the best person to reach out to
to discuss xyz with right and if
we're still looking for more tam
we can literally just type in
marketing as a job title this is
going
to pull in every single marketing
job title in the search and we're
at 91 000 people we went from a
we went from a thousand to 91 000
people by adding in marketing as a
as a broad job title
yes this might get you some
interns and some weird people that
respond to your emails but they
will
they will direct you to their
higher ups the cmos the ceos the
people you want to speak to so if
you're struggling to find enough
tam total addressable market
inside of list kit this is your
best bet
expand the job titles um obviously
you can expand keywords and do
like digital
media but if you're really
struggling to build a bigger
audience all you want to do is add
in those
extra job titles because they even
if you don't want to work with
them will direct you to the right
person
at the company and you will have
you'll have more deal flow right
so that's pretty much it
hopefully this makes sense thanks