What is going on christian here
co-founder at list kit in this
short video i want to give you
a rundown and a quick tutorial of
how list kit works and how it can
save you hours upon hours
on your data and outbound
prospecting efforts let's dive
into it so self-serve platform
similar
to zoom info similar to apollo
right the the dashboard is very
similar we have the search
filters on the left the outputs on
the right let's build a sample
search for example let's do
in advertising companies um with
you know 10 to 100 employees in
the united states let's see what
we
get and then let's add in um ceo
cmo owner job titles and the
output is going to populate here
right like any other data tool um
this is very similar to what
you've seen with other tools in
the marketplace let me go over the
few key differences with list kit
first off when you
get a um a search outputted like
this and you see all the contacts
here 65 000 people all as you can
see with other tools is the first
you know 50 to 100 records and
that's your entire um glimpse into
the search that you built you
don't know if it's actually
accurate and up to your standards
for what
you want to target list kit
changes that with our data
visualization chart that you see
here you can
actually see all 65 000 people in
the search and what continents
they're in what location industry
job
titles keywords and you can
eliminate outliers that you do not
want in your search for example
let's say we don't want any social
media or let's do no branding
agencies in my search we cut out
branding and now the search is
going to exclude you can see it
went down to 59 000 it's going to
exclude
every branding agency in the
search because we don't want that
right let's say we don't want
europe
in the search we don't want um
africa or asia we just want north
america we can sit here and trim
this search down until it is
exactly up to our specifications
not for the first 25 leads but for
the entire search of you know 47
000 people right once that is done
the export process is way faster
than any other tool in the
marketplace because all you do is
go here select how many contacts
per company
you want select how many credits
you would like click redeem and
you're going to be presented with
um a list in your email inbox that
is fully verified and ready to go
and let me explain the next
feature
what i mean by verified and ready
to go because when you get the
list in your inbox i'll pull one
up here
as an example every single email
in this list and in this output is
verified by us now what does that
mean
with apollo with zoom info with
seamless these guys say that their
data is verified but they're just
giving you email contacts from
their database without cleaning
them at all and they're saying
good luck you have to use a
third-party verification tool like
million verifier like never bounce
to
actually make sure that these
email contacts are deliverable and
verified which takes a ton of time
a ton of effort it's a headache
list kit solves that we build the
verification to process into our
backend so every email that you
get from us is verified one credit
from us is one verified email
whereas with apollo zoom info you
may export 10 you know emails into
a search and only six or seven of
them are verified so you wasted
three credits or you know three
dollars or however much the cost
is
on bad data we only charge you for
good verified triple verified
deliverable email data and that's
a
key differentiator also you can
export up to 10 000 credits at a
time right from this search bar
and
click redeem without needing to go
25 at a time exporting 25 25 25
and taking 30 minutes to export
a list of a few thousand records
right that's the key
differentiator with the export
process it is as
simple as that to the point where
you can get a list in your inbox
in five minutes and you're ready
to start sending emails on the
flip side we also have phone
number data and all you do like
let's say
we built the exact same searches
before marketing agencies instead
of choosing email you just select
with phone and this is going to
bring up a database of completely
new contacts with phone numbers so
if
you want to do cold calling and
send some you know dial some
outbound cold calls you can do
that too
right export process is the exact
same you know three credits per
company let's say we want 10
credits to
redeem we click redeem there and
i'm now going to get a list of 50
or 10 phone numbers in my email
inbox that
are ready to send or ready to make
dials to and here's what the
spreadsheet for phone numbers
looks
like once you get it so we give
out mobile numbers um i did a
couple cold calls i'm a complete
rookie
but i just did it for marketing
purposes and some of the people
that picked up were literally like
how do you have this number it is
my personal cell um you know
that's crazy that you have this
number so
these mobile phones are really
really um you know high quality
data points where you can call
them and
you're going to get right through
to their their mobile you're going
to hear their voicemail or
they're going to pick up on their
cell phone in the middle of a
workday no um gatekeepers no
landlines
no no you know bad numbers like
that we give you mobile phones
that are right to the decision
maker
and if you don't hear you know if
you don't connect with them we
also give you a direct and a
personal
phone which is most often a
business phone a landline things
like that so you can call that as
a backup
that's the quick rundown with list
kit um a few quick you know other
ancillary features that are
not as important as the ones i
just went over once you get a
search in your um in your order
history
you can actually hook it up to our
we have an api with a tool called
smart lead where you can literally
um send your leads directly to
your sending tool from list kit
what does that mean instead of
getting
the email with the spreadsheet and
then verifying the spreadsheet and
formatting the spreadsheet
and sending it off to the sending
tool after an hour of work you can
hook up an api that will
literally send the list of emails
or the list of email leads from
our tool into our sending tool
for cold email called smart lead
let me log into a different
account because my api is not
hooked up
on this account real quick to show
you how this functionality works
because i'm sure if you guys are
sending cold emails with mailshake
smart lead instantly apollo
different tools like that
you don't want to go back and
forth you know zapping between a
spreadsheet and a sending tool and
a data
tool we condense it all into one
right so right here when you hook
your api api up with smart lead
you'll be able to literally add
the leads to a smart lead campaign
like this and click i'm not going
to
do it but save changes and click
send a smart lead and the leads
will populate in your sending tool
and they will start in the
campaign automatically without you
lifting a finger you're not
touching a spreadsheet
you're not doing any manual work
and you can see with these that
it'll label once the the leads get
sent to the campaign that it's
ready to go right so that is a
quick rundown of our platform it's
meant
to be extremely simple so if
you're like wow that was you know
a lot easier than i was expecting
that's
what we're going for we want you
to spend as little time on the
platform as possible
and before i leave you off i just
want to go through our packages
real quick
for phone numbers specifically we
start at 79 bucks a month for 500
credits which boils down to
about 16 cents per credit ultimate
plan 489 9.8 cents per phone
number credit and then 889 for the
elite
plan nine cents per credit for 10
000 phone credits extremely
competitive pricing compared to
the marketplace
right now um and then of course we
also have email plans that start
at 79 bucks for a thousand
599 for 10 000 and 1200 for 40 000
email credits and if you want to
you know sign up with both you can
select an email package and add
phone credits to your package and
it'll show up inside your
dashboard
like this segmented by phone and
email data hopefully this was
helpful if you guys have any
questions about
how to use list kit for your cold
calling and your cold email needs
and your data needs
please reach out to us thank you
for watching i hope this was
helpful and take care