What's going on guys?
Andre Hagel Jr.
here from Client Ascension and in
this video I'm going to
reveal to you the new way of doing
cold email in 2025 and this is for
Client Ascension students
only so if you're watching this
congrats you have access to a
strategy in a way and essentially
a
private infrastructure which I'll
get into all the details about to
just get the best possible
results from cold email in 2025
and really just capitalize on all
this momentum we have going
between Donald Trump getting
re-elected to the White House,
stock markets skyrocketing, crypto
meme coins skyrocketing, Bitcoin
on its way to $100,000.
There's so much momentum in the
world
right now and so let's continue to
ride it and create that momentum
and replicate that momentum
here in cold email outreach and so
let's just get into it.
It's really straightforward and
simple
really all this offer is is to get
your cold email system set up
completely done for you by the
ListKit team on ListKit's private
sending infrastructure which is
performing better than
any other deliverability tools on
the market.
If you stay until the end I'll
show you all the proof of that
so you can see how well our
infrastructure has been performing
for us and for our clients
but more importantly by being a
student in Client Ascension you'll
get the $1,500 setup fee 100%
waived.
So you just pay the monthly
subscription depending on the
package you choose.
The packages
are as follows.
It's $500 a month for 15,000 email
sends and then that goes all the
way up to
$5,000 a month for 210,000 email
sends and for even higher volume
if you want to go past 210,000
email
sends.
Personally here at ListKit and
Client Ascension we're sending
anywhere from 10 to 20,000 emails
per
day and so a little bit past that
higher package.
So for the higher packages you can
stack 15,000 email send
add-ons on top of the highest
package for $350 a month each and
also this is not fake urgency but
prices will be increasing by 20%
on December 1st 2024.
I'm currently recording this video
on November 20th
2024 so you have about a week and
a half to lock in on any of these
packages before they increase by
20% so this package will go to 600
or yeah 600 and then this package
will go to 6,000 and all the rest
will go up by uh 20% as well and
so get in before then lock in on
this pricing and uh reap the
rewards.
So packages include the following
you get cold email scripts from
christian you get email accounts
on our private setting
infrastructure with dedicated ip
addresses you get access to a free
smart lead
account which is the cold email
sending tool you get triple
verified email leads from list kit
unlimited
intent data topics and targeting
filters by list kit automated
warm-up automated cold email
ramp-up
deliverability health monitoring
low health ip address immediately
swapped for fresh ones automatic
email
account reconnects private slack
channel exclusive weekly support
calls and so much more the cost
comparison breakdown if you were
to do this yourself essentially
your option is either you do cold
email yourself you go figure out
the tools you want to use for the
inboxes the tool you want to use
for
the sending the tool you want to
use for the email leads and all
that uh and you can see the cost
breakdown
for doing it yourself versus the
cost if you were to just do this
through the list kit setup offer
not only is it actually cheaper
this is just an example based on
the 45 000 email sends per month
package but it's also going to
save you so much time because cold
email takes a long time to set up
okay and this has been a
bottleneck for client ascension
students since we've launched the
program
which is why i'm so excited about
this offer and this opportunity uh
because we can now get cold
email checked off and out of the
way so we can move on to action
items and other legion sources
like
posting organic content on twitter
linkedin and youtube or doing
dream 100 outreach or doing
outreach on upwork or just
refining our sales process with
david by putting together a sales
script
um and doing the three pillars and
doing sales mock calls there's so
much other tasks that you could be
focusing on crafting your your
perfect vsl following nick verges
training like there's so much you
could be
doing the problem though is cold
email is is obviously of utmost
importance especially for
client ascension students just
getting started and it just takes
a while to set up if you were to
do it
the old way if you were to do it
yourself but if you were to do it
through list kit it's really
simple
the steps to sign up are so simple
if you already have a list kit
account you can just skip to step
three
if you don't already have a list
kit account sign up for a free
trial account here which is
listkit.io
slash free dash trial and then add
a payment method here which is
just this portal link you have to
sign up for a free trial account
for first or you have to already
have a list kit account once all
that's
taken care of your account set up
and you have a payment method in
there dm me at andre on slack
with your list account email and
the package you want to sign up
for and i'll take it from there
it's really
really quick and simple to sign up
and once you're signed up your
cold email campaigns will
launch within 14 days with your
only responsibility being to one
fill out the onboarding form which
takes 10 to 15 minutes and to
schedule and attend an onboarding
call with our team which also
takes
around 30 to 60 minutes that's it
the ongoing responsibilities
include inbox management which
you can do through implementing
rev reply which we have a great
community discount for and we have
weekly coaching calls with the rev
reply founder which is just like
an automated ai inbox manager
tool you can see the community for
more information on that and then
just launching new campaigns every
single month which you can do
through all the training that we
provide and also by attending any
of the cold
email coaching calls that we have
in the community we have calls
with nick abraham every week we
have
calls with matt lucero every week
we now have calls with christian
cold email chris on twitter every
single
week we also have cold email
script review and campaign review
calls with christian and niall
the copywriter from list kit every
single friday so there's almost a
call every single day related to
cold email where you can get help
with launching your new campaigns
so not only does this save you
money
while getting a fully optimized
and improving cold email system
set up for you but you also buy
back your
time to complete more action items
assigned to you by your student
success coach while also attending
more
live coaching calls like we've
already talked about here's the
thing guys if you do not choose to
do
cold email using this offer you'll
spend time writing your own
scripts register and configuring
your
domains and dns settings
configuring your own cold email
inboxes setting up your own cold
email sending
tool manually connecting your
inboxes to smartly doing the
proper warm-up process setting up
your
campaign and smart lead
configuring the proper ramp up
sending schedule manually
reconnecting inboxes when
they get disconnected monitoring
deliverability and domain health
guessing if and when inboxes need
to be
replaced and so much more not only
do you have to do all of these
things but you also have to pay
for all of these things
individually whether you use you
know a hyper tide or an inbox
automate or a mail
reef solution for your inboxes in
addition to a solution like
instantly or smart lead for your
you're sending you have to pay for
all of these out of pocket on your
own in addition to doing all of
the manual work and so by signing
up for list kits done for your
cold email setup offer with the
setup fee 100 waived and for free
it makes it such a no-brainer
offer not only is it a no-brainer
in
terms of time and cost savings but
it's also such a no-brainer in
regards to the actual performance
of
your cold email campaigns because
that's what truly matters here is
how can we get client
ascension students to get the best
results from cold email
consistently time and time again
it's by
getting you guys on the list kit
private cold email sending
infrastructure if you see in this
tweet that
i recently posted on my twitter
account you can just read this
i'll read it out loud real quick
uh
right now our private
infrastructure has the best
results on the market we're the
only sending
infrastructure that actively turns
people away from sending on our
private infrastructure making it
truly private we're like an invite
only country club and only anyone
who possesses a risk to our
infrastructure deliverability is
turned away as a result we have a
0.59 percent bounce rate on more
than three and a half million
email sends in just the past 14
days across dozens of industries
with
dozens of services and offers
being pitched so you can pair up
with our delete if you pair up our
elite
deliverability with list kits
triple verified data you'll get a
bounce rate under one percent uh
you'll
never have to worry about us
getting thousands of senders on
this infrastructure it'll always
be
truly limited which is why it'll
consistently outperform the others
as they become more and more
commercialized and you can see the
actual stats screenshot that was
reported by our email
infrastructure team
just recently you could also see
daniel's vsl gamma doc for more
selling points on why this offer
is truly such a good offer um you
could also see some case studies
how guillermo booked 28 calls
with this gets cold email setup
offer how nivan generated eleven
thousand dollars for his
accounting
firm with our cold email setup
offer how mohammed used the cold
email setup offer to close two
high
ticket clients for his email
marketing agency and then you can
see some screenshots of actual
results
this screenshot was taken right
before i started to record this
video campaigns launched october
29th it's
now november 20th 35 000 emails
have been sent 1 000 replies which
is a six percent reply rate in 430
positive replies which is more
than one percent of the email
sends that we're getting positive
replies on
that's more than the reply rate
most of you guys are getting most
of you guys are struggling to get
even a one percent reply rate and
our client right here is getting
an over one percent positive reply
rate and it's not a fluke that's
on 35 000 emails sent we also had
this case study recently from josh
sprague from seven clay saying
he's been using list kit for a few
months now and has an incredible
pipeline
building in the past month they
got 4700 order 27 000 order and a
new account onboarding that should
be
200 000 annually that's almost a
that's a quarter million dollars
worth of deals generated from the
list kit setup offer for josh
david more uh watered down example
of what results could look like
four cold
email positive replies one call
booked uh that he actually closed
for 800 a month if he's on you
know just
the base package you already saw a
positive row as in just that first
month's revenue we have
campaigns from a client uh here as
well that consistently over the
across one two three four
five different campaigns getting
anywhere from a six to a nine
point six four percent reply rate
and
consistently getting 14 to 20
positive reply rates and another
one here uh with 10 000 emails
sent
almost a two percent reply rate
with a 20 positive reply rate and
so the results speak for
themselves
this doc will continue to add more
and more results as we get more
and more people onto this
infrastructure
i literally spent maybe 20 minutes
putting this doc together it's
just the selling points are so
straightforward and clear the
results are there and because
you're in client ascension and
because we're
about to usher in the golden age
of not just the united states of
america but also cold email and
business in general it's time for
you guys to get on board lock the
fuck in and make 2025 your best
year yet by sending cold emails
the right way the list kit way by
getting on this private sending
infrastructure again the steps are
really simple choose from any of
our packages based on how many
cold emails you want to send every
single month and then follow these
steps to sign up if you already
have a list kit account great dm
me your email account uh your list
kit account email and the package
you want to sign up for if you
don't sign up for a free trial add
a payment method and then reach
out
to me and again your campaigns
will be launched within 14 days by
you simply filling out an
onboarding
form and attending an onboarding
call and we'll be in touch of
course uh as you go through this
process
as well to make sure you have
everything you need uh to succeed
and so let's get it guys it's
really
that simple i hope to see you in
there soon peace for now let's
fucking grow
you