Browse abandon flow let us get
into it moving right along so the
purpose so this flow the
browse band and flow is going to
fire when somebody views a product
but they don't add
anything to cart they don't go to
checkout they don't do any of that
and they don't end up buying
so that's the lowest they get in
the funnel is they view an actual
product page they clicked
on a product they looked at it saw
the price all that good stuff so
now there are a number of
possible reasons why somebody left
behind but in most cases it's
because they weren't fully
bought in on the brand or the
product that's the most common and
so our purpose of this flow is to
get someone farther down the
funnel go from viewing a product
to adding it to cart going to
check out
purchasing so another thing is
just to kind of get them to go
back to that item it might be that
item
that they want maybe they didn't
like that item so we also want to
show them different products in
their in our store to try to get
them like maybe they like those
ones more so at the end of the day
we want them to get we want them
to view their product and we also
want them to go back to browsing
the store to maybe finding one
that they like more so let us
break down the flow simple five
emails
here so this is the trigger view
to product filters someone adds to
cart zero times started checkout
zero
times placed order zero times they
haven't been in this flow in the
last 30 days so that they're not
getting like spammed a ton they're
getting the same thing over and
over again so typically from the
beginning i like to wait 45
minutes but again this is just
like a starting point we've seen
some stores
have like a four hour time delay
be the best typically the higher
the aov the longer you want
your time delay to be uh whoa that
rhymed um but typically that's
what you want to do and so for
typically we find like 45 minutes
to an hour two hours is typically
the best so after that time period
we
just want to send a simple simple
reminder just reminding them of
the product and show the dynamic
abandoned content that's literally
it because maybe they just got
distracted while viewing
and it's just like a nice subtle
reminder to go back and shop on
the store so that's all we need
for this first email wait one to
two days brand info and risk
reversals um try to get that trust
email
three testimonials trust again and
then we enter a discount for these
last two so let's go down into
each email in a breakdown of each
one so email one sometimes all we
need to get them to get them to
convert it's just a simple
reminder they could have just
gotten distracted um or maybe they
were on the
edge of i adding to cart but
they're just waiting for a sign
from the universe to have them
pull the
trigger i know sometimes like a
lot of people they just like to
shop around they they like
shopping and
finding something but they know
they shouldn't buy it they know
they shouldn't get it and they're
just
waiting for a sign from the
universe to help them justify
making the purchase and sending a
whole email
on this to somebody is their sign
so purpose remind them um content
simple reminder dynamic abandoned
content so some winning subject
lines that you can use you can see
these are just really up front
about
the abandonment see something you
like to have your eyes on
something you've got good taste
waiting for
you ready when you are leave this
behind those are all subject lines
that you can use for any one of
these emails so you can see the
email outline here just see
something you liked and then the
clavio dynamic abandoned product
section which is literally just
whatever clavio gives you as a
base
for that flow just use that and
then we just have a couple
different images uh just lifestyle
images
to bring it to life because it is
very plain we want this to be very
plain because that's what converts
the best we don't want it we just
want to show them the item that
they left behind and then if
people
want to shop other items then we
have these buttons in the footer
as always so simple info right
there
simple reminder so now we want to
talk about some brand info and
risk reversals so
customer didn't buy just looking
at the item could be that they
just don't trust you enough
and so risk reversals in any form
of social proof can help to get
them over the edge
um so risk reversals are anything
that remove risk for the customer
um in like their purchase so
things like shipping info
guarantees like refund guarantees
um
uh refund information social proof
all this it's really good to
include in this email
email um even then maybe the
product they browsed isn't the one
they like the most so in this
email
we're starting to introduce some
further shopping options so
purpose get someone to trust you
as a
service provider a bit more to
move down the funnel content we
want a branded headline uh we want
some
risk reversals to earn their trust
the dynamic content and the
recommended products so here's
some
examples that you can use in the
subject line you can trust us
waiting for you trusted by this
many
people you may also like something
fun like your move or like we're
ready it's your move something
like
that so super simple just like
this branded headline so maybe if
i was gym shark i could say
something
like um buy buy gym by gym
enthusiasts for gym enthusiasts we
understand that yada yada yada
yada
that's why we have uh risk
guarantee right here and we have
100 000 customers to back us up um
finish your
order keep shopping and then the
uh dynamic product section to show
them what they left behind that
you
could have a you may also like
section so just put some of your
best sellers here and you should
be good
to go shop all products always
finish with a shop all products
button and then you have the
footer of
course so that's email two trying
to introduce a little bit more
social proof and then email three
we're
going a little bit harder on
social proof so testimonials
that's what we're doing for this
email so the customer still may
not trust us so we're going to
nudge them even more and
testimonials
are the best way to get people to
cross the edge and purchase as
long as you pick good testimonials
um so find a few good ones that
overcome objections in the process
and it's just like
i like this shirt no if i was gym
shark i wouldn't just want i like
the shirt i would like
one to talk about like the price
and the quality and like this one
this is so worth the price
because this reason this reason
this reason um those are going to
be a lot more effective reviews
rather than just nice shirt um so
purpose build trust and
credibility um so we just want the
testimonials and abandoned content
again very simple so winning
subject line ideas we can see we
see these
like all emoji subject lines work
pretty well sometimes um so you
could say you could do something
like that
uh the people have spoken your
item is a fan favorite here's what
others are saying customer
approved
anything like this you can add an
emoji to any one of these um and
then you could have a subject line
where it's literally just like the
testimonial and that's just the
whole subject line uh we see that
work well as well so you can see
here um we just have a testimonial
right at the top of the email
just so someone can immediately
see it the dynamic product section
and then a few more testimonials
and a little bit more of a fun
layout and then shop all products
that's all you really need for
this
email we go with that one now this
is optional you can do discounts
so a quick discount at the end of
the flow for anybody who hasn't
purchased um you can do this as
well it's optional of course
uh but the customer at this point
they have all the necessary social
proof needed to trust you to make
a purchase a small offer maybe
just a little nudge that they need
so keep it nice and simple focused
on
the offer anytime i try to make a
discount email like more fancy
it's fancy or like more
information it
always just converts worse just
give them the discount and say use
the discount so get somebody to
purchase by the
offer offer discount have the
dynamic content and then have some
social proof icons we see that in
this email rather than doing like
a ton of different information in
a long section just these little
icons do the trick so some subject
line ideas just like flash
discount special offer for you
take
10 off your order special gift for
you act fast um so just something
like this surprise take 10
off your order and then the
dynamic section which will have
the button inside of it so that's
all you really
need here for email four email
five is very similar same sort of
look but it's a closer so send
this
like one to two days after so add
a bit of urgency um for the people
who are kind of like on the edge
um this will probably be like the
second best performer in the flow
uh behind the initial email so
keep this one simple focused on
the offer and the urgency so the
subject line will take care of a
lot
of that so offer expires tonight
gone forever your offers headed
out the door by last chance to
claim your
discount all that good stuff and
then an email outline here last
chance for 10 off uh we we don't
offer
discounts often yada yada and this
expires tomorrow it's your custom
code uh whatever it may be and
then throw in your code so that's
all you need for the email five
right there and that is the whole
flow
let's look at it from a wide lens
again here we go so just five
emails one to two days apart for
each
uh starting off with like a simple
reminder then email two um then
we're trying to show them some
other
products as well as mixing some
social proof email three going
hard on social proof and then
email
four and five optional if you want
to use a discount then you can
give them a discount
so that's the whole flow and yeah
i'll see you in the next video