Okay, email marketing flows.
This is the intro to flows.
This is a big part of your email
strategy, but let us get into it.
So when we're looking at the
funnel, this is the flows that
we're talking about right down
here.
Of course, we have the signups,
website, and then signup
forms to get people onto the email
list.
We have two types of emails that
we're sending.
We have
flow emails, and then we have
campaigns.
And what we're talking about is
flows.
So let's talk about
flows, automated emails that get
sent to the customer after they
complete a specified action.
These are automated.
You set them up, you turn them
live, and then they're going to
fire
once a customer does a specific
action.
Things like joining the email
list, abandoning an item
that they added to cart, or making
a purchase, something like that.
That's going to fire some
follow-up emails for them.
So flows allow us to automate the
customer journey and send high
converting reminders, cross-sales,
and relevant information to the
customer, depending on where
they are.
So they should make up around 50%
of your total email revenue.
With around 50% coming
from campaigns, you can do 60%,
40%, 40%, 60%.
Generally, you want to be within
that range.
If you're only generating like 10%
of your email revenue from flows,
that tells you you have
a lot of extra revenue that you
can pick up.
That tells you that you can
automate more of
your revenue, because who doesn't
like automated revenue?
So you can see for this example
brand,
every 30 days, $237,000 is coming
in automatically.
And that's just on flows.
So again, why use flows?
Automated revenue.
Who doesn't like automated
revenue?
It takes pressure
off your campaigns.
So if you have really good flows
set up that are always firing, say
you only send
one campaign to your email list on
a given week, when you usually
send like three, because like
somebody
was sick on your team, you're
still going to be generating
revenue, because you have the
flows
going on in the background.
Three, it's going to convert your
high intent traffic.
So rather than having people who
abandon
an item in their cart, and then
they would otherwise just leave,
just letting them leave,
we can send high converting
emails, because they're so warm,
and we can get more revenue.
Kind of bouncing off on top of
that, abandonment flows, recover
lost sales that you would have
otherwise lost.
Somebody added an item to their
cart, and then their kid spilled a
glass of milk,
they had to go clean it up, and
they forgot what they were doing
before, we send an email
to remind them, they finished the
sale.
And then a personalized customer,
personalized the
customer experience.
So if you're telling somebody,
hey, you bought this item, you
would also like
this item, and we automate that,
then people are going to
appreciate that.
Part of their journey,
they're in the welcome flow.
They just found out about our
brand.
We're giving them information,
being like, hey, thank you so much
for being a part of like our
community, our family, yada,
yada, yada.
Personalizes it, makes people feel
special.
So that's the other thing.
And so these are the main flows
that we have set up here.
We have like the welcome flow.
So
somebody joins the list.
We have the abandonment flows,
which we'll talk about here in a
second.
Somebody somehow abandons, they
were in a shopping, they were
doing a shopping activity,
and then they leave.
These are your abandonment flows.
And then we have like
post-purchase flows,
which you can add a lot more, but
these are just like the base ones
that I'd recommend.
And so
these are the flows.
Now let's break down like each one
of them, what the Klaviyo trigger
is,
and what the filter is.
And again, we'll be talking a
little bit more in depth
here on these, each one of these.
So we have the welcome flow, which
is the trigger,
somebody joins your list.
Filter, somebody makes a purchase.
So essentially a filter is before
anybody receives any further email
in your flow, they're going to be,
Klaviyo is going to run them
through this filter and make sure
that they don't, they don't check
any of these boxes.
They haven't
done any of these things.
So Klaviyo filter, someone makes a
purchase.
So if somebody makes
a purchase, we want them to be
removed.
Same thing, same sort of thing for
site abandoned,
browse abandoned, cart abandoned,
and checkout abandoned.
These are all the abandonment
flows.
And again, I'll be showing and
going over this in a bit.
So this is just like everything in
a table
view and then post-purchase and
win back, somebody makes a
purchase, win back, somebody
hasn't purchased
in 60 plus days and we want them
to come back.
So that's a brief intro on flows
and let's get into
the specifics.