Okay, let's talk about the site
abandoned flow, probably one of my
favorite flows because not a lot
of people have it and it is very,
very underrated.
So, let's talk about it briefly.
So, the purpose, this is going to
be sent to people who visited your
site but they didn't browse any of
your products or go any further
down the funnel.
Now, there are two reasons that
people will enter this flow
because they go to the website but
they don't go any farther, they
don't look at any products.
So, two reasons, they didn't find
a product that they liked or two,
they got distracted while browsing
your site.
Those are literally the only two
options.
They didn't find something they
like enough to click onto it or
they got distracted.
So, either way, we want to be sure
that we remind them and then nudge
them to keep browsing, to find a
product that they like or to go
back to our site in case they got
distracted.
So, this is the flow, just one
email.
This is the trigger active on site
and these are all the filters.
So, essentially, any further down
the funnel, we need to make sure
that they've done that zero times
since starting this flow.
So, visit product zero times, add
to cart zero times, start at
checkout zero times, place order
zero times because if somebody
goes down to that point, like say
they go to checkout and then they
abandon, we want them to receive
the checkout abandoned flow.
Not the site abandoned, browse
abandoned, cart abandoned, and
checkout abandoned.
We only want them to receive this.
So, the last one, someone's banned
this flow zero times in the past
30 days just because some people
will go to your site like multiple
times in one week.
So, we just want to wait two to
four hours is typically what I
recommend.
Any earlier, I don't really like
that.
Just because somebody didn't find
a product they like, we just want
to get them with like a fresh mind
because if we send this to
somebody like 30 minutes after
they just browsed the site and
they didn't find a product, that's
a little bit too early.
We want to get them with a fresh
mind where it's like, eh, I'll
take another look rather than we
send it 15 minutes after they left
the site.
They're going to be like, I
literally just looked and didn't
find anything.
So, two to four hours, just need
some help, remind them to keep
shopping, and then show some of
your best sellers.
So, this is just the simple email.
Email one, just need some help.
So, we don't want to waste any
time with this.
No need for any more than one
email because this user is still
going to be receiving your
campaigns, which you should be
sending three to four times a
week.
Make sure you are.
But, essentially, we just want to
get them back on the site.
So, simply remind them to come
back, show them more products to
keep browsing.
That's it.
So, purpose, get them back on the
site.
Content, address their interest.
So, you want to tell them straight
up, like you were on our site.
You want to show them best sellers
and then offer further browsing.
So, here's some subject line
ideas.
Just like, need some help.
Did you find something you like?
Let us point you in the right
direction.
We're waiting for you.
Here's what you missed.
Did you check these out?
And then, just a super simple
outline.
Lost in choices.
Let us point you in the right
direction.
So, then you just take them to
your best sellers page and then
you just list some best sellers
here and then shop all.
That's literally all you need.
The subject line will pique their
attention.
They might just be like, eh, you
know what?
I'll keep browsing.
And then, they'll click your
button.
So, it's literally that simple.
That's all you need for the
website abandoned flow.
And this is going to pick up some
extra revenue and re-engage some
people who maybe got distracted or
didn't find a product that they
like.
Okay.