Let's do this we have the email
welcome flow this is probably the
most important flow that you are
going to have so really breaking
this down this is going to be very
compact with a ton of
information so i'm going to try to
move through it fast just so the
video isn't too long but you'll
have the document um so you can go
through it yourself um but yeah
welcome flow let's freaking
do this thing so let's talk about
the purpose of the welcome flow
and what it is so this is going
to be the sequence of emails that
is sent towards people who join
the email list and emails are
going to be sent over a period of
7 to 14 days so dialed in welcome
flow is going to allow you to
automate and then predictably
convert your customers in the
pre-purchase decision journey
so the welcome flow is going to
leave us with two possible
outcomes these are the two goals
one of
these outcome a we're going to
convert customers who are just
curious and otherwise would have
left
your site so we're converting
people we're getting more sales
and then b we want to prime future
customers for purchases now that
all objections have been addressed
so those are the two outcomes
of a welcome flow and having a
good welcome flow you're going to
get some purchases and then
anybody
who doesn't purchase you've at
least overcome all their
objections and they're ready to
buy in the
future and we don't have to worry
about overcoming objections in the
future so that is the welcome
flow so overcoming objections to
lead to a purchase so we have all
sorts of objections we want to
overcome
things like who is this brand are
they real are they going to scam
me does their product work is
the product any good is this
product worth the price yada yada
yada bottom line you need to prove
to the
customer that you can handle all
these objections and that's not
going to be a problem for them you
need to address these one by one
and it's not like you can go up to
their door give them a sales pitch
person a person that's just not
scalable and it would be extremely
expensive to do that so we have
to send content we have to send
content we have to send emails to
get people to purchase to convince
these people these people are wary
they've probably been scammed
online buying before and so we
need to
send them content we can't go to
them in person so let's send them
content how do we send them
content
email because email is the
cheapest ads are expensive let's
send them emails so how to level
up your
prospects so essentially no matter
what everybody's coming in a level
one i do not know or trust this
brand you you're able to send them
content show up proving that
you're a real brand they then
become
intrigued oh yeah i've seen this
brand before they seem legit if
you come up in conversation that's
what
they say the more content you send
maybe they get to the interested
level i like this brand but i'm
not
fully there yet maybe they don't
have a huge need for the product
right now that they realize and
then
keep sending them more content
eventually you're gonna get a
buyer where they where they like
you
they trust you and they're ready
to buy so right here they you
don't address any of them right
here
they like you right here they like
you and trust you and then right
here they're also ready to buy
and the only way we get that we
get to that point is by sending
content and emails just like the
cheapest
way to do that and doing that
through the welcome flow is the
best way to do that and so that's
why we send
eight to 12 emails rather than
just like two to three emails
because we need to have multiple
touch points with the customer so
that we earn their trust over time
because you just send somebody
one email with a ton of
information we can see here that's
not what anybody wants so the
modern customer
has a fried attention span and
they're just not going to read a
bunch of junk everybody scrolling
tiktok
instagram all day every day
attention spans are cooked
everybody's cooked um even me i
will not read
anything i will not read any
advertisement you better hand it
to me on a silver platter or else
i'm not reading it so you need to
give short bite-sized bits of
information spread out over a
time frame because the issue with
many welcome flows is that they're
way too short in length and way
too
dense in information so you're
trying to do all this stuff and
you accomplish nothing as a result
like
some brands will try to throw all
their brand information into like
two to three emails each being
super
dense like this example you try to
do something like this like
welcome to the brand yada yada
yada yada
here's everything about our brand
then customers gonna open the
email and then leave and just be
like screw this and they're just
gonna be overwhelmed whereas like
the customer if you can
cater to their needs and spread
things out like email one you just
say like welcome in here's your
discount email two here's a brief
history about that about us email
three here's your number one
bestseller
and then you just go one by one
you send short quick emails then
that's more up their alley and it
converts
better so that's part of the
reason we have our strategy so
let's talk again about what
happens
to non-buyers in the welcome flow
so many recipients just won't buy
and that is okay not a lot of
people
will most people won't they just
don't have a huge need for your
product right this second
um but that why that's why it's so
important that you're constantly
reminding them of your products
and
staying top of mind by sending
campaigns and having uh
abandonment emails so say somebody
doesn't buy in the
welcome flow your email funnel
should have the following you
should be sending three to four
educational email campaigns a week
so you stay top of mind you're
staying relevant and you're
getting consistent traffic to your
site and then you'll also have
abandonment flows so say somebody
goes to a campaign and then they
like abandon a product they click
on a campaign about a product
they add it to car and then they
leave you have your card abandoned
flows and so even if somebody
doesn't purchase from the welcome
flow we've primed them to be able
to purchase down the line
and then we're sending campaigns
to get traffic eventually they
might buy something or abandon
something and we have emails for
that as well so even if somebody
doesn't buy we have responses for
them so now we're moving fast i
know but let's break down the flow
of emails that we're sending
so this is what we have trigger
this is exactly how it should look
like in klaviyo somebody joins
your
email list so anytime somebody
joins like newsletter that's what
the trigger is um and then the
filter
which essentially before somebody
receives any one of these emails
they're going to be ran through
this filter and klaviyo is going
to determine does this person meet
these requirements
um if they don't we're not going
to send the email to them if they
do meet the requirements we're
going
to send it so the filter is made a
purchase zero times over all time
we only want people to receive
emails if they haven't purchased
before and say somebody hasn't
purchased before they receive
email
one but they buy after email one
then after one to two days klaviyo
is going to run through this
filter and be like has this person
placed an order before they have
placed an order so they're not
going to receive this email
they're not going to receive the
rest of these and so that's the
point
of the filter but let's break down
the flow a little bit and then
we're going to go over each
email so email one we just want to
give a strong introduction most
people are just going to be there
for the discount if you're giving
a discount on your cube on uh like
your pop-up or something so we
just
want to do that deliver the
discount introduce briefly like
your unique selling propositions
will make
you diff what makes you different
have a little bit of social proof
and then show some bestsellers if
people need to be pointed in the
right direction so we want to keep
that nice and simple for you
uh and then we wait one to two
days so all of the distances in
here are one to two days i
probably
wouldn't go too far over um i kind
of like to send one day apart the
first couple emails because
right when somebody enters their
email address on like a pop-up
form for you that is when the
person
is the most warm they're the most
ready to buy and so i'd rather
send them a lot of emails right
off the
bat while we have their attention
so every so the first few emails i
like to do one day apart and
then maybe like after email three
or four then you spread it to two
but email two now we want to give
brand background have a founder
story put a face to the name
sprinkle in some social proof uh
wait again
then we're highlighting a
bestseller uh wait again let's
remind them of the incentive like
hey this
isn't going to last forever um and
you can trust us email five let's
just lay out real simple for them
here's how we um compare to
competitors email six now let's
really really earn their trust if
we
don't have it yet email seven last
chance and then email eight like a
note from the founder being like
hey everything everything okay
just to give that personal touch
so let's break down each email
here
so email one just the simple
welcome we just want to keep it
nice and brief and give the people
what
they want um they're only here for
the discount maybe a quick summary
of what your brand has to offer
before they continue shopping so
keep the design simple not over
the top clean easy to follow the
goal is just we want people to
click we want to get them back on
the site so purpose strong intro
content
incentive brand unique selling
propositions social proof and best
sellers that's it so here's some
subject line examples uh don't get
too crazy here usually you can
just do welcome to this brand and
so
you can see what i mean here with
the uh outline in terms of it's
not anything crazy welcome to the
brand
notice how the discount code in
the button is all the way at the
top of the email as high up as we
can go so that people can just see
the discount super easy right off
the bat and leave and then we
have a little bit of body copy
give some background to like what
makes your brand different maybe
sprinkle
in some social proof like how many
items you've sold how many five
star reviews you have yada yada
shop now and then show some of
your best sellers and then
continue to shop so super simple
hero section
bridge product section um and this
is the type of content that you
want to be sending so use this
outline for yourself now email to
brand story people haven't made a
purchase yet probably because
you're faceless brand and they
randomly stumbled across you on an
ad enter their email address
because why not um you offered a
discount and so yeah so we want to
slowly get these people to believe
that we're real brand with real
mission we're not just like a big
corporation trying to steal your
money
so we just want to earn our trust
points and remind them of the
discount with this email um this
email will
make some sales but the real
purchase is just prime them for a
purchase down the line get them
personally
attached to you um so that's the
purpose here give some brand
background to bring them closer
to the brand content talk a little
bit about the founding story
mission statement show a face if
you can it's going to help
conversions a ton if you show a
face give a personal feel and then
remind
of the discount as well so subject
line ideas that you can do here a
note from the founder the brains
behind it all meet the guys gals
meet the team whatever you want
our story this is us here's a bit
more about us something like that
usually something like our story
is good enough so this is a great
outline that you can use our story
just fill this information with
how you guys got started really
really brief don't write an essay
just keep it nice and simple um
just keep it nice and simple don't
do anything too crazy and then
we like to have a if you can show
the founder if the founders open
to it um if you as the founder are
open to it include a photo it
makes it so much more personal and
the conversions will skyrocket
and then just have some branded
images down here and then a ps is
always helpful here make this like
an important feature about you
guys but just talk about your
story show face and that's going
to help
people purchase down the line
realizing you're not just a big
big person trying to like steal
steal their money
yada yada yada so let's move on to
email three here which are your
brand usps which are unique
selling propositions so the
customer has a bit of trust from
us they know us and they know the
discount
let's get them thinking how
awesome we are so let's lay out
our benefits super clearly for
them give them
all the info that they need to
make a purchase from us in just an
organized fashion show so purpose
show off
unique selling propositions and
why you stand out content
highlight your mission statement
explain super
clearly why you stand out remind
of the discount again every single
email we're reminding in the
discount so subject line ideas our
mission not your average
supplement brand or whatever it
may be
made for you how we shine what
makes us so special uh things like
that are super easy and you can
see
what i mean by making it super
clear for the customers so state
your brand mission statement just
right at the
top remind of the discount again
um a button and then just list out
your selling points hand it to
them on a silver
platter um we give back x amount
of money to non-profits all our
materials are made in the us uh
you could do like if you're a
supplement brand all our
ingredients are organic and they
are proven by
this like i don't know quality
check system i don't know then
show the products a little bit so
really
we just want to make it super
clear for them these are the main
points of what makes us different
and then four let's address the
discount again so uh the customer
knows a bit about our brand
they believes we're legit now
they've heard from us a couple
times and so let's introduce some
urgency
to try to get them to cross the
line if they haven't already so
add some social proof and risk
reversals
and this email will crush so
social proof is testimonials
anything to prove that like you're
a real brand
risk reversals are things that
remove risk so um we have a money
back guarantee um if you don't get
your order if you don't get your
order within like five days we
refund you whatever risk reversals
you
have include those so purpose
introduce urgency try to get them
to buy on the spot uh content at
urgency risk reversals give
testimonials so subject line ideas
you can get a little bit more
aggressive
with this so something like
pending claim your discount blank
percent off your first order don't
forget
we can't hold this forever welcome
discount expiring so i like to
address things really right up
front
do you still want this discount
still want this discount reminder
uh have a little bit of urgency
on like hey this discount isn't
lasting forever it's only on your
first purchase um we can't extend
this
for you forever yada yada yada
reminder the discount shop now
then we have things like risk
reversals
like free shipping uh easy returns
and exchanges we're trusted since
this amount of time some social
proof
there and then more social proof
with some testimonials so people
can see exactly what
other people are saying um and
this email will do really well
because it's really just actually
telling them like hey this isn't
going to be here forever and then
even if they don't buy we gave
them
some social proof so good stuff
there then email five is going to
be kind of similar to email three
we're just going to show us versus
them directly it's just an easy
way to show your benefits is
compare
you to competitors so the elephant
in the room is your competitors so
why should somebody go with
you over someone else people just
love pros and cons they like
comparing and contrasting it's how
the brain likes to work um so we
want to give that to them and make
it obvious that like we're the
best
choice but make it seem like
they've made the decision for
themselves um so that's what we're
providing them so address it up
front and lay out the facts for
the customer so they can see the
full story so address the
competitors outline your unique
selling propositions and
distinguish your brand from others
so some subject line ideas us
versus them here are the facts why
we shine the nike difference
whatever your uh whatever it is
and then yeah so here's like the
simple
outline that we use here this
header section is super cool um
you can just like list out a quick
feature
um of specifically what you do
like maybe you say 20 donated and
then this brand it's like they
20 of revenue donated or something
then you could say only donate the
profit which is a lower amount
or like they cap their donations
at x amount we use this material
they use this they use this and
you
don't need to say who the
competitors are you can just like
hint at it and then remind of the
discount
again and then outline some
products as well talking about how
they're how they're different how
they're
special so that's what we like to
do in this email just to really
clearly lay it out for people
again to reinforce to them why
we're different email six
testimonials again proving that we
are
a real brand people buy from us
and they like us so we want to
like just make sure no matter what
that
the customer knows our product and
brand is great so maybe eat it's
fine if they don't have a strong
need for our product right now
like if you sell t-shirts for
example like lululemon maybe i
have a ton
of t-shirts in my closet and i
don't want to buy right now that's
okay i just want to make sure that
they fully trust our brand to
where if they do have a need in
the future they will come back to
us
so by creating a whole email out
of this it just proves that we're
confident in our product and
we'll stand by it and even that
alone just having a full email
dedicated to this will go a long
ways
so that's the purpose prove our
brand is reputable that our
products create happy customers we
want to
feature testimonials media
features and any content that can
prove that we're real so as for
subject lines
you can literally just have like a
testimonial as your subject line
um you can say like don't believe
us we're kind of a big deal if you
want to be a little bit snarky um
and the votes are in what
the fans say our customers have
spoken things like that then
here's the outline simple again as
well
will feature a quick testimonial
at the top maybe just like omg
this is my favorite brand whatever
it
is and then you can say something
like don't just listen to us take
it from our 10 000 plus happy
customers and then super clear
about the discount here's a
reminder the discount and then
branded
photo and then a few more
testimonials down here and then
friendly reminder that your access
to this
discount is expiring so adding a
little bit more urgency so that
right there give a few
testimonials
to keep earning some trust an
email seven here we are last
chance let's have some urgency so
at this
point customer has all the info
they need to make a purchase as
long as you've uh done everything
you
need with a copy and most of your
audience probably would buy from
you they're probably ready to buy
at this point but they're just
waiting for the right time to do
it they're putting it off and
waiting
until they need it so by going
hard on urgency we kind of force
their hand of just like hey if you
want
10 off you got to buy now so give
the customer last chance use a
timer urgency based graphic talk
about
your discount is expiring just
keep it super simple just have the
focus on the urgency so subject
line
ideas gone forever last chance for
this discount final opportunity
tomorrow's the last day something
like that so look at how simple
this email is beautiful just a
flyer your access is expiring
10 off last chance um you could
say like elegant outfits await as
like brand info and then ads of
urgency being like this is your
absolute last chance we can't hold
this for you much longer
yada yada yada and so super simple
and super easy for somebody to
click and start shopping
that always has great click rates
and then this is the last email in
the welcome flow so the customer
didn't purchase right off the bat
so what that's okay most won't
maybe they just weren't ready
but we might still be able to get
a few over the line with a nice
personal text-based email which
these perform super well across no
matter what account we work on um
so this is also going to prime
the customer for future purchases
knowing that the brand owner is
willing to reach out if you can
make it
from the brand owner um and then
also they might have a real
objection that hasn't been
addressed
and so we want to give them the
opportunity to like reply to this
email hit up the support team if
they
have any questions so purpose
personal reminder and a last
chance message uh to really let
the customer
know that we care about them so
contents a text-based email
reminder the discount code and
then offer some
resources so you could say
something like is everything okay
in the subject line just checking
in we're here to help all good
let us know if you need anything
then here's the outline just like
hey there i hope our previous
emails have been a warm welcome uh
we noticed you didn't use your
welcome discount since you're new
we've extended it for one more day
extensions work really well and so
you can do that and shop now
you say something as simple as
feel free to reply to this email
if you have any questions the xyz
team
and this email is going to clean
up a lot of people who didn't
purchase and then also you're
going to be
able to get people down the line
to purchase and get people to
potentially reach out down the
line if
they have questions because they
know that you reply to your email
so that is the full eight email
welcome flow let's just go back
here uh just flashing all these so
you can see them and then we can
go
look at the full flow here again
uh trigger and filter um strong
introduction brand background to
build trust
best sellers promo to try to get
them to focus on that email um or
unique selling propositions that's
really
like the main thing that we're
doing with that email reminder of
the incentive us versus them
heavy social proof last chance
incentive and then a note from the
founder so that is the welcome
flow
one of the most important flows
make sure you nail this and then
you'll be good to go and this can
generate you a lot of money