Okay last but of course not least
we have the win back flow which is
going to do kind of how it
sounds when people back it's very
straightforward we just want to
encourage people to make another
purchase these are past customers
and we want them to come back so
do not overthink this flow
the thing is like your customers
are still receiving your campaign
emails they're still
receiving like your sales and
whatever else you're blasting to
your list and if you're like us
and you have an optimized email
channel you're sending three to
four email campaigns a week so
somebody made a purchase three
four months ago and you're sending
three to four email campaigns a
week
that's going to handle a lot of
your repeat purchases 99 of your
attention in repeat purchases
will come from your campaigns so
for this reason we keep the win
back flow nice and simple and it's
more for like customer experience
and to at least automate a part of
the customer journey just to
be like hey we notice you haven't
bought in a while it's you don't
really get too many sales i
haven't
seen a win back flow like generate
crazy money for every brand that
i've looked in and even like me
trying to like optimize the heck
out of it it's just not how it
works a lot of people will just
convert from your campaigns so
it's more for the customer
experience um so let's break down
the flow
really simple just three emails
the trigger we're just doing a
placed order trigger then we're
adding
a filter made a purchase zero
times to start in this flow then
we have a 90 to 120 day time delay
so you could do that um what you
could also do is you could have a
segment based trigger so what you
do
is you create a segment inside of
klaviyo and what you say is
somebody placed an order um is at
least is
90 days ago or is at least is
after 90 days and so then anytime
somebody enters that flow you or
anybody
enters that segment you have a
flow set up so you create a flow
and then you have the trigger beat
somebody joins a segment and then
you set that as the segment for
the person's last purchase was 90
days ago um so that's my ideal way
of doing it but for simplicity
sake i just did this so with email
one email two email three email
one just a quick it's been a while
remind them of the brand encourage
them to come back for another
purchase just be like hey it's
been a while since your last
purchase we
miss you yada yada more for
customer experience and then we
wait seven days and then this is
where we can
introduce a discount make them
feel special with a unique
discount um to try to get them
back wait
seven days and then you can do a
text-based last chance from the
founder and reminding them of it
you can set whatever time delay
you want if you're like a hot tub
company you probably have a very
long time period between purchases
so you could set this to like a
year um but um for stuff like
supplements or something it might
be helpful to do like 120 day win
back uh flow um because usually
the
purchase periods are a lot shorter
so email one which is going to be
let's say 120 days um it's
been a while this email is purely
for client experience let them
know we're thinking about
them we want to give them the
sense that we're not just a big
company and this goes a long ways
being
able to customize things like this
i don't know why that's opening
but it goes a very long ways
so just keep it simple so the
purpose make them feel special and
like they're missed for a repeat
purchase so our subject lines are
just addressing that saying it's
been a while hey how's it been
let's catch up we miss you is it
time for restock new memories
await something like that and so
for
this email we like to say uh we
like to have this layout for it's
been a while have some have a
branded
image in the background add body
copy here about like hey it's been
a while it's time to stock back
up yada yada yada all that good
stuff and then you can say like
you've missed a lot um we're
always
releasing new products something
like that or you could do like
some social proof in this section
if
you want uh whatever you want to
do and then you can have some
products here so this is a cool
little
product section you just say shop
what you miss shop our favorites
something like that and this is
going to work really well just for
customer experience it usually
gets pretty good engagement
and then if you want to run a
discount for win back people to
try to get them back after a
certain
amount of time you can set
whatever time delay you want but
email to discount open even if you
ran
sales since customers last
purchase they may have just been
at the wrong time and then adding
a
discount that's specific to the
customer makes it clear that we're
trying to get them back and that
could get them over the edge it's
a custom discount it's not there
it's not like a generic spring 20
for
like a spring sale type of thing
um so some winning subject lines
uh x percent off just for you
just because we miss you take x
percent off your order limited
discount inside we got you a gift
notice how personal these are and
being like this is yours so take
10 off your next order you can use
this code miss you a 10 for 10 off
i just did miss you a 10 um what i
would recommend for a lot of the
discount codes is use one that
looks random so you can say like
miss you a dash seven x seven x
four z
and then have that as a static
code in shopify but it looks
custom to the person they can have
just
a product image or lifestyle image
and then just a couple of your
features again shop 10 off as the
buttons super simple nothing crazy
just get them to click and make a
purchase and then email three we
have a text-based discount closer
from the founder people just love
text-based emails from the founder
and offering them a final chance
for the exclusive discount just
because they miss them it's huge
for
the customer experience and
getting conversions and showing to
them we're not just some big
corporate
brand who doesn't care about you
after you make a purchase we're a
small enough brand where we have
the
founder reaching out to you and
offering a discount and saying we
miss you like that goes a long
ways
so add urgency and a personal
touch acknowledge they haven't
bought in a while so just be
straight up
with it offer them support and
give a last chance just checking
in for subject lines just checking
in
do you still want x percent off
are you still interested last
chance last chance to claim your
debt uh your gift have it from the
founder you just say something as
simple as this uh i noticed it's
been
quite some time since your last
purchase i wanted to check in make
sure everything was okay if with
your last order if it if nothing
if it wasn't good just let us know
uh if you did love i have an
exclusive discount just for you
use code yada yada for 10 off
thank you for for your support and
that's
it for the win back flow a lot of
your a lot of your retention will
be handled by campaigns so don't
overthink this like your big your
sales that you're running for
memorial day labor day a lot of
that is going to get
people so uh don't try to get too
crazy with this because you'll
just spend a lot of time for flow
that not a lot of people will
convert from so that is the win
back flow and yeah there we go
okay last but of course not least
we have the win back flow which is
going to do kind of how it
sounds win people back it's very
straightforward we just want to
encourage people to make another
purchase um these are past
customers and we want them to come
back so do not overthink this flow
um the thing is like your
customers are still receiving your
campaign emails they're still
uh receiving like your sales and
whatever else you're blasting to
your list and if you're like us
and you have an optimized email um
channel you're sending three to
four email campaigns a week so
somebody made a purchase three
four months ago and you're sending
three to four email campaigns a
week
that's going to handle a lot of
your repeat purchases 99 of your
attention and repeat purchases
will come
from your campaigns so for this
reason we keep the win back flow
nice and simple and it's more for
like
customer experience and to at
least automate a part of the
customer journey uh just to be
like hey we
noticed you haven't bought in a
while it's you don't really get
too many sales i haven't seen a
win
back flow like generate crazy
money for every brand that i've
looked in and even like me trying
to like
optimize the heck out of it it's
just not how it works a lot of
people will just convert from your
campaigns so it's more for the
customer experience um so let's
break down the flow
really simple just three emails
the trigger we're just doing a
placed order trigger then we're
adding
a filter made a purchase zero
times to start in this flow then
we have a 90 to 120 day time delay
so
you could do that um what you
could also do is you could have a
segment based trigger so what you
do
is you create a segment inside of
klaviyo and what you say is
somebody placed an order um is at
least is
90 days ago or is at least is
after 90 days and so then anytime
somebody enters that flow you or
anybody
enters that segment you have a
flow set up so you create a flow
and then you have the trigger beat
somebody joins a segment and then
you set that as the segment for
the person's last purchase was 90
days
ago um so that's my ideal way of
doing it but for simplicity's sake
i just did this so with email one
email two email three email one
just a quick it's been a while
remind them of the brand encourage
them to come back for another
purchase just be like hey it's
been a while since your last
purchase we
miss you yada yada yada more for
customer experience and then we
wait seven days and then this is
where
we can introduce a discount make
them feel special with a unique
discount um to try to get them
back
wait seven days and then you can
do a text-based last chance from
the founder and reminding them of
it you can set whatever time delay
you want if you're like a hot tub
company you probably have a very
long time period between purchases
so you could set this to like a
year um but um for stuff like
supplements or something it might
be helpful to do like 120 day win
back uh flow um because usually
the purchase periods are a lot
shorter so email one which is
going to be let's say 120 days um
it's
been a while this email is purely
for client experience let them
know we're thinking about them we
want to
give them the sense that we're not
just a big company and this goes a
long ways being able to
customize things like this i don't
know why that's opening but it
goes a very long ways
so just keep it simple so the
purpose make them feel special and
like they're missed for a repeat
purchase so our subject lines are
just addressing that saying it's
been a while hey how's it been
let's catch up we miss you it's a
time for restock new memories
await something like that and so
for this
email we like to say uh we like to
have this layout for it's been a
while have some have a branded
image in
the background add body copy here
about like hey it's been a while
it's time to stock back up
yada yada yada all that good stuff
and then you can say like you've
missed a lot um we're always
releasing new products something
like that or you can do like some
social proof in this section if
you
want uh whatever you want to do
and then you can have some
products here so this is a cool
little
product section you just say shop
what you miss shop our favorites
something like that and this is
going to work really well just for
customer experience it usually
gets pretty good engagement
and then if you want to run a
discount for win back people to
try to get them back after a
certain
amount of time you can set
whatever time delay you want but
email to discount open even if you
ran
sales since customers last
purchase they may have just been
at the wrong time and then adding
a
discount that's specific to the
customer makes it clear that we're
trying to get them back and that
could get them over the edge it's
a custom discount it's not there
it's not like a generic spring 20
for like a spring sale type of
thing um so some winning subject
lines uh x percent off just for
you
just because we miss you take x
percent off your order limited
discount inside we got you a gift
notice how personal these are and
being like this is yours so take
10 off your next order you can use
this code missya10 for 10 off i
just did missya10 um what i would
recommend for a lot of the
discount codes is use one that
looks random so you can say like
missya dash 7x7x4z and then have
that as a static code in shopify
but it looks custom to the person
they can have just like a
product image or lifestyle image
and then just a couple of your
features again shop 10 off as the
buttons super simple nothing crazy
just get them to click and make a
purchase and then email three we
have a text-based discount closer
from the founder people just love
text-based emails from the founder
and offering them a final chance
for the exclusive discount just
because they miss them it's huge
for
the customer experience and
getting conversions and showing to
them we're not just some big
corporate brand
who doesn't care about you after
you make a purchase we're a small
enough brand where we have the
founder reaching out to you and
offering a discount and saying we
miss you like that goes a long
ways
so at urgency and a personal touch
acknowledge they haven't bought in
a while so just be straight up
with it offer them support and
give a last chance just checking
in for subject lines just checking
in
do you still want x percent off
are you still interested last
chance last chance to claim your
uh your gift have it from the
founder you just say something as
simple as this uh i noticed it's
been
quite some time since your last
purchase i wanted to check in make
sure everything was okay if with
your last order if it if nothing
if it wasn't good just let us know
uh if you did love i have an
exclusive discount just for you
use code yada yada for 10 off
thank you for for your support and
that's
it for the win back flow a lot of
your a lot of your retention will
be handled by campaigns so don't
overthink this like your big your
sales that you're running for
memorial day labor day a lot of
that
is going to get people so uh don't
try to get too crazy with this
because you'll just spend a lot of
time for flow that not a lot of
people will convert from so that
is the win back flow and yeah
there we go