What's up guys Lucas here so in
this one I'm gonna be showing you
guys the email
deliverability and reputation
manager workflow so as you guys
know if you're
going to be running both cold
email or also actually email for
e-com brands
your domain reputation is very
important you're gonna have to
check to
make sure that your emails are
going to spam you know it's a big
part of that
whole process so what we developed
here is a flow that runs on a
schedule that
will check your domains to ensure
that they are still all good and
provide the
maximum deliverability for your
email accounts so as usual I'm
gonna walk you
through the different nodes in
this flow I'm gonna explain
anything you'll need to
edit or set and then kind of what
it sort of looks like at the end
result now with
this flow we're actually going to
be using for the first time what
we call
variables and variables very
simply are just a set of keys or
information you can
create and reference in any of
your flows they're very handy for
things like API
keys so that's exactly what we're
using it for here so you will need
an account over
at MX Toolbox now this is
mxtoolbox.com if we go to the main
page here you can see
there's a ton of domain related
tools all you need to know is that
when you get to
this site on the main site here
you're going to click your name
and click settings
then you're going to go over to
API and get your API key once you
have that if you go back
to our flow here you're going to
see variables here on the left
hand side now I open this in a new
tab and very simply it looks like
this you're going to click add
variable and you're going to name
it MX Toolbox API and paste your
API key in here now we've done
that as you can see and you can
see here we've got copy to
clipboard virus dot mxtoolbox API
and paste your API key in here now
we've done that as you can see and
you can see here we've got copy to
clipboard virus dot mxtoolbox API
and paste your API key in here now
we've done that as you can see and
you can see here we've got copy to
clipboard virus dot mxtoolbox API
and paste your API key in here.
mxtoolbox API so basically we can
now reference that API key in our
workflow this is so that you don't
have to go through every node
separately and you know copy and
paste your API key the entire time
very simply all we do here is uh
later on in the process we're
going to show you where to where
to put that uh how that's set up
so that it'll automatically pull
in your API key but uh how does
this work so there's a few ways
that this can kind of be triggered
it'll be triggered by an email
provider event so maybe your email
provider like smart lead or
something
uh you know can notify you can
notify you if a domain is
disconnected or if there's an
issue with it in which case you
can run this flow uh or by doing
it uh a forum trigger a manual
assessment and then we can run the
trigger on a continuous monitoring
or weekly audit weekly audit is
probably the best in terms of
keeping your API costs down you
should not have to pay for
mxtoolbox if you're just doing a
weekly audit should be fine
so if we go over here we're going
to see how this works so let's see
here from the form from the form
trigger i double click it at this
go to schema version
you can see the assessment type
we've chosen is a pre-campaign
validation this is essentially
you're running this before you
have started sending out your
email campaigns
you put in your domain name uh
your ip address uh the email
service provider uh the campaign
volume
the urgency level of checking this
as if for instance if there is a
performance issue or we're just
checking
beforehand uh add additional notes
this is for your own records that
we're going to save all of this in
air table so that runs and that's
we did a manual assessment so
we've got the manual assessment
data here
just get set it's the same stuff
that we had over here before then
what this does is it goes to the
mxtoolbox
blacklist check this checks if it
has been blacklisted then the spf
record check dkim record check and
the dmark policy check
basically all the things you want
to check to make sure your domains
deliverability is at the peak that
it
should be so let's take a look in
here we're going to see how we set
that api key we've already got all
the information
you need in here that's all set up
and good to go but if you go down
here you're going to see the
authorization and this is our
variable that we got from here
right so if you name this mx
toolbox api
that and put your your api key in
here then this will work
automatically but uh say you named
it
something else you wanted to add a
variable it's very simple as we
saw over here you copy this
make sure the word bearer and
space is in there for that's the
type of authentication that the mx
toolbox
api uses then we do a space to uh
curly brackets there we go that's
it paste it in so if we've got
the setup for you so just go to uh
variables create one named mx
toolbox api paste in your api key
and
then everything else will work so
then it runs through all of those
before we send it to an ai to make
an
analysis of it where it gives us a
score a grade a summary uh notes
any issues uh and ways to fix this
and then we save it to an air
table base so i'm going to share
the air table base that i've
created
for this uh with you guys so you
guys can essentially copy it uh
but all this does here is it
stores the
assessment in the air table base
so this is what it looks like uh
it's just called domain risk
manager
and if you go across here you can
see it's got all the information
we need gives us the
different uh results the score the
timestamp and the recommendations
and then the status
so this just helps us to keep
track of everything and make sure
that everything is all running
smoothly
uh we can check this on a regular
basis but also we want to be
notified if there's a problem
right
so it checks the alert threshold
so basically if the alert is or
the domain score is less than 70
it will send us uh an alert and if
not it just sends us the status
report after the thing is run
saying it's all good here's what
we've got so far so either way
you're getting a message in slack
either saying that there's a
critical alert or that everything
is all good and again as i've
shown you
in previous videos to set up slack
you simply just add your slack
account then choose whether you
want
the message to go to a channel or
to a user so you can send it to a
channel uh you know it's gonna be
your email to really check our
channel to make sure it's working
okay uh you just send message to
channel instead of user and select
your channel from here or select
user and then as i have done
select my username from slack and
that's how the slack notifications
work so again if you just roll
through this super quick you will
trigger the manual assessment by
uh opening the form and inputting
uh all of this information here
then it will send that through to
mx toolbox where we check all of
the
different uh things we need to
know about the domain our ai
summarizes it in a nice report
stores it in
air table and then sends us a
message in slack so again i will
share this uh air table base uh
with
you so you guys can copy it
exactly if you make a base and you
name it domain risk manager you
name
the table deliverability
assessments and add these fields
then we will be good to go uh you
also if
you're totally free to swap this
out for a google sheet it'd be the
exact same process you would
simply
just add a google sheet node and
you would change adding uh all
these uh different outputs that
you
get here so you don't score grade
summary issues remediation
optimizations just got all that
stuff
there so that's the basis of how
it works um hopefully this will be
a super useful one for you guys
especially any of you guys that
are doing uh both cold email
marketing and e-com email
marketing
and uh yeah i'll see you guys in
the next one peace