What's up guys, Lucas here.
So in this one I'm going to be
showing you a pretty simple but
very important workflow.
What this does is it makes a daily
report on your smart lead campaign
statistics as well as the health
of your domains and campaigns.
It also alerts you if your bounce
rate goes above 10%.
So this is super helpful for one,
just getting an overview of kind
of how your campaigns are doing on
a day-to-day basis,
as well as watching out for any
burn domains that may be affecting
your deliverability.
So let's take a look at what this
does and what you're going to have
to set up.
So you'll need to set up Google
Sheets using the Google Sheets
account and you need to set up
Slack as usual.
The only other thing you're going
to need for this is going to be
your smart lead API key.
And where you put that is on all
these nodes here, wherever you see
the little globe with HTTP
requests,
you're going to put this in, but
it's very simple.
Let's see here API key to get
this, go to smart lead, go to your
account icon over here, click
settings and click copy key.
And then you're just going to
paste that right in there.
And that's all you need to do.
So what this one does is it gets
different metrics for your domain.
If we look at the split out node,
you can see that we've got 293
items in total.
It basically goes over the entire
of the time that the campaign is
run and we update.
It gets to see how many emails are
sent, replied, bound, subscribed,
all those sort of things.
So it updates our sheet here daily
with that information.
This one does the same thing, but
for campaigns overall, this was
for each individual domain.
This just does it for campaigns.
So we check here, you can see
we've got two campaigns about a
hero section campaign and welcome
flow campaign.
How many sent, replied, bounced,
open rate, all our metrics here.
And this keeps it updated in a
Google sheet here.
And this trigger sets run every 24
hours.
It will also send us a Slack
message with the, you can see here
what it looks like.
It'll say just the date, the
campaign name, email sent, emails
open, replies, bounced.
Now, the reason it was open to
zero is because I'm not tracking
email opens.
But this just gives you a daily
summary of kind of how the
campaign is doing.
Then domain health checks the
health of your domains by looking
for bounced emails.
You can see here we get the same
information out again.
This is the domain health metrics.
So you can see all the information
we get here for each domain that
we have.
This is going to go down.
There's a bunch along here for the
table, a bit easier to see.
Yes, we've got nine domains here
and it's going to, or 10, I think
the total.
And it's going to update our
Google sheet with that
information.
And then what this does, it says
if the total bounce rate is above
10%,
then it sends us a message in
Slack saying, yo, critical bounce
rate and gives us all the
information we need on the metrics
so that you can go and quickly
take a look.
It says immediate action needed.
Stop all campaigns in this domain
now.
Check for domain blacklist
immediately.
identify authentication records
gives you an idea of kind of what
you should do straight away.
This is the same, but for overall
campaigns.
If the campaigns are doing poorly
and if the bounce rate is too
high, it will do the exact same
thing.
Critical bounce rate alert, the
severity, and give you all the
information that you need in order
to make sure that you are keeping
track of which domains and which
campaigns are currently
performing.
And which have high bounce rates
that could be affecting your
deliverability and overall domain
health and sender reputation.
So, as you can see, this is a
little bit more advanced than just
doing your basic, you know, daily
campaign reporting.
We've got that in there.
We're also setting up alerts for
high bounce rates and we're
keeping track of our domain
metrics.
We can analyze those over times
and see if anything we can do to
improve it and improve our overall
cold email setup, domain setup,
and deliverability.
So, it makes it super easy just to
keep track of everything and
really helpful reporting to your
clients as well.
You know, you could even put this
in the client channel with them so
they can see, say, for the daily
campaign metrics, how many sends,
the replies, et cetera, et cetera,
et cetera.
So, super useful.
As I said, kind of simple, pretty
basic and straightforward.
All you're going to need to set up
again, just get your Smart Lead
API key and just paste it in
wherever it says API key in here.
And you are going to want to set
up your Google Sheets and your
Slack.
And that's it.
Simple but important.
And make sure you got this one set
up if you are running lead
generation email campaigns for
your clients.
I hope this is helpful and I will
see you in the next one.
Peace.