What's up guys, Lucas here.
Today I'm going to be going over
the cold email script writer
workflow.
Now this is for if you want to
create cold email campaigns at
scale using a CSV file of leads.
If you've got a CSV with say a
thousand prospects in there
and you want to write personalized
emails for each of them,
that's what this is going to do.
Now we have other videos showing
you how to use the client
ascension AI dashboard
to also create your cold email
templates and scripts.
So make sure to check out that
video as well from Christian
and use these based on, you know,
your different kind of use cases.
If you're only doing a small
amount of campaigns for, you know,
a certain number of lists,
leads, and you just want to write
a template to kind of, you know,
send out to a few people at a
time, then follow the CIA
dashboard video.
If you are doing mass campaigns
and you specifically want to
personalize them,
then try using this workflow.
So as usual, I'm going to go over
what you need to have set up and
what is involved in this.
So let's take a look and see what
we have here.
So we will need your Google Sheets
connected.
Do you just use your Google Sheets
account to log in?
You'll be good to go.
You will need, as usual, open
router.
We use perplexity for the
research.
So we'll suggest setting your
perplexity there.
As usual, you just go here, get
your perplexity API key, put it in
there, and you'll be good to go.
And we will need Slack set up.
And as we've talked about in other
videos, you just connect your
Slack account, log in.
It's all good to go.
So one thing I want to note is
this little active button up here.
Basically, the way this works is
that once this workflow is set to
active, once you get your campaign
request form URL and you submit
that URL,
that will cause this whole
workflow to trigger.
So essentially, the way this works
for any workflow that goes off of
a form is you can create a
bookmark or create a list of all
your different forms that you need
to input to trigger certain
workflows.
And just once it's set to active
up here, when you submit that
form, those workflows will
trigger.
So let's take a look at what the
form looks like.
This is it.
It's very basic.
You're going to put in your name,
your title, a description of your
product or service, your value
proposition, your company website,
and you're going to upload your
lead list CSV.
Once you do that, then this
situation runs where we process
the CSV, normalize the data, and
we process the other form data as
well for merging it together.
And then we create an empty blank
spreadsheet that will be named
just cold email campaigns and the
date and time that it was it was
run.
After that, we will generate an
email sequence.
Now, these are generated based on
writings from Christian and his
previous examples.
We actually have a full list in
here of 30 scripts that won a
breakdown, how to write a good
cold email, and we have
instructions here directly on how
to write the cold email, including
your product on offering and
things like that.
Then that runs.
And we also have this up as an
output parser.
What the output parser really just
means is that instead of giving us
one string called output, it
breaks it down by how we delineate
it.
So we have told the output parser
that we want, uh, things like a,
uh, as a object, uh, sorry, the
email sequence, uh, we want the
timing, the subject suggestion,
the body CTA framework, key
elements, personalization, use
required things like this.
So that now when the AI generates
this, we get email number, timing,
subject suggestion, body, CTA
framework, key elements, et
cetera, like that throughout it.
Um, that will generate the basic
body of your email template.
Then what do we do is we actually
research the prospect afterwards.
We do a prospect research agent
use perplexity to do a detailed
research on the prospect.
Now I use an example, lead list
CSV.
I don't think they're actually
real people.
Um, but, uh, it did some research
on the first one was a law firm.
So it gave us, I'm going to go to
a conversation starters, a
personalized first line, uh, some
like the objections.
Uh, and these are also all based
around our, uh, service as well.
The service that we chose for this
was a, uh, content repurposing
service.
And we'd save them, you know, a
hundred hours or per month on, on
content creation.
Uh, after that, we send that to a
first line writer and this was, he
writes a personalized first line
for the prospect based again on
what you do and on the research we
have from over here.
So the one is after seeing the ABA
2023 tech report showing attorneys
using 40% of billable times and
non billable tasks like content
creation.
I've been curious how Grimes and
Huff balances thought leadership
with the pressure to maximize
partner productivity.
Then we create some AB variants of
our emails, including some first
lines as well.
So we end up with, uh, uh, three
variants in total, just AB tests
of our emails.
And finally we format all of
these, and this is what's going to
go into our CSV.
So you end up with the CSV,
they'll have the prospect name,
their email, the formatted
personalized, uh, email, the
company name, email one, two, and
three in the sequence, and then
various AB and C.
And if we check our CSV here, this
is what it looks like.
Now I have customized this
afterwards when the, when the, the
first, uh, row here is put in,
it'll just look like this Texas
white text, but you can then
modify it afterwards to make it a
bit easier to read.
And it'll, uh, update normally
then after that.
So prospect name, Victor Cochran
email company name.
Hi, Victor.
After seeing the AB 23, but we
just, the first time we just
talked about.
So with this whole content
production, getting a lot of
references to pieces, we have to
market teams have 10 plus hours.
Hope it was a quick chat about
your content workflow.
Uh, hi, Victor, struggling with
slow content production, getting a
lot of references to pieces.
Uh, hey, Victor, I put together a
short video showing you how you
can 10 extra content output,
creating anything new.
Victor, reaching out one last
time.
And then the very inside, Victor,
same first line.
Right now your partners will be
suffering from the bill of virus.
The draft should be thought you've
forgotten while struggling to keep
your digital presence consistently
updated.
Imagine this day that your
training is focusing solely on
billable work.
Uh, this one, did you know, clear
24 legal trends research revealed
first hosting weekly thought.
Later should be 46% hard client
conversation.
Uh, then I, Victor, many firms at
Grimes show the products needing
consistent thought issue.
But the ABI tech part shows the
trainers who's nearly half their
weeks and not available tasks.
So you get a bunch of emails out
there.
And the, uh, way this workflow
works is that once it finishes the
first prospect, it loops.
And it writes these for every
prospect.
So if you've got a hundred
prospects, it will write, uh, a
hundred of these emails and update
the, uh, CSV with those hundred
emails.
So that is essentially, uh, oh
yeah.
Finally, when it's done doing
that, it will notify you in Slack
telling you, Hey, uh, these are
all finished.
Uh, go check it out and a link to
the document.
So that's basically how this works
again, when you want to use this,
you're going to get this, uh,
NNJSON, you're going to copy it.
You're going to paste it into
your, uh, own NN, uh, workspace,
or you're going to do the three
dots and import from the file and
import the JSON file.
Uh, it will look like this.
You will get a red, uh, error on
Google docs, on, uh, Slack, uh,
perplexity and open writer.
So you have to set all those up,
just your accounts.
And then, uh, you will have to,
once they're all set up, they're
good to go.
Uh, you will set the workflow live
and you will do a test by putting
in probably a CSV of maybe just,
you know, one contact entity to
test it.
Upload it through the form to get
the form URL, you'll go here and
you'll go to production URL and
copy that.
And then paste that into a new
browser window.
It'll look like this.
You'll fill that out, uh, submit
it, and then watch it run through
and make sure that it is working
appropriately.
So that's the basics of how this
workflow works.
Again, as I said, if you are just
wanting to write one email
template to be used with a number
of prospects with no
personalization, then use the CA
AI dashboard and watch the video
from Christian, how to do that.
But if you want to process a large
number of prospects and write
personalized emails for them,
then, uh, you will run it through
this.
This is one of those things that
you can test.
You can run two campaigns.
You can try one with no
personalization, one with
personalization, see which
performs better.
Um, but this will, uh, help you
definitely to mass personalize
those emails on a, uh, you know,
major basis.
So hope this is helpful and I will
see you guys in the next one.
Peace.