What's up guys Lucas here.
So in this video I'm going to be
showing you our detailed cold
email
mass personalizer.
Now this works a little bit
different to our cold email script
writer
workflow which writes the entire
script for each prospect.
What this does is if you have an
existing
script that you're happy with that
you've gotten likely from the
client ascension AI dashboard
but you want to personalize the
first line for each prospect that
you have then you will run
this script instead.
So how this works essentially is
that we've got a form submission
then we will research the
prospects of the form write a
first line for them and then
format the
final email and store it in a
Google Sheet.
Now as usual I'm going to walk
through what you need to
have set up for this to work and
what different nodes there are and
what they do.
So you're going
to need to have Google Sheets set
up you will need to have your open
router set up as we do with all
of the other workflows perplexity
for the research and then Slack to
notify you at the end that
everything is finished.
So the way that this works is that
we've got a campaign request form
that we submit
and this here you can add your
sender name your sender title your
existing cold email
script body and you upload your
lead list.
So I've got a written a cold email
script here that
for the and offer that I'm running
and then I'm going to upload my
lead list CSV.
Now this is just a
temporary lead list CSV where I
put my own details as the first
lead so that it runs properly.
Then we're going to process the
CSV.
We're going to normalize the data
so we get out the information
here.
Then we're going to create a blank
spreadsheet.
This just creates a regular blank
spreadsheet to be named cold email
campaigns and the date.
And then our prospect research
agent performs a detailed research
on us.
So it looks for all information
about the lead me in particular.
We've got another system prompt
down here that gives it kind of
information on how it should be
looking for information, what
information to look for.
Then afterwards we get a detailed
report out of that that we send to
our icebreaker writer.
So this tells it that it's, you
know, an icebreaker writer.
Then it also tells it the name of
the prospect, the company, the
research analysis, and the cold
email body.
So you give the cold email body to
give an idea of what icebreaker
should write that'll flow properly
into the cold email body.
Then after that, we get our, our,
our first icebreaker out for the
first, uh, user.
Then we format the final email.
Now this way is going to be
formatting Google, uh, sheets is
going to have the prospect name,
the prospect email, the company
name, the icebreaker, the email
body, and the formatted
personalized email.
And the way that looks, if I go to
Google sheets is prospect name, my
name, prospect email, my email
company name, uh, the icebreaker
on its own, just got your latest
episode on the sauce podcast with
scaling agencies that ATK MRT in
six months blueprint is seriously
gold.
Then the email body that we
submitted at the start of the
campaign.
And then both of them combined.
So we can see what the full email
looks like.
Hi, Lucas, just got your latest
episode on the sauce podcast with
scaling agencies, struggle with
slow content production.
It's the full email kind of
written out, right?
So the way you would use this is
when you run this, uh, if you go
back here, actually, we've got a
loop here.
So this loops over the items.
It does it for every, uh, uh,
prospect that we have, then, uh,
we will, when it's finally done,
it notifies us in Slack.
It says it's done with the link to
the Google sheet.
But, uh, essentially what you
would do once you have this is
save it as a CSV by going to just
file and download and, uh, CSV, we
would upload this to smart lead as
part of your campaign.
And you would map the columns
appropriately.
So you would set icebreaker as a
custom input.
And then in your, uh, cold email
body, you would have custom input
as a high lead name, custom input,
and then your email body.
And that'd be your campaign pretty
much good to go with personalized
first lines for each of your
prospects.
So that's just a quick rundown of
that one.
This is a pretty straightforward
sort of one.
Again, all you need to input on
this is going to be the center
name, center title, your cold
email script, and your lead list.
After that, everything pretty much
runs smoothly and, uh, should
create some pretty solid, uh,
personalized email campaigns.
So let me know if you've got any
issues with this one and I will
see you in the next one.
Peace.