What's up guys, Lucas here.
Today I'm going to be showing you
our targeted prospect list builder
workflow.
This is a super interesting
workflow that basically finds
contact details for people
to add to your CRM for you, fully
enriched, ready to go, ready for
you to reach out.
So the way that this works is it
uses a tool called SURF, S-U-R-F-E
dot com.
I'm going to be going over, as
usual, how to set up all the
accounts you'll need for
this and just explaining how the
workflow works.
Of course, first thing you're
going to need is going to be a
SURF.com account.
They have a free trial, as you can
see here on their pricing page.
And then their essential plan is
about like $42 or something per
month.
And their pro is like $84,
something like that per month.
And you can see here, you get 150
email finders, 1000 email finders,
all this sort of stuff.
They all have unlimited email
validation.
And you probably want to get the
essential plan to get started.
But for now, we're just going to
show you kind of how SURF works
and why this is actually
extremely, extremely, extremely
powerful.
So the first thing is, this is
just for testing purposes.
We can just remove that and just
tidy up the workflow.
It's a little trick as well.
If you right-click anywhere on the
canvas, you can click tidy up
workflow to make things
look nicer.
So the first thing is the form
input.
You're just going to put in your
industry that you're researching,
the max employee
count, the country code that you
want to search within, your name
and your email.
Then from there, we set the
prospect data just, you know, I'll
put it like this.
And then we search ICP companies.
Now, again, I'm going to show you
here how you're going to set up
your SURF credentials.
So this one works a little bit
different to some of the others.
This will already be filled in for
you.
The method will be filled in for
you and the URL will be filled in
for you.
The URL, just if you need to put
it in yourself, https colon slash
slash api.surfe.com slash
v2 slash company slash search.
Now, here's the part you're going
to have to set up.
You're going to choose for
authentication, generic credential
type and header auth.
So you see down here, generic
credential type, and then it'll be
header auth.
And then once that's set up,
you'll have to add your details
here.
Now, this seems complicated.
It's not.
It's actually a lot simpler than
even some of the other ones we've
done.
You're just going to click add
new, create new credential or edit
the one you have and
type the word authorization with a
capital A.
Then after signing up for SURF,
just note they will actually make
you install a Chrome extension,
which is kind of annoying, but
just go ahead with it.
Once you sign up for SURF, you're
going to end up on this page here.
You're going to go to use SURF API
and you're going to copy your API
key and you're going to
paste it back in here under value
and you're done.
That's it.
This will be set up as well.
SendBuddy and then we've formatted
what you're going to be searching
for here.
But that's all you need to do.
So again, that is generic
credential type, header auth, set
it up with authorization, capital
A
authorization and paste your API
key in here and you are done.
And that's actually how a lot of
APIs later on in some of the other
elements.
We're trying to avoid API call
ones because it's a bit awkward,
but it does work really,
really well.
So what this node does is it
searches for ICP companies.
So you've put in your ICP and what
you're looking for, and now it
finds us a bunch of companies
that fit that ICP.
Now, of course, this is a very
broad one.
It's a SaaS with employee kind of
10 in the US.
It's a lot of people.
So you can be a bit more detailed
with that.
But after that, it prepares the
JSON payload, essentially just
outputs the company's names
and their domains.
And then we use Surf again to
search for employees within these
companies.
And we'll see them down along
here, the different people that
are part of the company.
It goes all the way down, all the
different names, all different
contact details, stuff
like that.
And then we prepare that for an
enrichment request.
And then we enrich those
companies.
It says our enrichment has
started.
We're going to enrich those names
and details to get their email
addresses on phone numbers,
things like that.
So then we check the emission
status, make sure that it's
completed.
If it's not, if this is the is
enrichment complete, if it's not
false, we wait three seconds and
check again until it says true,
upon which point we extract a list
of people.
Here's one guy got 20 items out of
this one.
And then we are going to add that
to our go high level CRM and then
send you an email to
your own name.
Again, send it your Gmail here,
put your email in here and you
will get a nice email telling
you that the enrichment is
finished and you can go check your
go high level CRM.
where you will find all of your
new contact details.
Now you could also set the
prospect data in here manually if
you're using the same ICP every
single time.
And instead for the trigger,
remove the form and instead add
your what's called a schedule
or yeah, schedule.
So you do it on a schedule.
So every 24 hours, you could
scrape a certain amount of people.
So to do that, you would simply
under here, delete these and just
type in.
So for instead of for industry
research, just type in SAS instead
of a, so just do SAS like
that instead of what we just had
there a second ago, which is
taking the data from the input
form like that.
And fill these out.
So these are basically always
going to stay the same.
And then when your schedule node
triggers and to do that, if I go
to plus and I go to add
another trigger and I do on a
schedule, you say every one day at
midnight, then we are going
to set the prospect data, which
you filled out manually and
doesn't change.
And then it will run the rest of
the automation.
So that's basically how that
works.
Again, by the end of it, you're
going to input your data, then it
will search for companies
that fit that description, search
people in those companies, enrich
those people with contact
information and add it to your Go
High Level CRM.
Now you will need to set up Go
High Level as well for your
authentication there.
I'm going to do a full video a bit
earlier on in the course.
So that's going to explain in
detail how to set up your Go High
Level CRM.
I go over it in one of the video
already as well, but I'm going to
make a dedicated video
that's going to teach you just how
to connect that to Go High Level
to N8M because it is a
little bit complicated.
So look out for that one.
And that's basically it.
So again, you input the
information here.
It finds all the information of
their prospects, add them to your
CRM.
You've got a bunch of new
prospects ready for outreach.
So hopefully this was helpful.
and any problems,
feel free to hit me up
and I will see you in the next
one.
Peace.