What's up guys, Lucas here.
So today I'm going to be going
over the AI client onboarding
agent.
This is going to be useful
regardless of what type of agency
you run.
Essentially what it's
going to allow you to do is input
the client details, get their
information, turn it into
tasks inside of your Go High Level
and add your client to Slack along
with a welcome email.
So as usual, let's break down what
you're going to need to have set
up for this and
what each node does.
So first of all, you're going to
have to have Go High Level set up.
You're going to want to watch the
video I break down in the N8N
course where I tell you
exactly how to sort of Go High
Level as it is a little bit
complicated to connect Go High
Level to N8N.
So you're going to make sure
that's done.
You want your Google Drive set up.
As mentioned in other previous
videos, if you're self-hosting,
you'll use the Google OAuth
method, which I break down in
another video.
And if you are using N8N Cloud,
you will simply
just log in with Google.
Then you will need Open Router,
your Open Router API key for all
of our AI agents, as we've talked
about in other videos.
And you also have Slack set up
and Gmail.
So the way this works is it's a
simple form input.
This is your client onboarding
form.
Now you just put in the client
name, the client's email, their
company name, their
website.
And then you have a choice of
either uploading a PDF proposal or
a scope document
that you may have created for what
you're going to do for the client
or just filling out here,
client information and tasks.
So this is going to be input very
briefly, just, you know,
I'm going to do this, this, this,
and this.
Then once that's submitted, it
will check to
see if we have uploaded a PDF
proposal.
We'll get the information from
there.
If not, we'll
go directly to creating the main
client folder inside of your
client's folder in Google Drive.
So as mentioned before, you always
need to have a client's folder in
Google Drive.
That's
the way a lot of these workflows
are set up.
We look for the client's folder in
there.
Then we're just going to rename
the folder ID.
This is just taking the ID of the
folder
and naming a drive folder ID.
Then we're going to create the
contact in your go high level
CRM.
And then if this is again, it's
checking if we have uploaded a PDF
or not, or if it's
just coming directly from what
your input here and client
information and tasks here, I'll
put
some basic information using
myself as an example, just said
paid 50% of $10,000 starting fee,
creating new website and BSR for
them, setting up funnel for them,
setting up Google Analytics
for them, need to get Google
account login details, need to
write copy documents based
on their current products.
Then this will check, see if we've
uploaded CSV.
If we haven't, it'll
run this agent.
And if we have, it'll run this
agent.
Essentially it's the same agent.
All
it's going to do is going to
create a number of tasks based on
the provided information.
So you can see, create a client
payment schedule, request Google
account access, create website
project brief, product analysis
review, BSL script outline,
initial copy framework, website
wireframe design.
It's going to break down all the
things you're going to have to do
for them.
Then we're going to split this out
and we're going to send it to a
loop agent.
What this
does is going to, or a loop tool.
This loop tool is going to create
all of those things
we see listed here.
All of these 26 or so tasks here.
It is going to create them inside
go high
level.
Only we can see these in go high
level is for our internal project
management for each
client.
And it'll also be for your team
that are in go high level so that
you can keep track of
what needs to be done for each
client.
So we'll create the tasks in
there.
You can see it's
created a 25 of them in total.
Um, and then when it's done, we're
just going to send it to
aggregate,
just so we don't get a bunch of,
uh, items going to our Slack
create channel.
It sends one item,
and we're just going to create the
channel with the client name.
So we just do the client name,
and then this is set to name it
client name, underscore channel.
So you can see there innovative,
underscore channel, uh, based on
the company, uh, uh, named they've
input.
And then we post a message
to that channel.
Just saying big, welcome to name.
We're excited to copy this
project.
The channel serves our central
place for communication updates
during the storyline
throughout the journey.
Next up checklist, give off calls,
next steps.
We've got you covered.
Let's crush it.
You can obviously change this to
whatever you want.
Um, the only thing they have
there is the name is the only
variable we have in there.
Uh, so then we are going to send
them a
welcome email.
Again, you're going to want to
edit this.
So, uh, obviously connect your
Gmail
account.
This would go to the, the, the
email address you put in on the
onboarding form.
Welcome to agency name.
Obviously put your name in there
and then it has their name.
So welcome to
innovative Lucas and your
onboarding is complete.
And then this message here, you'll
want to modify
this a little bit too.
Hi name.
Welcome aboard.
Uh, your project works is live.
Uh, you should,
you should receive the most of the
following slack, Google drive,
next steps about any relevant
documentation here, Google drive
folder.
And then you've got their Google
drive folder linked space there.
Uh, schedule your onboarding call.
You're going to replace this with
your calendar link.
Obviously
join the Slack channel.
You're going to want to replace
this URL with your Slack URL.
Uh,
this should work perfectly though.
This should be the channel ID
should be in there.
And then obviously put in your
name, uh, name, your agency and
your title and your website.
And that will send the email to
them.
So that's basically how it works.
Uh, again,
it's a form submission, uh, form
looks like this.
You put in their name, email,
company, website,
and then to either, either a PDF
or a description of the tasks and
information about the client.
And then this will roll run and
we'll, uh, basically create a
folder in Google drive,
add them to go high level, create
tasks for them, add those tasks
to, to go high level,
create a Slack channel, send a
message in that Slack channel and
send them a welcome email.
So, uh, I heard this part about
this program to be connected to
the DHL.
Check out that video in
the N8N module and hope this is
helpful and I will see you in the
next one.
Peace.
Thank you.