- What's up guys, Lucas here.
I'm gonna be showing you in this
video
what I think is one of our
probably handiest automations
so far, it's our Booked Meeting
Alert
and Prospect Research workflow.
So there's a few things we're
gonna have to set up
ahead of this, I'm gonna go over
these
by order of kind of complexity of
setting it up.
So first of all, you'll just need
a Google Drive folder
named Prospect Research, that's a
pretty easy one.
Just go to your Google Drive,
create a folder,
name it Prospect Research, done.
Next thing, this uses Explorium,
which is something we use in a
previous automation
as well, one of our other research
automations.
So you wanna sign up on Explorium
and then you wanna get your API
key.
Now where you're gonna input this
is if we go back here
and where we see Explorium Match
Prospects,
we double click this, this will
all be set up like this,
but you will need to create a new
header auth.
And to do that, you will just
click create new credential
and you will just type name
authorization with a capital A
and then you're just going to copy
and paste your API key
in like this and you are done.
That will use your Explorium API.
The next thing is gonna be
Calendly.
Calendly seems like it should be
very easy to set up.
Surprisingly, it's a little bit
awkward.
So I'm gonna show you what it
looks like
to create a new credential in
Calendly.
We're gonna be using OAuth 2 and
if you have set up
the Google Drive OAuth for the
Google Sheets,
then you know kind of what this
looks like,
but it's not super hard.
But first we're gonna go to our
Calendly account
and we're gonna go to integrations
and apps.
When you're here, you're going to
either scroll down
to API and webhooks or just search
API here
and you're gonna click on it.
Then we are going to go to OAuth.
We're gonna click get started
here.
This is gonna bring you to the
Calendly developer page.
You're gonna have to create a
Calendly developer account.
So again, you're gonna want to go
to developer.calendly.com
or you're going to want to click
that link
we see here under OAuth.
And then once you've signed in,
sign in with Google makes it super
easy.
Just go to account and my apps.
Then you're gonna create a new
app.
Making this very simple, just type
in N8N or whatever,
kind of app web, environment type,
I chose production.
And then you will copy your OAuth
redirect URL from here.
And you will paste it in here,
save and continue.
And then it gives you all the
details you need.
So you just copy the client ID and
paste it in here.
And then you copy the client
secret, paste it in here
on the Calendly page here.
And then connect my account and
log in and you're good to go.
Very, very simple, very
straightforward,
but it is slightly more awkward
than just, you know,
clicking a connect button or
something like that.
So just make sure to do that.
So again, your process there, you
are going to go to integrations,
APIs and webhooks, click OAuth,
get started here.
Then you will sign up for a
developer account
or just log into the developer
account with Google.
Then you will go to account, my
apps, new app.
And just fill in the details that
we showed you there a moment ago.
After that, you are pretty much
done.
We have some other basic set up
here that we will have seen in
other ones.
Go high level.
Again, refer to the video I did
breaking down how to connect,
go high level to N8N to get that
set up as it is a bit complicated.
Then we have, what else?
Open router for our AI agent,
perplexity for our research.
Perplexity again is an API key.
Very simple.
Just go to perplexity.com, get
your API key.
MD2 Docs, you will need your
Google Docs account, OAuth 2 API,
and your Google Drive account,
just connect it up.
Gmail account, connect it up, and
your Slack as usual.
So let's run through what this
does.
This listens for new Calendly
events.
So when someone books a meeting
with you on Calendly or with one
of your clients on Calendly,
what this does is it searches
through our Go High Level to see
if they're an existing lead.
If they are a new lead, then we
will get that lead.
We will just search through the
CRM, and we'll update their status
to meeting booked.
That's essentially all that does.
If they're not a new lead, then it
will create a contact in our Go
High Level CRM,
create an opportunity in the CRM.
And then finally, we get to the
important part here,
which is actually getting
information about the prospect.
The Explorium basically searches
through for information about the
prospect
and matches the email address,
things like that, to its database.
Then we will extract the prospect
IDs for the match results,
and we will enrich the contact's
information.
So we get extra information about
the client, including other email
addresses.
And then we enrich the profiles by
getting things like their
LinkedIn,
their previous experience, their
company they work for, all this
sort of information here.
Then we merge that together.
And this is just handling some of
the processing in relation to
how we're formatting the data we
got from Explorium.
And then we put it all together
here into a bio.
I've pinned some data, which is
why they're showing red right now.
But as you can see here, now we've
got the name, the city, the
country, the position,
about the current company, their
previous experience in JSON
format,
their LinkedIn URL, and their
education details.
Then we send it to our AI agent.
And what this agent does is we
tell it it's an agent specializing
in generating
meeting preparation documents for
business professionals.
We always provide the data,
specifically LinkedIn profiles,
and synthesize it into actual
insights.
Generate a conference of meeting
preparation documents.
You receive a JSON object
containing LinkedIn profile.
Then we have all this information
we gave it there, including the
LinkedIn profile URL.
We also just have just a system
message here telling it,
you know, so how it should kind of
create the report
and what it should include and
things like that.
So then it uses perplexity as well
to do a bit of extra research.
And finally, we take the output
and we create a HTML version of it
that we then send via email.
Now you can either send this to
your client or to yourself.
It's probably a pretty good idea
to have this sent to your clients.
They can see, you know, meetings
coming in constantly and things
like that.
And what the emails look like are
this.
So I hadn't set it up, but it
actually will have the client's,
the prospect's name and booking
date there.
And then it has a full breakdown
of the prospect and all a ton of
extra information.
That will help someone that's
meant to get a sales call
with this person repair ahead of
the sales call.
Then we do basically the same
thing, but we create a Google doc
of the information,
which I'm going to show you what
that looks like here.
Same information that email, just
a nicely formatted Google doc.
That gives us all the information
and kind of that we need to know
about the client ahead of time.
And then we move that to our
prospect research folder.
And then we send a nicely
formatted Slack message saying,
Hey, new call booked.
And here's the call date, the call
title, the prospect notes, the
name,
the company, the email address,
and the research document.
So basically every time someone
books a call with your client,
they'll get a detailed,
their, their, their, their, their
CRM will be updated and they will
get a detailed research document,
as well as notification that the
calls and booked the time, things
like that.
This is a lot of extra, more extra
information than just, you know,
call booked.
Here's a, you know, a quick
notification.
Uh, this gives us actual detailed
information on the prospect and
really helps prepare ahead of the
sales call.
So is extremely valuable and it's
kind of going that extra mile for
your lead gen clients,
you know, to show that you're
actually preparing documents for
them ahead of the call in order
for them to be as prepared as
possible.
So that's essentially how it
works.
Any issues, feel free to hit me
up, but I think this is actually a
super useful one.
Again, make sure that once you've
got all this set up, you set it to
active.
So that anytime a new, um, meeting
is booked in Calendly, this whole,
uh, flow will run.
Hope this was helpful and I will
see you in the next one.
Peace.