So guys, it's going to be a quick
one.
So this is just going to be
showing you
how you can use Poppy to analyze
your sales calls.
This is going to be an important
part
of running an agency.
You'll want to be analyzing your
sales calls, figuring out why you
didn't
close or why you did close, what
you can do better for next time
and overall improve your sales
abilities.
So the easy way to do that is
using, again, an existing Poppy
template called sales
call analysis.
This is in the template section in
Poppy, as I showed you in the
previous videos.
So it's very simple.
The way this one works is use a
blow to your sales call
transcripts
here.
These are already created and
linked up for you.
You can also put in your offer
down
here and give some information
about your offer.
So what I'm just going to do
instead is just
link up, make a new group.
I'm going to call it my offer and
I'm just going to put my website
to make it as easy as possible.
So we're going to add this in
here.
We'll connect it up.
Of course, you have more
information
about your offer, but for now I'm
just going to put that so it gets
an idea of what I do.
So all we have to do is just add
in our sales call transcripts.
So if I go here and I take
an existing transcript that I
have, I'll just drag it in here.
It'll upload.
We're going to drag
this over here and do this group.
And now the prompt is pre-written
for us.
All we're going
to do is copy this and paste this
in here.
I might edit a little bit.
So, uh, you know,
series sales call with closer.
It's going to say Lucas and the
prospect, Travis, give me a
contemplation why Lucas didn't
close.
And there we go.
Right.
So we send that in and
now we're going to get a full
detailed analysis of our sales
call, uh, that will help us
improve
for future, uh, calls.
So there's actually a discovery
call, not a sales call.
So I would
explain it.
Um, uh, while pain point W is the
sale.
Uh, yeah, so good breakdown on
what we
could have done instead.
We should have done, um, goal
setting, all this sort of stuff.
This
is a, a, uh, a super easy way to,
uh, again, this is, you know, not
a good example because
this is not a sales call, but, uh,
it's a pretty good, um, way of
analyzing your calls
and getting good feedback on what
you should do next.
So for any of you that are going
to
be as part of this course, you are
obviously going to be signing
clients and taking sales
calls.
The first few you get, it'll be
very important for you to analyze
your first few
and figure out where you're going
wrong.
That is after you watch all of the
sales module
training and, uh, you know, see
where you can improve on your
overall sales skills.
So, uh, this was showing that, you
know, Poppy isn't just for content
creation.
It can
be used for analysis as well of
your existing, uh, sort of
processes.
I can help you improve in other
areas as well.
Uh, in the next video, I'm just
going to show
you guys how to learn anything
with Poppy in order to, uh, and
get through this course quicker
and improve, you know, your, uh,
uh, launch of your agency and
develop this, all the skills
you're going to need, um, to, uh,
run a successful business.
So hope it's helpful and see you
guys
in the next one.
Peace.