All right so the goal of this
video is for me to give you kind
of like a poppy 101 crash course
whatever you want to call it i'm
not going to really dive deep into
specific use cases or how
to come up with scripts for your
videos or get a sales call
analysis or write an email
newsletter or
an entire sequence the goal of
this video is it's going to be
pretty short and sweet maybe not
too
short but um but the goal is to
walk you through from step one to
show you what the product looks
and feels like and then also how
you can use it in the best
possible way right so with that
being
said this is kind of how it looks
currently currently for my use
case now my use case my account
right
what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna
click new board and i am going to
be taken into this board so when
you
create a new board this is where
you would land now we do a lot of
updates to the product very often
so
there might be a little bit of
changes here and there but like
the core design and everything is
going to still stay the same so
maybe like an icon is in a
different place now right with
that said
um you can start off with like a
template if your main goal is to
come up with youtube video scripts
you can just click this and it
will give you a script a template
where you can get started with
that if not you can do whatever
you want so let me give you a
quick brief on what this ui is and
what
each button or whatever this means
right so this is the starter
screen which disappears right
after you
create something like if i create
a chat window boom it's gone right
so if i delete it the starter
window comes back now this is your
toolbar on the left and then you
also have a couple of other
different buttons over here and
then you have all of this now to
explain what the toolbar has this
is
the ai chat now if you are a
shortcut fan like instead of
having to click this to create a
chat
what you can do is you can just
click c on your keyboard and we'll
still do the same and then what
you can do is you can bring in
youtube videos instagram videos
tick tock videos linkedin posts
and facebook ads as well now the
cool thing about poppy is when you
bring in say an instagram video
tick tock video a linkedin post or
facebook ad not only does it take
the video and transcribe it but
you can it also visually analyzes
what's in the video which is
pretty damn sick if you tell me
does
not have that same capability with
youtube yet but with youtube it
gets the transcription of the
video so
it understands what the hell is
going on right now you can either
do this where you paste the link
here
oh let me show you a shortcut
right so let me just go to our
youtube channel right and then i
just i just
want to bring in this video i just
right click copy link address come
in here command c command v boom
the
video is here the video is already
here now i can create a chat
connected to this and i can say
give me
a breakdown of what's happening in
this video now as you can see
because i'm making this video i
love to talk
so instead of typing that i just
spoke to the chat and it's giving
me an entire breakdown of what's
happening boom right so that is
great now here are a couple other
different things that you can do
you can switch between different
ai models personally i love claude
because they are the best when it
comes
to creativity right it's if you're
writing a vsl if you're writing a
youtube video script if you're
putting
together a short form video script
whatever that involves creativity
claude is the best but then
we also have gpd5 gpd 4.0 gemini
2.5 pro grok gpd5 mini now gemini
2.5 pro and gpd5 they both
have a million token limit now
with claude 4 if i remember
correctly they have a 300 000
token limit what
that means is it's the limit of
how much knowledge or context you
can feed in now if you were to
bring
in say like five or ten different
two hour long podcasts the context
limit or the window of claude
4 is going to be over that limit
and won't be able to work with you
like it will just give you an
error
saying like too much connector now
if you still keep the same thing
in that window or whatever is the
same chat but just switch to
gemini 2.5 pro or gpd5 it would
work because it has a almost three
and a
half times more context limit so
that's the benefit of like having
multiple different models
depending on
what you're trying to work with
right so with that being said
that's kind of like the basic work
um and
then let's say you know you want
to bring in a facebook ad what you
would do is you go to something
called the ad library so it's
facebook.com's ad slash library
let's see if i can find some ads
you
know what i'm just going to bring
in hyros let's look up hyros um
hyros there we go so let's say
for example let's see if i can
find a video ad yes there we go
there's a video ad i'm just going
to
copy the link and then come into
poppy and then just paste the link
right and then what's going to
what it's going to do is it's
going to take everything in that
ad i'm just going to delete
this for now and then i'm also
going to bring in an image ad in
this example it's a carousel right
let's see if there's anything else
i can find you know what let's
just bring this to let's see if it
can
give us a complete breakdown of
all of these all right great so it
has extracted everything in
these images right so this is a
carousel right um this is another
carousel but this is i'm assuming
a video so now i'm going to
connect each of these right
connect connect then connect and
i'm going to
create a new conversation and then
i'm going to say go through these
facebook ads i've given you and
give me a creative breakdown of
each of the creative tell me if
it's a video ad carousel
or an image ad and then give me a
breakdown of if it's a video what
the video has if it's an image
what the image has if it's a
carousel what is the breakdown of
each card all right there you go
so ad
number one this is a testimonial
heavy video ad um bold text
overlay high-risk tracking will
increase
there you go it can see exactly
what's there right and then boom
there's a carousel alex
armosi testimonial tony robbins
playboy testimonial walk
testimonial russell brunson
testimonial so there
you go it's breaking down exactly
what it has right now you can
bring in facebook ads now this is
just
still scratching the surface the
other things that you can bring in
is you can record voice memos now
let's say you have an idea for an
offer or maybe you have an idea of
what the copy needs to be for
sales page that you're trying to
work on but instead of typing
everything you can just hit record
and then
talk like hey you know my offer is
x y and z this is the pricing that
i'm thinking this is kind of like
the icp you know blah blah blah
i've done this x y and z this is
my like this is what my offer
contains
all of that look you can talk for
like 10 minutes what however long
you want and then do that now
also here's another hack let's say
you have a voice memo you want to
bring what i can do is i can just
go here do command c come here do
command v i would still bring that
in as well which is pretty damn
sick
right like let's say you are doing
an in-person meeting with your
team or you're just like brain
dumping and you're like hey i'm
just going to talk through my
ideas and then you just talk while
you're
on a walk and then you come back
you come to poppy and then you
just copy paste it and boom it's
there
and then you can bring in images
um text nodes text nodes could
literally contain like a book or a
pdf
or like something from somewhere
you just copy just pasted it or
you can bring in websites you can
create
mind maps documents again you can
bring in pdfs excel files csv
files literally anything and then
here's
another cool thing about context
engineering right is you can
create groups so if you click
group and
let's say for example instead of
these ads um you just wanted to
bring in like a bunch of your
youtube
videos you can say something like
my youtube videos and then i'm
just going to go to youtube and
then let's
find a channel let's go to alex
and rosie's channel right what i
can do is i can just copy a bunch
of
these links paste paste paste
paste paste now this is why poppy
is super cool because you can
bring in
videos like this you can also
break down like your style your
verbiage how you talk in youtube
videos
and let's say you want to make a
new youtube video you can use this
and like guide it saying like hey
this is a new video idea that i
have again you can use a voice
memo feature you can come up with
a video
idea while you're talking and then
put that and say hey based on this
voice message around the video
idea that i have and then my
youtube videos help me put
together a script that sounds
exactly like
me and it will be able to do that
for you not only that you can take
it to the next level by bringing
in youtube videos on how to write
good scripts from for example
callaway he makes really great
videos
on script writing right so
callaway um you can just like copy
a bunch of his videos paste them
in here
saying like youtube resources or
youtube script writing resources
connect all of them and say hey
write
me scripts and boom it'll come up
with banger scripts for you and
then the mind map feature is
actually a
really good one you can use this
when you're brainstorming or let's
say you're talking to someone
and you're like okay you know this
is a sales call with lucas sales
call lucas um his problems his
objections um his next steps right
you're like on the call you're
talking to him while you're like
jotting these things down and then
you're like hey this is what we
decided to do on lucas call
and then you can bring in like the
recording of the sales call again
um even though you cannot see it
here you can just like drag and
drop mp4 files and it would work
so like if i just drag and drop
this
video boom there you go so it's
like it's a video on bro reach the
final stage of growth um but it's
going to analyze it it's going to
also visually see what is
happening in the video that's why
it's taking
a few a bit of time to give you
everything but then you can bring
in the sales call recording say
hey
based on x y and z what am i
supposed to do next like help me
put together an agreement
like let's say the the decision on
that call was like hey i need to
send you an agreement
you can put together an agreement
um by bringing in examples of like
previous agreements and say
based on these agreements that i
put together and what happened on
the sales call and the objections
deliverables all of this put
together a proposal put together a
an agreement whatever you want to
do
so that is the power of poppy ai
now let's take it to the next
level let's say you have an entire
team of people that you use poppy
with or you want to use poppy with
you can click share you can make
the board public copy link now
again it doesn't make the board
public it just makes it accessible
for everyone who you want to
collaborate with you copy the link
and then for example here what
what i'm
going to do is i'm just going to
open up in another tab but look
what it's going to show me there
you go
there's a month here because
that's where i left on the other
board right and then i can
collaborate and
you can have as many people as you
want and you can collaborate
together so this is really good if
you also have an amazing team that
you want to collaborate with so
with that being said i hope
this video makes a lot of sense on
how to use poppy or like kind of
like an overview of what poppy can
do in the next videos i'm going to
be going over like very specific
use cases of how to use poppy as a
student of plant ascension so with
that being said hope you enjoyed
this video and i'll see you in the
next one peace