So guys, so in this module, we're
just going to be talking a little
bit about Poppy AI.
This module is going to explain
what it is, what it can do, and
then some of the later
ones, we're going to show you how
you can use this specifically for
your agency journey.
So Poppy AI is very simply an AI
whiteboard.
It is a digital whiteboard where
you can add any sort of media or
content, everything
from YouTube videos to ads, to
documents, to images, text,
whatever you want, and you
can connect it up to an AI chat.
Now, the reason this is so useful
is because you can essentially
speed up your process of
say, writing your VSL or creating
social media content or writing
your YouTube videos by using
Poppy and using pre-trained
materials.
So what I mean by this, if you
look at the page here, this is our
digital whiteboard.
So let's start off by very simply
adding the chat.
If I press C on the keyboard,
we've got a chat here.
You can just talk to this
normally, like you would chat GPT
or something.
You see down here, we've got
different AI models we can choose
from.
ForSonna, 3.7, O3 mini, all the
way down.
You know, we've got a bunch in
here.
Let's make this a little bigger.
But the key part that comes into
this is when we start actually
connecting things to it.
So let's say we want to add a
YouTube video.
Say we want to know how to write
an email sequence.
Let's go over here to YouTube and
let's look up Jeremy Haynes and
his Hammer Them Strategy videos.
So this is a really good one,
right?
So this is where he kind of
explains this a little bit and he
goes into the email sequence kind
of process.
So we're going to copy this.
I just right clicked and copy the
link address.
We're going to go back to Poppy.
We're going to paste this in here.
I just did paste.
You can also add this by just
going over here and choosing a
social media and putting the link
in here.
But for now, let's put that there.
Now, the other key thing about
Poppy is the grouping system.
Groups help the AI to understand
what the content inside is and
what it does.
So if I go over here and click
group, we're just going to drag
this here and we're going to name
it.
Email sequence writing training.
And then we can drag Jeremy's
video in here.
Now, Jeremy, I actually have a few
videos on this.
So if I go back here, let's do is
a follow-up one here.
Paste this in here.
And let's grab this one as well.
This is a good video.
So grab here and paste this in
here as well.
So there we go.
So these are all in a group now.
Now, the whiteboard element comes
in similar to, as you may have
seen in the N8N videos,
when we're connecting things, just
click and drag to connect it
together.
Now, the next thing we need to
know is the AI needs to know about
you.
What does it need to know about
you to write these email
sequences?
It needs to know, like, you know,
obviously like your name.
It needs to know your, about your
business.
So we're going to use obviously me
as an example.
So if I do a group and I name it
details about Lucas Senate, put
that there and let's grab my
website.
That's the only thing you can do.
So if I go over here to the
website icon, I type in my
agency's website.
Paste that there, put that in
here.
It's like a second for it to load.
You can also add notes for the AI
to kind of understand what's in,
what the, you know, the item is a
bit better.
Usually not really needed once I
think it's in a group, but yeah,
it can be helpful.
And let's also add some stuff from
my YouTube channel.
So if I go here and I search like
killer, let's grab this one.
Let's copy this.
I took my background in this one.
So if I go back to poppy paste
this in here, up there, uh, I also
could go to like chat GBT and use
this memory to like write stuff
about me.
But for now, this is probably
enough.
I give enough information
throughout these videos.
So let's connect that up there
and, uh, let's see, we're going to
add a third group, but we're not
going to put anything in here yet.
We're just going to name this, uh,
output instructions.
I'm going to show you how we're
going to use this in a second for
now.
We'll keep that blank.
So here we're going to say, uh,
using the, let's see better using
the information in your knowledge
base, write a high converting
email sequence following Jeremy
Haynes strategy for, uh, Lucas
Senate from.
Innovative.
We'll hit enter.
It's a bit bigger.
So it'll think.
Based on Jeremy Haynes, value
dense email strategy and
information at Lucas Senate.
Innovative business.
Here's a high converting email
sequence.
Just put calls to boost your
e-commerce revenue.
Uh, before we talk, I want to
share something that happened the
last week.
Homer Brown.
And I kept us doing 30 K a month
frustrated stocks and familiar in
three days, 95 K a month, it's 57
K extra per month, but here's what
most people miss.
It wasn't about changing our
products.
It wasn't running their ads.
It was about fixing three things.
I control a conversion rate.
You're both the fall, your side
speed, your offer positioning.
So these are all right.
It's going to run a whole sequence
from here.
It's doing a great job on this.
So far, uh, you can get it to, you
know, uh, follow your, your kind
of brand voice a little bit more.
Uh, there's a ton of stuff you can
do, but it's adding more
information.
Now the third group I put in here
is the output instructions.
And the way it reads, I did that
is because we sometimes want to
get the same kind of similar
output each time.
We have rules.
We want it to follow, uh, for
instance, with most stuff that you
write online, you want it to be
written at like a, you know,
fourth grade reading level or
something.
Right.
So you hit T here to create text,
double click or clickers say, I
just write, write all content at
a, say an eighth grade reading
level.
That's one instruction.
We're going to put this over here,
smaller, and then we'll do another
and say, uh, you know,
always sign off any emails, uh,
Lucas Senate from innovative and
remind the prospect to book a
call.
If they have not yet, this is a
follow-up sequence.
So it's really, you know, make a
ton of sense.
But, uh, for now, I just want to
show you guys that it follows
these instructions and let's start
with, uh, start every email with a
Lucas here.
And put that in there too, small.
So now when I connect this up,
we're going to say, uh, let's just
do same thing again.
Copy this prompts, new
conversation.
And we're going to add follow all
instructions in your knowledge
base.
Hit enter.
So you go now starting with, Hey
Lucas here.
It should end with, uh, the, uh,
watch out the ending.
We gave it as well.
You can see like how this would
take you, if you're writing an
email sequence, it might take you,
if you're to watch each of
Jeremy's videos, these are, you
know, pretty long videos.
Uh, it could take a few hours.
You've got to kind of, you know,
write and test to make sure it's
okay.
We did this in literally like
what, like we're eight minutes in
this video.
I think they're actually writing.
It took like maybe a total of
four, five minutes, uh, to write a
ton of emails for our sequence.
Um, so that's just a quick example
of what we can do.
As you can see, you can import any
type of content you want into it.
You can even do voice notes.
So you can put in images and
texts, uh, websites, and you want
and connect it all up together
and, uh, you can write, uh, you
know, content way quicker than you
could if you were trying to do it
manually.
And another cool thing is poppy is
a ton of templates.
So if you go to the template
section here, uh, here's a ton of
items they offer for free.
So, uh, if we look at like, let's
see what's a really cool one that
I like, uh, the second brain is
pretty cool.
So the second brain is made for,
uh, people that want to use poppy
just to, uh, organize their
general life and thoughts.
They've got details here and how
to use the board.
Um, basically you put ideas you
have in here.
It's gonna be voice notes, it's
gonna be texts, it can be
whatever.
And then you just tell the AI to
run prompt five and it will
actually run through this prompt
here and help you categorize your
thoughts, uh, give you like, uh,
workflow suggestions, give you
action plans, uh, super, super
useful.
And then if we go back to
templates again, uh, the few other
really good ones on here, Brian's
YouTube script writing template is
phenomenal.
Brian's got all of his training on
writing YouTube scripts, a ton of
documents of writing YouTube
scripts.
Uh, actually this is all the
content on Brian.
So you just replace this with your
information about who you are.
And then down here, he's got all
his training on how to write viral
videos and then a prompt chain,
uh, then it will automatically
write your YouTube scripts for
you.
Uh, really, really good.
Brian's super successful with, uh,
running his content agency and
writing YouTube scripts for
people.
So, you know, the output is going
to be good and, uh, you know, it
makes it really easy for you just
to spin up new YouTube videos
whenever you want.
Uh, so I think poppy is a super
powerful tool.
Uh, the guys are poppy are also
great to work with, really nice
guys, and they are creating some
exclusive content for us here in,
uh, in the course.
So you guys get to hear directly
from them, the most powerful ways
to use poppy.
Uh, but I'm going to show you a
few other ways I've been using it
in the next videos.
So check those out and, uh, would
highly suggest using this for your
agency set up.
This will speed up your VSL
writing, your landing page, copy
creation, your, um, uh, email
sequence writing, your cold email
writing, anything to do with
creating content is going to be 10
times easier using poppy.
Um, so, uh, yeah, that's a bit
about it.
And, uh, let's go to the next
video.
We're going to show you guys some
of the kind of other systems that
I use inside of poppy in order to
always get solid outputs and, uh,
make this an integral part of your
workflow.
See you next one.
Peace.
Thank you.