What's up guys, Lucas here.
So one of the outreach methods
you're going to be learning in
this
program is called dream 100.
Now there'll be a detailed
explanation of this further down.
But a
quick summary is essentially you
make a list of your 100 dream
prospects, and then you reach out
to them manually, usually via DM,
and you offer them a finished
deliverable that is relevant to
them.
So one of the most important
things about this is going to be
researching your prospects
and, you know, making sure that
your outreach doesn't seem, you
know, too automated or awkward
or anything like that.
So I'm going to show you a basic
dream 100 ICP first line writer
here in
Poppy.
And essentially what this will do
is you will give some information
on your prospect links
to their social profile, if
they've got YouTube videos,
anything like that.
And this will help
you write really good first lines
for your opening DM to them.
So let's take a look here.
As I've
set this up with this board
already, I'm just going to walk
through what we have here.
And
then I'm going to show you how
we're going to make this work.
So we have three groups, the dream
prospects group, this is where
we'll put the social media
profiles, the people you want to
contact
the system prompt, where I just
put the system prompt, I'll go
over now in a second.
And then
there'll be information about me.
And this is so that it will have
an idea of your offer and what you
do.
So let's take a look first at the
system prompt.
The system prompt says you are a
detailed ICP
researcher and first line writer,
you find key information, details
and updates about people in
dream 100 prospects and write a
personalized first line DM,
mentioning something about them in
a
positive manner before pitching
your services, then follow up with
a relevant piece of work created
specifically for them.
Like I made you this because I saw
x on your profile.
That's a very basic,
you know, first line kind of
format.
You're going to be getting some
details later on about kind of,
you know, the ultimate way to
dream 100.
So you might want to modify this
system prompt a little
bit.
But this is the basic one that I'm
going to go with today.
So first, we need to get our ICP
social profiles.
Now, I am going to go with our
good friend and client ascension
Mario Lanzarotti.
And I'm just going to copy his
LinkedIn here.
Now, for now, I'm just gonna use
his LinkedIn,
but I could go and grab YouTube
videos of speeches he's done.
I could grab his YouTube
account in general, grab his
Twitter and like that.
But we're just going to start off
with his
LinkedIn because Mario is very
active on LinkedIn and post a lot
on there.
So there's some content
to work with.
Then we're going to get some
information about me.
And for this, I'm just going to
choose
two things.
This one video that I've used
across nearly all other poppy
boards.
And we're going to paste
this in here.
And then my website shows the idea
about my offer.
So we're going to type that in
there.
We're gonna let that load.
Now, as you can see, Mario's
profile is loaded here.
And my website
should load here momentarily.
There we go.
So now what we're going to say is
follow your system
instructions and write a
personalized first line or a DM to
the person in the dream 100
prospects
group.
Write the message from me, Lucas
Sennett tailored to my offer.
Now, if you have already
decided what deliverables you're
going to be giving, you'll still
mention that you'll say,
write the message from me, your
name, offering them whatever the
deliverable is.
But for now,
I'm just going to let it create a
deliverable that I'm supposedly
going to deliver to Mario.
So we're going to hit enter.
Based information from your
knowledge base, here's a
personalized first line DM from
Mario Lanzarotti.
Hey, Mario, just saw your article
series, how I overcame self-dead
and created the life of my dreams.
The journey from corporate success
to finding truthful and
re-presonated with me, especially
your
insight that most finders get
stuck, not because of a bad
strategy, because of deeper
blocks.
I'm Lucas from Innovative, and I
specialize in helping coaching
consultants like yourself
and more of their audience through
high converting landing pages,
email marketing.
I noticed you're building your
coaching practice around the
Zenpreneur method, and I actually
created a custom landing page
welcome specifically for your
work-life cohesion approach,
because
I saw how you're positioning
yourself differently from just
typical business coaches.
But you'd be able to be sending it
over.
I think you'd find the conversion
psychology behind it pretty
interesting, especially if you're
someone who understands the
mindset side as well as you do.
Best, Lucas.
This is actually solid.
It's a little bit too formal.
So I might say, write it more
direct and casual, emulating my
speaking style from the YouTube
transcript in what I call this
group.
And this one.
So.
Hey Mario, sorry for yourself in
overcoming self-doubt and creating
the life of your dreams.
A whole dream corporate defining
actual fulfillment hits different
when you've been there yourself.
I'm Lucas.
I run Innovative, where we build
high converting landing pages to
email systems for coaches.
Notice you're doing the Zenpreneur
thing, which is pretty cool.
Most business coaches just for
gird shape, the same hustle
nonsense.
Look, I made you a landing page
mock-up because I saw how you're
positioning the work-life
cohesion angle of thought you'd
want to see how to convert more of
your audience
to that message.
Want me to send it over?
Lucas.
That's pretty solid.
Again, I could use my brand voice
profile to be created in some of
the other previous
modules in order to make this even
better.
But for now, this is pretty solid.
And this is to show you kind of
how you would set up this board in
order to do this at scale.
So you could put a ton of Dream
100 Prospects in there and get it
to run through the whole
list.
But this is the basic idea behind
it.
Again, you will put three groups,
Dream 100 Prospects, System
Prompt, and Information About
You.
Then Dream 100 Prospects will
include the links to the social
media of the people that
you want to contact.
System Prompt is a system prompt
similar to this.
You're a detailed ICP researcher
and first-line writer.
You find key information, details,
and updates about people in Dream
100 Prospects and write
a personalized first-line DM
mentioning something about them in
a positive manner before pitching
your services.
Then follow up with a relevant
piece of work created specifically
for them, like I made you
this because I saw X in your
profile.
Then some information about you,
your website, some YouTube videos,
whatever you got on you.
If you've got a creative brief,
which hopefully you will, then
I'll throw that in there too.
And then the prompt we give the
system is just follow your system
instructions and write a
personalized first-line for a DM
to the person in the Dream 100
Prospects group with a message
from me that will send it to my
offer.
Then we just told her to be a bit
more direct and casually editing
my speaking style.
So that's the basic idea behind
this.
I think that this is a super
powerful way to, at scale, get
your first lines written.
I will put all of those in a
spreadsheet or something like
that, and then just start manually
sending these out one by one.
But again, follow the training.
You'll see later on about Dream
100 and how to do that whole
process.
And you'll be pretty much set.
So this will speed up things a bit
for you.
But this is another example of how
great Poppy is.
You can use it for content, for
analysis, for situations like
this.
We've got to mass create a bunch
of personalized information.
So Poppy is really, you know,
limited by your own imagination.
And I highly suggest using it for,
you know, other kind of things
like this as well as, you
know, writing your YouTube scripts
and things like that.
So hope this is helpful.
And I will see you in the next
one.
Peace.