Okay.
So in this video, I'm going to
show you guys how to create
content in Poppy AI that is in
your particular voice and style.
This is obviously one of the
hardest parts of AI, you know,
that very kind of common AI
speaking style is like super
awkward and stilted and weird.
This is going to show you how to
use Poppy to train the AI to speak
exactly like you do.
And the way we're going to do that
is there's an existing template in
the Poppy AI template section
called voice clone template.
And this creates essentially a
prompt that tells the AI
how you how you speak and how it
should write all content going
forward.
And it's very simple how this
works.
So you've got a section here is
called voice cloner, my content.
And then we've got instructions
over here.
So all we need to do is get some
of our existing content.
This does only need to have
examples of you speaking.
So if that's, you know, you're you
can add some audio notes, you can
add some videos recorded anything
of you speaking.
So if I go over here to my YouTube
channel, I'm going to grab some of
these here.
And we're going to put these in
into the box here into the box
here.
Just grab this.
Then we'll grab this one.
And we're looking for here is just
examples of how you sound and talk
and the kind of, you know,
language you use and things like
that.
Just to help personalize your
other types of content.
So let's grab all of these.
And I got some of the shorts I've
done too.
The more you have, the better it
will work.
So I'm going to put about six
videos in here.
So with all of our content in
there, what we're going to do is
we're going to copy the prompts
from here and put these in.
Let's take both of these and drop
down here.
And then we send it in.
And this should now create our
voice clone template.
So this is a quick context.
This is normal.
Uh, in smaller focus chunks, we
really build a little larger
section.
So now some of the tone of mood to
get section three locked in.
It's very direct cut to BS energy
and scale of one cent.
How important is maintaining the
bulldogs here.
Sometimes being more diplomatic.
Uh, so we'll say for number one,
uh, say seven, you can be
diplomatic sometimes, but we like
to be direct.
Two.
I noticed these phrases like
something to visit good for us.
It's a tough approach.
It's something you want to
maintain across all content types,
not across all content types.
Only when appropriate.
It's teaching tactical skills.
It's just to be more
instructional, but still casual.
Do you want to maintain different
modes for different content type?
Yes, I would like to maintain
different modes for different
content types.
How do you want to handle those
who need you more empathetic or
sensitive while still maintaining
your authentic voice?
Um, do you want to empathetic?
Uh, I would just say speak in a
clear, direct, but understanding
way.
I'm going to send that.
So it's going to keep going.
Language style and preferences.
I noticed you use casual language,
like peace, a sign off and phrases
like, let's check it out.
Do you want to maintain that
conversational style across all
content?
Yes.
So I do.
And use shorter, punchy sentences
makes it longer explanatory ones.
Is this rhythm intentional for
keeping attention?
Yes, I do that.
Uh, I see probably use you when
addressing your audience and I
when sharing personal experience
just to be consistent.
Yes, it should.
Are there any specific words or
phrases you absolutely want to
avoid in your content?
Uh, game changer or let's dive in,
uh, or any corporate jargon.
What's your preference on
profanity?
You know, just keep it clean in
tutorials with stronger language,
motivational contents.
Profanity is okay, but used
sparingly.
So signature expression questions.
Those existing and views of peace.
Is this preferred sign of across
all content?
It actually is.
Yes.
Yes, it is.
You often use less.
Check it out.
And here's the thing is
transitions.
Are these core phrases you want to
maintain?
Yes.
Do you have any other go to phrase
for opening content?
Uh, no go to phrases vary as you
see fit.
Any specific ways like to
introduce tutorials versus
motivational content?
No specific way.
Size P.
See if other probates drop up
different, uh, thing.
Yeah.
Uh, see you in the next one.
Bye.
You guys will notice some of these
in the, uh, tutorials that I'm
doing.
Okay.
So now we're into storytelling and
style questions.
You frequently share personal
stories to make points.
How important is being personal
experience to your content?
Yes.
This is important, especially on
social content, but not all the
time.
Any specific examples and case
studies should concrete results
always be included and possible
when possible and the facts are
provided or verifiable.
Here seems dry in situation rather
for us jokes.
Uh, yes, that is the right
approach.
For emphasis.
I see you use things like C and
direct statements.
You afraid this over all caps or
excessive punctuation.
Uh, yes, but a, but all caps is
okay.
Sometimes too.
You often structure content with
clear step-by-step breakdowns.
Is this a sort of approach?
Uh, some, some points too.
Uh, portrait teaching style.
Yes, it is.
Okay.
So grammar formatting.
Those use contractions naturally.
Should this casual grammar style
be maintained?
Yes.
What's actually pretty standard?
Is this your preference?
Yes.
Can you describe clear headers,
bullet points over the list of
tutorials?
Uh, yes.
Do you have any specific
preferences for how you want
headings formatted or capitalized?
No.
Any grammar rules you
intentionally break for
conversational flow, like starting
sentences with an and or but?
Uh, yes.
Sometimes use but to start a
sentence.
Almost there.
Okay.
Uh, final questions.
We need to shift from casual
social motivational to a more
serious topic.
Any specific guidelines?
No specific guidelines.
Are there any topics that
absolutely won't cover any special
handling handling?
Um, no.
Any interesting disclaimers you
need?
No.
Uh, not really.
What's your stance on giving
direct business financial advice
for sharing personal experience?
I prefer to share personal
experience, but I'm happy to
explain, uh, insights or
information.
I have seen work for myself and
others.
Uh, any cultural reference to
industry terms?
Uh, no, not particularly.
Uh, no.
I am from Ireland though.
So consider that.
Also, my name is Lucas Synod.
It's pulling my name wrong.
There we go.
So I got the full thing all done.
Great.
So I'm ready to share with chat
too.
So how does this work?
Now we're going to take this.
And one of the prompts below.
We're going to take this.
And we are going to give this to a
new chat.
So I'm just going to open a new
chat.
Okay.
So I'm just going to open a new
chat.
So I'm going to open a new chat.
Okay.
Uh, a new poppy window for this.
Great.
So ready to share with chat too.
So how does this work?
Now we're going to take this.
And one of the prompts below.
And we are going to give this to a
new chat.
So I'm just going to open a new,
uh, a new poppy window for this.
And we are going to go to the
example.
We just showed it a few moments
ago, writing email sequences.
So now we're going to add a fourth
group.
And the fourth group is for brand
voice.
Lucas Sennett's brand voice and
speaking style.
Okay.
Now we're going to open a text
box.
We're going to paste in that
prompt we just got.
Put that there.
Let's make this bigger because
we're ready to put another one in.
There.
Let's go back to our first one.
Now we're going to include this as
well.
another text box.
Based.
Put that in there.
And connect this up.
Now, our original thing was good.
So we're going to copy this, but
we're going to change this up a
little bit.
We're going to say same thing, use
the brand voice profile in your
knowledge base to write
all content in the style of Lucas
Sennett.
And now the versions of the emails
we get should match closer to my
general speaking style and tone of
voice.
Yeah.
These are more like me.
So, hey, Lucas here.
Just had a call with a homeware
brand owner yesterday.
Guy was frustrated because email
marketing was basically dead
weight.
15% open rates, barely any clicks
and his automated flow is bringing
in maybe 2k a month.
Here's the thing.
Most income brands treat email
like an afterthought.
They set up some basic welcome
series, throw in a few product
pushes and wonder why they're not
seeing results.
Here's what we did for this brand
in 30 days.
The difference.
We stopped sending generic buyer
stuff emails and started sending
emails that actually help people.
Look, your customers aren't
sitting around waiting for your
next sales pitch.
They're dealing with real
problems, making tough decisions,
trying to figure out if your
product is actually worth their
money.
When you answer those questions
before they ask them, everything
changes.
Tomorrow, I'll show you the
biggest mistakes I see brands make
with their subject lines and why
it's killing your open rates.
If you haven't booked a call yet,
here's the link.
Peace, Lucas Center from
Innovative.
That homeware brand, they're now
one of our best case studies.
Book a call if you want to be
next.
This sounds much more like me.
This is like, that's an email, but
I could read that as like a script
or a voice note or something like
that.
And it would sound much closer to
how I speak generally.
So I suggest you always, if you're
using poppy to write content, go
create your brand voice profile.
It'll save you a ton of time in
terms of prompting and trying to
alter stuff to match more how you
want it to sound.
You do that process once and then
you can copy and paste those
prompts into any other content
creation board that you have.
Super, super useful.
I think that the this system as
well that I have here is something
that I think you guys should take
note of.
I generally always try and do four
groups email.
So the first one will be whatever
it is you want poppy to know how
to do.
This was a VSL writer.
We would have VSL writing content
in the first group.
This is an email sequence writers.
We've got email sequence content.
Essentially YouTube is now your
open source knowledge base.
You can get any videos from people
that are trusted that know what
they're doing that explain
everything in detail.
And you can now have an AI know
everything that they know.
You can take a ton of Alex from
those videos and put them in here.
And now you've got an AI Alex from
those you can talk to anytime you
want.
So the first group is everything
that you wanted to know how to do
the actual skill.
The second one is details about
you.
So here you could include
everything from your website to
some of your content.
I highly suggest doing a creative
brief for your company in the
client ascension course.
You will see under the VSL section
a video from Nick Burge explaining
how to do that.
Definitely do that.
Then you will have your brand
voice profile.
That should be the same.
Once you do it once you have the
same thing over and over again
across all your content boards.
And then finally your output
instructions where you use this to
tweak the outputs you get, maybe
make them longer, shorter, more
complex, whatever you want.
These are the rules that you give
the AI to follow every single time
that it writes content.
That's the four group method that
I tend to follow.
And I find that it works really
well no matter what type of
content that you're trying to
make.
Hope this is useful.
I think that Poppy is the most
powerful tool out there to write
content in your voice and style
that actually gets results.
And it's the easiest way to take
people that are already doing well
with their content and figure out
how they're doing it.
And, you know, jack their whole
kind of, you know, flow and style.
And that's, you know, best way to
get ahead and best way to generate
more views.
So hopefully this was helpful for
you.
And I will see you in the next
one.
Peace.