What's up guys, Lucas here.
So in this video, I'm going to be
showing you how to use Poppy
to script a YouTube video.
Now for this, we're going to be
using a template you'll find in
the
template section called Brian ng
YouTube script writing template.
This is by far the best one
I've found here so far.
So as you can see, this is a
template board view only.
So what I'm going
to do is going to click use
template, and we'll create a copy
of this in my own Poppy account.
So now we're in here.
First thing I'm going to do is I'm
going to read instructions for
users.
So
before you begin, have your final
video concept and title ready.
Gather these resources to provide
context to AI, your target video
length, transcripts of two to
three high performing videos in
your
niche with similar content
structure, key points you
absolutely must include in your
video, and your
research data or sources you plan
to reference your hook ideas have
already developed as specific
retention tags that have worked
for your channel before it's for
best results crucial almost to add
your own PDFs, YouTube videos,
webinars, website, creative brief.
I think it's a document for
creating a creative brief.
You also find a tutorial on
creating your creative brief in
the client
ascension course from Nick Verge.
The golden rule of script
development.
Every 30 seconds ask yourself,
would I keep watching this and why
were the viewer?
The answer is an immediate yes,
stress in that section
by adding a surprise fact,
inserting a mini story, including
compelling example, creating a
curiosity gap,
or using a pattern interruption
technique.
So let's start with getting our
information in here.
This is group one who I am now.
Brian's got his information in
here.
So we're just going to remove
this.
Boom, all gone.
And I'm going to grab some of my
own YouTube videos.
So we're going to go to
youtube.com.
I'm going to go view your channel.
We're going to copy all these
over.
Let's go back to poppy, paste.
Copy, paste.
So we're going to copy a few more
of these in.
We want as many as we can.
Copy, paste.
That should be one or two more of
these.
And then we're going to do is
we're going to put my website.
We're going to hit W for website.
We're going to type in my website
name.
Put that in there.
I'm going to get my creative
brief.
I'm just going to find this on my
computer.
Okay, so I'm uploading my creative
brief.
We're going to put that in there.
And that should be pretty much all
we're going to need is wait for
that to extract the text.
So let's see what else Brian had.
Our target video length,
transcripts.
I'm also going to go and grab from
one of my previous boards,
if I can find it, my tone of voice
clone that we did before.
So you remember in a previous
video, we created this.
This was our brand voice and
speaking style.
We can copy this whole group and
we can go back here and we can
paste this in.
We can add this actually as
another whole group to connect.
And yeah, we should be good to go.
So let's see what else.
Now we're going to go down here.
So Brian has a prompt written for
us already.
There's someone's going to link
this because we don't need that
right now.
This is a flow chart.
Let's go down here.
I think this is a bigger, right?
Oh, copy.
Group one is who I am, my content,
analyze the content, give me a
summary of my
brown voice, signals to the tone,
speak words I use, group two's
guides, how to write viral videos.
Group three is a prompt chain for
writing the outline and we're
going to actually modify
this a little bit because we now
have a group four.
Voice, profile, tone and style.
I'm going to say group four is my
voice, tone and style prompt.
Follow this to write like
to write scripts in my voice and
speaking style.
Now we're going to say, I want to
write a YouTube video about, let's
say,
AI automations that you need to
have in 2025.
Now, one of the things you can do
as part of this
is we can take existing videos
that we know are high performing
and we can include those as
examples.
So let's see, what's one of the,
what's a good automations.
So this is a good one.
This is eight sales automations,
fairly cheating from Liam oddly.
Now we can actually get the
information from this by copying
this.
And let's make a new group and
call it group five.
We're going to name it
topic information and education.
So then we place that video in
there and we're going to describe
this as well to our, in our
prompt.
So let's grab this right.
Let's up here and connect it if we
can.
And then we're going to add to
this prompt.
We're going to say.
Group five contains information
about the topic I am speaking
about.
Use this group for research on the
topic of the video.
Now we're going to copy this and
we are going to paste it into our
chat.
So let's zoom in a little bit.
So I want you to script a YouTube
video about AI automations you
need to have in 2025.
Group one is who I am.
My content is the content can be
sorry, our voice.
Take note of the tone of the
speakers I use.
Group two is guys that headwrite
viral videos refer to the
documents that understand
headwrite hooks,
bodies, open lips, ETAs, et
cetera.
Group three is a prompt chain for
the outline.
If I should get the script.
When I tell you to call these
prompt chains, call them.
Group four is my voice tone and
saw prompt for the story scripts
in my voice and speaking style.
Group five contains information
about the topic I'm speaking
about.
So we might actually need to say,
analyze the content.
We can just say.
Use this to tailor the scripts.
To me specifically.
To me.
Lucas Senate specifically.
And pulling information.
Or stories.
Pulling information.
From my personal stories.
And experience to.
Include if necessary.
I can't spell.
Necessary.
There we go.
All right.
I'm going to hit enter.
Let's see what we get.
Let's make this a bit bigger.
Okay.
It's running through our prompt
chain.
So.
You can see it says.
I'll be creating YouTube script.
By automation.
With your knowledge base.
You can see who you are.
Let me start using our prompt
chain.
I'll choose your outline for this
video.
I'll call the first prompt to use
your outline development chain.
Great.
So.
We're getting this here.
Blah, blah, blah.
And this is writing to these over
here.
These ones here.
The prompt chain here.
So that's the.
Crafts TGQ script outlines.
And then.
Uh.
We're going to.
Say that's all good.
I'm just going to say continue.
So it's going to outline the
script now.
So we're getting the outline.
So we're going to say.
You know.
Main section structure.
The hook and authority building.
Open with contrasting reality.
When most people are still
figuring out.
ChatTBT.
It's average credibility.
Through client extension.
Innovative experience.
Uh.
Promise specific automation.
It's every winner's release in
2025.
Uh.
Why most AI implementations fail.
The difference between AI toys.
Versus AI tools make money.
So the automation hierarchy
concept.
Uh.
Lead response automation.
Proposal generation.
Client boarding sequence.
So Chris.
We've got some of the actual.
Uh.
Automations we're going to talk
about.
Involvation reality.
Here's the thing.
Why most people will do this.
Uh.
Direct CTA to work with you.
Key dependencies.
We'll establish AI credibility.
Lead response will come first.
Revenue fact.
Recovery last.
Nested loops.
We'll own automation.
That's already 295 weeks.
We'll be at the seven minute mark.
Uh.
The mistake that kills everything.
Involvation scope is section two.
Uh.
Right.
Okay.
Range movement is detailed section
by section blueprint.
Yes.
Continue.
So we're going to make the section
by section blueprint.
So this is all giving the AI.
And this is from Brian's prompt
chain.
Giving the AI.
Uh.
You know specific structures to
follow.
And instructions on how it's going
to do this.
I'm just going to tell.
Continue again.
So here we go.
So.
Detail section by section
blueprint.
We've got hook approach one.
And hook approach two.
We've got two to go from.
And three actually.
So let's see.
Let's start off with this.
So one of them is.
I recently surveyed over 100,000
AI agency owners.
To find out what's actually
working in 2025.
Most people are still playing
around with chat GPT.
Asking to write emails.
The smart money is already living
in a completely different reality.
We found a property developer
using AI.
To turn missed Sunday calls into
$2 million deals.
And an agency helping cosmetic
clinics started $100,000.
In just three days.
In this video.
I'm going to show you the exact
eight AI automations.
You need to have in 2025.
If you want to stay competitive.
First, let me show you why most
people are doing AI completely
wrong.
Second one is.
Here's the thing.
While you're manually responding
to leads at 2:00 a.m.
And spending hours writing
proposals.
Your competitors are using AI
systems that never sleep.
Never miss a follow up.
And are generating hundreds of
thousands in additional revenue.
I know this.
Because I just finished surveying
100,000 plus agency owners.
And that's what I found will
either motivate you or terrify
you.
Sorry.
And what I found will either
motivate or terrify you.
I'm Lucas Sinnott.
Head expert coach.
Client Ascension.
And why I help people scale the
agencies.
And co-founder of Innovative.
I've seen what works and what
doesn't.
This eight automations aren't
theory.
They're bottle tested systems
generating real money right now.
Third one.
An AI system just booked 200 sales
appointments.
And generated $220,000 in
additional revenue.
In five weeks with zero human
intervention.
Another one helped the cosmetic
clinic make $100,000 in three
days.
These aren't future predictions.
This is happening right now.
While most people are still
figuring out basic .gbt prompts.
I'm going to break down the exact
eight AI automations.
Behind results like these.
But there's one mistake that kills
90% of implementations.
For the even start.
Great.
So then keeps going.
It gives us our full outline.
Great.
So ready to do the retention
engine and strategic optimization.
Yes.
Continue.
As you can see this goes through a
multi-step process.
I'm just going to output a full
script for you.
It breaks it down step by step.
To get you to get it.
So AI understands what it should
be doing.
And how to break the best script
possible.
Based on Brian's frameworks.
So we've got retention wave
mapping.
Audience retention checkpoints.
Strategic content reveal pasting.
Psychological mental builders.
Keep going.
Continue.
Most of this is typing continue.
After you do the initial prompt.
And you get everything set up.
You got your information in there.
It's really solid.
So now it's actually going to give
us the high points.
Where we're going to do these
retention wave mapping.
It's just going to tell us where
to say these things in the script.
In order to, you know, increase
retention.
And to bring people back to maybe
not paying attention anymore.
Or losing interest.
So yeah.
We've got pattern interrupt.
Insert mini cliffhanger.
Add explanation subversion.
Strategic content reveal pasting.
The review of the survey
credibility.
The mindset shift.
But AI versus tools.
The conversion stat.
Personal adaptability story.
Psychological mental builders.
This is great.
So this is like all, you know,
super, super psychologically
focused.
And kind of detailed based on
YouTube.
Because Brian's study of YouTube.
The different kind of retention
tactics.
And things that work to keep
people watching.
Yes, continuous.
Now we're going to do the full
script development.
Using these retention optimized
elements.
So now it's developing a powerful
hook.
An intro.
And we're going to say continue
again.
So now it has the outline on the
instructions for what it should
do.
So now we've got our hooks.
And we've got delivery guidance.
So now we're in the value prop
section.
The engagement foundation.
Introduction overview.
Strategic open loops embedded.
Plugin drops built in.
There we go.
So that's our hook section on
intro done.
So let's see what this looks like.
So after we, I read the hooks
already, but let's go into the
next section of the value prop.
My name is Lucas Sinnott.
I'm the head expert coach at
client Ascension.
One of the leading programs that
teaches people how to launch and
scale agencies.
And I'm also co-founder of
innovative.
A full service e-commerce
optimization agency.
I've helped hundreds of agency
owners scale their businesses.
And I've seen what separates the
winners from the losers.
The winners aren't smarter.
They don't have bigger budgets.
They definitely don't work harder.
They just understand one thing.
While everyone else is doing
things manually.
They're using AI to create unfair
advantages.
In this video, I'm going to show
you the exact eight, uh,
AI automations that are generating
these kinds of results.
Not theory, not fluff.
The actual systems are the tech
stocks, the pricing, and the real
numbers behind them.
Here's what I found out for
talking to all these agency
owners.
There are two types of businesses
right now.
Yeah, perfect.
So he actually mentions one of my
personal stories there.
Here's the thing.
And this connects to everything I
learned going from screening and
metal buyers to scaling agencies.
Success isn't about having perfect
conditions.
It's about adapting faster than
everyone else.
The same adaptability, the same
adaptability that took me from
death metal to tech journalism
to running agencies is what's
going to separate the winners from
the losers in the AI revolution.
Here's what we're going to cover.
I'm going to break down the eight
specific AI automations in order
of importance.
We'll start with the foundation,
the systems that every business
needs to have in place first.
Then we'll move to the growth
layer, the automations that
separate
good agencies from great ones.
And finally, the revenue layer,
including the $220,000 system I
mentioned.
For each automation, I'll show you
exactly how it works, what tools
are using,
what it costs to implement, and
the real results it's generating.
No theory, no maybes, just the
systems that are working right
now.
But I'm also going to tell you
something at the end that most
people don't want to hear.
Because knowing about these
systems and actually implementing
them are two completely different
things.
And there's one reason why 90% of
people who watch this video won't
do anything with this information.
Let's check it out.
Great.
So we're going to do the core
content sections.
We're going to say continue.
And again, we're talking about a
complicated topic here as well.
I could have done this on, you
know, general, anything kind of
overall, but agency development or
growth or whatever.
But like, this is a very specific
topic of these specific AI
automations, you know?
So we're giving it kind of the,
uh, a pretty big task here.
And if we can pull this off pretty
well, using the information from
the video
we provided that contains that
information.
Uh, and you can add multiple
videos.
It doesn't have to be one that
you're kind of, you know, copying
from being put a bunch
in there that are similar to what
the topic you want to talk about.
It'll kind of take from all of
them.
But, uh, let's keep telling this
to continue.
These are good.
So we have our main points set up.
Uh, we have our, sorry, smooth
transition.
We have our main points set up and
then we have why this matters.
Look, if you're still manually
responding to every lead, writing
every proposal from scratch
and handling client onboarding
spreadsheets, you're not just
inefficient.
You're about to get destroyed by
your competition because while
you're burning out doing a $10
an hour task, they're using AI to
handle the heavy lifting and
focusing on closing deals.
Getting this wrong means you'll
spend the next year working harder
while making less money.
But nailed this mindset shift and
suddenly you're operating in a
completely different league.
It all comes down to what I call
the automation hierarchy.
Foundation first, complexity
later.
You don't start with the fancy
stuff.
You start with the systems that
handle your biggest time dreads
and revenue leaks.
Think about it like this.
When I was scaling my agency to
20K a month, I didn't try to
automate everything at once.
I started with lead response, then
moves to proposals, then client
management.
Each layer built to the previous
one.
The agencies in my survey that are
crushing it all follow the same
pattern.
They don't just jump straight to
complex AI workflows.
They started with automation
number one, mastered it, then
moved to number two.
For example, the property
developer making $2 million from
Sunday calls.
He didn't start there.
He started with basic lead
response automation, then added
qualification, then booking.
Each step made the next one more
powerful.
Here's the thing though.
Following this hierarchy and
actually following it, or knowing
this hierarchy and actually
following
it are two different things.
Most people want to skip the sexy
stuff.
Don't be most people.
Let's start with the foundation.
Automation number one is something
that every single successful
agency has.
If you don't have this, something
else matters.
These first three automations
aren't the most exciting, but
they're the most important.
Think of them as the foundation of
your house.
It's boring, but everything else
collapses without them.
Automation number one, lead
response system.
Here's a stat that will blow your
mind.
These contactives in the first
minute of inquiry have a 391%
higher conversion rate compared to
slower responses.
391%, and get this 78% of buyers
choose the first company that
responds regardless of price.
But here's the kicker.
The average lead response time
across all industries is 42 hours.
By the time most people respond,
their lead is already bought from
someone else, forgotten they were
interested or moved on with their
life.
This is where the AI lead response
comes in.
We're talking about a system that
responds within 60 seconds, 24/7,
365 days a year.
No sick days, no vacation.
No, I'll get to it tomorrow.
The system I'm talking about uses
tools like Vapi for voice,
make.com for workflow automation,
and voice flow over conversation
logic.
It picks up the phone, has a real
conversation, qualifies lead, and
books meetings for your sales
team.
So yeah, this is great.
So we're going through all the
automations.
Uh, now we're on to four to six
growth layer, and then we should
have, uh, four to six.
So we've covered the foundation
growth layers.
We even though these six
automations are operating levels
agency will never reach.
These are where things get really
interesting.
These next two automations are
where I've seen the biggest ROI.
We're talking about systems that
will save time, improve
efficiency, blah, blah, blah.
Great.
And then let's do continue.
We're going to do, uh, section
seven to eight under the
implementation reality section.
Forms reporting and then.
Revenue recovery system is a big
reveal.
All right.
Here's what we've been waiting
for.
The automation that generated
$220,000 in five weeks with zero
human intervention.
Before I reveal it, let me ask you
something.
What's the biggest waste of money
in your business?
It's not your tools.
It's not your team.
It's not even your failed
marketing campaigns.
It's your dead leads.
All those people who showed
interest, maybe even gotten a call
with you, but never bought.
They're sitting in your CRM like
buried treasure.
This is where the revenue recovery
becomes pure gold.
I'm talking about AI systems that
automatically segment your old
leads, craft personalized
reactivation campaigns and turn
cold prospects into paying
customers.
So yeah, this is pretty much
perfect.
So then we got the impatient
reality and CTA.
This takes back to everything I
learned going from screaming about
scaling agencies.
Knowledge action is worthless.
Success doesn't care how you feel
about these systems.
I'm going to tell you something
that might make you uncomfortable.
90% of people who watch this video
will do absolutely nothing with
this information.
They'll get excited, maybe
bookmark it, tell themselves to
implement it when they have
time, and then go back to doing
everything manually.
You know why?
Because implementing AI systems
requires the same thing.
So it repeats some things a bit
too much.
So you can always obviously edit
this as it goes on.
Let's see.
Here's what I've learned code
coders of HCRs.
It's not by the technology.
The tools are there.
The systems work.
The results are proven.
The problem is psychological.
If you want the results, that's
learning curve.
They want the $220,000 automation
without understanding lead
qualification.
They want the $100,000 revenue
recovery without setting up proper
data tracking
first.
But success doesn't work that way.
You can't skip to foundation and
jump to the advanced stuff.
Remember the automation hierarchy
I mentioned?
Foundation first, complexity
later.
So here's your choice.
You can be like 90% who watch
this, get inspired for five
minutes,
and go back to minding and
handling every lead and want to
worry
your competitors are scaling
faster.
Or you can be like the 10% who
understand the adaptability.
That adaptability is the ultimate
business skill.
direct CTA final challenge.
So if you want to help embedding
these systems, I've got a few
options for you.
First, if you're serious about
scaling an agency, check out
client extension.
Links in the description.
That's where I learned the
fundamentals.
It's allowed me to build
everything else.
And of course, this will be
optimized for whatever your offer
is.
That's the final element of there.
So now we've got everything
included.
We've got a full script.
We can make any refinements or
adjustments.
So I can say to her, for instance,
like I want to remove the
mentioning,
you know, from one of my videos.
Something like going from being a
death metal vocalist to running
agencies.
And you can kind of change
wherever you want.
But overall, we can get all this
copy now into a Google Doc.
And you've got a full script
pretty much ready to go.
This is optimized based on
Brian's, you know, his templates
and his formatting.
And he's got incredible results,
you know, running a YouTube
agency.
So he knows what he's talking
about.
So this is the easiest way to,
without any previous experience,
write YouTube scripts that are
going to get results.
If you do this for, you know, the
next, you know, 10 videos,
I guarantee you're going to book
leads off these.
So hopefully this is helpful.
This is kind of a long video.
I'm going to cut it down a little
bit, maybe.
But it gives the idea of how you
can use Poppy to create content on
autopilot.
This is really, as you saw, most
of what I did here was just typing
in
continue after giving up my
information.
And then I'll do some quick
editing afterwards to kind of, you
know,
make it exactly how I want it to
sound a bit more like me.
And we're good to go.
So highly suggest using Poppy for
this.
Highly suggest using Brian's
template,
which you can find the template
section on Poppy and let
Let me know how it goes for you
guys, right?
So see you in the next one.
Peace.