All right, so now I'm going to
talk about the core tool stack
and what you need to know.
So we'll start with automation
tools.
There's three main ones in the
space.
The first one in the space was
Zapier.
I don't recommend this one to
start,
but I just want to let you know
that it exists.
And if sometimes there's things
that need to use Zapier,
maybe there's an integration with
just Zapier
that's not available via an API,
which you'll learn later what that
is,
or it's available as like a module
in the different automation
platforms,
you'd have to go use Zapier,
unfortunately.
These are the two,
and these ones are called
step-based platforms, I would say.
And what that means is each step
in the automation
is what you get charged for.
There is some nuance there,
which I have a table here of like
when it's counted,
when it's not.
But each one of these squares here
is a step in the automation.
And every time it runs, it charges
you.
So if we come over to Zapier here,
we can see that if we come into
the plans,
it says I need 10,000 tasks per
month.
So what is a task?
It's any actionable step.
It does exclude like triggers and
things like that.
But yeah, I just wanted to show
you how,
when you see what is a task here,
that's what this means.
And for Zapier, you're going to
need at least the pro plan.
They might give you a free trial
here to try,
but they won't really let you
connect to very many things
if you just use the free plan.
So yeah, that's Zapier in a
nutshell.
So if we come over to here,
then we have make.com.
So this is my primary platform of
choice.
This is where I started.
I do use a little bit of N1N as
well.
But this is a good one for
beginners, I think,
because it's still visual.
You know, you can see exactly
what's happening.
So again, this trigger right here,
you can see this is a web hook.
Here is a web hook.
So it's like the same thing.
This is a step.
This is adding a cold email
response to a CRM in ClickUp
and then notifying the team.
Again, these are just steps.
These are called modules.
And yeah, so make is priced very
similarly
where it's per step.
So if we come over to the make
pricing here,
you can see, but it's a lot
cheaper.
You saw that on Zapier,
it's 10,000 tasks per month is
$193 per month.
Meanwhile, if you look at make,
the pricing is if you use the core
plan,
which I recommend starting with,
you don't really need money.
These upgrade features to start,
to be honest,
it's $9 a month or if we go,
or sorry, a year.
Sorry, it's $10 a month
and then $18 a month for the pro
plan.
But again, like that is a lot
cheaper
than the $193 on Zapier.
So that's why it's better.
If you see here,
I left a note for you guys here
is makes better for higher volume
automation.
So if there's a lot of steps in an
automation
because you get charged per step,
then that's when you'd want to use
make.
Meanwhile, Zapier sometimes has
those integrations
out of the box that make doesn't.
So it's easier to use.
And then you can see here,
there's a table showing you
what I mean.
So like a trigger,
one Zapier doesn't count as a
task,
but it counts as an operation on
make.
An action counts as a task,
counts as an operation,
and so on and so forth.
So those are the two early guys.
And then recently,
the new kid on the block
is this N8N.
And N8N is different as well
in the way they charge you.
So they've got a similar format.
You know,
they've got that background
and then you drag and drop these
modules
and connect them together.
But if we come over to N8N's
pricing plan,
the way N8N works
is it's per scenario
or per workflow execution
is what they call it.
So scenario and make
is like all the steps
to do one full automation.
It's the same thing in N8N,
but it's called the workflow
execution.
So you get limited
by the number of times
you get to run
that full set of steps.
You could run five
of those concurrently.
So say you built
five different automations.
Five of those could run at once,
but say you built 20 automations.
You could still have
the 20 automations on N8N,
but they are going to get queued.
So what that means is
the first five are going to go
and it's going to wait
and then it's going to run
the next five
and the next five
if there's things in the backlog.
So if things are like
meant to be instant,
that's where that's not ideal.
And maybe you'd want to upgrade
to say the pro client.
And then also knowing
how many workflow executions
you actually need
for the year is important
or month, sorry.
So that's where
if you go with N8N,
you have some options.
You can either do the cloud
hosted,
which is directly through them,
just like the other platforms.
You just click and pay
and they host it for you.
You don't have to worry about
anything.
Alternatively, Lucas
is going to have some instructions
on how you can
actually self-host this.
And that lets you run
unlimited workflows executions.
It's really not that hard to do,
to be honest.
So that's the route
I'd recommend
if you're going to use
N8N is to self-host it.
Yeah, so we won't get
into too much detail there.
So those are
core automation platforms.
Other things
from a comparison perspective,
lets you run
JavaScript,
which is actual real code.
So that makes it
a little bit more robust
if you're into certain scenarios
where the modules
in either of these
aren't cutting it.
I think Zapier
lets you run
a little bit as well,
but it is a lot
more flexible too.
The other thing
is their AI agent support.
So they make it really easy
to make these AI agents
with memory
and choosing
the database
and the model
that you want to use.
So that's the one thing.
They were the first people
kind of making
these agents down.
They all have agents.
I would say theirs
is still the best,
but they all have
that functionality.
it's not like
you're like missing out
on anything.
You just have to learn
how to use
the specific platforms
AI agents.
And yeah,
that's probably
the main thing.
So how do you
learn these, right?
You want to pick
one of these.
I would choose
make or any
and to start
just because
they are more visual.
Zapier runs
into some weird
limitations.
I sometimes call it
like the Zapier attacks
where people come in
like, hey,
I'm using Zapier
for this.
I can't do it.
And then in
make or any
and it's like
literally two seconds
to fix.
You're much better off,
I think,
starting with either
one of these platforms
and the content
out there for both
of these is very
good to learn.
So YouTube really
has everything you need.
And also the official
make Academy
is actually pretty solid
to learn initially
when you're getting
started.
So I've linked
the official Academy
here as well as
the YouTube playlist
to check out.
You don't have to
watch all the videos
in either of these.
I would say 20,
30 hours
until you're
comfortable.
And then same
with N8N,
I've linked
a YouTube video
here that's
an eight-hour
masterclass
as well as
Lucas is going
to provide
some resources
on how to
learn N8N
as well.
And yeah,
don't just
watch,
build alongside.
I would say
that's one of
the big problems
people do
is like they
just watch
these videos
and they
don't actually
take the time
to build
the things
and then
when they get
into it,
they're like,
I don't even
know what I'm
doing.
So make sure
you actually
take some time
and build
while you're
watching.
And then just
I wanted to
throw in one
other key
video.
So in
make,
N8N,
all these
things,
they're going to
sometimes have
these out-of-the-box
integrations.
So these are
modules,
right?
So this is a
click-out module
you can see
here and it
lets you create
a task.
This is out-of-the-box
already built-in
connected to the
API.
But there's going
to be times
we're going to
run into issues
where you need
to do something
on connecting
some softwares
together,
but you can't
actually do it
natively in
either of any
of these platforms.
So you're going
to have to
manually do an
API call.
So this is
just a video
on how to
connect any
API call
on make.com
but the
principle is
the exact same
using something
like NNN
and as always
use chat
GPT
or quad
to ask
questions.
If you're
into any
issues,
they'll tell
you what to
do.
The next
thing you
want to
familiarize
yourself
with is
project
management
tools,
not only
for yourself
but for
your clients
as well.
Again,
for me,
like I
primarily
help
businesses
with project
management
tools.
So I'm
building
automations
on top
of these
so you
need to
understand
their API,
how they're
structured,
where the
data goes,
all those
different
things is
very
important.
So that's
why you
should really
familiarize
yourself with
these.
Again,
it's the
same as
the
automation
platforms.
You learn
one,
you kind
of learn
them all.
So don't
stress.
And I've
linked also
a master
class I did
on doing
project
management.
This is
more so
like doing
project
management
in your
own
business.
But you
could take
some of
these
principles
and apply
them when
you're
helping
businesses
implement
this or
automate
on top
of these
tools.
Another one
that's very
common in the
business space
is CRMs.
These are
client relationship
management tools.
They manage
the data
related to
your clients
for you.
So you're
making sure
you're following
up and keeping
up to date
with all your
clients and
the deals
and your
pipeline,
all those
things.
that's where
a lot
of
opportunity
is
available
for
automation
just
to
increase
sales
velocity.
So familiarize
yourself with
these tools.
Close is
very popular.
HubSpot's more
enterprise.
There's also
Salesforce
they demand
here.
High level
is very
popular if
you end up
working with
agencies.
They really
like high
level because
it's an
all-in-one
and it has
all the key
features.
And then
Adio is
a new one
in the
space.
They're
more like
AI first,
automation
first,
which is a
very cool
platform.
so check
those guys
out as
well.
Ultimately,
each one
of these
is also
going to
have
their own
workflow
builder.
I recommend
trying to
do it
natively
in the
tool
if
possible
just to
minimize
risk and
overhead
and costs
for the
client.
But
sometimes
they can't
do it so
then you're
going to
have to
use the
automation
platforms
up here
to connect
all these
things
together.
Start
simple.
It really
depends on
what the
niche is,
which CRM
they're going
to be using.
Ultimately,
they're all
very much
and they're
just storing
data about
the client
and you
want to
enable them
to make
more sales
or manage
their projects
better with
your automations.
And the
biggest thing
I would say
is just
adopt a
just-in-time
learning
mindset.
what that
means is
instead of
sitting for
hours and
watching
YouTube
tutorials
and
building
random
automations,
just trust
that you're
going to be
able to
figure this
out.
Especially
with AI,
it's like
your junior
intern that's
available that
knows absolutely
everything all
the time.
You can
literally message
this person,
this AI,
and be like,
hey, how do I
do this?
And it most
likely will have
the answer,
and if it
doesn't, it'll
point you in the
right direction.
I've seen
people in
other automation
communities,
they're like,
oh, I don't
know what to
do, I don't
have any
clients, this,
that, and
other thing,
and you come
to learn that
they've been
learning automation
for eight
months, and
they haven't
talked to a
single client,
prospect,
whatever, and
that's because
they feel like
they're not
ready.
They don't
know everything.
Well, I'm
sorry to say,
but this is a
space where
you're never
going to know
everything, and
you're just
going to have
to learn as
you go, but
you just need
to trust that
you'll figure
it out as
you go.
So, yeah,
that is the
tool section.
On the next
video, I'm
going to talk
through some
specific sales
tips on how
to effectively
sell automation
to clients.