All right now we're going to talk
about automations clients want and
more importantly
how to spot automations that maybe
they don't know they want but you
can see that they need
so what does that look like focus
on ball next next slide talk a
little bit about the
theory of constraints i've already
mentioned this a couple times in
the previous ones but
think about automations that drive
revenue or leverage so time
savings making money
is it high value low value that
really depends on frequency right
so this happens task once every
three months probably not worth
automating even if it's in one of
these categories so think about
those cases as well theory
constraints is you want to look at
a business as a collection of
steps and
systems and processes and every
business has a constraint so one
business might be lead generation
maybe they don't have enough
traffic another might be their
closing rate they're not selling
well enough another might be that
their fulfillment is bad so
sometimes it doesn't make sense to
automate
the aspects of the fulfillment if
they don't have a good offer
already and traffic's bad and all
those
different things so you need to
think about what is the singular
bottleneck that limits how fast or
efficiently the whole system can
operate so instead of optimizing
everything you want to focus
your energy on fixing the
bottleneck that's why you don't
ask what do you want to automate
when you talk to
your clients you say what's
currently slowing down the most
and then see if there's any way
you can help there
so specific automations i've seen
work very well especially if
you're going to be looking after
agencies uh client onboarding this
is a big one creates a lot of
leverage there are so many steps
depending on the type of agency to
actually onboard a new client you
need to send them welcome emails
links forms you need to create
tasks in your project management
system you need to create folders
in your cloud
storage like google drive you need
to maybe save the proposal or the
contract you need to fill in some
checklists with
all their information you need to
create the different resource
documents for your team to
understand
what's going on you just sign the
roles and timelines and notify
everybody maybe in slack that you
signed
a new client there's so many steps
there and i think this is one of
the best ones if you're going out
for that that agency but think
about this from the perspective of
like in any business what is
something
that has a lot of manual steps and
is really painful to do so that's
an example of leverage
another example here is of
generating revenue so automating
the creation of proposals what you
can do is take their winning
proposals that they manually wrote
for years and years and years
feed that into a reg bot and train
it up on the best practices and
then from there habit generate
what the problem statement is what
the solution statement is maybe
even timelines
that have it to auto send for
signature other things you can do
also here is like take it from
their meeting transcripts to all
their sales calls if they click a
button maybe in slack or in their
project management system or crm
it'll go and generate this if the
person is a fit based on the
discussion using the transcript of
the meeting all these are good
opportunities because if you can
increase
sales velocity they can get their
cash faster than they can pay you
more money to do more things right
another one is crms and project
management systems i've already
talked about those systems are
very
common in all service businesses
and really they're just a place to
store data and collaborate with
but you can really supercharge
those so for example um it's
creating automation so from
calendly for
example automatically captures the
information and puts in the crm
and notifies the sales team that
there's a new uh lead so they can
actually earn away same with like
cold email if you get a positive
cold email response you could
automate the notification of that
auto scheduling follow-up
reminders or emails
for you maybe even drafting the
next response using ai based on
how you've um written it i
wouldn't
recommend sending it yet it's not
quite there yet and i'd rather
have a human load because this is
like
as close to money as you can get
so you want to make sure that that
stuff is airtight or another good
use is like when someone books in
so building on top of these ones
is actually researching their
website
and them through apis and then
storing that research for the
sales rep to see and then even
working in
some case studies that you have
and saying okay this case study
fits this type of client and stuff
like
that so there's tons of
opportunity there and then from
project management after you do
the onboarding
and the sale like you built some
automations to auto create tasks
so maybe every week you have to do
a new marketing campaign so you
could automate the creation of
that task and the assignment and
you know pull on the stats from
the last week and have ai analyze
that these are just things i'm
coming up with the top of my head
i haven't built all of these four
coins you just gotta get creative
right if someone asks for this
this is where you can help them
out if this is a problem they have
send slack alerts for key
milestone changes um you know
notifications and assign team
members
so yeah think of crms and pm
systems as your stock engine that
you can upgrade automation mods to
make
the system better the big problem
is as businesses grow
communication becomes an issue um
and as soon as one
person drops the ball again going
back to that theory of constraints
if that person is the bottleneck
and
they forget to tell somebody
something and maybe something gets
delayed for a day or two and then
the client gets mad happens all
the time in service businesses
this is where you could help with
if
you know something moves to a
certain stage it alerts the team
tells them it's ready for your
turn
to do this um it really eliminates
the uh hey did you do this yet
messages that happen all the time
uh a lot of the tools now
especially click up which is what
i use for project management
have these awesome ai stand ups
that'll generate daily updates and
you can just click on each person
and they'll automatically generate
like what they did for the week or
even for client updates you
automatically generate those so
just by virtue of setting them up
there's some ai features they
could
benefit there from using a project
management system yeah building i
guess i kind of just spoiled this
next one but yeah that that's kind
of what i was getting at is like
the weekly kpi summaries or
client updates big one too like
cold email agencies they have all
the stats positive reply rates
email sent
emails replied to emails and
campaign to yet to be sent all
those different things
those stats could be just like a
templated message that the owner
gets every day for each one
or even you send it to the clients
like we sent 500 emails today and
we've got this many responses
just like if you want to like
really keep them in the loop um
another one is real-time
dashboards
so again kind of that same stuff
but just building the dashboard
itself and then hooking up the
automations to collect the data so
that two-in-one thing you get paid
to build the dashboard and you
also
obviously you do the front end but
then you're like okay now we got
to get the data in here so you
don't have to manually put it in
and then click buttons to make it
happen you can just have it
automated
you can use something like looker
studio or now the ai coding tools
are getting so good
you could probably just use that
and then connect some apis and
call it a day i just like maybe if
projects are delayed so you could
look at if project doesn't move
for three days notify the owner of
the project manager like hey can
you check in on this so sometimes
people miss things as as you grow
and then yeah just like creating
this frictionless sync right so
like those were all the individual
systems but now if you think about
the whole business as one big
system you could have the
lead generation you pull the leads
from the outreach tool it's
directly in the crm with tagging
you qualify them maybe you put
them through some kind of
screening process with ai to say
who's the
best sales rep for this product or
this service type um maybe you
send them different free call
sequences depending on what type
of business they are and then once
they close you automatically
onboard them and
put the right task type and
project tasks with the right
templates in the project
management system so
like there's just so much
opportunity there another big one
is just like enabling founders
with ai
automation so just asking them to
share their day to day oftentimes
it's like they just want to really
know what who they're meeting with
like background all the
participants maybe some pm
information
um or then just like getting a
daily digest email of like maybe
what tasks were completed in the
project
management system who did what
kind of thing just so they can get
a pulse check while these don't
like
scale across the whole team it's
super beneficial for the owner
themselves um and then just some
other
ways again i want to teach you
guys to fish as opposed to me just
telling you like build these
automations
interview the team members of the
um the clients so ask to interview
your shadow employees doing work
look for better tasks watch their
screens find the rev lab
opportunities in the skies and
then if once
you've got some trust get audit
their whole business interview
their team members and then find
using
this framework some more things
and then if you get a if you've
got trust you probably charge for
the audit but
as you're starting out just offer
it for free if you feel like this
business could really benefit from
this i'll give it to them for free
and then just charge for the
implementation so yeah yeah to be
honest
some of the best automation has
come from just chatting with
people's employees and then here's
kind
of uh impact to implementation
effort just knowing which ones are
the best um these ones are good to
get
the ball rolling take care of
these ones first and then um if
you've got time if you haven't had
a chance
to do a lot of discovery i'm sure
you could find some more impact
quick wins do those and then
obviously
these are the best ones that get
you paid the most money and this
should be the long-term focus
so that is in a nutshell what
automations you can help build for
businesses