So we're going to talk about
finding your ideal client profile,
landing your first AI automation
agency client.
So the best way to identify your
ICP is twofold, in my opinion.
So you want to do businesses with
high volumes of deliverables and
preferably
service businesses, because they
have more money.
So that this is businesses driving
in repetitive tasks.
That's time consuming agencies,
coaches, and B2B service
providers.
So that's who I primarily work
with.
Myself, businesses generating 10k
per month revenue plus, like they
need to have some
money to pay you.
Otherwise this just doesn't work.
They have teams that are drowning
in disconnected tools.
That's why agencies are good
because they have so many software
tools to actually run
their businesses.
And then the founders that are
about to make their first hires,
but they need management
systems.
So a lot of the work I also do is
help implement project management
systems, CRMs and things
like that, because they start
needing those tracking on
information is more important as
they grow.
And then companies just like
losing money to inefficiency,
which is probably every company,
to be honest.
The other thing to consider is
your background and experience.
So as I mentioned previously, I
used to work in project
management, right?
So I was familiar with all the
different project management
softwares because I'd used them
extensively in the past.
I'd also at the manager IT service
provider helped on several CRM
implementations.
So I was familiar with things like
Salesforce and HubSpot and all
that stuff.
So that's how I ended up working
primarily with those tools and the
automations.
Use your past experience.
You might not think you have any,
I'm sure you have some kind of
insider knowledge, but it just
makes positioning yourself better.
I also talked to engineers.
I haven't signed on engineer yet,
but I talked to them regularly
under the pain points because I
used to work with them and be one
myself.
So all that to say, consider your
background when picking your ICP
and niche.
The best clients have clear pain
points that AI automation can
solve and can easily show a
visible ROI.
And doing everything for everyone
just isn't scalable.
So you have to pick something to
start and you don't have to,
you're not married to it.
So like, it's okay if you change.
So what's next after you pick
something, okay, I want to maybe
pick two or three things to
research.
Now you're going to research these
things.
You're going to go to chat GPT,
use AI here and just start asking
questions.
Just keep it really high level,
say what you're going to do and
then ask what are the specific
operational challenges they run
into?
What can I help them with use your
findings to develop some potential
solutions?
And then after we get the next
stage where you're going to learn
how to use these automation tools.
Once you learn that, try to build
a minimal viable product.
So a basic thing maybe does one of
the several things that you found
talking to AI, just so you can
have something to show that click,
look at the magic.
It might not be exactly specific
to that business that you talk to,
but at least they see that like,
Hey, this guy can actually do
something.
And then as a beginner, there's
this thing called market
sophistication level.
You want to choose businesses that
have limited technical knowledge,
right?
So think like home services, like
these guys don't understand tech.
And you want to think of
businesses that have a lot of
operational efficiencies.
Like they're still using
spreadsheets for everything.
Processes just like haven't been
optimized.
A lot of marketing agencies now
are getting a little bit more
sophisticated.
So they're moving up that train a
little bit.
But that isn't to say that there's
still a lot of marketing agencies
and coaches and consultants that
are not sophisticated.
And then you also want people who
are open to technology, but I'm
sure where to start.
So the thing with these limited
technical knowledge, people like
home service businesses, you're
going to have to educate them on
like why they want this and how
it's going to work.
And like the media is doing a
pretty good job of talking about
the benefits of AI, but sometimes
you got to sell them on the AI
first and then sell them on your
solution as well, as opposed to
with some marketing agencies, like
they already know the benefits.
They just don't know how to get it
done.
So it makes it a little bit
easier.
So once you have all that, then
you want to develop your first
offer.
So identify those common pain
points, create those solutions.
Daniel's got really good offers
training, follow that all those
principles apply.
One of the things you want to
prepare is some demo assets.
So as I mentioned, build a sample
automation, showcasing some
abilities of what your solution
is.
And then don't price it too crazy,
get an understanding.
Typically, you don't reveal price
before you understand their
business, because a $3,000
solution for one business can
actually be a $10,000 solution for
other businesses that provides the
value.
But you don't know that until you
talk to them, right?
So you can sell the same thing for
3K and 10K.
It doesn't really matter.
All the numbers are made up in the
day.
And your existing goal isn't to
maximize revenue.
It's building credibility through
successful implementations.
So how do you get that first
client now?
So Daniel talks a lot about cold
email, ads, content, all those
different things.
For me personally, these were the
kind of the couple that I used off
the start.
So one was a warm network.
You might say, I don't have any
experience.
I've never run a business.
I've never worked in the
workforce.
To that, I say, you have contacts
in your phone that know people.
And guess what?
You're not actually going to be
pitching your contacts.
You're going to ask them if they
know of anybody who could benefit
from what you do.
So there's a couple ways to do
this.
I have the steps here.
If you click down this and review
it, it'll give you all the steps
on how to do warm outreach.
There's also this video here from
Gary V on the fastest way to get
your first clients, which is just
like the video version of this.
And you could, I feel like this
would convert better.
I actually didn't do this, but I
think this would actually convert
better.
So the second strategy I would say
to get your first client is using
a platform called Upwork, which is
a freelancing platform.
People are posting jobs on there
all the time, how they need help
with AI automation.
And after you've learned a little
bit, you can just go on there and
apply to those.
This is how I got a client early
on as well was through Upwork,
which led to a referral and so on
and so forth.
So there are some good people on
there for sure.
You just won't make a ton of money
to start, but that's not the focus
right now.
So the first thing you want to do
is optimize your profile.
So just do a quick Google search.
Make sure that you're describing
your previous accomplishments, all
the things you've done in the
past, how you've driven revenue or
save time in businesses, whatever
you've done in the past.
Make sure that's highlighted.
Put up some case studies or demo
projects that you've done.
If you haven't done actual work,
put some demo projects up, those
ones you built earlier, those
sales assets, put those up, talk
about the impact they do in your
portfolio, do the Make Academy
course.
And then you can put some badges
up there to show that, you know,
you're certified automation, all
those different things.
It'll just increase the likelihood
that people actually view your
profile and hire you for a job.
So these clients on Upwork are
problem aware.
So what does that mean?
So there's five stages of
awareness of a prospect.
First of all, they can be unaware,
which is they consciously don't
realize they have a problem they
need solving.
They can be problem aware.
The prospect feels a pain and is
aware they have some kind of
problem.
They could be solution aware.
So the prospect is aware that
there are solutions to their
problem available.
And then there's the prospect is
product aware, which is they're
aware that your product service is
one of the available solutions.
And then the most aware, they
think your product or service is
the right solution.
So I would argue, like, maybe
based on this diagram here,
they're more like product aware.
Like they know that a make
automation or any automation will
solve their problem.
So ultimately, all you have to do
is convince them that, like, you
are the solution.
You are the guy to do that for
them, as opposed to if you work
with cold traffic, you're going to
have to move them through these
stages through sales calls and
providing information and things
like that.
So that's why it's a lot easier to
move someone up one step, as
opposed to like all five of these
steps when you're first starting
out.
Another pro tip for using Upwork,
most people are just copy and
pasting chat GPT proposals on
there.
And people hate that they feel
like you don't care about them.
The best way to win deals is to
send a loom videos of yourself
talking through the solution.
So just basically pull up a
automation you've built and just
say, here's how I built this.
Here's what it does.
Here's the results it will
generate.
Or if they have something, if the
job is for something unrelated,
but you think you can solve it,
you just never built it.
You can go on there and just talk
to the process of how you do it,
maybe like partially build it.
People really like that, too.
And as you're going through this,
focus on feedback, focus on
learning, getting early
testimonials, case studies.
So, yeah, that's pretty much how
Upwork works.
I think it's a great place to
start when you're first starting
out.
Another option that I also used is
a free value exchange for
strangers.
So, I don't recommend like just
giving this to anybody.
You can create an absolute
disaster.
You want to qualify people and
preface the free stuff with, hey,
I want to get paid for this one
day.
Not everybody's going to convert
and pay, which is fine, but I
think I just wanted to make sure I
added that note here.
Because if you just go and just
give free shit forever, like
people are going to take advantage
of you.
Unfortunately, there are those
people that exist.
So, yeah.
Basically, the best way to find
these people is either in your
circle or in communities.
So, I've used this approach in
communities, including client
ascension, where initially we
would start an engagement where we
did a free automation.
They were posting about it in one
of the channels and I saw the
opportunity.
I was like, hey, man, like I can
help you with that.
They did a free automation and the
next thing you know, you get paid
to do it, which is awesome because
they know I can trust you now.
So, that is the best way to do it.
Show them the impact and then say,
hey, we can work together long
term.
I'm sure there's other stuff in
your business, so on and so forth.
And then same with the cold
outreach.
Christian talks about it in client
ascension.
When you're first starting out
with your cold email agency, you
could send an email and just say,
hey, you know, I'm just starting
out.
But I'd love to.
I'll spend all the money.
Like, you don't have to do
anything.
Just let me, like, run outreach
for you.
And if you get some stuff, cool.
You can even just pay me per call
if we can even do that.
I'll still pay for all the tech.
So, you could do it with cold
email.
So, combining both cold email and
the free outreach and then just
convert those into case studies,
testimonials, or upsell them into
a retainer or other projects.
So, those are the three main ones
I used in the beginning to get my
first few clients and get my first
few case studies.
In the next one, we're going to
talk about the tools, technology.
We're not going to go too deep on
this, but just really the basics
of what you need to know.