Okay so now you need to something
to sell so i'm going to talk about
how to package this
the different ways you can price
it and then ultimately how to
deliver whatever you sell so
different ways of packaging
there's three different ways i'm
going to blur this just
so we can talk about one at a time
custom builds this is where you go
in you understand their
business and you build them
something completely custom
tailored to their unique process
usually
this is a higher price point since
it's tailored to them and it
typically takes longer since you
don't
have any templates or things to
start 80 of the way there this is
where you typically start to be
honest you can start with a
template and then just tailor it
as well that's another way that's
more
of an offer based but if you're
going to like say upwork or your
warm network or wherever you're
getting at your first client
oftentimes it's like something at
a left field that you've never
seen
before which is okay it's good to
get that practice but you want to
move away from this as soon as you
can unless you like this i kind of
like this i sometimes still dabble
in this because i feel like
i'm learning new things throughout
but it's not the most scalable if
a guy's being honest
the other one is the product high
system so this is where you've
already done this for different
clients
say you choose a niche of like
home service ai calling agent and
like that's your product you
come in but you say hey you know
what we're going to tweak this
exactly to your business
um so if you know you're a cleaner
we're going to change all the
copies so it talks just like it
owns the business can know
everything about your business
that's like that 20 tweaking so
that's
where it's faster implementation
it's reliable tested you've
already done it and you have more
predictable outcomes of what
you're going to do but this is
typically going to be a little bit
cheaper
you'll be able to sell it to
unless you're like you're really
good at making a good business
case
but it's hard to make a good
business case with like limited
information so that's the
trade-off between
these two is like this one you're
going to be able to sell easier
this is a lot harder to sell but
it can
also lead to more money so let's
pick what you want easy to sell
hard to sell easier to fulfill
hard to fulfill i think alex ramos
he talks about this is 100 million
dollar offers there's like a
continuum of easy to fulfill and
hard and easy to sell and hard to
fulfill and hard to sell same
thing
here so um and then a retainer so
this is typically after you've
done some work for somebody they
trust you
already you can move into a
retainer where you say we'll give
you x number of automations a
month or x
systems a month or it's unlimited
for this price the only downfall
of this is like you might be
underselling yourself because
you'll discover opportunities you
might save them thousands of
dollars you might help them grow
from 25k to 200k but you're
charging them a small retainer so
that's
for like things like rev share and
all that stuff comes in but that's
a lot harder to sell with
automation because the impact
isn't directly related like to the
actual getting of money so it's a
lot
harder to actually quantify that
you trade stability here for the
biggest amount of revenue as
opposed
to like with these custom builds
and these product high systems if
they're just one time setup fees
then your revenue will be a little
bit more lumpy as you go you'll
likely use all three of these
structures as your agency matures
each has its place depending on
your current skill level and your
client's specific needs and
timelines so now that you've
chosen a way to package this now
you need
to a way to price it so there's a
few different ways to price
automation this is typically where
you
start this is what those guys on
fiverr and upwork are doing and
it's hourly because you don't
really
know how long things are going to
take the advantage of this is
there's a little risk of the scope
grows
and you say okay you asked for
five hours of work customer but
now you're asking for all these
things
you can charge more per hour um
but there's going to be an income
ceiling pretty quick because you
can
only charge so much for hour and
clients may micromanage hours this
is good starting out if you have a
hard
time quantifying the value of the
automation ideally this is where
you want to move into which is
like
fixed price um so value based
pricing is probably the best here
and of course also accounting for
your
time because even if you price on
value you still want to make sure
that like you're making a good
hourly
rate as you're doing it i think
there's this thing where you could
maybe say okay i can get this much
money
but like the value is really high
but the hours i'm gonna have to
put in to actually generate this
value is very expensive so you
need to consider that so that's
the risk of under pricing a really
complex work but it's higher
received value and rewards
efficiency that's the other
problem with
hourly's this is good if you suck
because you take a long time to do
the work so you get paid more
but if you're actually good at the
work then you're being basically
handicapped by an hourly rate
and then next is of course the
retainer so this is like taking
these two pricing models but then
like bundling them so like you
could have an hourly retainer so
it's like you get 20 hours per
month for
x price or it's like a fixed price
retainer it's like this much per
month every month and we do as
much work as we can or x number of
improvements per month or it's
value based so maybe you audit
their
business and you're like okay
we've got this many things and i
can do this for ten thousand
dollars a
month or you can pay me per
project it's going to be like
fifteen thousand dollars per
project and like
we can do it over a longer time
horizon or something like that
right so then they're like oh
there's more
value in doing it all at once so
um the biggest issue here is just
like strong boundaries with
clients
to prevent over delivery so you
need to monitor even though you're
not charging hourly you need to
monitor the
hours you're putting in to make
sure like you're not losing money
by working with somebody and yeah
keep it simple at the beginning
start with hourly or fixed price
if you can like the the biggest
problem with fixed price is like
if you don't know how long it's
going to take you you can like
just
lose money which kind of sucks um
so that's why i always pretty good
in the beginning because then
you start to get a feel of how
long things are actually taking
you and then retainers are going
to
come after people know i can trust
you and understand uh your
workplace so
based off that you're going to
sell something and once you sell
something you're going to need to
do
something called an onboarding
call so what this is to get them
into your business into your world
so the first thing you need to do
on that onboarding call um is set
expectations so clarify the
timeline the
deliverables talk about what
success looks like you want to be
very clear of what the expectation
is
obviously you've done a proposal
already you've said what the
deliverables are but you need to
make
sure you're still on the same page
before you get started
next you want to remind them what
they bought so you'd be shocked
even if it's been a couple days
you're like what did the client's
gonna forget what exactly is it
called did we actually include
you know connecting this to notion
and air table you're like no like
you told me you didn't want
that so like that's not included
do you want that now i can't tell
you the number of times i've had
that experience so remind them
review the contract really quick
make sure everybody thinks good
tell
them the next steps the process
and immediate action items explain
how often you're going to
communicate say we're going to be
communicating on click up or slack
or email or whatever just pick a
channel work with them whatever
works best for them and then get
all the access sorted out so
collect
the tools logins and two-factor
authentication before the end of
the call this is absolutely
massive so i'm just gonna sorry do
this so you can see everything um
two-factor authentication is super
important in automation it can
really make or break things
because the last thing you want to
do is text the
person at midnight hey i need to
get into your make.com account and
the t2fa is not working and
it just like looks super
unprofessional and just it's bad
experience um something i also
recommend
is if you're like using the same
tools over and over again you can
send an sop or video guide before
the calls the client can either if
they're tech savvy and like they
know what they're doing they can
prepare the logins and stuff but
most of the time they probably
won't do it ahead of time but
worst case
you have this ready to go so then
when you get on the call you're
just like hey i'm going to send
you a link to
this thing or just check your
email it has a link to like the
document to show you what you need
to do
um that works very well as well
but yeah let me just show you real
quick this email make
notifications
so what this means is basically
every time like you run the
automation if there's like an
error
or there's a warning like there's
something not working properly
it'll send an email by default
and if it's the client's account
they're gonna get all of that
garbage in there so when you're
testing the
automation and things aren't
working properly they're just
gonna get blasted with emails so
you
want to make sure you turn that
off but then turn it back on once
the automation's done so they
actually
do get notified if something
breaks because things do end up
breaking from time to time one
thing i didn't
write on this slide was you want
to set them up with their own
accounts so you don't want to
build the
automations on like your account
because that just sets a bad
precedent for relationships like
you're
essentially holding them hostage
so like if they decide to leave
you you just turn off their
automations and
that's not really what you want to
be doing you want to be working
with people on merit as opposed to
i'm just like holding them hostage
so make sure you're setting up all
this stuff on their accounts
themselves okay so let me show you
really quick what that make thing
looks like so if we come to
the so if you come over to your
name over here or the client's
name and then come to email
preferences
thing you want to turn off is
these two here so errors and
scenario runs and warnings and
scenario
runs turn these off while you're
building and then when you're done
you want to turn these back on
so you actually get notified so
just wanted to show you that there
okay so moving on you've done the
onboarding call you're like yeah
we get to go build automations and
no you don't have not quite yet
you don't want to build blind so
what that means is before touching
make any to end or any automation
tool map the process in detail
this is a critical step that
prevents costly rework for you and
scope
creep because again you've you've
just throughout this whole thing
you reviewed the proposal again
you
asked if there's anything missing
maybe they said there was you
updated the price you went back
you agreed on
it but then you build the
automation at the end they still
say hey this isn't right this
isn't what i
wanted like even if you do all
this stuff i'm telling you they
still might do that so don't worry
but
this isn't gonna i'm trying to
keep you safe throughout this
whole process so map the process
and then
document every step trigger action
in the workflow capture edge cases
and exceptions um if you don't
know what they are ask the client
is there any edge cases we need to
be considering this thing like
because do you ever enter i don't
know a french name with symbols
maybe like that breaks something
i don't know just consider all the
different edge cases uh as you're
going uh validate the technical
feasibility um confirm all the
needed apis and integrations are
available so check the websites
for
all the different tools that are
involved and make sure this all
works together accordingly and
then just
confirm expected outcomes this is
what you do after you build this
with the client so most beginners
skip
mapping and they just suffer from
angloscope creep don't be that
person it sucks because you you're
so
excited you're like oh i'm gonna
do this automation like two hours
when it makes so much money
and then it takes you like 10
hours because the client keeps
asking for stuff and you're like
oh i didn't set expectations here
um so like you re-deliver it you
make videos and looms like i'll
tell you
later to do do all this stuff and
i'm speaking from experience
basically just don't make that
mistake
so what does that look like here's
a basic system for very basic
project management crm for a
photography company for example um
and these are all the different
steps you could also add like the
different types of modules you
would add based on the automation
so maybe this one says let's say
create
lead so you could write here like
create contact or create tasks
because this was for click ups
would be a
created task of what the actual
module you're going to use in the
automation platform is called just
to
make it even clearer um okay so
you've done that you've got the
process map you want to show this
to
their client you can either set up
another meeting with them and walk
them through it it's probably best
or you can send them a loom and
walk them through it and send them
a link and explain each of the
decision points ask if it's valid
accurate is there anything we're
missing just based on feedback be
reasonable here if they're making
some small tweaks that isn't in
the original scope of work um and
it's
a fixed price like just accept it
but if it's a massive change it's
going to have like 10 hours to
project
then you you have a conversation
then and then just get explicit
appropriately okay are you happy
with
this can i build this now and just
this step increases trust again
because they feel like they
designed
right even though you did all the
work they feel like just by
reviewing this and like providing
because
every time i guarantee you every
single time they're gonna say like
one little thing it's okay can you
make sure like it capitalizes the
letters over here and you're like
yeah we can do that mr customer no
problem so yeah just doing that is
is super awesome for the client as
well because they feel more
involved so now you've done what
you need to do you want to build
and test extensively you want to
make
sure it works in every scenario
that you've talked about like a
single brook automation can
destroy weeks
of trust both up so like you've
done all that work at a time um so
make sure you take the time to
actually test it thoroughly um to
build up that trust further so
build modularly
um create small testable
components don't create monster
automations what i mean by that is
oftentimes
you can break up the steps for
example you have this automation
that enriches data so maybe the
first automation is it scrapes the
data from a scraping platform
called apify that lets you scrape
data
i'm just giving you an example
here and it captures it into a
spreadsheet then maybe there's
another
automation that watches when the
new data is added and that
automation just goes and enriches
it based
on researching that person's
website so that's emails or
something as opposed to building
that all into
one automation where like it
stripes it then it captures it and
then it enriches it um it just
creates complexity
and creates more risk and becomes
harder to fix in the future the
more things you add so try to
build
your automations in small
bite-sized pieces and then test
edge cases so empty input fields
like what
happens if we miss this data is it
going to break all these different
things make sure use error
handling
and again in all those videos um
it'll show you on how to actually
handle all these different
situations
this is just high level what you
should be thinking about as you're
testing the automations so
once you're done building again on
the idea of this is all intangible
the client can't touch and feel
this
you need to make it touchy-feely
so how do you make it touchy-feely
you document and demo the build
once it's done you create a loom
video very similar to what i'm
doing here and you just talk
through okay
mr customer here's the automation
this is the steps it follows all
this stuff and if this breaks we
have
this error handling route here and
this is gonna um send you a
notification that the process
didn't work
um and just explain all the
different decisions you made and
all that stuff other pro tip is if
you go to
um the the uh json sorry brain
fart um you can export the json
which is like just like the
instructions of
the automation so if you come to
make.com i'm just gonna find an
automation here so here's an
example
of automation where it's done in
two steps so like step one was a
new submission is generated so
triggers a
webhook and it goes and makes a
mock-up image for some clothing
this is exemplated for a prospect
and then once it's done it'll
trigger another webhook and then
that'll capture it update the
record
send an email to the client and
say hey your mock-up for the
clothing is done with your logo on
it
um so this is an example of an
automation that's done in two
steps so as opposed to like
connecting this part all to here
um it just adds complexity right
so it's better to have it in two
separate automations now i
explained to you what this did at
a high level but what you can do
is you
can click here and click export
blueprint and what that's going to
do is enable you to actually put
this
this in something like claude so
um if we put in claude and we're
just going to hit upload file
and just say give me a explanation
of this automation that i can use
as like turnover
documentation for my client
and it'll say what this actually
does and what each step does
and you can take this and copy
this into a word document and
paste it or into a google doc
whatever
the case may be paste it save it
as a pdf it explains everything
accordingly and what it does
that's just an example of using
the ai put that in a template to
tailor it exactly how you want it
add your own letterhead of like
documentation and then be like
okay customer here is the complete
package you've got a loom we've
got documentation and they can
reference it later the ai is
pretty
good here doing this but make sure
you also add some like information
manually yourself in case it
misses
anything and then throughout this
whole process while you're
building the automation you want
to make
sure that you are communicating
regularly again i'm gonna beat
this to death but like clients
can't see
progress the way they could like a
physical product you're building a
house if you're like i'm 50
building
the house they can actually see
that visually like they can't do
that with this so you want to make
sure that you keep on with the
date while you want to include in
those updates you want to tell
them
what's been done what's happening
now what's happening next and when
to expect the next update
and you want to try to do minimum
two updates a week probably when
you're starting out
or if you guys agree upon a
different cadence that onboarding
call then do it not cadence
and then if there's any
emergencies or issues immediate
notification try to fix problems
at a
time then tell the client as
opposed to telling the client
something's broken and then be
like oh
we could be like okay like
something broke because xyz
someone put an image into a text
field and it
broke everything you can be like
hey someone did this and it broke
the automation but i fixed it just
wanted to let you know let the
team know kind of thing
and then expansion revenue so
after you've successfully done
your first project what can
you do you can continue with
either doing fixed price projects
so they're easier to price with
proper
discovery if you know exactly what
you're going to be building they
have lower risk of over delivery
they can be systemized and resold
so you can go back into that
middle column that we talked about
earlier which is that like product
high service um so basically this
is like getting paid to build
products which is pretty cool one
of the cons though is it's less
predictable sometimes the system
can't be resold like it's very
specific um or like there's like
annda or something like that right
they won't let you resell it so be
aware of that and requires ongoing
sales efforts you sell one and
done and there's no more revenue
per client so you need to sell
them more more and more things
which makes
your cash flow pretty lumpy and
yeah your relationship could end
after that and then the other
option is
monthly retainers so this is
you're gonna have predictable
monthly revenue you're gonna get
basically become a partner in the
business as opposed to just like a
vendor or like a transaction
relationship you're gonna get an
opportunity for strategic input so
you can charge more typically for
this if you're also product
writing strategy low over client
acquisition costs once you've
acquired a
client you no longer have to go
get them again you can just keep
selling so the ltv to cac ratio is
really good and then the cons it's
difficult to scope accurately high
risk over delivery challenging to
price
correctly requires very strong
boundaries which most new business
owners really struggle to do
and it's more complex to manage
multiple clients because you want
to make sure you're giving them
all value all at the same time so
yeah either approach works you can
keep reselling fixed price
projects
until you know you've earned the
trust and the right's probably a
bad word here the trust to
transition
retainers start with what you can
confidently deliver on so recap
here what is the full delivery
workflow
understand the client's needs
assess fit and gather initial
requirements on the sales call you
know if
you need to audit them you do that
then you have a closing call where
you get a contract then you do an
onboarding call once things are in
place map their process get
approval build it test it demo and
document handoff and then upsell
or go find some more clients so
yeah every step in the process is
key
to protect your time and
reputation don't skip mapping or
testing you'll almost always
regret it and
you're going to set yourself up
for scope creep which is a big
problem so yeah that is in summary
how
how to deliver a automation
service.