Okay so now we're going to get
into selling automation without
sounding like a nerd or
snake oil salesman one of the big
problems with automation is it's
very technical people don't
really understand it or it's very
buzzwordy where people start
bringing in the words ai agents
this
that the other thing and like
prospects are getting confused
they're gonna get overwhelmed
and they won't buy so let's get
into it so the number one beginner
mistake is do you want an ai
call agent so you come in there
leading with tools and solutions
before really understanding their
problems and that creates
resistance because it just feels
like you're you're coming in with
like
a shopping cart full of ai agents
you're like which one would you
like sir and that's not really
gonna work to be honest they feel
like they're being sold to rather
than helped
alternatively you want to approach
it with being curious i would say
is the biggest
skill set to have here so they
mention yeah we're really
struggling with no shows
um and then you go okay well how
do you handle those shows today
and you start understanding
their situation and they say oh
well we have them in our crm but
then we sometimes follow up
sometimes
we forget to okay so like when you
do follow up do you ever like
convert any of those people like
are
they actually still good prospects
oh yeah most definitely like they
booked a meeting they filled out a
form
they're probably still interested
in our product but we just like
forget to do it so would you say
if we were to build you an
automation that automatically
followed up with them um and ask
them to rebook on
your calendar and they rebooked
that maybe there's a chance they'd
buy oh yeah probably so it's that
line of questioning where you got
to dig deeper and understand their
current situation and see how
your systems could help um so
that's the better approach as
opposed to just like trying to
throw
any automation you can think of at
them so don't sell a tool diagnose
a problem
the most common mistake new
automation consultants make is
skipping discovery and just
recommending new
tools without really understanding
what's the issue in the business
to help you with this
to find problems that are actually
worth solving and that automation
can actually solve you want
to use something i call the rev
and lev framework so every
automation solution you propose
must solve
one or of two fundamental business
needs increasing revenue or
creating leverage if it doesn't do
either
it's likely not worth pursuing
it's really hard to come up with
an roi if it doesn't do any of
these so
when it comes to rev this is code
word for revenue um you want to
generate more sales you want to
capture misleads like the example
i gave earlier you want to improve
conversion rates any of these
things
enable upsell opportunities one of
the first automations i built for
a client was they wanted to launch
a new
offer but instead of paying a
developer a ton of money they
hired me as a no code developer
and i quickly
made a automation in make.com that
enabled them to look at the data
of people visiting their website
and
their prospects what or their
clients websites um see what links
they were clicking on and then we
use ai to
categorize um what the product
they were likely interested in so
that's an example of you know he
was able to
take that simple automation i
built and use it as a proof of
concept to see if his existing
clients
would buy this new software we had
built another one is a leverage so
pretty straightforward saving time
this is by far the number one
thing uh we talk about when it
comes to ai can save you time make
you more
productive but yeah always trying
to classify the pain points as a
one or two of these categories so
building
farther on the right line of
question the right way to sell
this is it's diagnosis not not
persuasion so
start very broad very high level
where are you spending most of
your time right now what happens
if this process issue continues
for another year like are you
going to be able to grow your
business still
what does your team keep
forgetting or missing are you
losing money because of this
where do clients and prospects
slip through the cracks all these
questions are opportunities to
just
understand real problems so you
can actually solve them next after
you've understood the problem you
need
to ask questions but okay so how
many hours is it taking what is
the hourly rate and this is
something
that daniel talks about having
like an roi calculator this can
help you can just have this
on your screen um plugging this in
whether it's just a spreadsheet or
something you make in a tool
really quickly like lovable bolt
whatever the case may be and you
can see here okay i spend five
hours
a week on manual follow-ups my
hourly rate is fifty dollars an
hour so that's going to cost
thirteen
thousand dollars annual
productivity it's like okay well
what if we could build you an
automation that
automatically follows up with your
clients um and that's just your
lost productivity of the the time
that it's taking them but what if
we could also by doing this
because sometimes the person will
forget
to do it like we talked about
earlier we actually you sold some
deals from the follow-up people
actually
came back like hey we want to buy
your product well that could say
make even more money so you know
just
the thirteen thousand dollars off
the time savings but not to
mention the opportunity cost
how about we charge you twenty
five hundred dollars and that
feels like a huge bargain it's
like wow
you're going to save time i'm
going to make money and you're
only charging me twenty five
hundred dollars
for that um you can see how by
framing it this way it becomes a
lot easier to sell these
automations
versus if you just say hey i'm a
automation integration guy go to
fiverr right now while you're
watching this just go to fiverr
and search like n8 and automation
consultant there's guys on there
charging like five dollars an hour
to do this same work it's because
their packaging is so poor they
don't know how to do stuff like
this right so you need to the only
way you can differentiate yourself
from those guys is by doing things
like this and having conversations
like this
another really valuable question i
like to use is once i understand
maybe their biggest problem or
maybe we're having a hard time
figuring it out i i pull out this
one i'm like
hey if i were like a wizard and
could fix your biggest problem
right now what would it be and why
and then they just like brain dump
and you start to understand a
little bit more like okay okay
that
sounds good and it's like so why
like why is that actually a
problem though like you've run
your
business up to this point like oh
well you know like if i don't do
this i'm not gonna grow blah blah
okay and like have you tried
anything else like what happens if
it's not fixed all the good best
practice sales questions that the
sales modules are going to teach
you this is how you tailor this to
the automation business model so
what happens if it's not fixed and
then you're like okay what would
change if it was like how would
you actually use that time better
if i fix this problem
you want to paint that picture for
them
the other thing here is automation
is one of those things this is
typically done online right
you're not physically going in and
like plugging wires in together
for them
um so they don't really know what
the hell automation is it's just
like code
um so you have to make it visual
you have to think of yourself as
like a graphic designer almost
but instead of showing them a
graphic design you're showing them
that canvas of all the
different steps that are happening
and that's why the no code
builders is so nice because you
can
actually visually show them what's
happening um and you can also get
them to visualize and like
see themselves in that by being
like okay here's a flow or
automation i built for another
client in
your industry in your case based
on what you told me we'd customize
this part here to handle your
specific lead capture process
instead of using calendly we're
going to use cal.com instead of
using type form we're going to use
fill out but the the process is
still the same so you want to come
in with with that expertise to
show okay this guy probably knows
what he's doing he's built
something
very similar and even if it's not
similar still show them like hey
look at this automation like
this is how we build it um and
maybe even just start dragging and
dropping modules on the screen of
like
hey like in your case we'd pull
this put this module connect this
one to this one and so on and so
forth
obviously there's more planning we
need to do here but just give them
that feeling of they have that
certainty of what they're buying
um and yeah remember to anonymize
client specific information so
i try to typically um import json
files of like the automation from
the client account and just like
don't connect anything so they
don't see like what the specific
tweaks we did for the client are
because that is kind of their ip
another pro tip if you know you're
struggling with all the other
stuff you still don't really
understand what the hell is going
on based on what they're telling
you
they're not really good at sharing
the problem of like what's
happening on their computer you
can ask
them a screen share um this is
very powerful automation because
what happens is have you ever
been in like driving and you leave
work and you get home and you're
like man i don't even know how i
got
here but like i my body did it we
were on autopilot we drove this is
what happens with most people when
they do repetitive processes at
work they're just like i've done
this a thousand times i don't
really
think about the steps so they
explain it to somebody else most
people suck as teachers to be
honest so
then they like omit so many steps
because to them they take it for
granted so instead you say okay
can
you like share your screen and
show me how you guys are actually
doing follow-up what are you guys
clicking
on how is this actually working
take them step by step because you
can see like broken processes
but yeah like then this part's
really messed up like it's really
hard to do this and you're like
well
you could probably just click over
there and if you could fix
something in that call in that
moment
you're also giving them free value
in that call they're like oh my
god if like this guy could just
like tell me that little tweak
what else does he know so there's
all these little psychological
things
that this approach actually helps
you with um and by far it just
helps you create a more robust
solution that actually works
because the worst thing of all is
to get to the end of an automation
project
and then the customer being like
well this isn't exactly what i
wanted because they
struggled to actually explain to
you what they wanted
so yeah don't force automations
you're going to sell clarity and
outcomes
and don't force one call closes
either i think a lot of people i'd
love to close on a long call but
sometimes that's not possible
there just isn't enough time
especially with um what you're
trying
to uncover in this case sometimes
you can though so that's what i'm
saying don't take this as gospel
but this is typically the flow it
goes by first calls like you want
to qualify them and see if they
actually have a problem that it's
worth investigating farther second
call is you're like hey we're
going to
dive deeper into your process on
the next call and just get a
really good understanding i'll
show you some
similar automations i built that
apply here and just document their
current state really well
and then you're going to say okay
next call we'll have a proposal
ready for you to present a
recommendation
you're going to quantify the roi
of like if you do this you know
that thirteen thousand dollar
thing i
showed earlier you're going to do
exactly something like that
they're like and yeah so this is
going to
cost twenty five hundred dollars
and don't rush the close i think
there's this thing where it's not
every sales call needs to be a a
one call close and yeah just build
trust be a doctor understand their
business before you get to the end
so yeah those are my sales tips
for running a automation agency