All right, guys, so I'm going to
teach you what an automation
agency is.
My name is Amir, and I've been
running one for about a year now.
Prior to that, I used to run my
own project management consulting
business
and also worked at a managed IT
service provider
where I sold over $2 million in IT
solutions.
So I'm very familiar with the
issues and bottlenecks
that a bunch of small businesses
have.
I've worked with over 25 of them
now at this point.
Basically, this business model is
helping small businesses with AI
automation
because really, there's just so
many software tools out there
today,
and our job is to come in and help
them connect them together
and help drive efficiency and
scalability in the business.
Everyone's calling it something
different.
You've got this AI growth agency,
automation consulting,
operations partner, automation
infrastructure.
It's all the same thing.
It's an AI automation agency, so
don't worry if you're not late to
the party
or anything like that.
People are doing the same thing.
They're just repackaging it to
keep it fresh
because this business model has
been around for a couple of years
now,
so people are just trying to make
it fresh.
But ultimately, it's the same
thing.
So what does a good automation
agency actually do?
So the first thing a good
automation agency does is build
trust.
So what I mean by build trust is
you really want to work with the
business owners
you're talking to to understand
what their goals and pain points
are before pitching solutions.
Sometimes you'll know what they
are if you've got a productized
offer
and you can just go out there and
be like, hey, I helped a similar
company.
But initially, you still need to
get the root cause of what the
main problem is in the business.
We'll talk a little bit later
about the theory of constraints
and bottlenecks and things like
that.
But essentially, you want to make
sure that you understand the
business owner themselves and
their business.
A bad agency, what they do is they
come in.
They've got all these NNN
templates, which is an automation
platform.
We'll talk a little bit later.
And they just try to like shove it
down business owners.
So it's like, you need this
automation.
You need AI.
You need this.
You need that.
And like, there's no ROI and like
nobody's going to buy anything.
It just doesn't work that way.
Unfortunately, you really need to
understand the business owner in
the specific stages
they're at and the problems that
they're actually having.
So how do you do that?
How do you actually understand
that?
Well, you need to audit their
systems.
So examine their current tools,
workflows, and bottlenecks.
That's done through discovery
calls, asking them questions, pain
points.
What issues are you actually
running into?
That's done through working
through their process with them,
having them walk you through
step-by-step what are you doing,
having them screen share and show
you how they actually do their
day-to-day.
All those different things are
important.
So you can design a solution that
solves a real problem
because that's what business is,
is solving problems,
as opposed to just having some
fancy technology,
which leads to the next point,
which is fixing problems, right?
Once you understand what the
problem is,
you want to see if you can figure
out a way to use AI and automation
to actually address these
operational challenges.
And I'll give you a good framework
to think in to understand
which automations are the best
ones to put in.
From there, unfortunately, you're
not perfect the first time.
At least most people are.
Sometimes you get lucky and it
works out,
but you have to optimize these
automations.
You'll run them in the live
environment for a little while,
and maybe they run into some
issues or something changes in the
process.
So you want to continually monitor
and make sure that what you
promise is actually being
delivered.
And the best way to do this is if
you retain the person that you
signed on for one project
and become their trusted partner
as new challenges emerge,
because as the business grows,
they run into different next
issues.
And then you just kind of
continuously do this over and over
again and repeat the cycle.
So why does this model work?
I covered some of it already,
but ultimately businesses have a
problem that you can solve through
AI and automation.
So that's manual tasks that are
consuming valuable time that just
like suck to do.
They've got critical information
that falls through the cracks.
So think project updates, things
in the CRM, not sending out
proposals fast enough,
all these different things that
people get busy.
They forget to do going into that
as like deadlines getting missed.
Nobody's reminding people on their
team, Hey, you need to get this
done.
And then they forget to do it and
all this stuff.
So you can use automation to help
with that communication aspect.
And then, yeah, their client
satisfaction because of this.
So you got to look at what is the
next stage after this?
So these things happen.
What happens then?
Well, the clients are unhappy.
Their team starts to burn out.
They started turning clients.
So those are all the problems that
you solve or prevent.
So the solution is they're freed
up to do other things because
you've
automated that task.
So they don't have to do it.
The computer is doing it.
You have complete visibility
across your system.
So you can think of this from like
a reporting perspective.
If you aggregate their data for
them, they can just see through
one
pane of glass, what's going on.
It increases consistency because
computers don't sleep.
If you automate a client's
onboarding process for their
marketing agency,
it'll happen the same way every
single time and the same speed
every
single time, which means they're
going to have clients that are so
happy
because, wow, this person really
cares.
They onboard me so fast and all
those different things.
And then they'll be able to
sustainably grow because they can
rely on the
systems you built for them.
And then why does anybody want to
hire you to do this?
Like I'm sure you've seen it
online where it's, you can just
ask ChatGPG to do
something and it'll code up an app
or this or that.
People still don't want to do
that.
At the end of the day, they watch
your video.
They don't feel comfortable doing
it.
They're going to hire you to do
So that leads me to the next
point, which is the real focus is
problems.
It's not technology.
Nobody gives a shit about your AI
agent.
What they care about is getting
their problems solved in an
effective way.
So what does that mean in
practice?
Types of problems you want to
solve for clients are getting new
revenue, right?
How can your system that you
implement get them new revenue?
Example of this would be cold
email personalization.
So maybe you build some kind of AI
agent that scrapes the web about
their ideal client
and personalizes a first line in
an email.
That's a way that you could help
them generate new revenue.
Another is time savings, right?
Maybe the founder has to do all
this manual work to create
proposals and invoices
and all this stuff that's just
draining time for him and his
team.
And you could eliminate their
repetitive tasks so that they can
save time
and ultimately save money.
And they could even redistribute
that time that they save into
things that make money,
which is new revenue, right?
Another big one that people pay
for is clarity.
So most businesses are an absolute
mess.
People start them and then they
don't keep up with keeping them
clean and systematized.
Most people don't think in
systems, but they are really good
sales and marketers.
So they've grown their business,
but now they don't know what the
hell is going on.
And cracks usually start to show
at the 10, 15K plus a month mark.
If they got a few team members and
things like that, if they don't
have visibility into what's going
on,
this is where you can help them by
building systems that support
that.
So that's one of the main things I
do primarily is help founders
scale these bottom two clarity and
scalability,
where I bring in project
management systems, CRMs, and then
automate things between them
or build dashboards and things
like that.
One of the big challenges in this
business model, unlike other
business models,
is it's constantly evolving,
right?
So every single day, there's a new
thing coming out on AI.
It's really hard to keep up.
And that's why some people don't
like this business model, right?
Copywriting has been the same for
years and years and years.
The fundamentals of copywriting
have been the same.
And now people are even using AI
to do their copywriting.
If you don't want to spend a lot
of time continuously learning,
you're not a genuinely curious
person, this business model might
not be for you.
Because this one, compared to all
the other ones in this program,
is going to require the most
amount of continuous improvement
and continuous learning.
Not to say that those other ones
don't, but I would say this one
requires the most by far.
New tools, APIs.
So that's why throughout this
training program,
I'm going to try to get you on the
right mindset, as opposed to just
like,
here's the tool, is this, that,
the other thing.
You can get that anywhere.
But really, the best way to think
about actually approaching this
business model
is what I'm going to cover the
most.
A good example, I see a lot in
client ascension, like the VO3.
Google came out with this tool
called VO3 that makes videos.
But someone in client ascension
took it and made ads.
And now they're selling that as a
service, like AI ads as a service.
Like that didn't exist two months
ago, but now it does, right?
So you can view it as like, oh
man, I got to learn all these new
things.
Or you can view it as like, wow,
this is a good opportunity.
I have all these potential offers
I can sell.
So as I mentioned, like the
mindset piece is really important.
So this is where something called
system thinking is quite key.
So oftentimes when people come
into this business model,
they think in, we're just going to
plug in one automation there
and one automation here.
But a business is a collection of
processes, right?
So you need to look at the lead
gen is connected to the sales,
which is connected to the
fulfillment,
which is connected to getting
testimonials and case studies and
referrals.
All of that is connected.
So you need to realize that your
automations that you build
and the systems that you build for
clients is the exact same way.
What I'm getting at is when you're
looking at a client's business,
look at it as a collection of
systems
so that you can pick out where the
bottlenecks are and where the
issues are
so that you're fixing the right
things
as opposed to just like picking
one automation
that might not generate a ton of
value.
And I'll give you some more
resources on this as we move
forward here.
So how does this typically go when
you engage somebody?
The first entry point is typically
you're not going to get to use
that systems thinking.
You're going to have to start with
a single pain point, which is
fine.
Maybe it is the bottleneck that
you're able to identify just based
on talking to somebody.
Sometimes you can do that.
So you're going to do a single
automation for somebody.
They're going to see the value.
They're going to get some ROI.
And that's where you then propose
something like a system audit
where you review their
comprehensive business processes
and operations and workflows
and see if there's any other
things you can do.
And then you continue implementing
the ones that drive ROI
because you want to do things that
solve actual problems,
not just shiny, you know, N8N
templates.
And I'll keep bringing that up as
we go
because that's a completely
commoditized thing at this point.
And then you want to become a
scaling partner.
So this is how you want to
position yourself.
You want to be someone that
unlocks scaling for these business
owners
by helping them use the latest
technology to scale
as opposed to human capital, which
is like, you know, employees and
things like that.
The most successful automation
agencies grow with their clients
and become partners as opposed to
like one-time vendors.
This is very hard to do in the
beginning,
but as you get more reps, more
case studies,
eventually people will begin to
trust you
and you'll work with them for a
long time.
So ultimately, the opportunity is
you get to solve problems
with the new and latest
technology, which is super cool.
But only if you focus on actual
business outcomes
as opposed to just like, I like
N8N or I like to do this stuff.
That's not going to help you grow
your business.
That's going to be good for maybe
like your employees in the future.
But you as the business owner need
to focus on actually driving real
results for your clients.
This stuff isn't super valuable
for, or not,
I would say it is still valuable
for people that are not doing 10K
plus a month,
but they don't have enough money
to pay you to help them with it.
So focus on businesses that are
growing.
They have a few employees that
have the potential to waste time
because as you add more people,
things get more complex
and that's where inefficiencies
start to crop up
and that's where you can really
help them.
You want to position yourself as a
growth partner, not just a tech
implementer.
You want to develop systems
thinking as your core competency
as opposed to just like, I'm an
expert in N8N or make.com
or whatever the case may be.
And in this field, you're going to
have to commit to continuous
learning
while also delivering client
results,
which may not be as much of the
case in other business models.
All right, we'll jump in the next
one, which is about the ICP
and how to get your first
automation client.