- What's up guys, Lucas here.
So in this video, I'm going over
the landing page
CRO analyzer workflow.
And what this does is allows you
to submit some details
about your client along with a
link to the landing page
that you want to analyze.
And then we actually download the
webpage,
send it to our AI agent and create
a full detailed document
with a full analysis, breakdown of
what to change
and what to test, suggestions for
what to improve upon,
and even some tracking details
for your Google analytics
dashboard.
Before finally moving that to as
usual, our client folder
and then notifying you in Slack.
So starting off with what you need
to have set up for this,
as usual, you need your Google
docs OAuth to set up
for the MD2 docs to convert the
markdown properly
to a Google doc format.
We will need a Google drive set up
up here
and we will need Slack set up as
always.
Aside from that, just open router,
which you should have set up
for all of your other AI agent
tools.
And if you want to use perplexity
model for research,
which I suggest you do, set up
your perplexity account.
So let's have a look at what this
does.
So the form we just have client
name, existing client,
landing page URL, funnel type,
industry niche,
and the current funnel metrics.
So if you're testing an existing
funnel,
you can just put it in the current
metrics that you know there.
If not, just type unknown or leave
a blank.
Obviously, put your landing page
URL.
The funnel type, it's a BSL
funnel.
Niche is online business.
And we're using alexromozzi and
acquisition.com as an example
here.
I'm sure that our funnel is top
tier already,
but you know, it's a good example.
So what this does is it actually
downloads the full webpage of the
URL.
You input.
So it downloads the full website
in HTML.
We convert the HTML to markdown to
get easier for our AI agent to
analyze.
And then the AI agent analyzes
this.
Now, it's a very detailed system
problem we have here.
First of all, up here, we've got
the client name, the sales funnel,
system type, industry niche, all
the information we just got from
our form.
They have an extremely detailed
system message here, as you can
see.
And as I mentioned, we do have
perplexity set up and we're
actually letting the model
itself to find the messages on the
output that we're using for this.
So to do that, you'll see a
little, this, this little icon
here is like three stars.
You'll see that over here.
That's what we click for that.
And so this is allows our agent to
actually set, come up with the
message that it sends to
perplexity.
Again, you want to connect your
perplexity account, just get your
API key and put that in there.
And then we're using sonar deep
research to do the research.
After that, we get our output and
we convert it to markdowns using a
basic markdown converter agent.
And then we send it to md2docs to
create our document before finally
checking is an existing client.
If they are, we'll move the
document to the existing client
folder.
And if they're not, we'll create a
new folder and move the doc in
there before notifying you in
Slack.
So if we take a look at what the
document actually looks like,
here's the full breakdown.
We get an executive summary,
critical insight, market context,
top five highest impact
improvements, rewrite the
headline, optimize the primary CTA
button,
inject scarcity timer and badge,
restructure social proof
placement, and consent and privacy
text in form.
Then implementation roadmap, the
risk factors we can see with this,
post implementation monitoring,
and the final notes to look out
for.
So that's essentially what we're
looking at this.
It's a very, very quick and easy
way for you to get some
suggestions on improving your
existing funnels you've already
created.
And as you can see, it's pretty
powerful.
It goes pretty in detail, provides
rewrites and copy suggestions and
things like that.
And overall is going to be super
useful for any of you guys that
are creating funnels regularly for
clients.
I want to test them and see any
suggestions or areas you can
improve upon.
So hope this one helps you and I
will see you in the next one.
Peace.