What's up guys Lucas here again.
So today I'm going to be showing
you what I think is actually
a super interesting and useful
flow for basically every agency
type.
It doesn't matter if you're
running a funnel agency, an
e-commerce email agency, a lead
gen agency, any sort of agency,
this is going to work both for you
personally and for your clients on
outreach.
So let's take a look
at what it does.
Essentially I'm going to start off
by as usual by breaking down the
prerequisites
you're going to need, what each
node does and how the flow works
overall.
So what it does is it
essentially takes a list of
Instagram accounts.
Now this is why it's perfect for
Dream 100 outreach
specifically.
You're going to input a list of a
hundred creators that you directly
want to work
with.
Then what it does is after these
are added to a Google sheet, which
I'll show you in a moment,
it gets the Instagram account
data.
It gets the recent post data.
If it is an image post,
it sends it to ChatGPT to analyze
the image, to make a comment on
it.
And if it's not an image
post, if it's a video, it simply
takes the caption and makes a
personalized DM based on the
caption.
Then it stores that message back
in the sheet for you to send
manually.
So starting off, we're going to
need the Google sheet.
Now over here, you'll see I've got
a little
explaining a lot of this and
there's actually a link here, make
a copy of this Google sheet and
I've made this available.
So this is what the sheet looks
like.
It has just the account, the full
name, the biography, and the
message.
So you're going to want to do
file, make a copy and copy this to
your own Google Drive.
And then you will set that in
here.
If you double click on this node,
just connect your Google sheets
account and set up your, make sure
the document is selected with the
right sheet name.
Then what it does is either when
you click execute workflow or on a
schedule, which currently we've
got set to every 24 hours, but you
can change that to wherever you
want.
Or as I said, just do it manually,
just disconnect that schedule
trigger.
It will fetch the Instagram
account data.
Now, as I said, you have to fill
this sheet out manually.
This is on purpose.
This is for Dream 100.
This should all be people that you
specifically want to work with,
you've already created
deliverables for, et cetera.
So we'll get that account data.
All this does is it runs the Apify
actor, you're going to have to set
up Apify with this, as we talked
about in previous ones before.
Just connect your Apify account.
All these settings will be the
same.
And then it will get the Instagram
profile of get the data of that
Apify actor run.
Then we will get there was recent
post data and we'll get that post
data run.
Then we'll aggregate all of it
together.
Now, if it is an image post, we
will fetch the latest image post.
We'll get download the actual
photo itself and we will send it
to ChatGPT, which will create an
analysis of that image.
As you can see here, I used a
photo of a one of my own, my own
Instagram photo of me and my
girlfriend.
And it explains in detail what is
in the photo.
Then it sends that to our
personalized DM writer.
There's some things you're going
to have to edit in here ever so
slightly.
So this is done in JSON format for
the best output.
If you scroll down, the things
you're going to have to change
here are going to be your booking
link, your primary service.
So change that to whatever your
primary service is, your booking
link, which you will change here,
just your calendar in there.
Obviously, it's a basic cal.com
placeholder.
And then your sign-off name.
Everything else here you can go
through and see yourself, you can
change it to true or false.
But I would suggest keeping
everything pretty much the same.
Then if we go down to the system
message here, you will see it
explains how this works and what
it does.
Just give it rules for exactly how
it should operate when writing a
DM.
So once that is done, you've got
to change actually here as well.
Just change your, in sentence
five, you're going to change the
sign-off name here.
Mine's set to Lucas, obviously.
Change that to your name.
So then when you run that, it will
create a personalized DM and it
will add that message to the
account.
If we go back here, you'll see
it's added to this message here.
Let me make this a little bit
wider.
So it gives us a perfect kind of
DM.
So that's what it does.
It creates personalized DMs for
your Dream 100 prospects.
So again, you're going to need to
set up Apify, as we've had to set
up in a bunch of other workflows.
You will need to connect your,
copy the Google Sheet and make
sure it's connected up in the
Google Sheet.
And you will need to modify the AI
agent with your name and booking
link and business type in order to
get the output that you want.
So that's how the flow works.
Super useful, again, for any type
of agency.
You could use this without doing
lead gen for your own clients.
And I think it's going to be very,
very useful for all you guys.
So I hope you enjoy this one and
see you in the next one.
Peace.