What's up guys, Lucas here.
So today I'm going to be running
you guys through the VSL Funnel
Writer Automation.
Very simply, what this does is it
writes absolutely banger VSLs.
And the way it does that, as with
most of these nodes so far,
we're going to start with a VSL
form submission.
So we get the client name, product
and service name, the price point,
payment
options, target audience, main
pain points, huge mechanism,
transformation,
promise, client results, core
offer details, bonus stack, total
value, VSL
style, VSL length, urgency
element, and the guarantee.
Now, some of these are dropdowns
and some of these you have to
input manually.
For instance, VSL style is a
dropdown as is VSL length, but
obviously the course
price and some of these are things
like target audience.
You will have to input manually
after that, we will do a search
for the strategy
documents that you are going to be
basing a lot of your funnels off
of.
As you mentioned for the, the, uh,
strategy, uh, sorry, funnel
strategy
creation workflow, that'll be the
basis for a lot of your, uh, other
funnel,
uh, kind of documents and, uh, uh,
uh, other elements going forward.
So after that, we go to the code
node.
What this does really is just, it
sets, uh, the document ID so that
our Google docs
can get the, uh, funnel strategy
document.
Then we prepare the context, uh,
just a code node here as well.
It's kind of formulates things in
the strategy context here and gets
us a session
ID so that our AI agents will have
access to their memory modules.
Then this agent creates VSL hooks.
It looks at everything from the
research doc, as well as the form
input submissions.
And it creates three, uh, opening
hooks.
After that, we have our story
architecture agent.
And what this does is very simply
is it takes again, the hooks as
well as a research
document on the details from the
form in order to create, uh, kind
of a story
around the VSL, uh, that will
really pull on kind of the
emotional elements that, uh,
trigger
people to purchase.
Once it creates the story
elements, then we have the
objection handling agents.
Later on in the VSL script, we'll
be handling the objections.
We will potentially have and
alleviating those concerns.
So that's what this does here.
It's just a detailed agent that
helps to, uh, go over the
different, uh, you know, elements
that people will be kind of maybe,
you know, question of the price or
the time investment,
things like that.
And this handles all of those.
And then finally, we have a
closing CTA agent that again, does
the same thing, takes all the
information and it creates a, uh,
perfect kind of CTA and ending
section of our VSL in total.
Finally, this code node will take
all of this information and we'll
put it together into this
VSL script over here, along with
the client name and the product
name, uh, that we can then feed
into our, uh, Google docs
creation.
So we end up with a Google doc
with the full VSL script, as well
as the file name here with the
client name and the date.
And then as you've seen in some of
our other nodes, it's going to
search for the existing,
uh, folder for the client in our
clients folder.
If it's not there, it'll create a
new client folder and then move
the Google doc into that folder.
If it is there, it'll move the
Google doc to that folder.
But we're finally creating a
summary and setting a Slack
notification.
As usual, you will need to have
your Google docs authentication
set up your, uh, Google drive
authentication set up, which is
your Google docs, your open router
authentication.
And then for MD2 docs, you will
just need your Google docs.
Uh, authentication to get that
working.
So let's take a look at the VSL
script that this creates.
If I copy this here and paste this
here, you're going to see that it
is a very, very large script,
a total of 44 pages in total, but
it gives us a bit of information
as well.
We're explaining kind of why these
things work.
So we get three hook variations,
uh, for going into the main story
section, uh, part one, part two,
part three, four, part five, then
it goes with the objection
handling.
And you can see there's also these
tone indicators here as well that
help with the kind of the
performance of the script and to
help whoever, uh, you know,
delivering the VSL to, uh,
understand
kind of how they should be
speaking at certain stages and
kind of emphasizing certain words
and things like that.
So this, uh, when it's done, we
moved into the folder along with
your other previous funnel
documents.
So you'll end up with the full
outline, your slide deck, copy
your thank you page, copy your VSL
script,
your webinar email, uh, sequence
and your webinar script.
So as, as well as your
registration page.
So you will have a full funnel
build that, including a webinar
and a BSL all set up in there yet.
That's basically it.
That's, uh, kind of how it works.
Uh, see anything else here.
Uh, the flow again, overall is
just the form submission with the
data.
We're going to get that strategy
document to provide context to
our, uh, VSL writers on what
the offer is.
Then we write the hook followed by
the story architecture, followed
by the objection handling,
followed by the closing CTA.
And then finally we compile that
into one script and then add it to
a Google doc.
And then we either create a new
client folder or move it into the
existing client folder
before sending you a nice
notification in Slack that just
says VSL is generated.
Here's the link to it, et cetera.
Um, so yeah.
Overall, if you follow through all
of these, uh, as we've been laid
out in the course,
you will be making absolutely fire
funnels that are ready to go.
All you got to do is put together
kind of the ClickFunnels pages and
get whoever's going to be,
you know, performing these sort
of, uh, scripts to actually record
the videos.
And then you're pretty much good
to go.
So, uh, any questions feel free to
hit me up and I will see you guys
in the next one.
Peace.