What's up guys, Lucas here.
So today we're going to be looking
at the Facebook ad analysis
workflow.
Essentially what this does is it
lets you input a keyword for an ad
that you're creating
and it will then search the
Facebook ads library for any ads
that match those keywords.
It will analyze them and then help
you rewrite the copy to what kind
of personalize it for
your product or for your funnel
and then it will save it to a
Google Sheet for you.
This is very helpful for getting
ads in bulk and rewriting a bulk
and, you know, kind
of modifying it for your own sort
of use case for your, either for
your clients or for your
own ads and content.
So let's take a look at what we
have here.
As usual, I'm going to run through
the prerequisites you're going to
need for this.
I'm going to run through what each
node does and how it works.
So first of all, very simply,
you're going to need an account on
apify.com, apify.com.
This is the scraper we're going to
be using and I'll be giving you a
link to this.
I'll explain a little bit later
why you should take a look at this
page, but you will need
an apify account to sign up and
you are, it's connected over here
by just using apify account.
It's just a quick single sign in
button and you'll be good to go.
The next thing you're going to
need is a Google Sheet.
And I would suggest that again,
I'll be sharing this sheet as
well, but it's just
you just name it the exact same or
just copy this Facebook ads
library analyzer db.
And we're going to need all these
headers here.
I'll go through these later on and
explain why, but, uh, probably
just, I will make the
sheet available for copy and you
can just copy it to yours and then
just modify it.
Uh, I mean, you need to, so let's
start by going through each of the
nodes.
As usual, we have an on-form
submission.
This is a pretty basic one.
We're just using it for keywords.
Uh, that's all we need at the
moment.
So as you can see here, I already
have some data pinned.
I just searched athletic greens.
Cause I know that it's a popular,
uh, brand that runs many ads.
So then our apify ad library
scraper is going to search the
Facebook ad library for athletic
greens.
Now, if we go here, we've got, we
call the input J S O N.
And this is why I'm going to give
you a link to the apify ad scraper
page.
If you go back here, you can see
all these different, uh, settings
here.
So keywords, uh, the max results
per page, you can choose the
target countries, the language,
the publisher platforms, the
status filter, like active ads or
inactive ads, uh, the category
media, media type, the from date,
a ton of different stuff here.
So what I would suggest that you
do here is modify this for your
own use case.
The moment you have it just set to
look in all countries for a
maximum number of 100 ads
and just our search query.
So our keyword.
So maybe you want to set it to
only United States.
So maybe you want to get 500 ads,
not 100.
And, uh, maybe you want only
active ads or in specific
category.
Once you've set all these in here.
So let's say you do, uh, United
States.
And then let's say you only want
active ads, uh, say media types.
You only want, uh, video ads.
Once you do that, if you go up
here to this manual at J S O N,
click J S O N.
You can copy and paste this into
our API input JSON here like this.
Now, one thing we're going to
change here is after you do that.
So as you see, we drew over the
active status ads, the country,
the Microsoft is still a hundred
videos, but let's just under
search queries, remove this
keyword here and drag and drop
over our Facebook ad library
keyword.
And now you can see we're on a
search for athletic greens.
So I would consider making that
change or just using this to
basically, you know, determine the
different, uh, kind of, uh,
filters you want to set when
you're searching the ad library.
So with that done, then, uh, you,
we run this and it will scrape a
number of ads for us.
Then very simply, this is a wait
node.
It waits for about 10 seconds,
just to make sure that the data
set has been saved to API.
And then we get the data set just
there and you can see we got 50
items in, in total.
Now these are a ton of different
ads, including the ad URL, the
text, uh, the image, uh, of the
ads, stuff like that.
Then we filter it for likes.
We don't want to pull in every ad.
You know, there's a lot of ads by
many smaller Facebook pages.
It's very simply we just filter
that if the Facebook page has, uh,
more than a thousand likes on the
page, then we send those ads
through.
And then we go down from 50 to 13.
Now here's where it decides if
it's video image or text.
Let's start by going through
image.
So if it is in, actually I'll
start with video.
So we go through video.
If it's a video ad, it will send
it up here where we will download
the video from Facebook and upload
that video to Google drive.
After that, we will begin our
Gemini upload session.
Now, essentially the way this
works is that with Google Gemini,
you don't directly upload the
video.
You start a upload session to tell
the AI to prepare for something
being uploaded.
So one thing you're going to need
to set in here is your API key.
So by clicking here, you'll see
right here, the first query
parameter we have is key and your
API key goes here to get that.
You're going to go to just Google,
Google AI studio.
Once you find the Google AI studio
page, you will log in with your
Google account.
Then you'll go to dashboard API
keys, click create API key, and it
will ask you to either create or
choose from a previous project
that you had.
So you just do it there and create
an API key in existing project.
You'll get your API key, paste it
in here, and then this node will
work perfectly.
It will simply start a Gemini
upload session after the session
is uploaded.
It's now waiting for us to upload
the video.
So we're going to re-download the
video from Google drive and then
upload the video to Gemini for
processing.
Again, you'll need to put your API
key in here.
Then we wait till that's done, and
then we analyze the video with
Gemini, also need to put your API
key in here.
Gemini will analyze the video,
break it down.
We've got a prompt in here telling
it what we're looking for.
It's just going to describe the
video in detail.
Then when that's done, we output
the video summary to our AI over
here.
Now, this is the, uh, the
parenting about what it modifies.
So this is the one that says your
task is take an input as a script
JavaScript object from an
advertisement of the Facebook ad
library and then summarize it and
spin, repurpose, re-write the ad
copy.
You're doing this for Siege
Intelligence, we're always looking
at what our competitor advertisers
are doing.
Then we have some rules that we
tell it to follow, but we might
want to modify this or add more to
this to, you know, give details
about your, your,
uh, product or your service,
whatever it is that you're trying
to advertise in order for it to
rewrite the winning ads for your
brand or, uh, service.
Then after that is added to our
Google sheet and then simply waits
and then does this again for
however many videos have been sent
through image works very
similarly, but it's a bit more
straightforward.
If it's an image ad, then it will
download the image from Facebook,
then it will send that image
directly to chat GPT.
And while we'll ask it is what is
in the image be comprehensive.
And then here is where we again,
have a similar prompt where we
break down, uh, tell it to break
it down.
And rewrite the, uh, copy for what
we're, uh, uh, our own products.
And then we output this to our,
uh, Google sheet here.
You can see we have the page type
and ID.
We've got the page name, the URL,
the summary of the ad, the
rewritten ad copy.
Uh, the image prompt time is what
it was in the image, then the
image URL.
And then finally, if it's just a
text ad, uh, which is unlikely,
but possible, then it just does
the same thing.
We just send it to the, uh, AI to
analyze the copy, uh, to, uh,
output it into the ad library,
along with all of the other, uh,
details of page ID, type, added
page name, all sorts of stuff.
So, uh, yeah, this is super
useful, you know, if you're
looking to write ads at scale and
you want to kind of copy your
competitors' ads or people in the
industry who are doing well, uh,
basically you can see, you know,
if an ad has been running for a
long period of time and it is
still active, it's likely a
winning ad in that keyword search.
So it's probably going to get to
try a variation of it or some
similar sort of copy to it.
So this is an easy way to get that
in bulk.
You should end up with a Google
sheet that is filled with, uh, you
know, ad information that you can
analyze yourself or just review.
As long with rewritten, uh, copy
that, you know, you can use for
your, your own ads and your own
content.
So hope this one is useful and see
you in the next one.
Peace.