What's up guys, Lucas here.
So today I'm going to be walking
you through the funnel copywriter
automation.
What this does very simply is from
a form input, it processes the
data,
does some market research using
ChatGPT5, as well as the SERP API,
which allows for internet search.
The funnel strategist agent
creates a whole funnel strategy
around the market
research on the inputted user
information.
Then it writes a sales page and
writes all the email flows.
Then it creates a Google doc.
If they are an existing customer,
it puts the file in the correct
Google drive folder.
And if they are not, then it
creates the folder and moves the
file into it.
And then finally sends us a Slack
message.
So it's running through just very
quickly how this works.
If we look here, I've got some
data pinned.
So I made up a fake company, a
SaaS called Productivity Flow Pro.
It's for busy entrepreneurs while
business owners.
The primary full type is the
landing page to a free trial.
The goal is to increase signups.
Basically, we have all here the
top three product benefits, top
three pain points we saw,
unique value propositions, special
offers, existing copy sample,
success metrics to track,
and if they're a returning client.
So this is just the information
you need to give it in order to
write about your client.
So you will need to do a little
bit of information yourself.
So like look at the benefits of
the client's product or their
brand voice, things like that.
But you should know most of this
if you've already spoken to your
client and get that information
from them.
So then our market research agent,
I've got some very detailed
prompts here, but essentially it
creates an executive summary.
It is a snapshot.
It creates audience personas.
It does all these things.
Again, using ChatGPT 5 along with
the SERP API.
Now, you will have to set up your
open editor account, as we've
discussed in previous videos.
Open editor is the key
authentication that you'll need
for all AI.
SERP API is one you won't probably
want to set up.
It's very simple.
To set it up, you simply have to
get an API key.
To do that, you just go to
SERPAPI.com, sign in or register,
and it will give you an API key
immediately that you copy and
paste in.
And now your AI has internet
access.
So let's go back here.
The sales page agent, after the
funnel strategy agent, creates a
full detailed funnel strategy,
including the foundation, the
architecture, the confirmation
page strategy, email sequence
architecture, all this
information.
Once that's all created, it sends
that here along with the market
research to the sales page agent,
which then writes a fully detailed
sales page based on best practices
from a number of experts on sales
page creation.
Then the email flow agent creates
detailed email flows again, taking
all the information from the
previous agents and outlines the
whole email strategy as well as
actually writes the emails you
need to write.
Then it compiles all this into a
success package very simply just
puts it all together here.
And then we create a Google doc
here from the markdown to create a
nicely formatted Google doc.
When that's done, then it will
check if it's a returning client
or not, which you will have marked
in the initial form.
If it is, it will search for that
client's name in your client's
folder in Google Drive, which as
mentioned before, you need to have
a client's folder set up.
And then it will move the file
into the correct folder.
If you don't have a folder for
that client, if they're not a
returning client, it will create a
folder with the client's name
based on what you put in the form
and then move the completed Google
doc into the folder for finally
sending you a message in Slack.
And your output will look
something like this, where you
will have the full funnel strategy
up top.
As you can see, this is super
detailed.
This is nearly 20,000 words in
total for this whole document.
It'll go over all the information
here.
I've actually scrolled in here.
We'll get to the sales page copy
where you'll see here is a full
sales page written for you.
Again, based on the best practices
from existing funnel experts.
What Holly's just giving as much
information as possible about the
product or the client in order to
get the most accurate text
possible.
You will still obviously have to
edit things slightly depending on
what your client's doing.
But this is a really, really good
base to start from.
And then finally, it will create
our email flows where it goes over
the details of the strategy,
themes, et cetera.
And then the actual emails are
here below.
You have to do a bit of formatting
or just, you know, line breaks and
stuff, but everything there is
pretty much ready to go.
And then finally, as I said, you
will get the message of Slack
telling you that it is done, ready
to go, ready for you to build it.
So this turns, you know, what
would be hours maybe of research
and learning how to write sales
pages and stuff into probably a
total five-minute process maybe
for this flow to run.
You simply just input the details
into the form, and then you are
good to go.
You will get a Slack message with
the Google Drive link saying, here
you go.
Here's all the information on this
client ready to go.
So, yeah, this will save you
having to hire a copywriter.
It will save you having to learn
how to write copy yourself.
It will save you the majority of
what's involved in the research
and copywriting part of funnel
development.
Any problems with this, feel free
to hit me up.
Again, the only things you need to
set up, you will need to set up
your Google Drive authentication.
Again, to do that, you'll just add
a Google Drive account.
It's just log in with Google.
Same for Slack.
You'll have to set up your Slack
authentication.
It's just log in with Slack.
And you will have to set up your
OpenWriter and SERP API
authentication.
All done very easily.
Again, credential to connect with.
You'll just search for SERP and
then, or SERP will already be
here.
Just create a new credential and
put in your API key, and you're
good to go.
So, any issues, feel free to hit
me up.
And let me know how it goes.
See you in the next one.
Peace.