What's up guys, Lucas here.
So I'm going to be running you
through the Static Ad Generator
workflow.
So essentially what this one looks
like is we have, as usual, a form
input.
In here we put the client's
business name, service
description, the website, target
audience, key benefits, brand
style, primary brand colors.
They can do, you can actually do
like the hex codes for this or
just like the actual names of the
colors.
Returning client, yes or no.
And then we send that information
to an AI agent that creates ad
concepts.
So you can see here, we put the
information from the business, put
their website in here, their
target audience, all the
information we got from the form.
And we have given this agent
specifically access to SERP API,
which as we talked about before in
a previous one,
we go to SERP API.com is Google
search API.
So you register there and then add
your API key there and we're good
to go.
Then we split those prompts for
processing.
So we'll get out a basic JSON with
a ton of information in here about
all the different prompts.
And if you go to here, you can see
it.
These are all three different
prompts and the information we've
got from the AI agent.
So over here, we split these out.
As you can see, there's three
items.
What we've got for each of them,
we'll have the psychology
framework, the headline,
subheadline, body copy, CTA, all
that stuff there.
We aggregate that and then we send
it to, we want to create three
different ads.
So we just have three different
ones here that I'll create.
This one creates from JSON image
prompt zero.
Then this one creates one from
image prompt one and this one
creates from image prompt two,
just to make variations.
So if you look here, I've actually
done this one already.
And you see if the output, if you
go to the binary node and go to
view, here is what we see.
So this is what the ad we've
created for my company Innovative.
And then we run through the usual
final setup, check, are they
returning client?
This information comes from the
form at the beginning.
You'll have selected yes or no.
And then we search the client
folder, upload to Google Drive,
not create the client folder,
upload to Google Drive.
And then success response.
And then we can throw at the end a
Slack message or, you know, we can
just have that set to create that
and put that in the Google Drive
for us.
So that's what we're looking at
there for the static ad generator.
This is obviously super useful if
you are making ads for clients at
scale, if you're running funnels
for them, if you want to just
create a bunch of ad concepts.
You can do a few different things.
Like, for instance, in here, you
can change the resolution of the
ad itself.
So you can do kind of horizontal
or vertical or square.
We're using the GPT Image 1 model
for this.
So far, this does seem to be the
best one.
It may be a case that the new
Google Nano Banana might be
better.
But for now, GPT Image 1 is kind
of best of following, you know,
prompted variants, it seems, with
text and things like that.
So it's probably what we're going
to stick with for now.
But, yeah, super useful one for
just making ads, static ads at
scale.
As you can see, this is a much
shorter flow than some of the
other ones we've done because it's
a very simple process.
But this is pretty much ready to
go and should get you some really
good results for your first few
static ads.
And you can always modify, you
know, kind of the prompt and kind
of what you're looking for by just
messing around with the, you know,
information we have here in the AI
agent.
All this is pretty detailed as it
currently is.
But feel free to, you know, modify
this and see if you can, maybe if
you want to change up how it
operates or what it does or kind
of the type of ads you're looking
for.
But a lot of that should be
affected by simply just the
different things like the target
audience, the brand style, the
primary brand colors, things like
that.
So, yeah, that's the static ad
generator.
And let me know if you have any
issues.
And I will see you guys in the
next one.
Peace.