- What's up guys, Lucas here.
So today I'm gonna be running you
through
the Reddit to add scripts
workflow.
What this essentially does is you
input information
about your product, your client's
product,
and a subreddit where there's
likely users
for that product gonna be talking
about it in there.
And then what we do here is we
research the subreddit.
We get the most common pain points
and issues.
We analyze that and we write three
ad scripts with it
and move it into Google Drive.
So as usual, we're walking you
through each node,
what it does, and then explaining
any prerequisites
you might have to have for this.
There is one slightly kind of
different setup
we're gonna have to do for this,
but it's not hard to do.
It's just to do with the Reddit
API.
So as usual, it comes from a form.
You put in these details, the
topic or product name,
the client name, returning client,
business product description,
target audience,
content source, drop the URL here.
And so like, you know, anything
that is kind of,
the more detail you give it,
the better out what you're gonna
get.
We just kind of put some basic
information here
to get started.
Then that's just, this is kind of
sets things up properly.
Then we send that to a code node
that just creates a session ID
for our agent memory here.
As you can see in our agent here,
we have a few more nodes connected
than we usually do.
So we have a chat node selected
here.
As usual, it's open writer.
And we're using GPT-03 Pro for
this one.
But sometimes we get so much
information from Reddit
that it has a problem with the
token limit.
So in case of that, we have
enabled a fallback model.
To do that in an agent, you just
go to settings.
And you, sorry, just further down
actually,
you click the enable fallback
model button here.
And then you can set another model
to be used
if this one doesn't work.
So we've just set the Google
Gemini 2.5 Pro,
which has a slightly larger
context window.
So that if this one fails, it'll
run this one for it instead.
Then we have a simple memory set
there,
just so it remembers, I think the
five most recent kind of chats.
And this is just helpful because
we'll get information from here.
They'll talk back to each other.
Then we have perplexity over here
as a tool.
Just use your perplexity account.
And we let the model define the
input for it.
To do that in some of these,
you'll see these little,
this little kind of star icon here
besides some of the inputs.
And you can let the model actually
determine
what you wanted to put in there
and questions you wanted to ask.
That's helpful because this is our
research agent
that will be creating questions
and ideas to research.
And we can send those ideas and
prompts directly perplexity.
Now, here is where the extra setup
is going to come in.
We're using a Reddit tool to
search Reddit.
As you can see here, the tool
description is automatically.
We're using a Reddit account.
The resource is searching for
posts.
It's going to search through them
all and all of Reddit.
Now, we could put that to a
particular subreddit.
We could do it for the inputs of
Reddit specifically.
But for now, we're going to do all
of Reddit
to get as much information as
possible.
The keyword is going to be defined
automatically by the model.
And we've limited it to 10, but it
can sometimes go
like a bunch of really long posts.
And that's what affects the
context length.
But in order to connect Reddit
here,
you're going to need to use your
Reddit OAuth 2 API.
So if I click the edit here,
you'll see the usual kind of OAuth
2 setup
that we have where you need a
client ID and a client secret.
And it gives you the OAuth
redirect URL.
To set this up, you're going to go
to Reddit.
You'll need an account on Reddit.
So sign up on Reddit and then go
to preferences.
You'll see this in the top right
over here.
If I just click preferences here,
we'll see the page.
And then we're going to go to
apps.
When you go to apps, scroll all
the way down to the bottom.
And under developed applications,
click create an app or create
another app.
And this will give you all the
information you need.
If I do create another app now,
you're going to see it's going to
ask you to put in the name.
Choose web app for the type of
app.
You can put it in a description,
but it doesn't really matter.
The name also doesn't really
matter.
I just called it.
This will make N8N.
You're going to be using it
personally.
It's linked to your account.
It's fine.
So it's whatever name, web app,
then the description.
You don't have to put it in an
about URL.
But for the redirect URL, you're
going to grab that from the OAuth
redirect URL here.
So you just copy that.
And you'll just paste that in.
Then you click I'm not a robot and
create app.
I can't do it because it only lets
you create one app per account.
But once you do that, it'll give
you your client ID.
And it'll give you the client
secret after you click create app.
So you just paste those back in
here and it'll connect and you're
good to go.
So what this does then is it
creates a, we've got it outputting
in JSON.
So it's got a kind of a, you can
see here it's doing sample
metadata, total engagement, the
subreddits.
It searched through the past three
months, the primary pain, the pain
frequency, top emotional triggers,
wallet rate anxiety, solution
must-haves, all these sort of
things.
It sends that information to our
analysis agent.
And this creates a detailed
analysis and executive summary of
the information we got from the
research.
So this kind of formulates things
in a more kind of understandable
sort of way.
And then we send that to our ad
scripting agent.
And this will create a three ads
for us using different frameworks.
So you'll see the framework listed
up here.
So we've got the villain hero
framework, followed by the past
framework, followed by the BAB
framework just there.
So when it creates that, we
finally want to send that to our
Google Docs creator.
As usual, MD2 Docs uses Google
Docs OAuth 2, which we've talked
about before.
I should have set that up in
previous videos.
And it will create our ad scripts.
So if I open these now, let's see
what these look like.
These are actually ready to go.
So again, it's for an app that's
an alternative to Claude.
This is part of the description of
the chat model.
It's for people who find Claude
Max expensive.
And then it gives our ad scripts.
So the first one is the villain
hero framework.
The hook is AI models that charge
with token are silently draining
your wallet.
Big AI companies got greedy.
They've designed pricing models
that punish developers who
actually use their products.
Every prompt, every iteration,
every debugging session comes with
a hidden tax that adds up fast.
Have you noticed how quickly those
credits disappear?
That's not an accident.
It's a trap designed to hook you
with free tiers for forcing you to
expensive enterprise plans.
Meanwhile, your development slows
down because you're constantly
worried about costs.
This is where Open Dev AI changes
everything.
We've built a developer-first,
open-source AI solution that
eliminates usage caps completely.
To play locally or use our cloud,
the choice is yours.
While they charge you for every
token, we offer unlimited
interactions at a fraction of the
cost.
Our models deliver cloud-quality
outputs without cloud-level
pricing.
Join thousands of developers
who've taken back control of their
AI workflows and their budgets.
Hit the link below to start your
unlimited 14-day trial.
Your wallet will thank you.
We have some visual cues in here
as well that you can add in.
So that is how that works.
And then finally, we go through
the usual process.
Are they an existing client?
If you selected yes, then it will
search the files and folders for
that client name and move the
Google Doc there.
If not, it'll create that folder
for the client and move the file
there before waiting.
And then finally, sending you a
message in Slack telling you that
it's ready to view with a link to
the ad scripts.
So that's how that one works.
The most complicated part of this
is going to be getting the Reddit
thing set up.
That shouldn't be super hard
again.
As I said, create a Reddit
account, preferences, apps, create
a new app, give it the name, give
it the OAuth redirect URL, get the
client ID and client secret, paste
it in, good to go.
The other things here as well, as
usual, open writer for all of our
AI models, then SERP API for
searching the web for the analysis
content.
And that's pretty much exactly how
it works.
I think this is going to be a
super useful one for anyone
running the funnels and ads
agency.
You can just automatically create
highly detailed research ads from
just a few inputs.
So hopefully this is helpful, and
I will see you guys in the next
one.
Peace.