- So guys, Lucas here.
So today I'm gonna be running
through
the webinar funnel generator
workflow.
I'll start off as usual by telling
you the prerequisites
you need to have set up, how each
of these nodes works
and the overall run of the flow.
So you will need open writer set
up as usual
for all AI agents.
You will need your Google Drive
set up
and you will need your Google Docs
set up.
We've talked about how to set
these up in previous videos,
but most of them for Google Drive
is just going to be logging into
your Google Drive account
with the OS redirect URL and stuff
as we went over
in one of the previous N8N videos
and same for Google Docs.
So that's all you're gonna need
for this one.
Nothing else too complicated.
So let's go over exactly what this
does.
First of all, we have a form
submission as usual.
We get information such as the
client name,
the Google Doc URL, the webinar
type, date and time,
the platform, the duration, the
fast action bonus,
the replay availability, the
teaching style,
the pitch intensity, special guest
or interview,
and then we have to submit it out
and stuff as usual.
So then if this is a existing,
sorry,
if we provide the Google Doc URL
of our funnel strategy document,
which we've gone over in the
previous methods,
then we will get that document and
get the information from it.
Now, if we don't have that
information, that's fine.
Let's go directly to our code
node, which just cleans things up
and gives us a session ID for us
for our memory for some of our
other agents.
So basically, again, if you've
created a funnel strategy document
for this client,
it will search for it in your
client's folder.
Then we'll get the contents of
that document and send it on over
to our webinar copywriter agent.
This is a detailed webinar
copywriter agent that takes our
strategic blueprint.
Again, it doesn't have it, not a
problem,
but it'll take all the other
information we got from the form
and then details to it,
how it should write the initial
webinar script.
We started off by actually writing
the full on script of the webinar
first.
After that, we're then going to go
on and have an agent write the
slide deck.
So the slide deck is all of the
information on screen and the
slide deck will be shown during
the webinar.
This means your life way easier.
You don't have to make it from the
script.
It just does it automatically for
you.
Then we are going to write a
registration page.
So we create a high converting
registration page copy for this
webinar.
It does everything you need to,
you know,
create a kind of landing page that
gets people hyped and ready for
the webinar ahead of time,
including the information they're
going to find out on the webinar.
Then we write a detailed email
sequence.
So we're telling the agent here to
create a complete pre and post
webinar email sequence
from the inputs below.
Again, you've got all the same
stuff again, all the details of
the webinar.
We're including the script here as
well.
And this gives all the context it
needs in order to write two sets
of email sequences,
the pre and post webinar
sequences.
Finally, we have the thank you
page copywriter.
This is what's shown after the
webinar.
Again, the same information goes
in again, but this tells it how to
write a super detailed
thank you page that gets people
hyped and gets them even more
likely to purchase post webinar.
After all this, we just organize
all this content here.
And then each of these creates a
Google doc.
As you can see, create webinar
script doc, create thank you page
doc.
Oh yeah, you will need MD2 docs as
well.
To do that, all you have to do is
set your Google docs API here.
Exactly the same API that you will
have over here for the get
document node here.
After that set up, it will
automatically create the different
documents.
Then it was going to collect all
those documents again.
Then the code node here
essentially just splits up our
outputs of each of the URLs.
Then it searches for the existing
client folder.
If we have an existing client
folder, it moves all of those
documents to the correct folder.
If not, it'll create a new client
folder.
As usual, as we've talked in other
videos, you have to have a Google
drive folder named clients
where you will be creating all the
documentation for your clients.
If that client exists based on the
name you input on the form at the
beginning over here,
then we will move those documents
to the correct folder.
If not, we'll create the folder
and move the documents to the
folder.
And then finally, we create a nice
Slack notification that tells you
what documents
have been created and includes a
link to the folder where you can
find all of those documents.
Now to see what these documents
look like, I'm just going to grab
it from here.
So we'll see what the webinar
scripts looks like.
Open this.
As you can see, it's a super
detailed script goes on for 42
pages in total.
This is, you know, a fake company
that I've made to give us some
detail on just a test
information that we can use, but
it goes over everything that is
needed for the webinar.
Super long, super, super detailed.
And if we go back here again to
the email sequence one, let's copy
this and open this.
Then you can see there's a pretty
webinar sequence for registrants.
Writes the full webinar, you know,
registration thing here.
So you can put, you have to edit a
bit with your own links and
information,
but it does 99% of the work for
you.
And then if we go to the slide
deck document, we'll take a look
at the slide deck docs.
Let's see what this looks like.
This tells you, again, the, the,
there you go.
So we've got the different
information we should have on
different slide decks.
Welcome title and slide, et
cetera.
Promise slide, all that stuff, all
the way down.
Then the thank you page.
Let's take a look at this one.
There you go.
You're officially registered after
they, you know, sign up for the
webinar.
They put in all this information
here, get a nice thank you page
telling them,
you know, thanks for signing up
and what they're going to get
ahead of the call.
Obviously you're going to have to
edit this sort of stuff, but it's
good to go.
And then finally we have the
registration page, the page they
see before they register for the
webinar.
Let me get this in here.
There we go.
We've got a full sales page.
I got a webinar registration page
kind of set up and ready to go.
So as you can see this creates
pretty much everything you need to
get the funnel going.
This is 10 times you have to do
this individually yourself or, you
know, write it from scratch.
So super helpful if you are making
webinar funnels for clients, which
you will be if you're running a
funnel agency, most likely.
So this is definitely a very
detailed one.
You know, we've got about five AI
agents running here that are all
kind of doing deep research and
going really in depth.
It gets better outputs if you use
the funnel strategy document.
So highly suggest you do that and
input the URL to that here at the
beginning of your form.
So that it can get that document
and do a really good job of
writing all that information for
you.
So that's how this works.
Hope this was useful and I will
see you guys in the next one.
Peace.