What's up guys?
Lucas here.
So I'm going to be breaking down
for you the funnel outline and
strategy builder workflow.
As usual in these videos, I'll be
going over the different nodes
that we're using, how they work,
the end result we're going to get,
and we'll go into a bit of
detail in the preview because
you're going to need to run this
workflow.
Luckily, there's not too
many for this one.
You need open writer setup as
usual as with the other workflows.
You will need
your Google Drive set up with a
folder named clients.
You will always need a folder
named
clients as we're storing all of
our information on our clients,
and you will need Slack connected
to do
that.
Again, you will just connect with
Slack normally, and that's to send
you a notification
about the workflow completion.
So let's see how this starts.
It's a form.
Very simply, it's a
detailed form that goes over the
client's details about their
funnel.
So the business and product
name, what type of business they
are, the industry and niche, the
ideal customer, the primary funnel
objective, the core offer price,
the stage their business is at,
their top three to five customer
pain points, what makes them
different, primary traffic
sources, what funnel elements do
they
already have?
If they have none, that's fine,
but if they have any, put them in
there.
Successful
competitors, their preferred
funnel type, if known, when do
they need the funnel live by,
their
implementation budget, how have we
built a funnel for them
previously, and anything else we
should know.
After that's done, we send it to a
research agent that uses
perplexity to perform
deep, deep research on the client
and the funnel based on this
outline here.
So we look for their
funnel architecture
recommendation, the competitor and
market analysis, psychological
triggers and
persuasion tactics, detailed
funnel stages, the content
strategy by funnel stage, pricing
and offer
architecture, technology stack and
tools, conversion benchmark and
KPIs, quick wins and advanced
tactics, and a 90-day
implementation roadmap.
Now, again, this is not actually
going to write
every single piece of the funnel.
We have other workflows for that.
What this is doing is it's
creating a detailed strategy
document, and I'll show you what
that looks like near the end of
the
video.
Next thing we have the funnel
outline builder.
So this actually builds the
outline.
What we do
here is we take the research along
with the other information about
the client, and we create a funnel
strategy overview, funnel
architecture map, audience
psychology profile, offer strategy
framework, content
strategy matrix, conversion
optimization strategy, traffic and
scaling roadmap, metrics and KPI
framework, implementation roadmap,
and strategic recommendations.
From there, we simply convert the
output from our funnel builder to
markdown formatting.
That's just a very simple markdown
formatter.
It just
tells it to turn that text into a
markdown format so that then we
can use MD2 docs, which as
mentioned
before, you will need to use your
Google Docs OAuth 2 API setup for
this.
It just creates way nicer
looking Google Docs than using the
Google Docs node directly.
Then we check to see if they're a
returning
client, which we are getting that
information from our form.
Simply we said if they were or
they were not.
And if they are, then we look for
their existing client folder and
we move it to the Google Doc to
the
correct folder.
If they're not, we create a new
client folder and then move the
doc to that folder
before finally sending you a nice
notification telling you that the
funnel has been created with
a link to the document.
Now let's take a look at that
document and see what the actual
output of this
looks like.
I made up a company for this
called Scale with Confidence
Coaching.
As you can see here,
we get the full funnel strategy
overview.
We go through the different stages
of the customer journey.
Then we go into competitive
positioning strategy, the funnel
architecture map.
The page types are going
to be required for this, the
conversion mechanisms, technology
stack requirements, integration
points and automation triggers,
the core emotional drivers, the
sophistication level analysis.
It's super detailed.
This is 15 pages straight of
funnel strategies, everything you
possibly need,
including an outline of what the
email sequence should look like,
the story arc development,
authority building elements,
conversion optimization strategy,
the traffic and scaling roadmap.
Super, super detailed.
And the real benefit of this is
going to be feeding this to some
of our
other funnel builders later on.
So for the funnel copywriter and
for the webinar generator funnel,
this is super useful.
And there's a way to add this to
there with that workflow.
So hopefully this is
going to be one of the first
things you use.
If you're creating a funnel for a
client, it gives you
a great output that you can then
use as the basis for your other
elements.
And also you can give it to
the client directly to show them
kind of what the strategy is going
to look like and what's going to
be
involved.
It's super detailed as you've
seen.
It's very impressive and is
actually super useful for
you later on when you're writing
the rest of your copy and creating
the other elements of the funnel.
So I hope this was helpful.
Any issues, feel free to hit me up
and I will see you guys in the
next one.
Peace.