All right, can you guys see it?
How do you feel so far?
Good?
Good.
A little sleep deprived?
A little tired?
All right, all right.
Everybody just take a deep breath
real quick.
Okay, good.
You guys, you can't let your
fatigue set in,
but there's a lot of the crazy,
crazy, crazy stuff you know
from .
Look at his screen.
His screen's bigger.
Why?
Why don't you have a screen like
that?
His screen's bigger than yours,
bro.
The more that you...
How much we can actually impact
people,
how much that we can help people
through our services.
Because somebody may not be super
passionate about Klaviyo for email
marketing,
but in reality, you guys, if you
go far enough, are really changing
people's lives.
All right?
So back in 2020, this was when
Andre had gotten onto that bad
partnership that he mentioned.
We were restarting the agency.
And we were struggling by their
footing.
We had one offer.
Didn't work.
Fell flat on our face.
We had another offer.
Didn't work.
Fell flat on our face.
We didn't know about cold email
yet.
This was before we took cold email
mastery.
Shout out to Lizard.
And we were getting calls through
paid media.
Which, for a young agency that has
no clients pretty much,
and is closing out like a 5% rate
because their sales guy sucks.
That's the tough situation to be
in.
So, we found ourselves probably
five months in,
and just like, less than a
thousand bucks in the business
bank.
It was really dark.
I'd like to think that we wouldn't
have quit if we hit zero,
but I can't tell you what we would
have done.
We might have.
We might not be here today,
and you guys might not be here
today in this beautiful city
and this beautiful venue with all
these beautiful people.
And for whatever reason, when I
was scrolling there,
on Instagram, Facebook, whatever
it may have been,
I clicked on this app, and I sent
it to Andre.
I was like, this is interesting.
And I read through it, and I was
like, man, this is really good
copy.
Like, I want to buy this thing.
And we were in no position to
really buy anything.
Right?
Because we literally had zero
dollars.
Almost like we had just about
enough to sustain us for another
month.
And this is only a 97-hour
product.
I'm going to run out of hands, so
I think I am going to take this.
I'm going to take it.
Well, I'm going to take it because
I need to set it down and see it.
I was freaking out so much about
it because it was helping the
sales process
and we just weren't closing deals
partially because we put it in our
rider.
Yeah, I was like, Andre, listen.
You know what that is?
I'll work on this massive $97
investment.
I'll pay you back in full.
And I had no money in my bank
account.
So that was like me basically
putting my life savings online.
I'm like, whatever it takes, I'm
going to do this thing.
I'm so convinced from this copy
and just from everything I've seen
so far
about this guy that this is going
to help.
Right?
The whole thing was about
increasing closure.
Hopefully that's compliant.
It is.
Okay.
Yeah.
Because it works.
Exactly.
And you know what?
The next 12 sales calls that I
took, I closed four.
For us that was massive because
they also all had set up fees as
well.
So that gave us enough cash,
right?
This was like just when we were
finding cold email.
So it was kind of perfect timing
with that.
Combining with me, finding this
course and going through it and
actually having a real sales
process.
And right off the bat, just like
you said, my close rate went from
shit to 33%.
And since then we've had good
months, we've had bad months, you
know, like with anything.
There's always going to be another
problem that pops up.
The grass is always green, right?
There's always more that you can
be doing.
But we never really look back.
From that moment on, after I took
that course, we've always had
clients.
We've always had money coming in.
And that was when we started to
actually build a real business.
And the guy who made that course
is standing right over there.
So when this guy's talking, it can
legitimately change the business
of speaking from personal
personal experience and basically
save ours.
And hopefully that builds up
enough credibility because we
obviously build a couple of cool
businesses.
That's why you guys are all here.
It's really just fantastic.
So take notes.
Take notes.
Without further ado, we're
welcome.
Man, get along.
Thanks, bro.
You're the man.
What's up, crew?
How we doing?
Hey, let's stand up real fast.
Let's do it.
Come on, stand up.
Let's give a round of applause for
the wizard, for Andre.
for Christian.
Hey, look at them in the eyes and
say thank you.
Yeah.
As you collect the applause.
All right.
You can sit back down.
How many of you run events as
you're sitting down?
Raise your hands.
Nobody.
How many of you run events?
So you guys know it's hard.
It's hard.
How hard is it to put this thing
on?
It's a lot of work, isn't it?
Yeah.
It's a lot of work.
And it's a lot of money.
Believe me?
You lost money on it.
So we should give them another
round of applause.
Can you guys see me okay?
No.
No?
Cool.
Perfect.
We're going to talk a little bit
about,
we're going to talk about how to
hire teams
and how to manage teams.
And real quick,
if you've done the math on your
targets in your business,
raise your hands.
Targets in your business.
If you've never sat down and run
the math on targets in your
business,
how much money you want to make.
You've never done that.
You raise your hand.
You raise your hands.
You guys have been coddled by the
speakers.
I'm going to make you talk to me.
Raise your hand if you've done the
math on your business.
On your targets.
It's okay.
Throw them all up in the air.
How many of you have something to
write down notes with?
Do me a favor.
Have you ever visualized the
amount of money that you want to
make from your business?
Yes or no?
Yes.
Write that number down real fast.
On whatever it is you're taking
notes with.
How many of you have gotten really
excited at an event like this,
in a cool room like this with
entrepreneurs like this,
you're really excited to go make
your goals happen,
only to get back into the work
environment.
And it's hard as hell.
And maybe even you're like,
I don't even know if I want that
anymore.
And you change your goals.
Anybody?
Yeah?
Today, what I want to talk to you
about is,
I want to talk to you about how to
hit these targets
without actually having to do any
work.
Raise your hand if that's exciting
to you.
If you would like to hit the
numbers that you say you want to
hit with,
with being able to be perfectly
positioned as a founder, CEO, and
someone who thinks for a living.
Sound good?
Yes.
This will be interactive if you
can't tell.
So, like, if I feel like,
hopefully I don't feed back here.
I'm going to do it anyways.
If I feel like you're not talking
back to me, then we're just going
to like, have a moment.
Are you safe?
Are you going to sue me if I touch
you?
You're good.
I love your shirt.
It's amazing.
We've got to raise the level of
the room for a minute, because if
I can get you guys to not only
participate in what we're doing,
but to write your own notes down.
Did I do something to break this?
Oh, there we go.
If I can get you guys to
participate actively with me, you
will go home and you will change
your lives forever.
If I could promise you, this is a
guarantee, by the way, if I could
promise you that in the next 60
minutes I could help you hit your
targets without having you to
actually do all of the work,
would you invest 60 minutes with
no distractions into making that
happy?
Yes or no?
Hell yes.
This is me.
Go ahead and look and say, aw.
This is a Memphis Grizzlies hat.
I was broke, 24 years old, no
money, hated my job.
Can you relate to this?
And one day my wife says, this is
my wife right here.
How many of you are married?
Let me see a show of hands.
Congrats.
There's nothing like it.
How many of you want to be
married?
Cool.
We'll work on that.
One day my wife comes home and
she's like, hey, I think that you
should quit your job.
I was like, why?
My wife was an entrepreneur.
I wasn't.
My wife made a ton of money
compared to me.
But she said, I think you should
quit your job because you're not
making any money and you hate your
job.
And I said, okay, I'll quit my
And I started, I started buying
books.
That was my first home office.
Just let them pass for a second.
It was my first home office and
one day I came home with a pile of
books.
How many of you enjoy reading?
Or buying courses?
Yeah, yeah.
This was like 2012.
Your courses is like you had Tai
Lopez and Mobe.
This is it.
Anybody remember that?
Like basically an MLM thing.
My wife, she was like, I'm going
to sign up for this network
marketing thing.
And I'm like, okay, cool.
Get scammed.
I'm going to buy books on Amazon.
And I come home and I got lucky
one day and I read a book called
Psycho-Cybernetics.
Anybody read this book?
Yo, this is a fire book.
If you haven't read this book, you
should read it like tomorrow
morning.
It changed the way I thought about
identity and it changed the way
that I thought about myself.
I started making money.
I started making really good
money.
So I went as an entrepreneur.
You guys remember the picture of
my home office.
I started making tons and tons and
tons of money.
I went from basically nothing,
broke, working at a church, to
4,000 clients at a profit, by the
way.
The pros, I'm going to give you
some things that you're going to
want to write down.
And this will be one of them.
The professionals care about
customers.
Amateurs are focused on lead
generation.
No offense.
Professionals are focused on
customer acquisition.
And we started printing customers.
We got over 4,000 clients at
profit.
A couple hundred thousand
customers came into the
organization.
700 team members.
I've hired 700 staff and fired
most of them.
Which is exhausting.
The capital cost of having to fire
that many people.
And it took me a long time to
figure the system out.
At one point I woke up and I was
spending over $800,000 a month in
team and fixed costs.
That's a lot.
And I still fired everybody.
Because I didn't know what I do
today and what I'm going to teach
you.
And you can see there's a lot of
people.
Anybody ever seen 100,000 people
all at once?
Yes, no?
Do we need margaritas?
Or some cigars?
We can do cigars but maybe later
we'll do margaritas.
I'll make you stand up and sit
down as many damn times as it
takes.
100,000 students.
We had over a couple million email
names, addresses.
One of the worst things that ever
happened to me is I actually went
through a bit of,
you could call it a battle, with
the regulatory agency in the
United States.
And I had to give all of these
names back.
Two million people we just had to
delete essentially.
And we scaled this thing from zero
to multiple millions of dollars a
month.
But then something started to
happen.
I started to burn out.
Somebody say burn out.
Burn out.
Have you ever felt close to
burnout?
Yeah?
Or you're running out of energy?
Man, it's the scariest feeling.
Because you never know if you're
going to come back from this
feeling of burnout.
And I hit burnout and by the year
2022, all of the companies were
gone.
It was crazy.
700 staff, millions of names,
hundreds of thousands of
customers, thousands and thousands
of clients.
And I basically burned it because
I got burned out.
Now, anybody right now asking
like, why would I learn from this
person if he basically destroyed?
Because if you can destroy eight
figure companies, you can build
them too.
So I've built and destroyed more
eight figure companies than most
people.
And the reason that I got into
this place of burnout is because
how many hours in a day do we
have?
That's it.
And the only way to get more than
24 hours is to buy it.
And you can purchase labor,
talents, and decisions and people
can multiply the amount of time
that you have in a day if you know
the stuff that I am going to take.
So, by the way, does anybody want
to have a copy of my slides?
Yes.
I can tell you guys, like, do I
take a picture of this?
It's a nice circle.
It's like, I want to remember this
for later.
You don't have to.
I actually put all the slides
together.
Pull out your phones real fast.
If you go to
taylorawells.com/ascension, you
can download my slides.
Make me one promise.
Do not skip ahead.
I hate that shit.
It's disrespectful.
And then look back up at me when
you're done and we'll get back to
it.
If you need help spelling
ascension, let me know.
Yeah, some of y'all are like...
Yeah, it's tough.
It's a big word.
Do you need help?
You got it, bro?
Okay.
With an O.
T-A-Y-L-O-R.
All right, how about we do this at
the end?
It's taking you guys a really, a
really long time.
Well, I'll just give it to you,
okay?
I got some goodies for you guys up
my sleeve.
Sound good?
Say, "Whoo!"
Man, I love rooms like this.
Entrepreneurs change the world.
The world hangs in the balance of
people like you.
You realize this?
Like, nothing good ever, ever,
ever happened without somebody
selling something,
inventing something or marketing
something.
So, this is the highest honor to
be able to come and learn how to
build movement.
And I basically torched the old
companies.
Somebody say, "Torched."
Torched.
Just set them on fire.
Killed them.
And over the three months in the
summer, I decided to reverse
engineer.
This is a powerful lesson.
If you have something in your life
that you do not like right now,
raise your hands.
Keep them up.
Cool.
Everyone in the room has their
hands up.
Which is good, because I was going
to call you out if you didn't.
The greatest thing you can learn
how to do is reverse engineer,
because this is Charlie Mugger.
He said, "If you just tell me
where I'm going to die, I'll just
not go there."
He's reverse engineering.
And so, I reverse engineer.
What is it that makes businesses
work long term?
There's eight categories.
I'm going to actually read them to
you.
You can write them down if you
want, but you do not have to.
The first is marketing.
Somebody say, "Marketing."
Marketing is defined as the
acquisition of attention and
reputation.
People don't think about this, but
if you convert people, they should
not be converted.
You actually chip away at your
reputation.
True or false?
True.
The second is sales.
This is monetization and
certainty.
The third is offer, desire,
fulfillment.
This is your deliverable.
How many of you feel like you have
a great offer right now to offer
your crowd?
Cool.
The fourth is finance.
If you like money, say, "Yeah."
Money is a great thing.
You know, we're raised societally
that, you know, if you're just
like a capitalist, rich
capitalist, there's nothing wrong
with you, but capitalists actually
finance everything.
And so, it's good to have money.
Next is team.
Say team.
This is what we're going to focus
on today.
How do I build a team that
multiplies the hours in the day
and hits all of my targets?
The subtitle is how to get rich
through other people.
And this is the key.
It's a symbiotic relationship.
And I'm going to give you guys
frameworks.
If you do have a team, can I see a
show of hands real fast?
Amazing.
It's a change of life.
I think it will be an amazing
training for you.
And when you have all of these,
the next is balance, mind work,
retention.
I run a company today that trains
on all of these eight drivers.
And so, today I'm going to give
you about 5% of the team playbook.
And we basically go in and we
equip members on how to build
their teams.
I'm going to give you guys
actually the entire playbook at
the end for free because I don't
need your money.
When you actually get this right,
there's only two things that can
kill your business.
Two.
Would you like to know what they
are?
Yes.
You want me to keep going?
You sure?
Number one, taking the wrong
clients.
Think about it.
How many of y'all just took a
client to hit your numbers?
Then they ruined your literal
life.
There's nothing worse than taking
the wrong client.
The only way, the only acceptable
way to get rich is through the
exchange of service.
The second thing that can kill
your business is hiring the wrong
team.
If you've ever had the wrong team
members, don't look at them if
they're here with you.
But man, you know it's a pain.
And then the hardest thing is
getting rid of them after you know
that they're not the
right hire.
You're in an event called Client
Ascension.
These guys are some of the best in
the world at getting clients.
So I'm not going to talk a lot
about getting clients.
You've been trained on that.
But what I am going to teach you
is how do I assemble an Avengers
squad that can multiply
my business.
You want to hit nine figures?
Only way you're doing it is
through a team.
Or else you're going to lose your
minds.
Okay?
We're going to do some exercises.
Is that cool?
Yeah.
So here's what I want you to do.
And before I prep you for this,
but we're going to get ready.
We're going to put some time on
the clock.
Write this down in whatever you're
using to take notes.
You can make money by doing stuff.
Somebody say stuff.
Stuff.
But you get really rich by what
you don't do.
You can make money by doing stuff.
But you get really rich by what
you don't do.
You guys know what a to-do list
is, right?
Yeah.
We all have a to-do list.
But you have a do not do list.
Something written down like I will
not do this.
The money is energy.
And it flows.
And it interacts with the realm of
the spirit.
I just get really weird sometimes.
Because if you do things that you
hate doing, you actually will end
up killing the business.
Because it's not worth it for the
money.
And we're going to prove that.
So I'm going to prove it to you.
We'll get into it.
First exercise.
You ready?
We're going to put two minutes on
the clock.
And did you guys write your goals
down in the first section?
Were you obedient or rebellious?
You wrote them down?
Okay.
We're going to put two minutes on
the clock.
I'm going to actually turn some
music on.
This isn't weird.
Don't make it weird.
But I want you to write down three
things.
You ready?
The first is, what is the amount
of money you make per month?
By what date?
And what are the things that you
are not doing on a day-to-day
basis to make that money?
Think of it this way.
If there's things that are going
on in your business right now that
you don't enjoy doing,
write those things down.
Because we're going to cross those
things off.
What are the areas in your
business that you're currently
having to do for money
that you do not want to do?
All right.
You've got a minute and a half
left.
You can turn that music up.
Write it down.
Be detailed.
What are the things you're
currently doing in your business
that you do not want to do?
How much money do you make per
month?
By what date?
And what are the things you're
doing now that you don't want to
do and you're going to stop
doing?
How much money do you make per
month?
What do you make per month?
How much money do you make per
month?
And then rehearse wins every
morning.
Whatever it is, it doesn't matter.
The point is we're being
algorithmic in taking our
objectives,
breaking them down into key
results,
and then breaking those down into
assignments.
You'll write this down because
it's not on my slides.
Every objective should have two to
three key results.
And every key result is usually
going to have
three to ten assignments
underneath it.
And here's how this starts fitting
in to the equation.
You can see this water flow
effect.
As you begin setting objectives,
your team begins going in and
implementing the key results.
And then the managers tend to the
assignments according to the key
results.
Does this make sense?
Yeah.
So this is the chart we have.
Your T1's up here at the top.
These are your what?
Decision makers.
Your T2's are what?
Managers.
And your T3's?
Laborers.
Are your laborers.
So here's the main job,
and I'm just going to give all of
these to you.
Your T1's, these are your decision
makers.
They set the objectives,
and they manage the implementation
against the key results.
Is this a little bit too in the
weeds?
Do you want to bump back up?
We're good?
Cool.
The T2, they set the assignments,
and they ensure that the work is
being completed on time, under
budget, inside of quality control.
And T3, these are the people that
are doing the actual work.
One break at any level can slow
your organization down or break it
all together.
It's terrifying.
People will say, Eddie was talking
about the importance of A players
earlier, which by the way, he
crushed it.
He's a brilliant dude right there.
Worth listening to.
An A player has to fit into every
level.
So you need A players on your
T3's.
You need A players on your T2's.
A players on your T1's.
And your job, part of your job as
a CEO, is to fire the people if
you cannot train them.
If you can't change the person,
you've got to change the person.
Make sense?
How are we feeling?
Good.
Scale of one to ten?
Ten.
Cool.
Alright, we're going to do another
exercise.
You ready?
Go back on the clock.
Here's what I want you to do.
Pick one objective for your
business.
Write down a couple of key
results.
And write down a couple of
assignments.
You have two minutes.
We're going to turn the music on.
Just one objective.
Don't do like 12.
We'll be here all night.
Alright?
Give me that sophisticated tunes.
One objective.
Couple of key results.
And a couple of assignments.
You're doing great.
You've got another minute.
Do the work.
You're doing great.
You've got another minute.
Do the work.
You done?
Yeah.
It's fast.
I was thinking about it.
It was fast.
I want to hire you.
30 seconds.
15 seconds.
All right, here we go.
Turn to someone you haven't talked
to.
So if you turn to the right the
first time, turn to the left this
time, and you guys are
going to share your OKRs with one
another.
We have a minute and a half
because I don't want to go late.
So go ahead and pick your partner.
Share your plan right now.
Let's go.
Hey, real quick.
What time do I actually need to
cut off?
We got like 20 minutes.
20 minutes.
That's good?
Yeah, that's great.
Whatever you need.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, bro.
What's your job?
I'm going to skip ahead a little
bit.
Oh, sure.
That's better, huh?
Way better.
30 more seconds.
All right.
Let the other person talk.
Switch.
Objective key result and
assignment.
Good stuff?
It's fucking dope, bro.
Good.
What do you think?
I'm taking notes.
You've already heard this before.
Really?
On how you're doing it, too.
I'm like, this is fucking good.
Yeah, bro.
It just keeps the room, like, way
happier.
That way we don't all fall asleep.
Let's get drinks next time and
start morning.
Bro, I actually do that for real.
Do you?
I was speaking at an Agora
conference, and I was like, can we
get tequila for everyone?
And Gabe's was like, you're going
to have to pay for it.
I was like, do it.
Fuck it.
And nobody remembers anything
else.
The tequila guy was there, and
like, I was everyone's favorite.
It's more, what happened?
All right.
We ready?
Yeah.
How did you say you were giving
people drinks when you were
talking and they were like, dialed
in or what?
Yeah, people always pay attention
if you give them drinks.
Okay, how we feel?
Great.
How many of you are feeling a
little bit more clarity?
A little bit better?
Anybody want to share one of their
objectives, one of their key
results, one of their assignments?
What do we got?
Instagram, man.
Are you going to work with me or
not, dude?
This dude's trying to hard sell me
in the bar.
You did pretty good, though.
It's not true.
All right, tell me.
What'd you got?
100 courses within the first 30
days of launch is the objective.
The key results, just one of them
would be start a wait list and
build anticipation.
And then an assignment for that
result would be create content
firstly and then launch trailer.
Epic.
You feel like you're getting a
plan dialed in to scale your
business?
100%.
Anybody else want to share?
Anybody?
You don't want to.
I can tell.
He doesn't want to talk to me.
I keep trying to look at you and
you're looking away.
I can share, but it won't be lit.
Like, because I'm still a sales
guy.
Like, so it's going to be hard.
Yeah, you're the best of us.
You're sales guy.
No, we're going to go with him.
You're not confident, so we're
skipping you.
Okay.
500K a month in new sales, not
counting back end.
So in order to do that, we need
400 book calls, 80% show rate, 20%
close rate at a ticket size of
like 8K, which is between our two
offers.
The assignments to get that would
be at least 2,000 opt-ins.
So I don't know how much that's
going to cost.
Probably not that much.
Probably not.
Yeah, he'll let me know.
He'll let me know.
Need to have 200 sets.
So our setters back there got to
get dialed.
I'm guessing at least $50 a day.
We have to text each and every
lead immediately within 10 minutes
if they don't book a call from the
BSL directly.
Hell yeah.
Round of applause right here for
that brilliant plan.
Who's your setter?
Stand up.
Who's the setter?
I'm in.
All right.
Round of applause.
Wait.
You're a setter too?
Both of you?
All right.
150 calls a day.
It's easy.
You'll be fine.
Go to the bathroom before you
start and then power through.
All right.
One more person.
Anybody else?
We don't have to.
All right.
We'll skip it.
Because the world belongs to the
enthusiastic.
We got to be enthusiastic.
You know what happens when you
share your goals?
I don't have time.
I've got to end in 20 minutes.
Would it be nice to know if the
team you have right now is going
to get you to your goals?
Like if we had a way to sort of
qualify or disqualify, we're not
going to do it for you guys.
You guys are safe.
How do we actually qualify the
people before we hire them, after
we hire them?
At the end of the training, I'm
actually going to give you guys a
playbook.
And it's the same playbook, Colin,
that you have access to.
And it goes through some of the
personality profiling.
We have like really deep research
on personality profiling.
But I want to give you two models.
Just two.
And then we're going to wrap up
and get into takeaways.
The first is person, personality,
and position.
If you put a person with skill,
but they do not have the
personality for the position,
they're going to fail.
Make sense?
Yeah.
If you're going to be a setter and
you hate talking to people, what's
the problem?
Like, do you think that a setter
who hates people is going to be
able to actually dial and talk to
people?
No.
It's going to be very difficult
for them to do that.
And so we'll go deep into this
person, personality, position.
I'm going to skip it for now so
that we don't miss the bar.
But the next thing we're going to
go into is rating current team
members.
So, we rate team members based on
a three-pronged approach.
It is also a triangle.
Different colors.
It's different colors.
And here they are.
Attitude is number one.
Let me say attitude.
Attitude.
Now, attitude we're going to
define as culture, communication,
and teachability.
If you have people on your team
that are not teachable or
coachable or they do not accept a
level of feedback from you, their
attitude is going to rate low.
Scale them one to ten, we rate
people on one to ten very quickly.
Make sense?
Yeah.
Where did you get that hat, by the
way?
Carte Blanche.
It's sick.
It's cool.
I just saw it and I was like, I
need one of those.
I need yours too.
But I got one.
Give me hats.
Attitude is your culture, your
communication.
And your teachability.
The second is competency.
Whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa, dude.
Competency.
We're back.
Skill, resourcefulness, and follow
through.
Have you ever assigned something
out to your team and they do not
do it?
Oh, dude.
Oh, my God.
Like nothing in the world is worse
than that.
And so the follow through is
actually a competency piece.
If they are competent, then they
have the follow through ability.
And then experience is the
decision making, the street
smarts, the poison confidence.
Real quick warning on experience.
When I say experience, I mean
experience at the level that you
want to get to.
Not experience at your current
level, but experience at the level
that you want to get through.
And typically, this is just for
later.
We can talk about it on the boat.
We stick in realms of threes.
If you're at $100,000 a month and
you hire the CMO of Coca-Cola,
they ain't going to do a good job.
They're too big.
And so you want to stick into this
realm of like three to five X your
current business.
Okay?
Is that helpful?
Yeah.
What is culture though?
I want to define this quickly for
you.
Because when you look at attitude,
what do we see up here?
Communication, teachability, and
what?
Culture.
Communication, teachability,
culture.
Culture.
Culture will make or break your
organization.
What is culture?
How do we define it?
What do we think?
Just raise your hands.
Blurt it out.
Yes, sir.
Dude, you have always come through
for me, by the way.
The polo, the answers.
It's all perfect.
Anybody else?
What people do.
What they do?
When no one's around.
Great answer.
What else we got?
Can you guys see me in the back?
Yeah.
The kinds of videos you send each
other out.
Round of applause for whoever you
are.
That's actually maybe kind of
true.
Here's what I want you guys to
mentally think about in terms of
culture.
Culture is what they believe, why
they believe it, and what do you
see?
How strongly they believe it.
What do they believe?
Why do they believe it?
How strongly they believe it.
You can honestly, if you're taking
notes, you can put next to
strongly, you can put parentheses,
and put violently.
Because when you believe something
really strongly, you're protective
of it.
You're defensive of it.
True or false?
True.
A good culture.
You want to know how a good
culture is a good culture?
They will literally eat you alive
if you don't believe the same
things that the culture believes.
A good culture is not a safe place
unless you belong to the tribe.
Does this make sense?
Yeah.
So we've kind of deviated in the
last 30 years with corporate
America to kind of trying to build
culture that's pleasing and safe
for everyone.
But real good culture, you've got
to fit in or you do not fit in.
And so this is my charge on this
is make sure that when you're
rating culture, you're rating
their attitude and it'll fit on
whether they actually buy in to
what you are doing.
Who has a written set of values
for your organization?
Show of hands.
Cool.
This is a great idea for you to
know.
When we read our culture, if that
person looks sick, fire them.
Easy.
If we're reading our set of values
and somebody does not align with
the values, they're not going to
be a culture fit.
It doesn't matter how skilled they
are.
They don't belong.
Does this make sense?
Yeah.
Raise your hand if you would like
my organizational values to read.
Yes, please.
If your hand's not up, what are
you doing?
I'm going to give them to you.
It's fine.
We'll get there later.
Once you have your players, the
question is what do you do as a
CEO?
Huh?
Embody?
Embody them.
They go into...
I didn't know it was that kind of
event, dude.
Pretty sus.
Was that my dude who...
Is that you?
Bro, you always...
This is the first time you've
failed me.
Our job is to engineer an
environment where people have
almost enough time to perform
their best but not quite.
I'm about to blow your minds.
I can see you wrestling with it
right now.
And I'm going to explain it.
This man looked at me like I was
stupid.
Our job is to engineer an
environment where people have
almost enough time to perform
their best but not quite.
I'm about to blow your mind.
I can see you wrestling with it
right now and I'm going to explain
it.
This man looked at me like I was
stupid.
He's like, do you even math?
All right.
So we want to actually create
flow.
Yes.
Flow comes when you are right at
the line of your abilities, maybe
even a little bit beyond the line.
I was telling somebody at one of
our off sites that I will always
be understaffed.
Always.
Forever.
You want your business to
perpetually be understaffed.
You know, this is why you're
fighting with your managers
because it's crazy.
But when you actually don't have
enough resources to get the job
done and you don't have, you
almost have enough time but you
don't, then you have the flow
state that forces creativity.
She's smiling like you do this to
her all the time.
You guys are doing it right.
I'm sorry.
But this is how you create flow
state.
Somebody say capacity.
Okay.
When you're wanting to increase
your capacity, how is it done?
Pushing the limits.
If you want to get biceps like me,
how do you do it?
Listen, Hormozzi is always flexing
and stuff, but my calves are at
least double his size.
When I go to the gym and I do my
calves, people leave.
And it's because, it's because I'm
a dad, bro.
Have you seen my son?
I have an eight-month-old who's 30
pounds.
I have a four-and-a-half-year-old
who's 38 pounds.
That eight-month-old is going to
be a freaking titan.
And he's strong.
I almost pulled my pants down in
front of everybody the other day.
He was grabbing onto it.
Flow state is what you get when
you run out of time.
Think about it.
Flow state is what you get when
you are stretched beyond the
normal limits of your traditional
performance.
The greatest gift you can give to
an A player, to a high-performance
team, is higher standards that
move everyone's life forward.
Does this make sense?
If you want to run an eight-figure
team, a nine-figure team, a
high-performance team, do you guys
remember when Elon took over
Twitter?
He comes in, fires everyone, and
says, hey, we're going to double
the innovation, and you're all
fired, except for like a hundred
of you.
And people are like, what in the
world?
And what happened to Twitter?
It got better.
Waste and excess surplus makes you
weak.
It makes you lazy.
This is the gift that we give
other people, is we expect more
from them.
Can we do that?
I want you really to grab this,
because this is probably one of
the biggest takeaways.
People come into my teams, like I
remember them all.
I've trained 58,000 salespeople.
And I remember all, like the
A-listers of today, and they're
all brilliant.
And I remember when they were not
brilliant.
And they came into my offices in
Nashville, and we had all of these
crazy people, you remember this,
in an office, for 14 hours a day.
150 calls a day, by the way, is
your starting point.
They're never going to invite me
back to speak at this.
I feel like I'm ruining my
chances.
And the gift that I gave, Cole,
Payton, all of the crew, is higher
standards.
When a person's standards are
lifted through culture, they do
things that they never thought
they were capable of doing.
This is where we've got to get to
with our team.
Make sense?
Okay.
Does this make sense?
Right here.
If you do want to take a picture,
you can, but I'm going to send it
to you.
This is like a traditional,
classic org chart for one of my
companies.
We do run a portfolio.
I don't talk about it often
because portfolio has become a
thing that I don't want to
infringe on.
But you take the C-level, you put
them at the top.
If you have finance people, you
just have to put up with them.
They're over here in the corner.
I didn't want to give them more
spots.
Finance people, their main job is
to tell you what you can't do.
Boo.
You have to listen to them.
And we have the C-level.
These are your T-what?
Ones.
And then we have the managers.
These are your T.
Look over here.
You've got SDRs.
This will be your setter manager.
Your AEs.
This will be your closer manager.
You've got your reps underneath
it.
This is something that you will
print money if you can get this
type of org chart in place.
Again, number two, bros.
Two of the biggest yawns I've ever
seen.
Can you come up here?
Yeah, come sit with me, dude.
Come on, man.
Just give them a round of
applause.
Let's go, dude.
Let's go.
Hey, what's your name?
Charlie?
It's great to meet you, dude.
Do you take, like, sleep
supplements?
No.
No, I've just been eating a lot of
that gum, so I think it's been...
You've been eating gum?
The...
Like, swallowing it?
The focus gum.
What's one takeaway you would give
to the audience?
From this?
Sure.
Might as well.
Culture is everything.
That was an easy one.
Give me a better one.
Hire the right people.
That was also an easy one, but I
think it's great.
You can go sit down.
Thank you, bro.
You're the man.
Give him a round of applause.
Are we having fun?
This is freaking fun.
I'm telling you.
Listen, we just make money.
Charlie falls asleep, and it's
awesome.
Okay.
I'm going to skip a quick exercise
because I want to wrap up, but the
thing that we have
to get to after we have this in
place is, what do I do?
Because what I thought the goal
was was to escape.
This is what everyone's chasing.
I got a call a couple weeks ago
from someone who's a really dear
friend of mine, and he's
crushing it, and he said, you
know, we're crushing it, and I
only spent like 20 minutes at my
last
event, and I was like, ooh, dude,
that's not good.
The escapism is not, you don't
want what other people are
chasing.
Your job as an entrepreneur is to
engage, not to escape.
It's not to escape everything.
It's to engage in the things that
you love to do more than anything
else.
So we're actually going to do,
we're going to do a one minute
exercise.
We have 60 seconds to do this, so
you better do it quick.
And I want to, I want you to write
down in one minute, you can put
some music on, the things
that you feel like you could do
forever, for hours and hours and
hours, and you don't run
out of time, and you don't run out
of energy, maybe it's writing
copy, maybe it's doing sales
calls, you can turn that music up
now.
We're good to go.
Write down a list of things that
you love to do more than anything
else.
Just join a webinar, Charlie.
Gosh.
Oh, I love you, Charlie.
These are the things you just love
to do.
You got some good ones?
Yeah.
I got some great ones.
Yeah?
Yeah.
All right, cool.
Cool, cool, cool.
What is it?
What do you got?
I got filming videos, creating
offers, and writing BSLs.
Epic.
That sounds like a pretty good
list, yeah?
What do you have right here?
I got looking at numbers and
setting objectives, team meetings,
and hiring.
Epic.
You like hiring.
Praise God for you.
You're an amazing human.
Okay.
Here's the thing.
That list is going to become our
new guidebook.
We're the things that are actually
going to grow our business.
The entrepreneur who feels like
their business is killing them
will eventually kill their
business.
So the job that we have is to
backfill ourselves out of the
things that we hate and plug
ourselves into the things that we
love.
True or false?
True.
Okay, so if we do all of this, you
have four jobs as the CEO.
Hire team, train team, equip team,
hold team accountable, and then as
the final, whatever you want.
It's true.
When you have team in place using
this protocol, and in the
playbook, there's a whole suite of
training from meetings.
How do you run them?
How do you do them?
This is the job.
Hire them, train them, equip them,
hold them accountable, and then do
whatever you want.
So listen to this real quick.
At this point, you have a list of
things you need to stop doing.
Yes or no?
Yes.
And then you have a toolkit, so to
speak, of how to go replace
yourself by finding the right
person.
Yes or no?
Yes.
And then we have a list of things
of what we actually want to do.
Yes or no?
Yes.
That will push our business
forward.
Yes or no?
Yes.
And then we have the numbers,
objectives, key results, and
assignments necessary for us to
hit any level of business that we
want.
Yes or no?
Yes.
How many of us are feeling rich?
I feel wealthy right now.
You feel wealthy.
Good answer.
How many of you are feeling
clarity?
Yes.
Yeah, 100%.
Here's what I want to do.
The beauty of a room like this is
there are people doing $20 million
a year who won't partner with me
because he hates me.
And then there are people that are
doing less than that.
And we all learn at different
levels.
How many of you have a takeaway
that you can share with the rest
of the crew?
We're going to just do this for
just like 30 seconds.
Do we have time?
Yeah, five minutes.
Five minutes?
Jeez.
Okay.
We're going to do some cool stuff
now.
How many of you have some
takeaways you want to share?
What you got?
Me doing the things that I hate to
do is like the riskiest thing I
can do.
You doing the things you hate to
do is the riskiest thing you can
do.
You want a second shot.
I'll be right back, dude.
Let's get somebody in the back.
What you got?
Running an audit on the team that
was nice on the memories that we
said.
Running an audit so you know who
to fire.
Let's fix it for you.
That's great.
Who else?
What do we have?
Yeah, what you got?
Stop trying to be a tough guy and
thinking you're better because
you're doing boring shit.
Stop being a tough guy because
you're boring?
No.
Sorry.
Stop thinking you're a tough guy
because you're trying to do boring
shit all the time.
100%.
Who else?
Yeah, hold on.
Let me give you the mic.
You can't get good at things that
you hate.
Where'd you get these?
Down the street.
My man.
Who else wants to share?
Yep.
Give the employees more
responsibility when you know how
they can handle it.
Do more.
Have them do more.
Anybody else?
What you got, bro?
Blow our minds.
Pretty much I feel very
irresponsible for not having the
objectives.
I feel like a dumbass.
Like, oh yeah, we got the goal,
but just didn't make an impact of
that at all.
Well, now you're not a dumbass.
Now you're really, really smart.
You're actually brilliant.
Don't talk about yourself that
way.
Round two.
But a lot of people tell you that
you got to do the things that you
don't want to do,
but that kind of went against
every thought of order of order.
It makes sense.
Do the shit that you love.
Also, breaking down everything,
kind of like the key results.
Like, oh, I need to take this many
sales calls.
We need to have this show rate and
this close rate.
It makes it a lot more apparent to
actually get those calls.
Love it.
Amazing.
Round of applause for this man who
finally looked at me in the eyes.
Do we have any Q&A or questions
that you guys have?
It can be directly relevant on
this.
Andre's going to come kick me out
of this room in a second.
Is there anything you guys want to
know that I didn't cover?
Just yell it out.
Yes, sir.
What?
What does it mean to equip the
team?
Equip the team is giving them the
resources necessary and the
autonomy necessary to make
decisions.
So, a lot of people will hire
people, train them, fire them for
making mistakes.
That's not.
Equipping is giving somebody the
permission to learn and the
permission to decide.
Because if you're going to hire a
T1, they've got to make decisions.
And they're going to make
decisions different than you do.
Make sense?
Yes.
Yell it out.
How do you create congruency of
vision?
Congruency of vision, like from me
down and passing it into the rest
of the team?
I have a vision.
If they like that vision, they get
behind it.
If they don't, they go work
somewhere else.
How do you like to be realising
over time?
We talk about it a lot, so we'll
share it a lot.
People tend to get in line with
things that they're exposed to.
They'll get behind things that
they understand and have
communicated about.
So, it's more a communication
thing than anything else.
What benchmarks do you hire T2s?
T2s?
So, this is a great question.
When you can no longer manage the
implementation of the work around
you,
you need T2s to backfill you out.
That's okay.
Totally fine.
The T1s right now are doing a
little bit of management.
They might not like it, but
they're doing it.
As soon as they can't manage the
implementation, you've got to put
a manager in between.
Have you ever moved to T1s?
I typically don't move them down
or you're going to lose them.
You can move them up.
However, businesses die most often
due to internal promotion.
Yeah, because if I have like a
manager in ops and I raise them to
a COO.
Think about that being compared to
me going and pulling a COO from
someone else who's a little bit
bigger.
You're paying an opportunity cost
that might as well be cash.
So, in most cases, it's actually
safer for the business to go pull
someone with the expertise, bring
them in.
Unless you're willing to let that
person really go through the trial
and error process.
Yeah, because they're not like T1
titles.
But using that org chart, they
have the T1 responsibilities.
If they're making all the
decisions for the department,
they're a T1.
Yeah, who else?
As you scaled, how do you balance
scaling the business with your
family?
With my family?
He said, how did I balance scaling
the business with my family?
This is a great question if you
want me to tackle it, if I have
the time.
Let's do it.
I actually didn't.
That's the short answer.
I had to learn how to do it.
So, the people who have like, the
people, talking about productivity
without kids is a joke.
When I had my first kid, I was
like, oh, shit.
There's no time anywhere.
And then we had the second one,
and I was like, ooh, this is even
worse.
So, reading is like a thing of
glory for me now.
Like, I'm, oh, my God, I have an
hour to read.
The prioritization is a law.
So, if you misprioritize, you'll
lose all of the priorities.
And so, what I've got right now is
I've got myself.
I'm actually at the top.
I just posted about this today.
If you cheat yourself, you'll also
fail everyone else around you.
So, there's a rule book for me.
I need a certain amount of
reading, a certain amount of
studying, a certain amount of
exercise.
And I try to be very un, like,
yeah, I don't compromise that.
Second is the family.
So, I'm not going to miss, like,
I'm going to wake my kids up every
day.
They wake up at seven.
I'm going to wake them up every
day.
If you cheat on priorities, you
begin to feel like you don't
deserve anything.
So, it's not really a balancing
effect.
It's a prioritization matter.
After my family's taken care of,
there's a playbook for that.
So, like, I'm going to wake my
kids up every morning.
I have a weekly date with my four
and a half year old, Kate.
I have a weekly date with my wife,
Lindsay.
And when that's done, we're good.
And I can put all my time into the
next priority, which is the
business and the team and the
staff.
And then after that, I've got
relationships and everything else.
And so, that's kind of, like, my
four things.
And, like, this morning, I'm on a
plane.
I missed donut date with my
daughter.
But I'm grabbing that Monday.
So, I'll just backfill it in.
So, it's not a sacrifice.
It's just a moving around.
Does that help?
Yeah.
Cool.
All right.
Let's do two more questions.
And then we're going to bring the
boss back up.
What you got?
So, you know how you said you
should hire someone who's working
at another business that's, like,
three to five X your current
business size.
Yes, steal them.
So, my question is, like, number
one, how do you sell them to work
for you because you're
three to five X smaller?
And number two, how do you
properly align the incentives?
Yeah, great question.
How do you steal them and how do
you align the incentives?
The vision that you have as an
entrepreneur is like a vacuum.
It sucks people in or repels
people away.
So, if you're trying to hire
somebody from somebody who's a
bigger company, it doesn't matter.
What you really are going to
battle is you're hiring from
someone with a bigger orbit of
vision.
Make sense?
So, like, Arena is one of my
businesses.
The priority for Arena, the
mission for Arena is to deprogram
victimhood from the world and to
eliminate suicide.
Is that big or little?
People want to work for me for
free.
They want to leave other companies
and work for me for free.
The mission for a wealthy
consultant is to unlock and
monetize human expertise.
Is that big or little?
So, it's a missional thing.
If your vision is big enough,
they'll be attracted into it.
How do you align incentives?
With their T1s at the very top,
most of the time giving them a bit
of profit share and then a three
to four type of, like, bonuses.
One year, three year, and
quarterly.
And we get into all of that in the
playbook.
One more question.
You?
Yes.
Isaac.
Wonderful name.
What do you got?
Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob.
It's in the Bible, dude.
You're blessed.
David?
King David?
What do you got?
Can you talk to, like, values and,
like, how you might think about
those in your company?
Values?
I'm going to give you my values.
Yeah, so I'm going to skip that
question and do one more because
I'm going to give them to you at
the end.
Was it hard for you to unlearn the
strength?
You talked about that big shift.
You burned a business to the
ground and then you have this
model now for doing whatever you
want, which is what you need to
do.
Did you have to unlearn, like,
just, like, stress?
Dude, everything.
Yeah, everything.
Because the piece of me that felt
like I was dying in the middle was
equally next to the piece of me
that felt like I would be a
failure if I quit.
So you've heard, like, quitters
never win and winners never.
Bullshit.
Winners quit all the time.
Like, they literally quit their
way to success.
As soon as you are not deeply
passionate about the outcome, if
you win, you should not be playing
the game.
The game doesn't matter.
And so what happened with me is I
hit that point where I no longer
cared about the outcome because I
was out of energy.
Not out of time.
I was out of energy.
Energy is superior to time as a
resource.
And so when I got into the new
business units and I started
building the new thing and the
portfolio came together, my first
instinct was, like, I have to
grind.
Because that's what it was like a
TF.
That's what it was like a sales
mentor.
And I felt like I was unproductive
because I was not busy.
And so that just works.
You had to go through unveiling
the layers.
And, like, you know, I would
rather be productive with a little
bit less time than unproductive
with 40, 50, 60 hours a week.
So it's something that you,
there's three things that you
learn all of the time.
There's only three categories.
Things that you have to unlearn.
Right?
Things that you have to relearn.
How many of you have had to learn
a lesson for the second, third, or
fourth time?
Yeah, it sucks.
But a lesson will repeat itself
until you learn it.
And then the third are the things
you learn for the first time.
A very small portion of our lives
today are the third category.
Most of them are the first two.
And if we want to learn more
things, we have to actually grasp
the lesson so we stop relearning
the same old shit over and over.
But, yeah, dude, it was incredibly
difficult.
In fact, mentally, if you're not
feeling like it's difficult,
you're just not doing something
worthwhile.
So it's still difficult for me.
Every once in a while I'll still
be like, you know, I'm just like,
I'm poor.
Literally going broke.
And people are like, what are you
talking about?
Makes zero sense.
Cry me a river.
And I'll be like, I'm completely
out of time.
And so I need to work harder.
Which doesn't make any sense.
So you have to have that time to
really piece it all together.
And have friends that work.
All right, one, two, three, round
of applause for the crew.
You can come take it if you want.
Thank you, guys.
We love what you do, man.
Thanks, bro.
You're the man.
One more round of applause for
Taylor Rose.
Oh, hey.
Also, that ascension link.
Oh, yeah, it's on here.
Yeah, it's on here.
I just, he's got it off, I think.
It's not a QR.
If you go to this link, don't
share this, please.
Promise.
Yeah, I promise.
Scout's honor.
I have your IP.
I'll find you.
This, I'm going to give you guys
just a playbook.
So this is literally, it's a
10,000.
People pay 10 grand for this.
And you don't have to pay for any
of it.
But I want you to go in more
detail.
Because I need you to change the
world.
If you can get this material, it
makes all of the last five years
for me worth it.
So thank you, guys.
I wanted to, I kind of like that
style.
So I'm going to come on the stage,
keep it casual.
But, I mean, there's not much more
to say at this point.
I think we're all just excited to
get on that boat.
Boats.
But that's really important.
Because you've got to make dials.
And right now it's like 530, 540.
And so we've got to go over there
because it's going to move,
whether you're on there or not.
Sorry.
What was your question?
It was similar to that one.
I was going to say, is it worth it
to incentivize employees with
profit share or equity model?
T2 and T1.
We're dealing with that literally
right now.
T2 and T1, 100%.
Thank you to each of you for
allowing me to just live out our
experience as well.
So thank you guys so much.
You're going to be on the boat.
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.