All right i strategically placed
the open bar right before my
presentation
for a reason so hopefully this
works out um but anyways i got a
hiring master class for you guys
uh number one question i get from
all of you guys in olympia is
essentially how to hire where to
hire from what to do when you hire
someone how to know if they need
to be fired how to know if they
need to be promoted how to manage
them on a day-to-day and so
hopefully i'll cover all the
questions uh in today's
presentation so uh your path to
scale so all day today you heard
from dan
christian and daniel on the
marketing and sales systems that
drive our businesses growth but
those systems only scale as far as
your fulfillment systems allow
them to there's like the biggest
missing piece that i've seen in
any info marketer business or any
business that comes from the money
twitter space is they're really
good at sales and marketing but
they can't figure it on the
fulfillment side and so today
we're going to go over key mindset
shifts you have to make as a
business owner to go from player
to coach why hiring a players is
the ultimate growth lever the
framework
to hire manage and retain a
players and then common hiring
mistakes to avoid
and so first action item this is
going to be like super actionable
i think there's six of these
slides
um the first one is to just get
clarity on where to start so the
first question you might be asking
is
what do i hire for who do i hire
and so to answer this question we
first have to understand why
we as business owners and ceos
need to hire and so the reason you
need to hire is to simply protect
your energy buy back your time so
that the business can scale um and
so that with that said uh we're
going
to spend a couple of minutes
answering and brain dumping on
these first two questions which is
one
what do i currently do in my
business that gives me energy also
known as like what you actually
enjoy
doing in your business and then
two what do you currently do in
your business that drains your
energy and
that you absolutely hate to do and
so just spend a couple minutes
writing those things down all
right evan what do you got bro
uh draining energy definitely
meeting with clients uh vendor
meetings customer support being
vendors
making landing page changes for
the nuance and client copy okay
what do you actually like uh
making content
good ads and honestly like writing
someone like the highlight like
copy assets sweet andy
uh i really don't like managing
support um or like i don't like
doing our conversations
like firing and we're resetting
expectations you just have to hold
someone a little bit more
accountable
i can do it i just don't enjoy
doing it yeah um i don't like that
um something that gives me energy
is i love just building out
operational flows like a lot of
agencies work flows for everybody
just writing content the email
list and things like that solid
solid how about uh jay uh gives me
energy
closing sales okay uh grains my
energy uh fulfillment and just
back and forth yeah just with
clients
pretty much yeah clients are when
like fulfill inside booking
meetings for the clients solid max
you got
you got anything uh uh closing
sales though is uh like a protocol
so they're they're just like take
my money
it's pretty nice making content
hiring and managing people and
people solid awesome well a major
thing you guys said is like client
communications fulfillment getting
on client calls
that's one of the most common
roles that we hire for at the
different companies uh i actually
have
scorecards for and examples for in
this presentation but the reason i
have you guys do this
is because a lot of you go into
the hiring step of this overall
process
not knowing like what to actually
focus on um and hiring takes a lot
of time and effort just like
creating a new offer does and so
you might as well get clarity on
what's worth hiring for
immediately rather than
approaching it having no idea what
you're doing and so uh the five
steps of a
winning hiring strategy and also
keep that list that you guys have
of what you don't like doing
because
those are all the different roles
you're eventually going to hire
for um but the five steps of a
winning hiring
strategy so the first is uh well
the steps to hire management 10 a
players as follows one offer two
traffic three
onboarding four retention and five
expansion so does this sound
familiar to you guys
it's the same thing as selling an
offer hiring someone into your
organization is the same thing
as selling someone your services
and actually fulfilling your
services and i'm going to break
this down
to show you more in depth what
each of those steps actually looks
like and so step number one is you
have to sell the role like you
sell your offer and so here's a
couple of ways on how to hire or
sorry
how to position your job
opportunity as a compelling offer
that actually attracts a players
uh so the first
thing is to create and define your
umbrella vision so this is a
concept i learned from patrick bet
david
your umbrella vision is your
company's overall vision and
mission and the way that you
attract
high level a players into your
organization is to have a mission
big enough whereas someone else's
mission or vision can fit within
that quote-unquote umbrella and so
at client ascension we have this
massive coaching organization that
other coaches that are doing their
own really cool things outside of
our organization with their own
offers with their own coaching
with their own info products
could play a role within our
overall ecosystem which is
basically online education for
business owners
and entrepreneurs and so you want
to have some sort of an umbrella
vision like you as a leader and as
a ceo you have to sell future
talent on where you're going and
what you're building and that has
to
excite them there's also the
reason why elon musk is able to
attract the best talent in the
world
every turn of the way because he's
working on the coolest he's
building rockets and sending
people
to mars and so like that's an
umbrella vision that even if some
person within that umbrella vision
just wants to be a part of
building the rocket or doing the
radars or doing the underground
tunnels
whatever it might be he's able to
attract that talent because his
vision is so big okay the second
is
use a hiring scorecard instead of
a job description and on this
second slide here i'll go into the
next
action item which is going to be
to work on a hiring scorecard
who's familiar with this concept
of hiring
scorecards
just a couple of you guys okay so
hiring scorecard is just a really
easily digestible understanding of
what
you're hiring for uh you see all
the time like these job
descriptions on linkedin uh that
really look
like they're just written by chat
gpt they don't really speak to you
the same way you would skip over
an offer or an ad or a vsl that
just sounds like a bunch of fluff
and so your hiring scorecard
should be approached and written
the same way you'd write your ads
or your vsl um or really just any
of
your content on the marketing side
um my favorite on this entire list
is number three which is designing
a
performance-based compensation
package how many of you guys pay
your guys hourly or base pay only
a lot of you i don't have a single
team member at any of the
organizations
which i think at this point we
have at least over 60 people
working with us that are hourly or
base
only um it's every single team
member in the organization is
performance-based pay the same way
you hire a salesperson and pay
them 10 commissions is the same
way you hire a customer success
person
and i'll get into what that
actually looks like um the the the
next one here is teasing future
leadership opportunities so to
attract an a player you have to
understand that a players like
more
responsibility they like having a
bigger role within the
organization and so you want to
show them
what that could look like when
you're hiring a closer if you feel
like this person can be an a
player
within your organization you
should tease to them that they
could potentially be leading your
entire
team of closers one day and that's
where you want to get them
especially if that's something
that they
show interest in when you ask this
question great example of this is
when we first hired a setter way
back in the day and i asked him
the question of like what is his
future at this company look like
ideally rather than saying he
wanted to go from being a setter
to a closer he said he wanted to
run the
setter's team one day and to me
that was the biggest green flag we
could look for uh and we
hired him and he's still with us
today um and then share team
member testimonials uh just like i
think it's glassdoor is the the
main software and this is like
used in brick and mortar and b2b
it's
kind of old school but like
testimonials work the same way
they do on the uh sales and
marketing
side like show that people enjoy
working for you and your business
and actually use those in the
hiring process
um and then the next uh bonus tip
here is kind of stupid but it
actually does work is get creative
with job titles um this is why
it's kind of hard to answer your
guys questions sometimes because
you're
like i'm trying to hire an
operations manager but like your
definition of an operations
manager might
be way different than mine and
like this scorecard example on the
next slide i i promise you not a
single
person here has one of these roles
which is a cold email systems
engineer like how cool does that
sound
cold email systems engineer like
people get super excited when they
see that as their job title like
they seriously do i had one guy uh
his name is waleed he's in this
role now he's like dude i just
went
from being an engineer to this
this is way cooler instead of
onboarding specialist which was
his original
role so all i did was i changed
the job role to cold email systems
engineer and he had way more
buy-in and
way more excitement about what he
signed up to do at our company and
so uh action item number two you
can't
really do this uh while we're here
because it's going to take a lot
longer than the time we have
um but this is an action item for
you guys to take home with you
which is to create your first
hiring
scorecard can you guys see like
the words on here it's kind of
small decent amount i'll send the
slides
after anyways um but your
scorecard really as simple as uh
there's there's three sections
there's the
mission for the role which is
almost like your hook the core
responsibilities and a detailed
breakdown of what
goes into those and then your
position description and so this
is like the modern take on a job
description it's a hiring
scorecard so the mission for a
list kit cold email systems
engineer again
they're really just an onboarding
specialist it's to minimize churn
and maximize ltv by helping new
users on the done 40 cold email
setup offer get onboarded quickly
and swiftly it goes through all
the
core responsibilities like
minimizing churn daily execution
of team and admin task and then it
goes through the
the description that does a
breakdown of the time the
compensation and then as you can
see there
bonuses and so let's just focus on
compensation real quick we have a
1500 base pay for someone in this
role in addition to the base pay
they get bonuses if you add up all
those bonuses that's an additional
two thousand dollars in bonuses so
they can more than double their
base pay if they were to hit every
single
bonus in any given month which is
super exciting than a player
because they like to be
paid and rated based on the actual
value they provide to your company
and so bonuses that you
can use for an onboarding
specialist or a csm or more of a
cs type role within your company
are
if your churn rates 10 or lower
and you can also tier it so we pay
250 for churn being lower than 10
and then an additional 500 if
churns lower than five percent uh
you heard daniel talk about this
concept
called nrr we compensate them 250
if it's above 90 and 500 if it's
above 95 and so if they were to
hit
all four of those bonuses they
just doubled their base pay and
they're super excited and the
first
time that they hit those bonuses i
promise you it's not the last
because they're addicted at that
point
it's just like a salesperson
getting that first commissions
check and realizing what it
actually
means to go out and close deals
for the company some other bonuses
that we do is average time to
fulfill
and so we pay them a bonus if the
average days for them to launch a
client's campaigns is 10 or less
after the onboarding call so let's
make sure that clients are moving
through the fulfillment system
and that last one is one of my
favorites it's to protect
ourselves against people that
don't
show up on a daily basis it's 250
dollars paid only if you have over
110 county calls completed
and dan i don't know if you went
into this in your presentation but
we do a similar thing with
sales people even rather than just
paying them 10 sales commissions
we tear it they get started right
at seven percent but they unlock
another percent if they have
enough calls on calendar if they
do enough
follow-ups if they're using their
their crm if they're attending
team meetings if they're filling
out the end of day type forms so
whatever actions you want to
incentivize for is what you want
to bake
after so i'll go into the actual
like hiring steps uh the scorecard
itself is only used up into the
point of the position description
the position description is the
thing you pretty much gatekeep
until the very last interview and
i'll go more into what that
interview actually looks like go
ahead
yeah yeah because it stands out
and you can put in like the
description and wherever else in
there
like onboarding specialist or
customer success so it'll still
show up in a search but like
imagine
someone searching for a customer
success role it's like account
executive account executive
account
executive csm csm csm onboarding
specialist cold email systems
engineer it's like it stands out
immediately right it's almost like
a unique mechanism on the
marketing and sales side
um a company that does this really
well that i was doing it before
but it kind of validated
why this works or that it works is
clay you guys familiar with clay
they do uh kind of like
leads list building with
spreadsheets and automations and
integrations type thing go to
their linkedin
profile and look at all the
different people that work at clay
i promise you you've never seen
those
job titles at any other company
they have like gtm engineer gtm
success strategist like you've
never seen
these job titles before and
they've essentially built an
entire brand around it i was
reading a blog post
from clay talking about why
go-to-market engineers are like
the new account executives and
what that's
doing for their growth is pretty
insane they just raised at a 1.25
billion valuation and so the
biggest
companies are doing this not just
uh the ones on money twitter okay
any questions on the scorecard
before
we move on go ahead um so like
this is for the overall company
performance so at the end of the
month i go into our dashboard and
see what the churn rate is and
what the nr is those numbers are
really
easily accessible on the average
days to launch after onboarding
call we have that set up in
hubspot
on a per rep basis easy to check
and then on the last one calendly
it's in the calendly analytics
but the important thing and i'll
go into it more in the rest of the
presentation is don't wait until
the end of the month to show them
their performance you want them to
know their performance at least
on a weekly basis so that they can
do things throughout the month to
improve
anyone else all right we'll keep
it moving okay so the second piece
of it then is traffic right
so the goal of traffic is to get
as many candidates into your
hiring funnel uh one of the
biggest mistakes i
see everyone here including myself
make when it comes to hiring is
you hire someone that you really
shouldn't have hired and the only
reason you do that is because you
didn't have enough candidates
to choose from in the first place
and so if you don't have enough
candidates this is the slide
that's
going to help you fill that
pipeline and so hiring is a
numbers game the same way you need
to send
thousands of cold emails and do
dream 100 outreach you need to
drive traffic using various
channels to
build a consistent pipeline of
potential a players and so here's
kind of like my order of priority
first
place i go to is i ask my clients
my existing team members and close
industry peers for referrals at
this
point i never really have to go
past this first step because i
have so many clients so many team
members and so many industry peers
and i know a lot of you guys have
that as well so it's very rare
that
i even have to move past that
first step the second step if you
don't find your ideal fit or an a
player
through those sources is to post
on your social media in your email
list this is like to me the most
underrated reason for building a
personal brand is to attract a
player quality talent to your
company
it's not to get clients it's not
to you know have authority in the
industry it's to get people to
respect you enough and to look up
to you enough to just want to come
work for you like gary v probably
has dms full of people that just
want to go work for him literally
for free there's people out there
it was me actually a couple years
ago that would drop everything to
just go work for gary v for free
and so that's the type of
authority you're trying to build
through your personal brand
and you could do that through your
email list and wherever wherever
else you've built an audience
if you still can't find enough
candidates the next place to go is
to find niche communities
to share the opportunity with so i
can't tell you how many people
have successfully found an a
player
by posting in client ascension's
opportunities channel that simple
and once you have the offer
right once you have the scorecard
created and you know exactly what
you're hiring for
you can just put it anywhere it's
like the same thing when you have
an offer or vsl or a landing page
it doesn't take much more effort
to send it through cold emails
dream 100
post it on tick tock email your
list it's just you just send it
everywhere uh and so that's
exactly
what you're doing here uh with
finding niche communities to share
the opportunity with
whether it's client ascension or
something else the next step that
i usually like to go to if i still
haven't found enough candidates is
to pay a recruiting agency um my
background is is that my dad is
from
lebanon so i'm lebanese and so
i've found uh this niche uh to
hire from people in lebanon uh
it's really
similar to the amount you'd have
to pay someone in the philippines
or in latin america but i've
just found the quality to be a lot
better and it's also a good
feeling to give back to where my
dad is
from but a lot of people are
having success hiring from lebanon
um including liskin and client
ascension
we have uh almost half our team at
this point is based in lebanon and
they're killers you guys have
probably been on calls with some
of them and i know dylan and alex
as well have uh an a player that i
keep saying i want to poach from
them uh that's from lebanon um
they got to her first
unfortunately
uh if you still haven't found an a
player or enough candidates to at
least go through the interview
process with you you can post a
job on linkedin um again i don't
really like to resort to just
doing
this uh someone here today was
telling me they had success with
this was it you re you put adspend
behind a linkedin post or was it
you guys who who's oh milad yeah
that was you okay so like
i've heard some people having
success with this we even ran five
dollars a day to our account
executive job posting uh for link
for uh for list kit on linkedin
and we got over like a thousand
applicants i don't think we
interviewed a single one of them
um usually if i were to post on
linkedin
i wouldn't use like their quick
hiring process like where you can
do like the easy application like
one
click application you have to do
that setting i'm pretty sure but
what i do is in the description is
i put a
a link to google form and knowing
that most people will not read the
description far enough to see
the google form go to the google
form and fill it out but if they
do they're high intent candidate
that
i should probably look at um and
so you could post a job on
linkedin and put just a couple of
dollars
of spend behind it the same way
you'd run an ad to your offer so
you could literally run ads to
find a
players uh you could post on job
boards so you could go to upwork
you could go to indeed you could
go to
fiverr again this is like scraping
the bottom of the barrel right
again the way i look at this list
is start at the top and and max it
out and if you still don't have
enough candidates move to the next
ring move to the next ring move to
the next ring until you get all
the way down to outbound
recruiting
outbound recruiting is there's not
really a clear definition for it's
where you get creative and so i
remember uh there was a point in
time at list kit when we were
literally looking up prior sdrs
and aes that
worked at apollo and we would
outbound recruit to those specific
people didn't work that well
and you can kind of burn some
bridges and uh piss some people
off doing it just like christian
was
saying happens when you send cold
dms and cold emails but it's kind
of part of the process so
that's uh the traffic part of it
and so action item number three is
to put together uh outreach
messages and so here's some
screenshots of the different
places we've posted our job
opportunities
and a couple of different ways
that we've done it and so this
first one over here is a tweet on
my
account basically saying list
kit's looking to hire a cold email
expert um we're looking to hire an
onboarding specialist that was
before we had a really cool name
for it i probably think uh if we
had cold
email systems engineer in there
would have got even more people to
apply i genuinely believe that
um so that's an example of a post
that you can put on social media
this is another example that
we tweeted from our company page
because client ascension has such
a strong following we're able
to tweet that it got almost 10 000
views on twitter and i think we
hired two closers specifically
from
this post i don't know how they
worked out but we got tons of
applicants um and the different
approach
here is dan actually did a loom
video which works really well um
and so you can test out a loom
video
in addition to just your post um
that top one is i believe that's
in the opportunities channel on
client ascension and then this one
here is in the opportunities
channel on client ascension as
well
that was to hire a student success
coach and that was to hire more a
more aes and sdrs and so
take a minute to craft a message
similar to what you see here
whether it's a tweet or a post in
the
client ascension opportunities
channel to call out uh for your
next hire and any questions on
that feel
free to just throw them out there
can you guys see those all right
that honestly though the best
example on here that's applicable
to you guys is top left
because it's the most fleshed out
and detailed the others we can get
away with because the middle one
has a loom video that explains
more of those things and then the
top one on the right the bottom
one on
the right are just in client
ascension so people kind of know
what those roles uh entail at this
point
go ahead mark
however many it takes so it's not
about how many candidates apply
it's about how many actually make
it through to the interview
process so i'll show you i think
in the next slide the actual steps
of the interview process once
you've sent enough traffic through
um there's not really like a
benchmark
for like i want because like i
said on linkedin we had over a
thousand applicants i didn't look
at a
single one of those applicants
right um but to some of these
tweets we might have gotten five
applicants and we
interviewed all five of them and
then out of the five interviews we
sent you know a couple through to
the next stage and then from that
stage we had a better idea but i'm
usually looking for at least
like just from my own experience
if i follow that process i laid
out and go through each of those
different channels if i get 10
candidates i usually have plenty
to look through
do you both like separate those
things for lebanon or different
countries where you're hiring
um no so if i'm hiring through
like lebanon or through a
recruiting company the nice thing
is they
do all this for you right that's
kind of like the the selling point
of a recruiting agency is you just
tell them what you're looking for
they handle everything so you
don't have to rely on attracting
your own
talent so you only hire recruiting
agencies if you can't get talent
this way or if you want to hire
from a really specific geographic
location that they have way better
access to than you do does that
make
sense okay are we good to move on
anyone still working on this one
we're good all right cool
403 it's already been half an hour
okay uh so my my five-step vetting
process so mark this will go more
into what to do once you actually
get the candidate so again never
settle for mediocre talent it's
like by far the biggest mistake
you can
make in the hiring process is
settling for mediocre talent it
does your your current a players
the
biggest disservice and it does you
a disservice because guess what
you're gonna have to go back and
do it again please please please
if there's one thing you take from
this is never ever ever settle for
mediocre talent um and so the way
you you are safe from ever running
into this being a potential issue
is sending enough traffic right
sending enough candidates through
this vetting process until you
find an a player that you'll go to
your friends and brag about you've
probably heard me brag about and
name drop so many of the different
team members that work at our
companies and i do that genuinely
because i've put candidates uh
through this process and i've gone
through this process to hire
everyone
at the company um and so the the
five-step process is one
application right so the only goal
of the
application is to quickly weed
people out that will save you time
from doing so many interviews so
like
if you have 10 people interested
in the role don't make the mistake
of hopping on 10 interviews
it's probably likely that five of
them will not be worth your time
and you can figure it out real
quick with a google form and i'll
show you some of the applications
we use and and how we use some
strategic questions in there the
second once you've actually put
them through an application and
you
think okay this guy's got
potential let me let me see put
them through a screening interview
screening interview is a cat like
a casual interview 15 30 minutes
uh that assesses culture fit
and the way to assess culture fit
in my opinion is to just ask them
like why do you want to work here
and why do you think you're the
right person for this specific
role those are like the only two
questions i think to ask on a
screening interview and then i see
how easy it is to hold the rest of
the conversation the easier it is
to hold the conversation the
better culture fit that's
literally the only way i think
about it if they make it past the
screening interview which most
people
usually do you give them a
homework assignment the way to
think about a homework assignment
is
it's a test of their skills
relevant to the responsibilities
of the role and so again the
sales the sales examples for
hiring are the easiest in my
opinion because it's like okay for
sales the
homework assignment is mock call
interview you just get them on a
pretend sales call and see how
they do
for an onboarding specialist it
looks a lot different for a
student success coach at client
ascension it looks a lot different
but you want to create scenarios
or projects or questions that they
can work on that are as closely
similar to the things they'll
actually be doing in the
day-to-day and
again i have examples of this that
you guys will look at on the next
slide here if they make it past
the
homework assignment which you'll
actually weed people out at this
point because you're already
asking so much
you had them fill out an
application you had them attend
the screening interview now you're
asking
them to do homework and you're
still not giving them more
information about the role you're
gatekeeping
the compensation the price all
that sort of stuff and so a lot of
people will naturally drop off at
this
point which is the intent of the
actual system that's how it's
supposed to work but if they've
made it
through this is where you do the
scorecard interview the scorecard
interview is i already know i
want to hire this person but let
me make sure they're aligned on
the expectations and the kpis
and all i'm looking for in this
interview is i just walk through
the scorecard on a screen share
and i read it to them and i say
any questions what are your
thoughts on this and i see if
their facial
reaction changes of like oh shit i
have to go on daily calls oh like
no so like you're really analyzing
their reaction to the different
parts of the responsibility to see
is like that's something
that gets them excited or is that
something that kind of is like oh
man i didn't know that was
involved and so all i'm doing on
this call is i'm reading through
and i'm asking them you know for
their
thoughts for their questions if it
still seems like something they'd
be interested in doing and then
the
biggest reveal at the end is time
and compensation once you show
them compensation it's like again
on
a sales call you get the reaction
immediately you get the reaction
immediately it's like they're
either
no like this is not what i thought
it was going to be and it's not
enough pay or wow that's amazing
let's get started how can i get
started it's there's really never
an in-between if there's an if
there
isn't an in-between there's like a
conversation around it which is
pretty easy to navigate but
again the scorecard interview is
just to see like how how excited
they are or how their reaction is
to
everything you're going to be
asking them to do and what the
actual offer is right it's where
you reveal
the offer again it's like the end
of the sales call where you drop
the price the end of the hiring
process
where you drop the actual details
of the role um and at this point
it's very rare that you'll have
you know two or three candidates
that you're super happy with and
torn over as it's been maybe three
or four times in in my career
since we've started these
companies where it's gotten to
this point
which is step five uh which is
optional which is a team culture
fit interview so if i have like
three
candidates and i'm like i just
don't know which one to go with
all three of them could crush it
for these different reasons i've
done the t chart of like this is
good this is bad about each person
i still can't come to a confident
decision and if i can't just hire
multiple of them because sometimes
it's just like well we need two or
we will need two pretty soon so
let's just bring them both on
i'll do a team culture fit
interview um just to do a sanity
check for myself and be like yo
christian
well i never actually do it with
christian no no offense i do it
with someone that's in the
specific department that i'm
hiring that person for and i'm
like no i don't know why i
mentioned
christian no offense to christian
uh but i'll send it to someone
that's either in the role already
or plays a big part in that
specific department and i'll have
them just hop on an interview and
say
let me know your thoughts about
this guy like are you seeing what
i'm seeing like could he crush it
here
or am i crazy um and i'll put all
three or all two of the people
that have made it to this step on
an
interview with someone else on the
team to get their input on it
because a lot of times i'm just
very
tunnel vision and i see something
i like but i'm ignoring all the
red flags right again you can
relate this to to any other
process including selling an offer
go ahead george um
10 to 20 000 what do you mean okay
i'll do like uh what do you call
like a range give them an idea
i have that all the time yeah
right i mean i have that all the
time i do a range and then you
could
also get an idea like some of the
interview questions we ask are
like how much are you making
now and then what are your goals
financially and if their goal is
like i want to make 15k a month
and
it's a two thousand dollar a month
role like i'm going to probably
bring that up sooner because i
don't want to waste my time and
their time going through the whole
interview process just to drop
a price on them that is totally
out of expectation that's
application yeah screening you
don't want
to get into like those types of
questions it's again why do you
want to work here what about this
company excites you and then why
do you think you're a good fit in
this specific role those are the
only
two questions no no i just want
them to have a conversation with
them because they're going to
be working with that person right
so i want them to be able to get
along and and then they also like
your team will really appreciate
when you do this because they feel
like they have a say of who
they're
going to be working with every day
which not many companies give
their own team members like that
you know free reign well yes but
also again it's like how many
hires make it all the way through
to
five right where you don't have
someone you're thrilled with and
there's just one of them
at step four so it's very rare but
it is like a nice thing to pull
out of your back pocket when you
need it i don't think it really
matters entry level or you know
more senior but yes for more
senior
people that might not even be
optional it might be something
that i is i send them through to
five
team members to see their thoughts
on him just like adding on all of
the bad things you're going to
find it anyway so let me just give
it to you right now yeah we'll go
through this whole and waste
everybody's time and money and
things like that so i took that
and then my first interview is
basically
just i'm just having a
conversation yeah i'm having
questions i just want to talk to
them and just see
if they're cool basically but at
the beginning i'll say now let me
talk at you for five minutes
because
they'll probably answer a lot of
questions you have and i'll tell
them tell the reasons they should
not want to work with us and then
the cool things like why they want
to as well but like i don't know
if they're just like you know
you're the person that's hiring
them so they say it's great i
don't know
they actually think it's great but
people are always like wow it's
unique i had like
yeah i like that i like that just
being up front i think it'll save
you a lot of time
so i like that i'm gonna try it
sweet uh use if you had one you're
good all right i'm gonna keep
ripping it just because we're a
little behind but anyways
throughout the interview process
the things
that you want to prioritize are
culture fit potential cognitive
ability which is just how
they perform in a homework
assignment and then their buy-in
the way to assume their buy-in
again
is like are they actually doing
the application with like full
effort long answers loom video
lots
of thought are they coming to the
screening interview on time well
prepared uh with good questions
for you
as well right they always say in
in the hiring process like if they
don't have questions for you
after then it's a red flag uh are
they doing the homework assignment
and then how long after it's
assigned are they submitting it
these are all things you should be
looking for um and then the
scorecard
interview what are their facial
recognition saying about how they
look at the offer when you present
it to them in real time um and so
this is action item four
application homework assignment so
there's
examples of my pre-screening
interview applications there's
examples of post-screening
interview homework
assignments um and then a bonus
here something i like to do that i
would caution you about doing as
well
is intentionally ghost candidates
at different stages throughout the
interview process to test their
buy-in
yeah i feel like a scumbag when i
do this yeah terrible feel like
follow-up perfectly on time great
email and i'll just hold back i
want to email him back so bad but
i just need to test that this is
this is real and then the next
morning follow-up and i'm like
perfect i could finally tell him
that was
a test and he passed right um
there was a story actually of like
someone that went through an
entire
interview process crushed it had
all the signals that he was going
to get hired and he didn't and so
he just
went back to the to the guy and
said hey i thought it was a really
good fit for this
i thought i deserved the role out
of curiosity like why didn't i get
it and he's like you're hired he's
like what what do you mean he's
like you're the only person that
got turned down and asked why
and that's what we're looking for
here and so it's like kind of a
sick thing to do
but if you do it in just like a
simple email
what are you referring to
is that christian is that your
tick tock dm strategy
all right so i mean again you'll
get these slides i don't want to
go too deep into them because i'm
behind um but anyway so how to set
your new hires up for success this
goes into the nitty-gritty
um now that you have uh your
potential a player hired uh it's
actually time to facilitate
the environment for that new
talent to thrive this is again
something i hear all the time is
like
this person sucks they're not
performing i hired the wrong
person and if you dig a little
deeper it's
not always the case it's you have
hired someone that has tons of
potential to succeed to be an a
player
but your environment's not right
uh and so that's also something
that you uh need to think about
facilitating is an environment
where they can thrive um and again
think of this the same way you
think about
onboarding a new client right when
you onboard a new client you don't
ghost them at that point
right you want to be very
intentional about following up and
providing the right information
so get really clear on what are
the next steps what are the
activation points that'll get them
closer to their goals how can you
over deliver along the way and so
how do we clearly map this out we
have an independent contractor
agreement for signing which i'll
give you guys a template for
send a personalized welcome email
with next steps schedule a kickoff
call to get clear on their
goals and personal ambitions that
that second one key you have to
understand their goals and their
personal ambitions because you
need to keep them around the same
way you understand your clients
goals
to book more calls or to generate
new clients or to lower their
churn we're doing the same thing
with our
talent in our team members so
create a company email account uh
invest time in their development
with
one-on-ones and huddles uh
leverage other team members to
shadow their onboarding calls uh
and then
constant check-ins and pulse
checks um and then equip them with
software tools sops and external
trainings one of the things we do
at our companies is we invest in
trainings from let's say cole
gordon
taylor welsh bill walsh to train
our guys on sales they're all
invest in trainings from uh for
example
i i i learned from this guy named
lincoln murphy on the cs side that
uh really helps our cs team at
list
kit drive down churn so i bring in
experts to help train uh and
improve my team's skill sets
the next thing is uh how to test
their readiness now that you put
them through like the typical
standard onboarding procedures
it's time to like i like to call
it baptism by fire you just throw
them
in see how they perform uh and so
we we still want to do this in a
way that follows a due diligence
process and so the steps that i
like to take here is really three
steps i start them off by
shadowing
you or another team member in the
same role doing the work they're
tasked to do so again sales is a
great example if you hired a
closer have them shadow existing
closers to see what those calls
are going
like or if you hired an onboarding
specialist or a customer support
representative have them get on
client calls with your existing
csms or with you if you're the guy
for that um just so that they can
learn and be a fly on the wall um
and they can also watch sops if
you have them or previous call
recordings in this step so the
same way on the sales side you
record your calls and watch them
back
you should be doing the same exact
thing on the cs side you should be
recording every
single call of your clients and
using them in your trainings once
they're shadowing and being a fly
on the wall for long enough um you
can then switch them to doing the
actual work with you on a live
call while either you or again
someone else in the role is still
on the call with them so again
it's
like you ever go to like a grocery
store or the dentist and they're
like this is you know my
associate or this is like a junior
doctor or whatever and they're
basically you know in their first
days
here and i'm watching over them
it's the same thing right like you
can put them in the role and have
someone more senior still there to
look over and make sure that
they're doing a good job right
it's
like having the training wheels on
is the way to think about it once
you do this long enough uh and
when they feel comfortable or even
a little bit before they feel
comfortable right because baptism
by fire we like to throw them in
before they're fully ready have
them do the work themselves and at
this point all you're doing is
call reviews so you send them on
to an onboarding call or a client
call
all by themselves and then have
them send you the the call
recording after and then you can
watch the
call recording back and give them
feedback on how to improve on the
next call and that's really like
the three steps in the beginning
that you actively want to make
sure you're doing and once you
finally
do those three steps it's time to
take the training wheels fully off
and get out of their own way this
is
another problem that a lot of you
guys have is you never do that
final step which is get out of the
way a lot of you guys are babying
your team you're scared to just
let them go off on their own
because
for whatever reason you don't
trust they're going to do a good
job and it's probably because you
didn't
follow structure that i mapped out
leading up to this point um and
then really all you're doing at
that
point it's not like you're just
going on vacation now and you have
no work left to do you're doing
other
things in the business but you're
also monitoring to see if they
need help with anything you're
responsive on slack you're
available for one-off calls you're
reviewing their end of day type
forms
you're getting on weekly team
meetings and so you're still in it
but you're not in their way
and so action number number five
again i've realized that these
things are not like sit down and
do it
here in this room action items at
this point um but drafting an
independent contractor agreement
which
will give you the uh the template
for outline all the software tools
you'll need to give them access to
with the
sops research external trainings
like books podcast courses uh that
you can give them access to
identify existing team members to
help with the onboarding process
and then compile examples of
successful work again on the sales
side when you onboard a closer
give them a folder of 10 calls
that other closers close or if
you're an onboarding specialist
give them calls of other
onboarding
specialists getting really good
feedback from the client at the
end of the call and so you want to
show them what successful work
looks like and it doesn't just
apply to roles that involve calls
either
if you hired a copywriter show
them your 10 best performing ad
creatives or show them your 10
best
performing cold email scripts
because that's the easiest way for
them to learn uh and and know what
works any questions before we
continue because we're getting
into like a lot of detail i think
we got
just just just a couple more
um
so like are they submitting
projects at some point
so yeah yeah so it's almost like a
campaign manager on the cold email
side go set up this client's
campaign with all the details and
sops that i've given you and let
me know when you're done so i can
go
in and check that all the settings
are configured the copy was you
know copy and pasted and formatted
properly the leads list is in
there with the same amount of
leads that i originally gave them
sort of like that yes yeah you
want like a launch checklist for
that type of stuff of like things
to look for right so like again on
the cold email side do the leads
add up to the amount in the
original csv is it titled and
labeled to the right client are
the right email accounts assigned
is the
copy copy and pasted into that
software without any formatting
issues or weird white spaces so
you
could come up with a list of like
things to look for
in the beginning in the beginning
same way you don't review every
single sales call
right but you'll do it ongoing and
by doing it ongoing they know that
any campaign that they work on
could potentially get reviewed and
so they apply the same level of
standard to all of them in case
that
just any one of them gets reviewed
because they don't want to be
exposed right that's what that
does
just because you're not reviewing
all of them doesn't mean they
don't have in the back of their
mind when
they're doing it this might get
reviewed at some point and that's
why you do the reviews it's a big
part of it right
okay so this is one of my
favorites so systems to manage
without micromanaging right
because this
is one of the biggest pain in the
next is when you hire a bunch of
people and you're just running
around micromanaging all of them
it's like you're almost doing more
and more annoying work than you
were
doing before and so first off the
reason for the performance based
compensation structures
the reason they're so great is
because they make it so you almost
never have to micromanage
the only reason you have to
micromanage is if they're not
doing things that are adding value
but
if they're compensated on adding
value they're going to do those
things naturally because they want
to get
paid right not just because you
want them to but you can also do a
couple of other things to manage
and
improve performance ongoing so one
of those is having mandatory end
of day type forms which we'll
get into weekly team meetings
where you review kpis call reviews
or like george was asking review
their
work whatever that looks like to
find their work or their
deliverables and review those and
then
implement a pip when necessary a
pip is a performance improvement
plan the the times to implement
those
are when kpis are being missed
they're not showing initiative and
there's other red flags that come
up that you guys could probably uh
you know know when to implement a
pip but what a pip looks like is
just getting clear on exactly why
and when and what they're
underperforming on creating a
30-day improvement
plan with them and then making a
real effort to help them that's
like one of the most important
parts
of a pip is like we're in this
together type of vibe it's not
like i'm disciplining you because
you suck
and you're underperforming turn
around or you're gone it's like
you're underperforming but i want
to help
before i just let you go and that
does a lot that can turn around
underperformers and put them back
on track to being an a player or
what a pip does really nicely is
it almost forces people out
without
you having to have like andy was
saying the awkward conversation
firing someone a lot of people
will
just leave after something like
this and so uh here's some
performance tracking tools that
you guys can
go through and implement uh on
your on your trips back home so
number one is end of day type form
in my
end of day type form i've tested
so many different ways of
structuring these things but the
best
structure i've ever come up with
for this uh is the following four
questions here's what i did today
here's what i'm currently working
on here's what i need help with
and here's how i'd rate my day and
why
four questions and let them fill
in for whatever they feel they
need to fill in for that day
and then all you're doing is
you're setting up a type form
automation into a specific slack
channel
and you're reading through all
their responses and you're seeing
what did they do today you can ask
questions on that what do they
need help with you can provide
help right there in slack what are
they
currently working on you can see
if they're working on the right
things and if not you can court
you
could course correct and then
write their day maybe someone put
two out of ten day rating because
they got bad news from a family
member dan touched on the
importance of also checking in
with your
team not just in the business
realm but also from a personal
side of things because you're
working with
humans at the end of the day um
the next one here schedule weekly
team meetings with proper notes so
a lot of you are doing team
meetings but you have no idea what
to talk about there's no structure
you lose
control people are talking over
you and it almost feels like you
just wasted 30 minutes and so the
easiest structure to follow for
team meetings is start with wins
set the set the vibe um get you
know the
culture right get people excited
and then go into kpi updates the
kpi updates on team meetings
should
align with how that specific team
is paid on the performance based
side of things so if if we flip
back to that scorecard example
earlier on when i do weekly team
meetings with my cold email
systems
engineers i update them on churn
rate nrr average days to launch
and how many calendar calls
they've
completed so far this month so
they know exactly where they're at
in relation to their bonus at any
point in the month and again if
they're off track they can course
correct right so uh that's the
weekly
team meeting structure and then
action for you guys there's almost
a hundred percent chance that
there's
an underperformer on your team
right now that you need to pip and
so pip them right uh really simple
have a
written agreement with
expectations conduct weekly
one-on-ones and if you don't see
any improvement
fire them fast and move on if you
don't fire someone that's
underperforming not only are you
not getting your money's worth
from that person but you're
creating a cancer within your
organization
because the last thing an a player
wants is to show up to work and be
surrounded by people that
have lower standards than them and
the last thing they want in a
leader is someone that doesn't
hold those
standards and allows for
underperformance they'll lose
respect for you and i'm going to
get into
uh a slide next that goes into you
as a leader and how you're
supposed to show up um but i kind
of
hit on it right there and it's so
important like you have to fire
people that are underperforming
you do it in a way that's
respectful right and you do it in
a way that you at least gave them
a chance
to get back on track so it's a lot
easier of a conversation because
it's not abrupt and it's not
surprising at that point but don't
delay that decision because by
delaying the decision you're
having a
negative impact on your culture
you're losing respect as a leader
and your a players are starting to
think of
going elsewhere because they hate
showing up to work and not being
surrounded by other a players
so one last slide and then we can
do q and a i think sorry two more
slides shit uh how to keep your a
players producing forever um same
way again you want to keep your
clients forever you want to keep
your
clients paying forever you want to
keep your a players not just on
the team but continuing to
produce right there's kind of like
a drop off after the beginning
phase like the honeymoon phase
you hear about this in the
relationship world right how do
you continue the honeymoon phase
forever
so on a hiring side a players need
growth opportunities they need
recognition they need
performance-based incentives and
once you identify the a player in
your organization
it's time to invest significantly
more time to develop them into a
leader for your company
don't wait right i think gary vee
has a saying where it's like hire
fast fire faster but promote
faster or promote fastest and so
like when you see that someone's a
killer and an a player
the ways to identify those people
is they're self-sufficient they
exceed kpis they take initiative
but beyond the specific
responsibilities you assign to
them they're proactive in solving
problems and helping
the team and they're willing to
push back on your ideas it's the
one people hate it's the one we
hate
because we have big egos you show
up to a team meeting you present
this idea that you think is
sick and then your guys are like
that's not going to work it's like
that's what you are looking for
a players are willing to speak up
and push back on your ideas a
players are not the ones that
just think every idea and
everything that you say is right
and amazing because they're just
pandering
to you those are not a players a
players can think for themselves
because what's going to happen
when
you're gone you're not in the
day-to-day and they need to think
on their own and lead another team
you want them to be able to come
with their own ideas again it's
not the greatest feeling when you
when you have this but if you
think about it this way you'll
actually be happy when you hear a
team
member push back on your next idea
and so then how to retain them now
that you have identified them
get clarity on their career goals
and how you can help them get
there number one most important
whether
it's financially whether it's uh
where they want to live whether
it's the type of work they want to
do
the work schedule whatever it is
get clarity on those goals help
them get there through the role
that you have them in uh spend way
more one-on-one time with them
right i feel like most of us spend
way more one-on-one time with our
underperformers trying to get them
back on track and by doing so we
neglect the overperformers but we
really should be flip-flopping
that and spending all of our time
with the guys that actually
deserve our time and so spend way
more time with your a players uh
give
them shout outs and recognition uh
paint a future vision for where
this company is going right you
want to get them excited that
they're investing their time in
their career and a leader that's
actually
going somewhere this this company
is not just you know existing for
a couple of months and then it's
going to fall off the map and
you're going to go do something
else like show them a long-term
vision
and then give them upside upside
can come again through
performance-based incentives but
it could
also come through promotion
opportunities upgrading them to an
actual leader within the company
and so
many other things so quick action
items here identify at least one a
player and promote them to being a
player coach this makes sense uh
if you have like let's say three
or four onboarding specialists
promote one of those onboarding
specialists to be a player coach
meaning they're still an
onboarding
specialist but they're also
coaching and leading the other
three onboarding specialists so
it's almost
like a trial role that eventually
then leads to them becoming a
full-time leader uh if you guys
are
in client ascension most of you
are uh you know andy who's a
student success coach andy was one
of four
student success coaches and over
time i identified andy as an a
player because of all these
reasons and so
i told andy look i have a vision
for you long term to run the team
of student success coaches is that
something you'd be interested in
yes okay cool so i start working
on that idea and i eventually
make him a player coach he stays
student success coach but then
he's also getting on one-on-ones
checking in update type forms
running team meetings and managing
the entire team of student success
coaches which frees up my time for
managing four people to only
manage one person make sense
and then that second one is to
create a wins channel in slack
create a wins channel on your
slack
internally right when your team is
out there doing really cool things
for your company a lot of times
it gets swept under the rug no one
sees about it no one cares about
it and they feel underappreciated
create a wins channel and
encourage your team to post in it
and when they do go crazy with the
slack
emojis people love that people
love that yeah
i'm
i love it all right one more slide
and then we could get into q a
um so again this all falls back on
you being able to step into a
leadership role right so
the question becomes how you can
become a better leader and so i
heard this recently and this was
like the best this is like the
best leadership tip i've ever
heard and it was about donald
trump
and patrick bet david was
basically describing like what
donald trump has essentially
turned into
recently i don't know who's a fan
of trump who's not but i think
you'll resonate uh with what
patrick bet david calls trifecta
mode he's talking about this from
a leadership perspective
donald trump has achieved trifecta
mode he's currently in trifecta
mode which means he's respected
he's feared but at the same time
he's liked and he's got all three
of those things a lot of us just
want to be liked and so when we
just want to be liked we're not
telling our underperformers that
they
need to step it up and we're not
pipping them we're not firing the
people that shouldn't be on the
team
anymore because we want them to
like us we're not feared because
we're not we're not expecting and
actually holding the team
accountable to the standards that
we've set and so all the things
that i'm explaining to you guys is
so that you can get into trifecta
mode where you're respected as a
leader you're feared as a leader
because they have no idea what
you're gonna do or if they don't
do
certain things they're they're
scared to tell you right i've had
team members tell me this and it's
not
a great thing to hear all the time
but part of it knowing that i'm i
ear on the the side of being liked
a lot more but like when they get
a dm from me they're kind of
scared to open it they're like
oh shit what's what's andre gonna
yell at me for this time and so
like that that's good feedback
because i again i i over index i'm
being liked and so to hear that it
means yeah i'm starting to be
more like a leader who's feared
but at the same time is still
liked right so if you can achieve
trifecta mode you can run up a
massive organization with a ton of
a ton of a players working for you
and so
how you show up for your team sets
the standards this is also what
culture is and so three things
model the behavior you expect show
up early leave late do what you
say you're going to do over
communicate always take
responsibility constantly level up
by investing time into training
right all of
you guys as business owners go
back to your teams on monday and
and tell them about the training
that
you receive right if you go
through training they're going to
be more motivated and excited to
go
through training if you just
assign them a bunch of training
and you don't go through any
training
yourself it's kind of it's
backwards you want to model the
behavior right that you expect
from them so
you're here for training there you
go talk about it step into the
challenges to squash uncertainty
and inspire a great example of
this dan and i reference each
other a lot in our presentations
because it's really the same topic
it's just for two different
departments but like a great
example
of squashing uncertainty and then
also using the opportunity to
squash uncertainty to also inspire
is when dan put himself back on
calendar when sales are low or
close rate decrease to prove that
it's not
a lead quality issue it's a skill
issue or a mindset issue or a
behavior issue it's just not a
lead
quality issue because dan was able
to go back on calendar and close
at the rate that they were
previously closing at so there's
something else here and again it
squashes uncertainty the
uncertainty
about the lead quality and it also
inspires them to see that they
have a leader that's willing
to get back into the trenches with
them and do the work and then the
last one is be proactive and
direct as a leader you have to be
proactive and direct so set clear
expectations and actually hold
your team accountable to getting
the results and doing these things
and then address issues
immediately
before they become bigger problems
the last thing you want to get
caught up you know spending your
time
in is drama and you can do this by
just squashing and solving and
addressing issues immediately when
they
come up and not letting them go on
any further but again the entire
goal is to get into trifecta
that's why he's such an effective
leader at a time he was only fear
he wasn't respect he wasn't
like but now at this point in
history he's hitting all three of
those boxes which is why you're
seeing
such like a euphoric reaction to
where we're at as a country and
how he's approaching this new
administration and you guys can
achieve that same thing within
your businesses and so that's all
we made it to
the end uh thank you sweet all
right uh we got time for questions
still
um yeah if anyone has questions we
can do it
yeah well i wouldn't create a
powerpoint and teach them anything
because the trainings for you as
the
business owner and so it usually
doesn't trickle down to them in
their specific role it's more so
again like a
a respect thing of like okay
george asked me to do something
but he also is out there doing it
and so
i respect this guy right um and so
with training i would simply just
document the fact that you're
coming out here like tell your
team like hey this weekend i'm
traveling uh to florida to go meet
with
these guys that have consulted and
helped us grow to this certain
point um they're actually the
reason
i've hired a lot of you guys and
so i'm excited to see you know
what their next level of learnings
is for
this business um and if you have
any questions on what i learned
feel free i'm you know i have my
doors open that's it that's the
extent of it they just need to
hear it right um i think a lot of
uh
entrepreneurs and business owners
fall into the trap of like they
share their lifestyle on social
media
a little bit too much and their
team sees that and they're like
what is this dude doing out at the
club
every night on a tuesday or he's
in dubai and then he's in europe
and then he's not even working he
can't be and it's like no one
wants to work for that person they
want to be that person right
essentially
but if they see you hustling and
grinding and you know investing
back into the business and its
growth
they're going to respect you a lot
more so i gatekeep a lot of what i
do in my personal life
for that reason because i've heard
horror stories um and it's not
like i do that stuff for the most
part but
uh you you have to you have a
higher level of responsibility if
there's a summer in a year
to the point where you have to
really like watch your everything
how long do you usually post like
tv for do you keep it 30 minutes
right max 30 minutes
now if you can't get it done in 30
minutes you're not you're over
over complicated the only reason
you can't get it over 30 minutes
is there's either too many people
on there which means you need to
teach the meetings down further by
department or you're not meeting
frequently enough so there's
a build-up of things that need to
get talked about because you're
waiting once a month or once every
couple weeks prior than we did and
do you pay the team out at the end
of the month yeah last friday
of every month that's what i do
and how do you pay them out like
how do you pay them out ach uh it
depends where you're located so we
really just use wise.com which is
like a direct deposit ach bank
wire
or from our bank account without
fees don't pay them after fees pay
them the full amount to take on
the fees
so you said you uh listen to the
calls initially a lot and then
once they're in the zone you kind
of just do it
incrementally so that they think
that they can check in time do you
if somebody's doing well would you
still give their uh yeah yeah so
like and it doesn't just have to
come from you right so like this
week
the theme and uh our onboarding
specialist team was called reviews
i didn't do a single call
review and i i should have because
again model the behavior to expect
but the point i'm trying to
make is the entire team was doing
call reviews so we had four
onboarding specialists i told them
all
the week we needed send three of
your recent calls that you're
really proud of and then you think
the other
guys on the team to learn from and
then everyone else would review at
least two other calls and so
they're doing that so all week in
slide they're getting messages and
threads and things about feedback
from the calls and the team is
hyping each other up at this point
which is feeding into the culture
so it could be a peer review not
necessarily it doesn't always have
to be from you
right because it could also serve
as training for someone else and
again part of the call review
process is to show them that
you're watching right because they
talk about character character is
what
you do when no one's watching not
everyone has you know the best
character and so what are they
doing
if you're not watching and we're
doing certain things are they
slacking off right like you're
telling me
not to expose you but like your
work mentality is like are they
reviewing how many hours you're
logging
and all this sort of stuff like
probably we've got a lot more
value if they did right so
same thing that's like what enough
to do
i probably do get this a lot going
when you know is that in the right
time to hire someone
when um
i think the right time to hire
someone is when you can't scale
any further
number one like when you have the
fear of like oh i should i pick on
another client at this point
i don't have capacity for this or
when you're doing the role to a
lesser quality than the client
would
expect simply because you're time
restricted so like if you're doing
fulfillment you're doing the media
buying and at this point you're
just doing it for so many clients
you can't like in your head to
process all the different
strategies that you can go into
plus all the other stresses that
come behind your
business so that when you show up
and do your app creative it's half
you know it's half after
it's just not standard you can
expect that's when you need to
hire it's when the quality of work
finishes because of the time for
the sprint that's a big part of it
i don't know a quick question uh
do you ever feel like you're not
firing people enough
oh yeah all the time yeah all the
time how do you is there like a
way to think about that one
because i
kind of i did fire people enough
really i'm not doing it more often
but still if i don't fire somebody
for long enough
i kind of get like this feeling
about a whole few people in that
place because there has to be like
financial or how to tell for a
number it has to be a lot of what
we're doing so you're like
probably requiring somebody or
like i don't even think about it
so well i mean i guess it depends
it's different on the css side we
hire so rarely yeah on the
customer success side because of
this budget
constraints um and also we usually
need more people than we don't
yeah like we have the issue with
not having
enough calendar availability for
an onboarding call so yeah like
there's other performers that i
wanted to fire during that time
but couldn't simply because
capacity issues which is a hiring
problem
so the way you solve that problem
is you just go back to the certain
presentation you do the process
over
you you're usually not firing
someone because the limiting
belief or like the belief that you
can't go and
find another person to replace it
yeah so like go find more talent
you that's the best way to do it
it's like you have someone you
really want to hire but you can't
because it's a role during build
you're going to go and find out
who fired as soon as possible
because you want to make room for
that
next person so better hire your
funnel fire more often but i still
think you need to pit and you also
need to
get you need to give them a chance
to potentially be in a different
role so like for example we just
hired someone like three months
ago i listed it like a customer
support person and i thought she
was
doing great she's awful uh and so
i got on a call to to fire her
because it was like at the point
where
she was and still in a curve um
and she just brought up the point
like she she feels like she can
still
have value but in a completely
different role and she explained
really logically why she didn't
perform
because she doesn't get well
stressed she doesn't do well
thinking on her feet but she would
be really
good at organizing things and
doing operations and so i it was
like a a light bulb moment like i
wasn't
wrong to hire this person just in
the wrong role and so i moved her
into uh an operations uh assistant
role or q able so this is elisa
who works with us at list kit and
so she's amazing she's like to me
the
most valuable team member i have
this has just been a week in this
new role and all she does is she
like
goes for all the meetings looks at
the notes looks at the action
items make sure the person that
got
assigned to that action item gets
followed up with throughout the
week to make sure that it got done
and if it
doesn't get done she reaches up to
the person that they need help
from to get it done and so she's
just keeping things organized
across slack hubspot trello my
email she's essentially like an
executive
assistant and i just had her in
the wrong hole and so that's a big
part of it too
um i have a question relating to
like fire and morale so like uh as
you know there's something on
Thursday but i'm trying to give
another person on a hip that's
like going to fire the next couple
weeks
back to back people there so i'm
curious how do you approach the
organization holistic things like
i can tell the pc team like hey
this person's doing it for yeah so
this might help yeah sometimes
you really are asking too much
sometimes your performance as i
said are unrealists
and so you should ask your team
then like hey by the way i i i
fired this person for this reason
and now i'm
not going to fire this person for
this reason help me out here guys
is five percent turn unrealistic
okay it is okay okay i understand
let's move it to seven and a half
percent and go from there and so
i've
done that sometimes i'm like i'm
so anxious to get turned down so
low that i set it to the point
where it's
number of those and that has a
negative effect because now
they're like honey can you try at
this
point because there's no chance to
get it yeah all right so that
could be a part of the problem too
like check yourself in any event
that it is realistic and what
those people needed fired then how
do you
communicate that organization
around you still have that
conversation so that they can see
that you're not
unreasonable person yeah right
you're inviting them into the
conversation like you're basically
telling them to tell you why
you're not wrong to fire that
person rather than you explaining
to it
explaining it to them on the call
you see what i mean like get them
involved in the conversation
okay and then it's like an open
dialogue yeah you need different
departments and everything
like when something happens on the
snail side yeah i don't tell my
team like i don't know if you do
that but no i think after i fire
people if you bring it the right
way they kind of fire the main
guys
as long as we don't be strong like
yeah because we're always wrong
we're having this if you watch
that let's get it and just once
again we're here hey guys this is
what happened this is why i feel
a lot of you're working here but
you guys are all here we're not at
the top of a underperformance so
you guys all want to integrate and
put up 10 percent of this month
and then you're like okay cool
like i'm hard to like improve
where like the standards i would
i'm still here so i'll keep you
that standard real time so you're
reassuring that if you're okay
like it's not you just george's
lost my growing fire experience
like no the companies will be in
the right direction you guys are
still
there for a reason this is the
standard let's keep building okay
unless the company's done i mean
it's right you're growing right
yeah we're growing okay we can go
faster there you go
so if you fire them you'll fire
them no i get the whole team on a
closet
yeah that'd be like why you stop
you've only done that once for
like a rep salesman you put the
you put the trump and
you put it on in too far yeah
right uh just in a minute so if
you fire them do you get them like
next week yeah yeah yeah yeah oh
it's good that's what you're
renting too usually usually
because there's a lot of cleanups
yeah uh if they're terrible then
you can just try to just get them
off immediately if it's mutual but
i would always give 14 days and
usually go on 14 days even if
they're not good because you just
need
the extra body there temporarily
so it buys you 14 days to go find
a replacement even if they're not
great
at least you guys don't have to
step back into the room so
if they're like excited about
what's going on yeah um
not yet right not yet
yeah it's been like yeah three of
course correct yeah it's been
before five weeks
so kind of treats
just talk about the go after the
approach it's like okay we're
running this we're gone i'm new to
this
like big boy grandparent right
because this is someone that you
build but i've been up trust
at this point like look i've been
running the show one-handed show
i've not really hired a lot of
people yet but
we just now have a realization
that this is something we can
really learn from people right the
people
around me really smart people that
i get consulted with training from
are telling me that this thing has
huge potential so we've got to
really walk in because i don't
want to miss out and it's one
time opportunity and so that means
things are going to be around a
lot a little different here north
forward right we can still have
our phone we can still you know
have this culture but let's
identify hey guys the things that
we're going to come to and make
sure we get done and so now you're
you've just created an opportunity
in a window where you're going to
slightly change behavior
with an actor where you support i
mean that sounds like actually
what happens like at the beginning
you're not running it the other
thing now you're like oh shit like
i gotta i gotta strap in and take
this thing way more serious
explain it that way to them and i
think from there you can slowly
change
your behavior a little bit and the
way you think about changing your
behaviors if you see something
that they did that you don't like
that you might have called out
before but you just didn't
like do it this time or if they
say something on a meeting that
you like laugh at but you're
thinking you're in my life like
say that right so when you get
those feelings of like i want to
say
something what i'm not saying
that's all that and it's not even
we talked about this in my
relationship
around too right that's how you
should show them your relationship
so anyone else i do um um
okay so real line overall and just
be a specific part of the one on
the shoe back and then assign the
other part of someone else well
you can't just bring them on
overlap and that would just help
you to
see how you're performing so you
gotta go to the existing person to
say where you're ever performing
why you think they're performing
or you guess there's a possibility
to open up the door for
the other person behind and you
know what you just set up right
here yeah so what's that where the
main role is and then i saw that
okay she also has time to like
make it higher because she's been
being involved yeah or just i mean
try to approach her career have
you tried to push her career have
you
told her that the quality checks
aren't good yeah okay you can try
to approach her career like what
to look for
okay so go based off of that just
have to read that again like i had
someone in the wrong role
and she was just not happy with
the specific responsibility she
was doing that and just
re-focused her to nothing else
that's okay too but maybe like the
quality checks is something that
you
you can't i try to limit them i'm
not going to pay a show for the
project you can you can i don't
like to
because that sets the standard
like again if you go back through
the presentation like what is an a
player right an a player how can
we identify them they exceed cave
guys they take initiative beyond
the
specific responsibility right so
if it's a player they're happy to
do as long as it doesn't become
like the standard without some
formal conversation around look
the role is different than what
you
originally signed up for and
therefore pay is going to be
different right usually they'll
get a quick
project that fits into their skill
setting and help the overall team
or help them or help you or help
the company they'll happily take
it on and run with it and you can
decide to notice them or you can
just
point to how it gives them a
better chance in the performance
and he's happy to do it and i
actually i think people were still
going to want to give them that
and that was my fear like i don't
want to have to be the president
or whatever you can ask him to do
this why do you do that because
you want to be like maybe that's
like three month project three
times probably yeah five percent
but
even just saying that without you
know thinking about it and going
through a problem i've done this
before and i'm like i don't you
know i want to be like oh that's
awesome right but that that's kind
of
worth the fact and it's not saying
you can't pay that for it if it's
a size of a project that's going
to
take them away from their core
responsibility sure uh but yeah
don't just assume you have to pay
for
any additional things you ask them
to do because again a player to do
things beyond the scope
go ahead do you like allocate a
certain amount of margin to um
fulfillment and to continually
yeah
um but that kind of also changes
the scale you're going to pay more
now then you will look later but
if you don't pay more now you'll
never get till later right so like
you almost have to pay like
an initiation degree like you have
to pay for a team that's more
expensive than how much revenue
you're currently building or
building for um to get to the next
revenue tier so there will be
times
when you go on a harness where you
bring people in where your margins
don't look that good but it's not
variable to as you're ready to
grow those costs that will fall in
73.
they're what allows for the
increase
so it comes first the investment
comes first before you so don't
play too much in the margins
well i think uh we're out of here
now that's why
we have all the rest of today
first of all thank you guys for
being here
this is a great group um we had a
lot of fun with this harbor just
because we could get
way more of the weeds with so many
content uh get some q a going but
anyway we got dinner at 6 30
and then we have scars uh after a
night bridge so i hope to see
everyone there continue the
questions
and conversations throughout the
rest of the day uh but go get some
staff time to support them