Hey there, guys.
My name's Andy.
I'm the head of client success
inside of Client Ascension.
Today, I'm going to go over how to
hire your customer success
manager.
If this is the first time you're
ever going to do it, this is going
to be a comprehensive guide
and more of a strategic kind of
framework of basically how to do
it properly and how to do it most
effectively.
If you are on the path of now
making your first hire or maybe
your additional hire to your
client success team,
you're probably making the biggest
step towards making the most ROI
you possibly can out of any
employee
that you can possibly imagine.
CSMs are kind of like really the
core pillar in terms of your
fulfillment for your clients
and bring in the highest amount of
ROI returns.
You're talking six figures a year,
potentially.
If you can hire properly, if you
actually follow this framework and
make the right steps.
So, the data is clear.
73% of CSMs' hires fail within the
first 18 months.
I actually see this more commonly
across a lot of businesses.
I see a lot of guys hire customer
success managers in most
businesses
and they don't actually hire a
customer success manager.
They end up hiring basically an
overpaid customer support rep.
There's a big difference between
having someone to just remove
yourself from the client-facing
aspect in your business.
A lot of founders just want to get
away from the client-facing.
It's very time-consuming.
But you cannot replace that with
someone who is inadequate in terms
of skill set
and someone who is basically a
pretty face or a nice guy.
You need someone who's actually
going to drive results for your
clients.
So, it's a critical hire to make
and you need to understand the
principal reason of someone who
lacks both client success
management experience
or business acumen in your
industry or your niche or your
service.
You're just setting yourself up
for absolute hell.
You're just going to have to
double train them on so many
different aspects.
You're going to have to train them
to be a good CSM.
then on your business and your
service.
That's just a nightmarish kind of
situation.
I really do not recommend it.
This is kind of like my experience
across the board.
If you can find a CSM, this would
be ideal for your first hire is
someone who has client success
manager experience
and someone who has knowledge
experience in the space and the
service or the product that you
serve.
That is an absolute winner.
That is what you're absolutely
looking for.
Depending on your business, that
could be quite tricky.
So if you can get someone with
client success management
experience, amazing.
They're going to be way more
effective in a much faster period
of time
because it's much easier to have
the actual frameworks and
understanding of being a client
success manager
but then just having to learn the
business knowledge.
However, if you're taking someone
who has just standard business
knowledge
but needs to learn the client
success management actual role
itself,
you're going to be in for a much
longer kind of period.
I wouldn't typically take someone
in that role
unless they have a really solid
experience in the business
because then they're going to have
a faster ramp-up period
but they would really need a good
like year or two under their belt,
have done something in the role,
really understand your business
and that would be come down to the
vetting process like for that
individual person
and I'll show you some kind of
frameworks of how you can do that
a little bit later on in this
video
but that's essentially what you
kind of want to establish here.
If you can nail these two here,
CSM experience and business
knowledge,
you're in for a winner.
It'll be like two to four weeks
until they start really at the
ground running.
Yeah.
But yes, anyone with no prior
experience in either field, just
never hire them.
You will, yeah, you're going to be
a long, long period of time
until you really get them up and
running.
It's going to be a really negative
ROI.
I'm not even talking about the
investment in terms of training
them.
I'm talking like a client's
journey as well.
So there's a learning curve with
being a really good, airtight
client success manager.
It takes experience.
It takes interpersonal skills.
It takes someone who actually can
be quick on their feet.
They have good communication
skills.
They have the ability to be
multitasked.
They have the ability to wear
multiple different hats across the
business.
Again, this is especially if you
service like multiple different
types of business types.
You know, it's not the same as
like an account manager for
e-commerce, right?
I really want to get that clear.
Sometimes account manager and
client success manager can
sometimes fall into the same kind
of category.
They're not.
Account manager is there to just
kind of manage like certain
accounts that are the same niche,
same service, same business model.
Like it's very repeat and
re-rinse.
It's very heavy on fulfillment.
Account managers actually do a lot
of like done-for-you work.
Client success managers don't.
Client success managers are there
to make sure that your actual
client is adopting to the product,
to the service.
They're using it.
They're making sure that they're
getting an ROI out of it.
That is the important difference
there.
Just so you know.
Again, with client success
managers, having sales experience
is just invaluable.
If you don't have to train someone
in sales, you're in for an
absolute winner.
That's not always going to be the
case.
Getting people with sales
experience can be a bit tricky.
But I mean, even if it's something
as simple as they cold called,
they did door-to-door sales,
you know, even if they worked in
something even like retail or
something,
as long as they kind of understand
how to kind of like motivate
people to purchase a product,
that's okay.
But actual sales experience like
closing, setting, amazing.
If you can, you're on to a serious
winner because sales is actually a
massive part of client success
management.
So your interview kind of
framework here, you know, you kind
of want to kind of go through this
in like pre-interview kind of
requirements.
You ideally are looking for
someone with some sort of
experience, minimum of kind of two
years.
One year is going to be generally
fine.
Again, the business human can
match up to that, but that's fine.
But any experience whatsoever is
going to be solid, especially if
it's something in a similar agency
model that is your own.
Whether that be an info product,
an e-commerce agency, a content
agency, cold email agent agency,
whatever, funnels, whatever it
might be, right?
But yes, and then you're also
going to want to like demonstrate
it like that they have some sort
of metrics of like client
retention or expansion.
That would be fantastic.
And then experience in not just
like SaaS platforms and CRM
systems, but if they have some
sort of tech background in
general,
that would be also really
important because there is a
little bit of tech involved when
there is when it comes to customer
success management.
And then, you know, communication
skills is really important.
Avoid these red flags, like people
saying I have people skills, like
that's great.
But what specifically, like client
success management is really about
the specifics of what your skills
really look like.
If they don't have any metrics, if
they don't have any outcomes, but
they're claiming they have client
success management skills, they're
probably lying.
Customer service experience is not
the same as client success
management experience.
Someone who was a rep in the
company is not the same.
So just nil void that.
And those sort of things as well.
So successful CSM candidates
demonstrate a strong combination
of technical ability, strategic
thinking, and client relationship
management skills.
That's kind of the core of the
role.
And their application should
reflect some sort of specific
accomplishment and metrics to
showcase their impact on client
retention and growth.
And be aware of candidates who,
again, people, you know, people
pleasers, people, persons, people
skills.
It's like you could get yourself
kind of caught into a bit of a
weird situation with those kind of
folks.
It's like because client success
management, you can't exactly be
like, oh, I'm your friend.
And you're trying to make, you
know, people pleas in this sort of
role.
It doesn't work.
So here's like a 60-minute
interview kind of structure that I
have.
You know, your first one to 15
minutes, you just kind of kind of
could do a business knowledge
assessment.
You kind of want to evaluate their
understanding of your business
model, your industry, your
challenges, the competitive
landscape.
Strong candidates will have
researched your companies early.
That's how you really identify an
A player.
An A player knows your business,
your competitors, your market.
They've done their due diligence.
They've done their research.
Because an A player isn't going to
settle for no one.
And if they're going to be an A
player, they're going to come in
with all of their ducks in a row.
Come very well prepared.
That is the strongest indication
that you're actually going to be
speaking to someone who is in it
for the long run and is looking
for somewhere where they can
really grow.
So first 15 minutes, you just want
to get some experience.
What do they know?
What do they not know?
What their experience is in the
past?
Then you want to give them some
scenario-based problem-solving
skills.
It's like, you know, present
real-world client situations and
assess their problem-solving
approaches.
Because that is like 80% of the
job is problem-solving on a
constant basis.
And like, how do they communicate
that problem?
How do they strategize the
problem?
What's the kind of, how do they
balance the, you know, the
client's needs and the business
needs?
You know?
And then it's going to be like an
experience deep dive.
Probe specific examples from their
past work to demonstrate
competence.
You know, you want to see like,
how do they manage client
retention strategies, expansion
techniques, and conflict
resolution?
These are all really important
aspects of client success
management.
And then finally, like the last
couple of minutes, that's when you
can just kind of evaluate.
Like, they're going to be a
culture fit.
Client success managers have to
blend in all areas of your
business.
They're going to be talking to
your sales team.
They're going to be talking to the
fulfillment team.
They're going to be talking to
you.
They're going to be talking to a
lot of team members.
You have to make sure that they
actually are a good fit for your
business as well.
This isn't just like the web dev
guy in the back who doesn't really
talk.
This is someone who's going to be
bouncing around, talking to a lot
of different people, being a part
of a lot of different meetings.
And oftentimes, like the client
success manager is a guy that has
to play devil's advocate in this
situation.
Because they're the voice of the
client.
Like, no one knows the client's
pulse of the business just as much
as the founder is the client
success manager.
Like, they know what clients they
like.
They know what they don't like.
They know what results are there
that clients want to meet.
So, you know, you have to make
sure that this is a person that,
like, fits into that team across
the board.
So, this is a structured approach
to gather some comparable data.
Here's some CSM questions that I
usually typically use when I'm
interviewing a CSM.
And you really kind of want to,
like, really press them, if I'm
being completely honest with you.
Like, tell me what you know about
your business.
This is always a big one.
It's a normal one for a lot of
different companies and things
like that.
You're looking for someone who's
done specific research, not just
generic industry knowledge.
You know, it's just like, again,
red flag.
Like, oh, I know you help scale
businesses.
Or I know you get leads for
clients.
Or, yeah, I know you help e-com
brands, like, you know, get
revenue from email marketing.
Or, yeah, I know you build funnels
and VSLs.
So, it's just like, Jesus, like,
this is a person that needs to
really show, like, a lot of
curiosity and really know what
they have.
If they can mention your service,
your pricing, they've probably
funnel hacked you.
They've looked up your trust
pilots.
They've looked up your case study
interviews.
That's what you're kind of looking
for.
Who do you think our ideal client
profile is?
That's also a very strong one
because it shows that they've done
their research.
You know, what would challenge us
with this type of client face is
another good follow-up question
there.
Because then you can start having
a really engaging conversation
then about your business, about
the product, about the service.
And those questions can lead to
even more questions that you can
prop them about a little bit more
and really see, like, what's the
scope of their knowledge for the
company?
And then it's like, have you ever
used their products or similar
ones?
Often cases, they might not, but
just in case they might have or,
like, what experience do they have
in that type of service and
industry?
That's also really helpful as
well.
Conflict resolution in difficult
situations, like, strong CSMs must
navigate complex client
relationships while maintaining
the business interest.
Like, this is the trickiest part
as well when it comes to being a
CSM.
Because you are going to, you have
to be loyal to the business at the
end of the day.
But because you are the person
that is working with the client
relationship there, you are going
to oftentimes be in the gray.
And it'll be you who is the
person, that's the client success
manager, that is going to be
working with the client on the
best thing.
It's their behalf and working on
the business on the best of their
behalf and trying to make the best
of both worlds and trying to find
a win-win situation for all
parties included.
So, pay attention as well to how
candidates describe their thought
process, not just their outcome.
The best CSMs have, like, a
systematic approach to conflict
that balances the relationship
reservation and the business's
objectives.
Again, this is why the role can be
really tricky.
CSMs often have to kind of walk a
tightrope, you know, and find this
kind of win-win for all parties
included.
And that's where the sales skills
really come into play because they
have that negotiation kind of
understanding.
And they're being able to spell
out very clearly to the founder of
the company, to yourself, this is
the ROI we're going to expect to
get.
And the client then goes, well, if
you scratch my back, I scratch
yours.
See what I mean?
So, these are good questions to
also ask as well in your interview
process.
A client is ignoring your
instructions consistently.
Walk me through your approach.
You know, you're looking for
someone who's going to actually
break down the patterns here.
Someone who's going to diagnose
this situation.
You know, they're going to, like,
do root cause analysis, escalation
process, and relationship
preservation.
A weak answer is just going to be,
like, you know, oh, well, if
they're not listening to me and
they don't want to take the
instructions, then what can I do?
Like, you know what I mean?
Like, he's not going to listen to
me, so just let him go.
It's just, like, no.
That's, like, the opposite of your
job.
Your job is to actually, like,
make sure that they are adopting
to the product and using the
service to the best of their
abilities.
Otherwise, you just are going to
have churn in, like, two months,
maybe less.
You know, how do you handle
conflict with a client who
believes they're right but they're
objectively wrong?
You know, and this is another
situation, you know?
It's, like, this could be a
situation of a client who's, like,
I'm asking for a refund but they
didn't hit all the stipulations
because maybe they didn't give all
the assets or maybe they didn't do
the onboarding call or, you know,
maybe they didn't, like, they were
just, like, radio silent for two
weeks and it was, like, we
couldn't get a hold of you.
We couldn't start any work.
We couldn't get you to approve any
work.
We couldn't get, actually,
anything moving here because you
weren't part of the process, you
know?
So, yeah, you're looking for
someone who can have, like, a
diplomatic influence without
damaging relationships and then
being able to use actual data,
using the business's contract, the
understanding, the stipulations of
the company and things like that
to kind of promote that and do it
in a very nice way.
It's often called nonviolent
communication, basically holding
someone accountable but without
actually, like, causing a
confrontation and potentially
causing a problem.
So, again, someone asks for a
refund, you know, problem-solving
methodology, list and investigate
options, resolution,
documentation.
Like, again, you're just looking
for someone who's looking to save
the situation here, someone who's
looking to try and help convince
the client that they need to stay,
not someone who just throws in the
towel and goes,
you want a refund?
No, no problem.
You want to quit?
That's no problem.
Like, yeah, let's just go, we'll
just end this.
Okay, we'll off-board you now.
Like, if that, if your CSM ever
does that, fire them, like,
immediately.
There's either something gone
seriously wrong in your training
and you haven't prepared them
enough for the situation or just,
like, you know, you need to dive
into that problem a lot deeper.
But that is, like, the biggest red
flag you can possibly imagine.
No one should ever just be
throwing in the towel because a
client throws a tantrum.
Most oftentimes, clients just need
to vent.
You know what I mean?
They just need to get some anger
off their chest, you know?
So, great candidates, they'll
show, demonstrate, like, the
balance of empathy and boundary
setting.
You know, they can't be walked on
all over.
Like, it's never going to work if
you're just going to be getting
thrown through the grinder and
just kind of, you know, used as a
human punching bag.
And again, they need to have
proper systematic approaches for
difficult conversations that leads
to resolution and protects the
business relationship.
Like, these people are speaking on
behalf of the brand.
They are representing the company.
Bad CSMs are the reason why people
get bad trust pilot reviews.
Good CSMs are the reason why there
are five-star trust pilot reviews.
This is the reasoning why you need
to be very, very careful of who
you pick as a client success
manager.
Like, you're looking for evidence
that they've successfully
navigated complex issues before in
the past.
If they don't have that
experience, you are taking a
massive, massive risk.
So, operational excellence as
well, you know, you've
accidentally overcharged a client
or if you've got the charge and
what's your response?
Integrity, problem solving, you
know, you're looking for
transparency, correction plan,
process, you know, improvement and
things like that.
Like, the CSM's not going to be
like, oh, I made a mess up, but
can you fix it for me?
It's going to be like, the CSM
should be on to the client
straight away and saying, hey, I
have to make a mistake.
Be very transparent with you.
I apologize.
This is actually, I've overcharged
you for this.
Or, hey, I forgot to send you your
billing for this month.
Could you please fix this for me
as soon as you can?
Could you do me a favor?
You know, a client then asks to
switch CSMs.
How would you reflect the
situation?
Again, like, offer an exit
interview, get some feedback
analysis, like, do a relationship
handover.
Make it as sweet as possible for
them.
If a CSM, if a client comes to the
CSM and says, I want to switch
over, I want to go to a different
person because I don't feel like
you're doing me justice in terms
of actually getting an ROI out of
the product.
They shouldn't be throwing a
tantrum and getting mad at the
client.
They should be then realistically
be saying, okay, I'm really sorry
I've let you down.
Is there any way, do you have any
feedback for me of how I can
possibly improve?
I'm going to get you set up with a
new CSM.
If we can't repair this, that's no
problem.
And then I just want to ensure
that there's as diligent of a
handover as possible so that the
next CSM that you are working with
is going to be able, is mapped out
for your success.
We don't have to start from
scratch.
Like, they can't take it
personally.
They should, to a certain degree,
professionally take it personally
because they've really let down
the client.
And this client is now after
asking for a change.
But, I mean, realistically, you're
looking for someone who has a
serious amount of accountability.
Your CSM is never going to succeed
unless they can take constructive
criticism and hold themselves
highly accountable.
This is the most highly
accountable role that you can
possibly have inside of a company.
If you let the client down, you've
let them down badly.
Like, the key word in client
success manager is the success
part.
If the client's not getting
success, it's on you, the CSM.
Learning and adaptability.
This is another question that I
would really push you to do in
your interview process because
being a client success manager
means that you also have to know
the product, the service, the
industry, the niche, inside and
out.
I would honestly tell you that
your CSM should know your product
and service better than you, the
founder.
Straight up, they should.
That's what they should strive to
do.
You know, like, for example, I'm
the head of client success for
Client Ascension.
I know Kajabi much more in-depth
and what videos are which than
possibly some of the founders
because it is my job and my
responsibility to know it inside
and out.
Not really theirs.
It is my job to understand it.
I should know what's happening in
current market trends.
I should know what outreach
channels are working.
I should know what type of sales
strategies and content strategies
and all these sort of strategies
are working.
I should know what offers are
working.
I should know what offers are not
Like, you understand, like, for me
to do my job, I need to be on the
ball all the time.
I need to be self-aware of what is
happening constantly.
And I need to also not only do my
work and complete my fulfillment,
I also need to stay on top of
current market trends because
there is a market and it's always
moving.
It's always shifting.
So, describe the time you had to
learn a completely new product or
industry and, like, how would you
go about it?
That's a good question, like,
because that's going to give you
an indication then of, like, how
is this person going to study us?
How is this person going to step
in and learn?
Like, what is their learning
style?
Does their learning style match my
training style?
That's also a really big indicator
there.
Some people love just doing a
bunch of Google Form tests,
constantly rinse and repeat.
Some people love modules and
watching SOPs.
Some people want to be on a call
and just probe you for questions.
You want to find out what their
training style is because their
training style is the difference
between you,
having to invest two hours a week
in the training to, like, 10, 12
hours a week in training.
And then you obviously want to
find strategic thinking.
Like, this is very
self-explanatory, but client
success managers need to have the
ability of actually being able to
think in a strategic way.
Like, you know, they need to
identify opportunities.
They need to identify ideas.
They need to put one and one
together.
They need to possess logistical
intensity.
You know, they need to be able to
assess when they're speaking to a
client, like, revenue growth
opportunities and give some
analytical thinking and being able
to break down
the numbers.
Like, you kind of can't be a
fucking idiot when you do this
role.
It doesn't particularly help.
You know, so data analysis.
Again, when I say data analysis as
well, to a certain degree, a lot
of people get themselves really
fucked up about it.
You don't have to get yourself
completely, you know.
It's just simple math.
Like, you just don't have to mess
around it.
Like, as long as you know metrics
in your industry, that is, like,
kind of like the standard KPI,
you're going to be sweet.
You don't need to do, like,
algebra and shit.
But they also need to know, like,
when's a red flag?
Like, what's a red flag in a
client?
What's a red flag in their process
and their review pattern and how
they do things?
Like, these are things that are
going to be very, very important.
So, you know, walk me through how
you conduct a client health
assessment and things like that.
These are good questions to also
ask as well.
Like, how do you determine what is
a good client in a healthy pattern
than a client that's in a negative
pattern?
That will also give you a really
good insight about if they
actually know anything about your
business as well, in terms of,
like, KPIs.
What's good, like, what's a good
result, for example?
You know, like, again, if you're a
content agency, for example, how
many views on a YouTube video
would you consider to be a good
amount of views if we published it
for a client?
It then lets you know, like,
what's their expectations and
what's the realistic expectation,
if they're aligned or not.
So, the curiosity of the test, if
they have no questions, this is
like a disqualifying red flag for
me.
Like, again, I've mentioned this
before.
Just if they don't have any
questions about at the end of the
interview, just.
It's not a good look.
They have not done any research.
They should be asking questions
about you.
What's your plan?
Where do you see me?
Why are you hiring me in this
role?
What's the impact?
What's needed of me?
If I was to start tomorrow, what
would be the first thing I'd have
to learn?
Like, you're looking just for
these sort of questions here.
It just really identifies an A
player.
But even a B player and a C player
will at least have one or two
questions.
An A player will have, like, five,
six, seven questions off the rip.
So, client types, team structures,
success metrics, growth path, and
daily work.
You know, these are good questions
that you're looking to have.
Again, how does it work?
How am I fitting in here?
Success metrics.
What KPIs am I going to be under?
What's the growth?
Where am I going to be in the
company in five years' time if I
was to join you?
What are your types of clients?
What's your daily work look like?
You know, what are you currently
doing right now that you want me
to come in and step and
fulfill for you?
And then quality questions to
listen for.
What does a typical client journey
look like from sale to renewal?
What's your biggest challenges
with your current CSMs face?
How do you measure CSM success?
What type of clients do you most
success in your solution?
How do CSMs team interact with
each department?
What support systems exist?
What does the first 90 days look
like?
How do clients' assignments
determine?
What tech stack do you run?
How are CSMs involved in product
feedback and development?
Like, these are just good
questions.
If you get any of these questions,
you're on to a very strong winner
here.
Evaluating candidate questions,
it's just before it's quality and
quantity.
Now we're going to go into CSM
compensation models.
There's typically two models that
you can go for when you're going
oh, sorry, technically
three, actually.
There's three kind of models you
can go for compensation models
when it goes to client success
management.
You can go with the strict
performance-based compensation.
This is going to be roughly  and
again, depends on the height
ticket and the actual touch
point of the business, and I'll go
into that in a later video as
well.
But, you know, depends on the
actual, like, ticket cost of the
client as well.
So you're looking at roughly $60
to maybe $150 per client.
You're looking to give them then
about 8 to maybe even 10% of
back-end revenue that they've
generated.
You know, $150 bonus for every
$10K of back-end revenue that they
generate.
And then there's going to be,
like, bonuses for referrals and
things like that, and maybe
run some team competitions and
things like that.
The positives of someone working
on a performance basis is that
they take their clients' outcomes
extremely seriously.
Like, every client counts.
If a client has to go on pause or
a client churns, that affects
their pay.
So, therefore, there's a genuine
incentive for them to actually
fight for that client to retain
in the company.
They have more focus on their
retention and their growth.
They're more self-motivated.
And they are there to kind of,
like, they're scaling with your
business success.
This is a really good way for
businesses, especially if you're
starting off getting your first
handful
of client success managers.
Because they're going to be
building and scaling with the
company, you know.
The problem is, the con with this
is, if the businesses has, you
know, volatile issues in
terms of lead generation and
you're not bringing in as many
clients as you want, your CSM is
suffering
in terms of pay.
Now, you can make the argument
that they're not doing as many
hours a week because they don't
have as many clients to fulfill.
That's fair enough, but there is
an element there at that beginning
period where they are
going to be doing a fair amount of
training.
So, if they are in the role for a
certain amount of months and
they're, you know, they're, say,
a medium-touched, you know, client
success manager, which typically
deals with anywhere between
50 and 60 clients, and they've
been stuck on 20 clients for a
couple of months, obviously,
their pay is going to reflect
that.
That may cause them to grow
frustrated with your lead flow.
It can also develop potential
short-term thinking.
In a way that if you have an
employee that's on a base salary,
you can kind of hand off more
additional tasks to take off of
your fulfillment.
But when they're only getting paid
per client, they are going to give
you the pushback of like,
that's not in my role.
That's not my responsibility.
I'm only paid for the clients that
I work with.
Any of these tasks that are
outside of my role, not my
problem.
So, it does come with it ebbs and
flows.
And then also requires you with
strong tracking systems, like
you're going to have to be very
on the ball because if you miss
payment or you miscalculate or
they miscalculate or in any
sort of capacity, it's going to
cause friction.
So, this works really well with
businesses with consistent lead
flow that have clear expansion
pathways, but it also really
attracts like the entrepreneurial
type of mindset at client success
managers who want to like have
more control about their actual
earning potential.
So, it's a really good model.
I would strongly recommend it,
especially if you're starting out
and you are worried about
like what that compensation
structure looks like.
And if you want to be very mindful
of your profit margins and your
business actual
income, the second option is the
salary-based compensation.
And you're going to be looking at
anywhere between $3,000 to $5,000.
They're still going to be getting
back-end percentages for all
back-end revenue generated.
If you don't give your client
success manager any sort of
back-end revenue compensation
whatsoever, you're not going to
retain any clients because they
have no incentive to do
so at all.
Their back-end sales conversation
is going to be, hey, so do you
want to stay on?
Nope.
All right.
It's nice knowing you.
And that's just not effective.
You're just going to churn so many
clients that way.
The pros of it, they have
predictable and steady income.
They can focus on more long-term
relationships.
It is easier in terms of payroll
because it's just the same pricing
kind of on a month-to-month
basis until that back-end revenue
really kicks in.
And like, you're not going to have
as much churn and burn when it
comes to your CSMs because
again, they just, they know what's
coming in every month.
They know what they're earning.
It creates, you know, a lot of
stableness.
However, the problems that come is
complacency because things aren't
going to change and
their pay is going to be one way
or the other.
And again, it's like, if you pay
them five grand, you know, their
back-end is only six
grand.
I mean, is it really that much in
the difference?
I mean, is it really going to
change my life?
Who knows?
And again, complacency is really
the death in terms of being a
client success manager.
There's no direct connection,
again, between their effort and
their rewards.
They don't really feel like
they've enjoyed the fruits of
their labor.
I mean, if you're paying them just
a flat fee, it's just like, cool,
I got my flat fee.
And you may attract people into
the role that are just looking for
something easy, remote.
These type of mindset of people
that just kind of want to work
from home and get a steady
income.
Again, not really push themselves
above and beyond.
And it's really hard to justify
the payments and the costs when
things do go tough and the
business is in a little bit of a
rut.
It's just, it's going to, it can
put you under quite a bit of
pressure.
So I would really only look at
this sort of model if you are
generating solid monthly
reoccurring
revenue.
You find an A player and the, you
know, the pricing model without
like a set base is like
a non-negotiable for them, or it's
someone in a more senior position.
So there's also this model here,
which I actually really do like.
And it's the hybrid model.
The hybrid model is basically a
structure of a small base between
$1,000 to $2,000, a smaller
cap than per client per head,
because you are compensating them
with a base.
So there's like, there's a ground
level of what they're making.
And then there's also like, you
know, the in-between of what their
back-end revenue is going to
look like.
Because one way or the other,
whether you like it or not, you're
going to have to reward your
staff with good back-end revenue
percentages or half-decent ones,
because if they're not
doing back-end and not retaining
customers, then there's no real
point in any of this.
So that always has to be decent.
I would never do anything less
than 5%, by the way.
And then over in time, when
they're with you long enough,
especially, you know, your CSMs,
and they've put in good work, and
they've brought in an actual ROI
to the company, you can look
at then increasing the base,
increasing their cost per client,
and increasing their back-end
revenue as forms of giving them,
you know, a salary boost that is
backed by performance and
work ethic.
So it works quite well.
So I do like the hybrid approach,
if that's something you'd like to
go for as well.
So, CSM types by business model
and things like that as well.
So you have three different types
of client success managers, and it
really does depend
on the type of business that you
have.
You have low-touch CSMs.
These client success managers can
take on to 100 clients.
It really means it's kind of more
so for like info products or like
SaaS products where
like clients don't really need
that much interaction with you.
They don't need weekly meetings.
They don't even need monthly
meetings, like some check-in
messages, maybe over email or
Slack,
and maybe the odd call to kind of
help them with a certain issue.
But calls are not like a high
priority.
It's just like messaging, emailing
on a day-to-day basis, and just
kind of like helping clients
through very small, mediocre
problems.
That's a low-touch point CSM.
So if you feel like your business
model isn't super high
client-facing, but you still need
someone to kind of manage things,
that's what you're going to get
here.
A mid-touch CSM is going to work
anywhere between 50 to 70 clients,
and this is going to be someone
who is going to run monthly
reporting calls with each client.
They're going to maybe host like
some sort of an office hour so
that all clients can step in and
ask kind of a Q&A question.
They're an expert in their field
in coordination and scheduling,
but they're also an expert in the
product and understanding how to
utilize it.
They're there to kind of really
make sure that people are getting
an ROI.
Like the actual SSEs inside of
Client Ascension are a very good
example of mid-touch CSMs.
So there's a few times a week
they're checking in with you.
They're doing calls.
They may even do like the odd
emergency call then if something's
really going wrong, and they're
also responsible for the renewals
and expansion conversations in
terms of the company.
Coaching companies, consulting
companies, mid-tier agencies, and
SaaS companies, and things like
that.
You know, these sort of
experience, again, for someone to
do this sort of role, you are
looking for someone for like two,
three years' experience.
For like a low-touch point CSM, I
mean, honestly, like a year's
experience is going to be fine.
High-touch CSM.
These guys are absolute experts in
their fields.
These are genuinely, they're not
even like just client success
managers.
They're more like the client
success advisors.
They're very strategic.
They know this industry inside and
out.
They do a lot of the heavy lifting
with clients.
They're going to be on multiple
calls per week.
You're talking like anywhere
between, you know, 20 to 25 calls
a week.
They're going to be very hands-on,
a lot of communication, kind of a
lot of element of like stepping in
and helping the client with their
specific issue.
You know, very hands-on kind of
approach.
You know, they'll have multiple
weekly strategy consultations and
planning in place, you know,
detailed implementation and
guidance, like really custom
strategy and development for the
client's goals.
Like almost like a done-with-you
project management, like high,
high accountability, daily
conversations and accountability,
and like really advanced renewal
and expansion strategies for that
specific client.
These guys typically only work,
again, with 20 to 35 clients at a
time because it is so high touch
point on such a constant basis.
They may be having weekly calls
with each and every client, at
least bi-weekly.
So these guys are very, very high
touch point, you know.
Common hiring mistake, many
companies hire CSMs with the wrong
profile for their business model.
For example, you know, again, I've
seen guys that like hire a high
touch CSM for a low touch point
product.
And that creates a serious amount
of frustration because this person
is like just generally drilled to
keep people engaged and highly
accountable and coaching them
through a situation.
And that just product and niche
and market just doesn't understand
that.
So really take into consideration
how much time your client's facing
is actually taking you before you
kind of really kind of push
forward in that as well.
And then again, for like hiring a
low touch point for a high value
client that needs a lot of
handholding as well, just kind of
like undermines the client's
success.
They're not going to be able to
understand how to scale that
person whatsoever.
So just take all that into
consideration and just like really
try and map out into your head
like what the client interaction
looks like on a day-to-day basis.
So, yeah, you know, average client
contract value, complexity of
implementation, frequency of
client interaction needed for
success and level of strategic
guidance required.
So CSM assessment scorecard.
So a standardized assessment
scorecard here is basically so you
get a little bit of an
understanding.
And like when you're doing your
interview process, you can
actually just kind of like monitor
like what the responses are.
Because sometimes if you don't
have something like this in place
when you're doing an interview,
you can sometimes get yourself
slightly fooled by a client
success manager, especially when
with sales skills.
Sometimes they can sound better at
the role than they actually are in
implementation.
So you want to kind of create a
scorecard so that you can actually
kind of monitor responses and kind
of rate them and having your
questions kind of organized.
helps with just a piece of paper
and pen, to be honest with you,
maybe kind of like, you know, a
little clipboard to just kind of
help you and just having these
questions laid out with their
name.
And, you know, that way you can
actually mark their competency,
their relationship management
skills, their strategic thinking
skills, and if they're a cultural
fit.
So it goes by this CRM, you know,
CRM experience, have they used any
CRMs in the past?
What CRMs have they used?
What are they proficient in?
You know, are they completely new
to CRMs?
Because that's going to be a,
that's going to be a training that
you're going to have to do.
Remember, all of these questions
here is going to be anything that
needs work is going to be
additional training.
And you need to take that in
consideration of how many hours
it's going to take you to train
someone to get something like this
done.
If they're good, then you're
looking at like, okay, cool.
We might just be a week or two
here and they're going to be
a-okay.
If they're excellent, it's like,
perfect.
This is right up their alley.
They're going to see this.
They're going to know how we work.
They're going to lock in within
the day.
So CRM experience, data analysis,
communication, process thinking,
industry knowledge, technical
learning.
So relationship management then,
conflict resolution questions,
client advocacy questions, trust
building questions, emotional
intelligence, and influence
skills.
So you'll be able to track and
monitor these, again, on a point
system from five, three, and one.
And then strategic thinking,
problem diagnosis, pattern
recognition, growth orientation,
business acumen, and resource
utilization.
Cultural fit, learning mindset,
curiosity, accountability, team
collaboration, and work ethic.
These are just things you want to
get yourself boxed off.
You want to craft your questions
around all of these sort of topics
here so that you can at least kind
of start ticking these boxes.
Again, someone scores 90 to 100,
like hire them immediately.
Anyone 75 to 89, they're strong
candidate.
Like the training's not going to
be super intense with them.
They're most likely a really
strong fit.
60 to 70 poor, they're going to
require more training.
You're going to have to give them
like a little bit of extra.
some serious handholding, to be
honest with you.
I would say 90 to 100, you're
looking at, you know, two weeks,
they're going to be up and
running.
75 to 89, they're going to be
anywhere between two to three,
four weeks up and running.
60 to 74, you could be looking at,
you know, six, eight weeks until
they're properly up and running.
Below 60s, like do not hire.
Like they're a high risk of
failure.
Like just continue your search.
Like no one should settle for less
than like a six out of ten.
Like just don't.
It doesn't matter how desperate
you are.
I really cannot stress that
enough.
If you hire the wrong CSM, you've
completely like fucked up your
business.
Because if your clients end up,
even if they're a bad CSM, build a
good relationship with that
person.
And that CSM leaves, that client
is then going to feel like, I
don't want to, I might not want to
be here.
It can generally cause churn.
It can mess up your backend
revenue.
It can mess up your current
And then it's like, no one likes
being in the midst of their
business, trying to run it.
And all of a sudden they have no
one there to take onboarding
calls.
And you then have to go back and
take all these onboarding calls
on.
And then that client
communication, then they feel like
they can always go to you, the
founder of the company, for all
this constant communication and
next steps and next tasks and
things like that.
And you're going to have to end up
doing that until you find a
replacement.
Like, it's a serious role that you
cannot fuck around with and doing
wrong.
Okay.
Implementation framework.
So, this is what you're going to
first want to do.
Job posting, create a detailed job
specific scorecard.
There'll be one linked below in
this video.
Post industry specific job boards.
So, you know, Indeed, LinkedIn,
things like that as well.
Even push some ad spend behind it
too.
You can also reach out to a hiring
agency as well.
Just make sure that the hiring
agency is getting talent that have
really good English.
You can try and reach out to some
CSM networks and communities.
I would always also recommend
asking, like, if you are inside of
Client Ascension Slack, asking the
Opportunities channel.
You can reach out to me.
You can reach out to some of the
other CSMs.
You can reach out to a variety of
different people.
Ask your network, really,
essentially.
Screen applications using the
experience matrix.
Initial interviews, you want to
keep them up to about 30 minutes.
30 to 60 minutes.
I've oftentimes had calls with
CSMs for about 60 minutes because
we just end up getting really deep
into it.
So, make sure you add that, like,
extra 30-minute buffer time
because it's just in case.
Complete assessment scorecard.
Check references if they have
some.
Evaluate cultural fit.
Again, people skip this step a lot
of checking the references.
Always check your references.
Top candidates.
Then I would give them some sort
of mock call scenario to do.
Some tasks.
Some assignment to do.
Something that they can do
themselves at home to kind of
really show how more proficient
they are in terms of the role.
And then I would set them up with
either a current CSM or another
founder or someone within the
company to vibe check them to see
if they are good team fit.
And then a final decision then
based on scorecard and practical
performance.
You're going to want to go through
that homework, that assessment, or
that mock call.
The mock call can also, by the
way, be a loom video.
Like, you don't actually have to
get on a second call and run a
mock.
You just want to give them a
scenario and say, like, record me
a loom of how you would actually
handle this situation.
And then finally, a founder
interview, whether that was you
again or another founder, whatever
your situation might be.
Have that final interview where
you can make an offer and maybe,
in some cases, negotiate on price.
And then onboarding.
So you're going to start 14-day
intensive training, shadow
experienced CSMs if you have CSMs,
complete supervised client
interaction, and a regular
check-ins performance feedback.
New CSMs should achieve 70%
effectiveness score within the
first 90 days of hire.
They should be comfortable
onboarding clients, taking client
monthly meetings, having
check-ins, completing on time, and
then have a really strong
understanding of the product and
the service.
You know, practical exercise
design is going to be, like, mock
calls, renewal conversations with
dissatisfied clients, analyze
client usage, data risk, identify
risk factors.
So, in other words, like, what are
clients doing that are going to
eventually cause a stress point
that's going to make them want to
churn?
You know, creation of a success
plan for a new client.
Reference questions, how did they
handle difficult conversations?
What is retention rate?
Things like that there, too.
You know, how are they handling
competing properties?
How are systems processes that
they improve?
Like, you know, again, go to CSM.
They'll be able to actually
improve your process a lot more.
So, final recommendation.
Building a successful customer
success team starts with hiring
the right people and using the
right process.
By implementing this strategic
framework, you'll not only reduce
costs, turnover, but you'll
accelerate your team's impact, and
you'll actually make a massive
ROI.
Okay, guys.
Sorry this video was long.
It's quite in-depth.
But reach out to me.
The next module is going to be how
to onboard your next CSM.
Take care.