What's up guys?
So in this video, I wanted to
quickly walk you through our
hiring funnel and
process for the student success
coach role here at Clan Ascension.
And I think just seeing how
our process works from A to Z
behind the scenes can help inform
some of your guys' different
hiring
and recruiting funnels.
And so the way I do it is through
a Trello board.
The Trello board is
essentially set up like a CRM
because hiring is similar to the
sales process of bringing on a new
client, right?
But anyways, I have a resources
tab.
So I have a link to the
application.
I have a link
to the assessment.
I have a link to book a screening
interview with Andy.
That's like our step one
interview.
And then I have a link to book a
final step interview with Andre.
That's like the final
step of the process.
And then pretty much there's a zap
that's linked to the application,
which is a
Google form.
So anytime someone applies,
they're automatically entered into
this new applications
column.
So for example, this kid, Adi
Verma, he just applied.
You can see his email and then you
have a
link to the responses as well.
These other ones were just added
manually because to be honest,
this is a
brand new thing I created to come
up with this training for.
So you have new applications as
the
first step.
Then you have for whoever had
submitted an application, who do
we have a screening interview
scheduled with?
And to schedule the screening
interview, you have that link very
easily accessible
here.
If the screening interview goes
well, then we assign them an
assessment, which I'll show you
guys
as well.
And you have the link to the
assessment here.
And then if the assessment is
good, we'll schedule
them for a culture fit interview
with someone else that's currently
in the student success
coach role.
And if that person says, Hey, this
person checks out, they'll be
scheduled with me
for a final interview.
And then from there, the person is
either hired or at any other step
in the
process, they can be disqualified.
So we have a pipeline for hiring.
And if you hire for a specific
role over and over and over again,
it's going to be really helpful
for you to create something like
this.
So real quick, let me just show
you some of the different assets.
So the first asset is the
application.
We do it in Google form.
I also recommend type form,
whatever works for you,
but keep it really simple.
Pretty much this first part is
building out like the introduction
to the
role and why someone should be
interested.
It's pretty much like a VSL
version of your hiring scorecard
with the OTE and what you're
looking for and why they should
apply.
And then it's the application.
You're just looking for their
name, their email, contact
information, where they're
located,
what time zone they're in, how
they heard about this opportunity,
what they know about your company,
what stuck out specifically about
this role and about your company,
why they think they're a good
fit for this role.
What is their experience with AI?
That's something that we ask
specifically,
so you can plug that in with
what's your experience with email
marketing or what's your
experience with
SEO or what's your experience with
account management, whatever is
relevant to the role
you're hiring for.
I always love to ask them this
question as well.
What's your career goals,
monetary, non-monetary growth?
How do you see this role playing a
part in your long-term vision?
Because I really want to find
people that are long-term focused,
right?
And then are you available
for a full-time commitment?
Yes or no.
If you're to get offered this
position, how quickly can you
start?
And then to complete your
application, here's a quick
assignment, which is basically
like put together
a welcome message for a student,
guiding them on the best next
steps to get started.
And I always say
this is like a bonus record a loom
video, but I always, for the most
part, weed out people that
submit this without a loom video
because I want someone who's
willing to go above and beyond and
do
everything that is in their best
interest to stack the cards in
their favor to land this job
opportunity.
So that's the assessment or sorry,
the application.
So once they fill out the
application, it shows up
here.
We basically review it.
If it looks good, we'll reach out
to schedule a screening interview.
If the screening interview goes
well, and we still think this
person might be qualified for
the role, we'll then assign them
the homework.
So the homework is this step here,
assessment,
assign, assessment or homework.
You can use either word.
But pretty much what this looks
like is
different scenarios.
So you can read through these
scenarios.
They're relevant to the student
success
coach role.
And it just is like mock, it's
like mock scenarios.
And it's just to see how they
would respond to these.
Obviously, they haven't gone
through our training.
They don't know the best
way to handle these situations
yet.
But I just want to see how they
think and approach these different
scenarios and problems.
And I love this last question,
especially scenario number four,
say a
student assigned to you has
communicated privately about their
disappointment with your coaching
methods.
They're hinting at wanting to
switch to a new SSC or receive a
refund.
How do you respond
to this situation?
So we're basically getting them to
fill this out and evaluating
whether or not
we think they can perform well in
the SSC role based on the
homework.
If they pass the homework
assessment, they then get sent to
one of our existing student
success coaches for what we call
a culture fit interview, basically
just asking one of the existing
team members that are performing
and
excelling well to say, hey, do you
think this person is cut out to
join our team and to help us reach
our goals?
And that's typically like a 15
minute interview.
They'll give you good feedback.
It's
basically just like a litmus test.
If you're the one doing the
interviews all the way through,
like in this example, Andy, who
manages our SSC team has done the
process up to this point.
It's
helpful for him to get a secondary
perspective from someone else on
the team.
And if that passes,
it's then scheduled with me, the
ultimate decision maker to say,
hey, I've heard from Andy,
I've heard from this other SSC,
I've reviewed your application,
I've reviewed your homework,
and it looks like you could be a
really good fit.
I'd see if there's any other red
flags or concerns
I want to hit on.
Otherwise, I go through the next
steps for the hiring and the
onboarding process,
and they're moved over to hired.
And again, at any stage in the
process, if they're disqualified,
you can put them all the way over
here in the disqualified column,
similar to like a closed,
lost column in a CRM.
So that's really it.
So it just becomes a game of
moving people left to right,
same way you'd work your CRM, and
getting more people top of funnel,
right?
So running ads,
campaigns to get people interested
to actually apply in the first
place.
So for example,
I posted this 22 hours ago, in our
school community, where there's
over 1000 people in our lower
ticket
program, to basically see if any
of these guys might be interested
in this opportunity.
So I put a hiring
post here, with a link to the
application.
And I posted on Twitter, we sent
it to our email list,
I sent it to some friends as well.
And it's like an ad, right?
I'm pretty much formatting this as
an
ad to get people to apply.
Like I'm actually using social
proof as well to say, look, you
want to come
work for this company that
produced 216 reviews that amounted
to the 4.9 out of five stars on
Trustpilot.
Like that's a company you can feel
good about helping and working
for.
So that's kind of an
example of what our hiring posts
look like to feed the top of
funnel, which in this situation
would be
new applications.
And then once these are fed into
your hiring funnel, you just move
them from left to
right.
So you schedule the screening
interview, if they're fit, if the
screening interview goes well,
you do an assessment with them.
If the assessment or the homework
results look good to you,
schedule them with someone else on
your team to do a culture fit
interview.
And if they look good
or have a good report, you can
schedule them with yourself or a
higher up or just essentially the
ultimate decision maker in the
company to do a final interview.
And then from there, they're
hired.
But
the entire idea and message of
this video is that you should
treat your hiring process the same
way
you treat your marketing and sales
process to get new clients.
So hopefully this video is
valuable.
If there's other parts of our
hiring process that you'd like to
see, such as screening interview
examples, more assessment
examples, maybe even an SOP on the
culture fit interviews, I'd be
happy to
collect those resources from our
various team members who are
involved in the hiring process
so that they can be helpful to you
as well.
But like first things first, just
set up some sort of
hiring funnel for the different
roles that you might be hiring
for.
Because you'll see as you
scale or as you start to scale and
build out your company, a lot of
these roles are going to be
repeated,
right?
For client ascension, it's just
going to come down to how can we
hire more closers and how can we
hire more student success coaches
as you know, the growth demands.
So here's the solution to that.
Same way
we do it on the front end, we do
it on the back end with our hiring
process.
So again, hopefully this is
helpful and I'm looking forward to
seeing you guys implement this.