Welcome guys.
So in this video, I'm actually
going to show you how to manage a
customer
success manager or client success
manager, CSM essentially,
effectively.
So this is going
to be my guide of how like you as
a founder can do this in your
time.
And I'll cover a
later video later down the line of
like how to actually like remove
yourself from the management
kind of situation there, what that
handover actually looks like.
But this is how you the
founder is actually going to
manage your customer success
managers or just customer
success manager in general, if you
only have the one.
So the management reality check,
why
CSM leadership matters.
Like the data paints a clear
picture.
CSM teams without systematic
management frameworks, they just
achieve like 30% lower retention
rates and 47% higher turnover
compared to teams with structured
oversight.
So in other words, you're going to
have, you're
you're looking at 50% churn and
you're like, you know, you're
probably going to on average,
if you're converting and retaining
50% of your clients, you're only
going to retain about 20%
of them.
And so it's, it's really not a
good look.
It's really much, much lower kind
of insights
there.
So again, you really do need to
keep an eye on your CSMs.
And again, they are pretty
much the brand there who your
clients are talking to on a
day-to-day basis.
If you're not keeping track
of this and you let them kind of
run wild and there's no management
there, they can easily get
complacent.
They can get lazy.
They're not going to be proactive
and they're probably not even
going to
put that much effort into your
clients.
And therefore your clients aren't
going to put that much effort
into your service and your
product.
So the unique challenge of CSM
management is just fundamentally
different approaches to most other
roles.
CSMs are the critical bridge
between your company and your
clients.
And so client trust and loyalty
and revenue retention and
expansion.
So, and then your brand
reputation.
So most successful CSM teams
operate on predictable rhythms
with continuous quality
monitoring,
not reactive management based off
problems.
So you want to be constantly
keeping an eye on things and
having a routine and having like
an actual system in your calendar
and in place, not just clients
pissed off.
Now I need to react.
Now I need to look and investigate
and audit and ask the client and
then ask the CSM
and then look at a call recording
and look back on Slack or like,
you know, like, let me show me
these emails
and going through this entire
investigation to uncover what the
actual problem is.
Because sometimes clients are just
being really, really difficult.
In some cases, CSMs are just not
doing their fucking job.
And so it's like
you're going to spend so many
hours wasted on just figuring out
what the problem is.
And no matter what,
you're going to be disappointed by
the answer.
So it's just really a head-racking
process for you
specifically.
So CSM management fails
consequences, extended more than
team dynamics and poor management
creates a ripple effect that like
undermines and client
relationships, damages trust, and
ultimately
it always leads to churn.
So structured teams have
consistent client communication,
proactive issue
identification, higher client
satisfaction scores, and lower
turnover rates, whether that's
team and lower
churn rates.
Unstructured teams are reactive
client management.
You only react to problems and
your
firefighting approaches to issues.
You've lowered client satisfaction
scores.
Your team's going to burn
out.
Your clients are going to get
pissed off as well.
So weekly management rhythm.
This is my personal
rhythm that I have with the team
that I run in Client Ascension.
So on Mondays, I like to run a
power hour
first thing on Monday morning with
my team.
That is there to focus on specific
tasks that we want to
cover.
Like that is important to us.
And I'll go into those in a lot
more deeper detail, but just to
give
you a quick understanding, it
could be churn reactivation, trust
pilot collection, check-ins,
health score sheets.
It could be something that we need
to, like anything that we need to
do as a team,
that's part of the work that we
actually have to do.
I just put it into an hour for us
to sit down and silence for the
first
hour of the day and just get
something that's a really high
leverage task for us out of the
way, first and
foremost.
So all CSMs and anyone that is in
the management position, that's
key.
They need to have the
accountability of the senior there
on the call so that people are
actually getting something done.
Otherwise, they will sit on a call
and fuck around for an hour.
an hour.
Not all, but most cases they will,
especially as like time goes on
and no one's checking that call.
Tuesday is the one-to-one that is
there where you, the founder or
the manager of the client success
team will have an individual
performance
development conversation with the
CSM.
They're typically 30 minutes.
I would use it as an hour for
anyone that's a new hire so that
you can kind of
have like a bit of more of a
training session with that person,
but typically they're only 30
minutes long.
That's going to be the manager of
the founder and the individual
CSM, not a team, just the one CSM.
Then you have Wednesday.
I like to do a team training.
Again, I like to run this at 9
a.m.
in the morning.
This sometimes is a duration of 60
to 90 minutes.
This is for skills development and
knowledge expansion.
CSMs always have to stay ahead of
the curve.
They always have to learn new
things and
new insights, whether you have a
new service, new offering, new
packaging.
It doesn't matter.
As long as your business is
evolving, they have something to
learn and understand about.
So you can leave them to learn
this on their own sometimes and
they can sometimes like they'll
forget.
It's not their fault because they
have calls and they're not
dealing with clients and they're
putting out fires and they're
helping strategic problems.
So it's helpful just to actually
set some time during the week.
So at least one hour a week, they
are taking the time to learn and
develop and they should be doing
this as a team so that everyone's
learning together and everyone's
asking questions and there's
alignment there across the board.
Then finally, Friday, the
leadership alignment.
That is your weekly SSE team call.
That is going to be founder,
leadership, CSM managers and the
CSMs.
Founders, most importantly, if you
are the founder of the company and
you have like a head of client
success, you should still be on
that call because that is the call
where you are going to give the
CSM team company updates.
What's happening with the company?
What are we doing?
How are we progressing?
What are we working on?
What's coming up?
What are we transitioning in and
out of?
What are we transitioning into?
What are we transitioning out to?
It's important.
And that founder presence there
holds a layer of higher
accountability.
You'll have people fucking around
less on your calls.
You know, you'll have people being
very serious and taking them very
diligently.
So that is there to also summarize
what's new in the company, what
we're working on, what updates we
have to cover.
And then you can kind of just do a
round robin in the room of
individual people of like, how is
your week?
What wins did you collect?
What like any case studies
collected, any referrals
collected, any trust pilots
collected?
Like what's, you know, what's
working for your clients?
What's not working for your
clients?
And then we can all have an open
conversation about like what's
happening in that specific space.
And it's like, are other CSMs also
running into this problem?
So do you as a company then are
aware like, oh, we need to fix
this because it's not just you and
this client.
It's a few other of you guys and
you're a few other different
clients.
So we're seeing a reoccurring
pattern and there's something we
need to fix.
And that's going to fall into next
week's situation, either your team
training or a power hour or
something to address in a
one-to-one call.
OK, if you don't have these
patterns and rhythms and your CSMs
are not talking and learning and
having coaching and having
one-to-ones
and having team calls that are
effective in pushing the needle,
there's no pulse on the company
and what's happening whatsoever.
And you can't hand up having
yourself CSMs that are just not
doing their job and just kind of
chilling in the background.
So your morning focus strategy,
again, just try and get them done
first thing in the morning.
It just lets the guys open up
their calendar for the day to take
on client meetings.
Not very often you'll have clients
wanting to do a call at 9 a.m.
in the morning.
Most often it's after 10 a.m.
And again, like there's just no
harm.
Just get it done first thing in
the morning.
It adds that.
It kind of kicks the day off in a
positive way.
So, yeah, critical client
meetings, team synchronization,
complex problem solving, strategic
planning, all that sort of jazz.
And then afternoon, then they can
spend time on Slack messages,
taking calls, things like that as
well.
Preparation for work.
So, call quality management
system.
So, I like to use Fathom for this
as well.
But like, as the manager, you're
going to have to review a lot of
calls.
And you're going to want to do
them like, you want to set up a
routine to do it and block some
time off in your calendar and
things like that.
But what you really want to do
there is kind of like almost
catching by surprise a little bit
as well.
So, there's always that feeling of
like, oh, I'm always kind of being
watched.
It's not to cause any sort of
creepiness.
It's just to let them know like,
hey, you're always being
monitored.
So, like every call that they get
on then, they have the expectation
of like, I need to put in my best
performance here.
Because if this is a call that
either the founder or my manager
is going to check, like I want
this one to be the one that they
check.
So, you're also going to analyze
it for structured frameworks.
Are they doing the right
documentation?
Are they saying the right things?
Are they, you know, are they
leveraging the product and the
support that we offer clients in
the most affectionate way?
And then you can get them actual
feedback.
You know, you can send them a
note.
You can send them like a voice
You can send them some notes in
general and just be like, hey,
review this call.
Send them the Fathom link.
I recommend you do this.
You did this really well, but you
didn't do that so well.
So, that there's constant quality
assessment and there's constantly
like room for improvement.
Because there is always room for
improvement with your CSMs.
Like, you're going to be dealing.
It's going to take a CSM years
until they're like absolutely
perfect.
They get everything absolutely
right.
Like, there's always room to
improve.
So, yeah, you want to check it by,
like, quality, you know,
communication quality, problem
solving, relationship management,
and process adherence.
So, these are some just kind of
like targets here.
Communication quality is going to
be the most important aspect of
it.
You need to make sure that, you
know, they're able to translate,
you know, complex concepts into
kind of like friendly language so
that the client can basically
simply understand what it is that
you need to do.
A lot of the times, they're going
to be doing a lot of problem
solving, diagnostic thinking,
solution creativity, resource
utilization, and effectiveness in
terms of addressing the client's
challenge.
Like, your clients are going to
have problems.
The CSM is there to make sure that
those problems are no longer
problems.
That's kind of the whole point of
this shit.
And then relationship management.
Did they do anything to build
trust?
Was there some rapport
established?
Did the client seem satisfied
leaving the call?
You know, do you see like a
long-term like relationship
developing here?
That's really another aspect.
And then just process adherence.
Just making sure, you know,
documentation was complete, that
they left notes, or they did take
notes, or that there's like, you
know, you know, you've marked down
like what you need to get done
this week or what they need to get
done next week.
Or if it was a monthly check-in
call, what they did that month,
what's the goal for next month.
Like, you just want to make sure
that it's, you know, everything's
up to scratch, and it wasn't just
a call, and that there was no
follow-up or handover after the
call, so then the client doesn't
go, wait, what did so-and-so say
to me?
What was my next step?
What do I have to do?
Like, and, you know, you can just
quality check it from there.
CSM types, again, you know this
already.
Like, high-touch CSMs, they should
be doing 15 to 25 calls a week.
Mid-touch CSMs are looking at 10
to 15 calls a week.
Low-touch-point CSMs are only
going to do about 5 to 10 calls a
week.
Those calls are going to go, like,
smaller and sooner.
Mid-touch clients are going to be
about 20 to 30 minutes.
High-touch-point CSMs are going to
be doing about 30 to 45-minute
calls.
Unless it's an onboarding call,
depending on the product and
service, your onboarding calls can
range anywhere between 30 minutes
to an hour, in some cases, even an
hour and a half.
So, you know, and you have a
certain quality target for those
calls, really nothing below 80%.
Like, no one should be doing
anything that's just 80%.
Like, an 8 out of 10 below that in
terms of quality calls is kind of
a waste of time for everyone
across the board.
So, yeah.
Daily performance tracking systems
as well.
End-of-day type form protocols.
Like, you need to implement, like,
an end-of-day type form.
It only takes, like, five minutes
to complete.
It's not that long.
Make sure you also, to avoid
missed end-of-day type forms,
don't send it out at 5 p.m.
on the dot when they finish their
day.
Like, they're going to miss doing
it.
Send it to them at, like, 4
o'clock.
Ideally, their last hour before
their day finishes.
So that they just do the
end-of-day type form and they
complete their last hour of work.
You know, because otherwise,
they're going to forget.
And, you know, so you want to ask
them, like, what did you
accomplish today?
Which clients need immediate
attention or follow-up?
Did you collect any case studies,
trust pilot reviews, or referrals
today?
What challenges did you face with
your work or with clients today?
You know, what process could we
improve based on today's
experience?
What are your top three priorities
for tomorrow?
Or pretty much, what's your entire
plan for tomorrow?
Like, what calls are you taking?
Whose clients are you meeting?
Things like that, too.
And, you know, response analysis.
So, like, daily review, you know,
for yourself, the founder, or the
head CSM, you want to review all
the submissions,
flagging urgent client details,
you know, so you can start all
having communication about certain
things that are happening.
You're just in the know of what's
happening in the company.
Like, there's intervention
planning as well.
So you can start seeing if there
isn't CSM particularly that's
having issues.
They can see the additional
support that they need.
You can give them some coaching
advice.
You can see their response.
And you can just basically help
them before, you know, this
problem starts spiraling out of
control.
And then, you know, weekly pattern
analysis.
You can start compiling insights.
You can start tracking all of this
data.
You can start seeing, like, what
problems are occurring.
What's the stress point?
Do we need to give extra resources
or extra support here to these
clients for, like, a specific area
in the business?
And then there's, like, a process
refinement.
Again, just like what I mentioned,
like, daily visibility creates
accountability.
And when CSMs know they'll be
reporting on specific actions each
day, they'll naturally prioritize
high-impact activities and
client-focused outcomes.
So this is why it's also very,
very important as well.
So auditing your CSMs.
Another thing you want to do, the
day your CSMs do their check-ins,
ideally, like I've mentioned
before, they'd, like, do Monday,
Wednesday, and Friday.
They should be checking in on
Mondays so that they set up a game
plan for the clients.
They should be checking on a
Wednesday so they can see how's
everything going halfway through
the week.
And then Friday, do you kind of
want to get an end-of-week kind of
wrap-up of, like, how things are
currently going?
Here, you also, this is the days
you also want to do your audits of
the CSMs.
You want to go through, like, all
the communication channels to make
sure, like, did you message your
client today?
Did you see if everything was
okay?
Was the response good?
Like, were you helpful?
Was it a standard check-in of,
like, hey, how's your day going?
Because that's not fucking useful
to anyone.
Or was it, hey, how are you
currently getting on with, like,
creating your VSL?
Or, hey, did you make that landing
page yet?
Or, hey, how did I call the email
launch?
Like, that's a client extension
example, but I'm just throwing one
out for the fuck of it.
Like, you want to actually add
something that's, like, why were
they actually working on it?
That was part of the plan and the
process and the implementation
that you're trying to drive and
adopt.
So, and did the client reply, but
the CSM didn't reply?
Why is the CSM replying?
You know, and how long was the
client waiting for the reply after
CSM?
You know, you want to check, like,
you know, response times and
things like that, too.
So, you need to audit all of this
as well.
And then also, like, on those days
as well, you really want to audit,
like, Stripe billing.
Like, did your CSM message clients
who missed or are late for a
payment?
Is there any clients who have not
been billed in the past 30 days?
And it's like, wait, has this
person had a back-end sales
conversation?
Have this person not renewed?
Like, are we doing free work for
this individual?
And they haven't even paid yet?
Like, what's going on?
You want to, like, check, you
know, communications.
Then you also want to check Stripe
and making sure all the payments
are in place and that there's no
failed payments and things like
that.
Because your CSMs are responsible
for collecting payments, too.
Then another thing you're going to
have your CSMs do is a bi-weekly
health score assessment.
This is going to be basically,
like, you can...
I like to do this on the Mondays
on a bi-weekly basis, which is
really, really helpful because
it's, like...
So, just to give you an inside
look at how I do my structure.
So, the first Monday of the month,
my team are going to do a health
score sheet.
When they do the health score
sheet, then, and it's complete,
they bring that with them on their
Tuesday one-to-one.
And we break down their health
score sheet of how their clients
are currently doing.
The second week, when they don't
have to do a health score sheet,
that Monday, I actually really
like to review calls.
So, then I can bring that call
with me to that meeting.
And then we can have a proactive,
instructive conversation of how
they can improve that call.
But also, then, hey, your health
score sheet, what's the difference
in this week than last week?
Like, how did we drive?
Did you take the advice?
Did you adopt the product?
Did you help them improve?
Like, how do we make that work?
Because the next week, they're
going to have to do their health
score sheet.
And if shit hasn't improved, then
we're going to have a problem.
So, it works really, really well,
you know.
So, health score sheets must be
completed the night before
one-to-ones with management.
I know it's a submission by 12
o'clock.
I don't really give a shit to get
it done that morning, to be honest
with you.
As long as it's done before the
meeting, that's fucking fine.
Like, they need to just be able to
have it done.
You know, full client company
name, who their SSE is.
Again, if it's your team, you're
just going to do it.
If you're a client, I'm going to
be able to see it.
Like, what service and package are
they on?
What's their contract value?
Like, you know, was it, like, how
many months they've left or how
many days left they have to
program?
Stage classification.
Are they on pre-launch, launch, or
post-launch?
You know, like, where are they
currently at in terms of, you
know, the service communication
assessment?
Like, when did you last have a
call with them?
Are they active on Slack?
You know, like, what's the level
of engagement here?
Are you proactive or reactive to
this client?
Performance metrics.
Like, what's their latest ROI?
What's their implementation status
percentage?
And what's their goal progress?
Like, where are they?
Like, how are they doing?
Like, it depends on the business
and the service.
But, like, if you're in the
business of helping people make
money, how much money should we
have we help them make?
If you're in the business of
helping people, like, fix
operations and save time, how much
time are we saving them here?
If it's, you know, so it just
depends on the business.
And then the SS, your CSM needs to
then give, like, a health score
sheet, like, a health score rating
out of 1 to 10.
One is, like, they haven't done
jack shit.
Like, this is the worst client
ever.
They're lazy.
They're not doing anything.
Like, they're going to fail.
Like, this person's bad.
Two, not far off.
Three, four.
Like, if any client is a four,
they should be marked in the red.
That's critical.
Like, they're a critical risk.
This person, we need to turn this
around very quickly.
Either we need to do everything we
possibly can in our power so that
we can uphold our reputation as a
company.
Or we need to have a serious,
honest, hard conversation with
that client and, like, why they
are not doing and working as hard
as they possibly should.
Orange is basically your middle of
the road.
You're not doing bad, but you're
not doing great.
You're just fine.
And it's, like, cool.
We're not in a bad spot, but we
have definitely room for improve.
And we have an area here where we
need to, like, increase, like,
communication and strategy.
And we need to turn things around
quickly before they do go into the
red.
And then green is, like, healthy.
And then you want to also, like,
in these notes, too, leave, like,
strategic notes.
Current challenges, opportunities,
required actions, next steps,
issues for leadership.
This is your notes that you want
to give to either your head of
client success or the founder of
the company so they can kind of
get a bit of a, like, a deeper
insight of, like, what's the
situation there with these
clients?
Non-responsive clients,
significant missed deadlines and
implementation gaps, expressed
dissatisfaction, escalation
concerns, declining business
metrics, or ROI.
Inconsistent communication, some
miscommunicates, like, some
miscommitments.
Mixed results, both success and
having some challenges, requires
attention and support.
Consistive proactive
communication, meaning or
exceeding implementation
timelines, positive ROI, strong
relationship and satisfaction
indications.
That's how you scale it.
It's not really that difficult.
You just need to be very, very
honest about, like, what the
standards of the company are.
And that's where you, the manager,
need to set those standards of,
like, what is good and what is not
good.
When you're doing these health
score sheets, you should be
holding the CSMs accountable to
why this person is green.
Tell me why they should be in the
green.
What results are they bringing in
that is such an amazing ROI that
we should be reaching out to them
for, like, a case study, for
example.
And then what puts someone in
orange?
Which, like, because if they're in
the orange, their most likely
could be as well in the red.
You need to investigate these and
you need to troubleshoot all of
these sort of situations.
So when you're in your
one-to-ones, then, your first five
minutes health score overview.
You just kind of want to review
this portfolio and identify the
red flags and the opportunities.
Then you want to start going
through your red and orange
clients.
You want to deep dive this
significantly.
What's the root cause?
What can we develop?
What intervention strategies can
we apply here?
Then you want to go through the
clients that are in the green.
Because there's expansion
planning, case study
identification, best practice
extraction.
We can take something like, what
are these clients doing that's so
well that we can start teaching to
the other clients.
And then also, your clients that
are in the green are the clients
that are most likely to give you a
referral.
They're the clients that are most
likely to jump on a client case
study interview.
They're the clients that are most
likely going to stay.
So it's like, okay, what back-end
strategy are we going to do?
What feature or service or product
that we have that they don't have
that they could use at this point?
Like, how can we benefit them
more?
What package do we want to sell
them on to retain them so that we
can add even more value to them?
So they get an even bigger ROI and
it's an even more successful
working relationship.
That's what you want to get
through when you're going through
your health score sheets.
And that's why it's important to
have them done before you're
one-to-ones.
Otherwise, you're going to have
one-to-one calls with the guys and
it's going to be like, hey, what's
the hell's your week?
And it's like, it's good.
It's like, is it?
Okay, cool.
And it's like a fucking waste of
time.
So you need to, this is really,
really important.
I cannot stress this enough.
Power Hour Meeting Framework,
again, simple things like that.
First couple of minutes, just
figure out like what you guys are
going to be covering this week.
The manager or the founder on the
call should have an idea of what
you're going to be doing.
It can be a churn, reactivation
campaign, trust pilot collection,
health score updates.
And then you want to re-engage
like, you know, some clients that
are just like inactive or like
slow to response.
And then you just want to use the
last five minutes to kind of
click, collect feedback, track
numbers and share a document or
something like that.
You know, personally, I like to
just drop my notes in my Slack
channel where all my CSMs are.
Task Execution Sprint.
Yeah, that's pretty much this.
I pretty much went.
The Power Hour comes from its
consistency.
When the team knows every Monday
at 9 a.m.
They'll focus on specific
operational priorities.
These activities become habitual
rather than occasional, which is
true.
Like if you train your CSMs on
like on this, that they have to do
this on a regular basis, it kind
of also falls into like, you know,
secondhand nature.
So, yeah, doing this, you're going
to have more tasks complete.
You're going to have more team
engagement.
There's going to be more
efficiency and you're going to
like generate way more reviews and
testimonials.
So, Power Hour is like nothing to
be slept on here.
Individual CSM development then.
This is just for their, like your
personal one-to-ones there, you
know, call quality feedback,
client satisfaction, scored
feedback, goal progress, challenge
identification, specific
improvement areas, role-playing
scenarios, resource
recommendations and learnings that
you can recommend to them
specifically.
Industry knowledge and competitive
updates.
Again, you're the founder, you're
the manager, you should know
what's going on more than anyone
else.
You know what's also happening
across all the other CSM teams so
that you can give that insight to
these guys.
And then kind of like career
growth and opportunities, maybe
let them know like, hey, you know,
you can get some more referrals or
you upset all these clients,
you're going to make some more
money.
Process improvement, suggestion,
implementation, team contribution,
leadership potential.
And then next week's kind of like,
you know, your priorities and like
you're what we consider a
successful week given what that
criteria looks like.
Your team development and training
calls, communication excellence.
So, you can talk about how to
communicate with clients.
You can break down one of the
guys' clients.
If one of the CSMs had like a
really amazing call, you can do
that.
And sometimes, actually, if I have
a team training and I've really
nothing planned for whatsoever, I
like to just jump on FASM and take
a random call and say, boys, we're
going to watch this and we're all
going to review it together.
That's a really good
accountability metric, by the way,
because someone kind of goes, oh,
shit, my call is getting picked.
And I don't know if I did this
call right or wrong or what's the
feedback, but it's all
constructive because we're all
learning from each other.
You know, you can also do like
strategic business analysis, you
know, work on ROI calculators and
things like that, too.
And you can work on like
technology processes.
We can work on like updates,
dashboards, whatever it might be.
And then revenue generation
machines.
Also, with like the team training
and development, sometimes I
actually really like to do a book
club with some of the guys.
We have a massive section, I have
a module that I'll be developing
in this section called
Unreasonable Hospitality, based
off the book Unreasonable
Hospitality, because it is
actually one of the most important
books to client success
management.
But that's a whole separate
module.
Career progression frameworks and
things like that, junior CSMs.
You're considered a junior CSM
within their first year.
Your senior CSM is going to be
around 12 to 24 months.
And then you're like a lead CSM
or, you know, like a really
advanced CSM is going to be
someone past like two years and
things like that.
You know, this person can mentor
teams and you can like hand over a
lot of leadership abilities.
Senior CSM is going to be like,
you know, really strategic
thinking, like a real go-getter,
very good, solid portfolio, like
showed proper revenue growth.
So, yeah, there's just some
metrics there for you just to kind
of get a little bit of an
understanding of like what I
consider a junior, a senior, and a
lead.
And that way, the responsibilities
and the interactions and the
communication and the style of
your management can then change
over time.
Because as someone is more in that
senior position who's been in the
role for like two years, you know
then they're going to be pretty
rock solid then.
And you can actually then start
using that CSM to get more kind of
like SOPs kind of build out.
And you can kind of give them more
higher leverage tasks and things
like that.
Performance monitoring, KPIs and
things like that.
Client retention, you always want
to target like, again, this is,
these targets, these numbers here
are a very generalized business
kind of, you know, projections.
It's very hard to like, you know,
do it in very specific fields and
things like that.
So, this is just a very generic
like, hey, aim for the fucking,
aim for the stars if you land on
the moon.
Amazing.
So, yeah, client retention rate.
It should be about 75%.
You'd like to retain 75% of your
clients.
It's like, you know, you don't
want to be losing more than really
that.
You know, and like, and by the
way, client retention is kind of
different to churn.
Churn is kind of like, you know,
to a certain degree, people
leaving after like past due.
So, if you have an offer, for
example, where it's like, like
email marketing, for example, it's
like, we'll add $50,000 revenue in
90 days.
Like, if you hit that goal and the
client just still doesn't stay on,
I mean, like, you know, you can
look into certain factors.
But if that client leaves like 30
days in, that's like, you know,
like, that's how you really want
to like, you know, check in on
like your churn and be like,
right, that was a, that was a real
fuck up on our end.
Like, what went wrong there?
But yes, client retention, you
want to aim it to be about 75%.
You know, your net revenue
retention about 80%.
Your average client health score
is about eight.
Your NPS score plus 70.
You know, your CSM activity is
like, they should be completing
95% of their calls.
Documentation quality should be at
least over 90%.
Their response time should be less
than two hours.
And like proactive outreach, like
checking out their clients three
times a week, absolutely
important.
Business impact, expansion revenue
per CSM, referral generation, they
should be like, you know, at least
getting, you know, out of their
clients.
At least 25%, they should be
getting referrals.
They should be collecting 25% of
like referrals from their clients,
like minimum.
They should be aiming to get two
case studies a month.
And then they should be like, you
know, really like increasing churn
prevention metrics as much as they
possibly can.
Essential management tools,
Fathom, Typeform, Zoom, Calendly,
some sort of customer success
platform, whether you're using any
sort of CRM.
I mean, you can use ClickFunnels,
you can use Trello, you can use,
you can,
you know, whatever that you are
able to use and what you're
comfortable with.
Like some people like to use
Notion.
Some people also like to use, like
build out their own dashboards.
Some people like HubSpot, like
whatever works for you, like
Monday.com.
Like I don't care.
But something to track, like
what's happening with your
clients.
So even if you want to use a
Google Sheet, like that's no
problem.
And then of course, Google
Calendar as well.
And this is important too, so that
you can also see what's happening
with your CSMs.
Because if you use Google Admin
and Google Calendar, you can then
go through like your actual SSEs
or sorry, your CSMs like calendar
and see how many calls they're
doing and things like that as
well.
And then monthly performance
reviews.
Allow 30 days for full system
implementation to focus on
foundational elements, one week in
process.
So, you know, data preparation,
trend analysis, contextual
assessment, forward planning, and
then recognition.
So, you're always checking the
monthly performance of your entire
team.
You want to make sure that
everything is going in the right
direction and that there's
constant learning in portfolios.
There's constant forward planning
and that you're never really
taking your hand off the steering
wheel there.
So, and then scaling and
implementation.
So, as your customer success team
functions and grows, your approach
evolving, you know, that's also
going to change then too.
So, you're going to have process
integration for your power hours.
You know, you're going to have
foundation.
Again, this is just kind of a
recap here.
So, foundation setup, process
integration, quality control,
optimization, and then your team
structure is going to evolve from
there.
This is basically just a TDLR of
everything that you're working on.
And this is going to be some like
client count and things like that
as well, depending.
Just to start you off to give you
an understanding of like, if you
are hiring CSMs and when you're
going to like manage CSMs, like
what that sort of is going to look
like.
So, if you have 25 to 50 clients,
you're really fine with one single
CSM and manager support.
And if you have 45 to 90 clients,
you're going to look at about two
CSMs with, you know, specialized
roles.
And then 100 clients, you're
looking at a CSM team with like,
you know, a lead CSM and a
manager.
And then 300 clients, you're
looking at multiple teams with
specialized focused.
So, yeah.
Metrics after 30 days.
Team engagement should be about
90% high.
Process compliance should be 95%.
Health score integration.
So, making sure they're all
actually done is 100%.
And early warning systems for
yourself, then be able to catch
all this and catch like problems
with your client should be 100%.
You always want to be able to
catch them.
So, yeah.
This framework requires about 8 to
10 works of weekly management,
which is true, and delivers about
a 25 to 40% improvement in team
performance and client outcomes.
So, this is going to bring in a
massive ROI.
So, you can read more about this
in the document.
You can reach out to me if you
have any questions, if you're
inside Client Ascension or
Olympia.
And I'm happy to answer anything
you possibly need.
All right.
This is how you manage your team.
Take care.
Peace.
Love you.
Bye.