Yo, welcome back guys.
Here we're going to go through how
to onboard your CSM in an ideal
like 23 day kind of framework.
The faster you can get your CSM
onboarded, the easier your life is
going to be.
No one wants to take too long
hiring a CSM, though I will say it
is depending on the type of
service and product that you do
have.
And how dense it actually is.
And then it also depends on their
experience.
But this is my framework to get
someone up and running in about 23
days where I'm comfortable enough
letting them take onboarding calls
and client meetings and things
like that as well.
So it's kind of my comprehensive
structure of how I do it.
This is based off my own data of
me hiring a handful of SSEs at
this point and very much my
systematic approach.
The foundation principle is new
CSMs must master your onboarding
process before they even touch
your clients.
I cannot stress this enough.
Like you always want to start in
the order of the work that they're
going to be doing.
Like, again, if you're watching
these modules, you might be new to
client success management.
That's very fair enough.
But like one thing that I would
not do when you hire a success
manager is like train them on the
back end sales first.
Why?
They're not going to be doing any
back end sales for a period of
time.
The first thing they're going to
be doing is onboarding clients.
So therefore, train them on the
onboarding of clients.
Then what are they going to do
after onboarding clients?
They're going to take, you know,
they're going to take meetings
with the clients.
So train them on how to run a
proper, correct meeting with the
client.
And then later down the line,
they're going to be doing renewals
and they're going to be doing back
end.
So train them later at that point.
It's kind of very straightforward.
It all falls a very linear line.
But onboarding process is
absolutely first.
It also sets them up to understand
the product service.
They understand, like, what does
the customer journey look like?
They understand, like, what is the
client's first steps?
Like, what do we need to get done
first in order to get to step two
and get to step three and get to
step four?
And so on and so forth.
So the foundation of a successful
CSM development rests critical
insight.
So CSMs must thoroughly understand
and master the company's
onboarding process before engaging
with actual customers.
This isn't just preference.
It's backed by compelling data.
So, you know, the faster, you
know, the more they understand how
to get, you know, a client a first
quick win,
you know, they're going to be so
much better in terms of actually
providing results and actually
getting engagement.
And when new CSMs need to
understand the client journey from
day one, they develop the context
needed to provide this meaningful
support at every stage.
So, every fail CSM started with an
adequate onboarding knowledge.
Master this first.
Again, if your CSM does not know
how to onboard a client properly,
not only is the client going to
churn or is the client become
disengaged,
like they've lost all authority
and the business brand and
reputation is sunk as well on top
of it.
So, you should give your entire
CSM development program by
intensively onboarding mastery in
the first 23 days you create, you
have a CSM.
So, what you need to have before
you onboard a CSM is comprehensive
documentation.
You need to make sure that they
have all the document, all the
information, all the business
operations, manuals, breakdowns,
client workflows,
everything they can possibly get
their hands on.
It helps significantly more if you
have Loom videos, SOBs, or like a
Kajabi, or like a school, or
whatever it is.
It's like, but just video learning
so that you, the founder or
another CSM or the head of client
success in the company,
actually breaks down the business
methodology and the service
delivery and can even show some
like recordings of like examples
of client calls and interactions
that they've had
so that they can get even further
experience, especially the
onboarding process.
And then knowledge verification,
like implement rigorous
assessments to ensure complete
comprehension of the business
fundamentals and the onboarding
process.
Pre-onboarding requirements, so
yes, set up SOPs, documentations,
libraries, all of that, like it's
all kind of written there.
Also, show them client case study
interviews.
This is really, really important.
They need to see what a successful
client looks like.
They need to know the standards of
the company, of like what you
consider a case study result.
That's very, very important as
well.
They need to see clearly the
service delivery.
They need to see previous
onboarding calls.
They need to see the tool
navigation and system tutorials
for all the technology products.
So don't just give them SOPs and
like how to also talk to clients
and how to like do an onboarding
call and things like that.
They need SOPs of like how are
they going to manage their
calendar?
How are they going to set up
Calendly?
How are they going to manage
Slack?
How are they going to manage, you
know, cross-team communications?
Like, you know, how are they going
to handle like emailing clients?
And, you know, just the standard
things, like the small things that
you really don't think about on a
day-to-day basis,
because these are the things that
are going to keep coming back to
you with simple questions of,
or they're going to, you don't
want to, you know, onboard a new
CSM.
And then all of a sudden, like,
you know, two weeks go by and
they're like,
do I pay for Calendly myself or is
the company paying for Calendly?
Because I don't have a Calendly
and the client's asking for a
call,
but I'm just going to have to do
it manually through Google Meet
and things like that.
But if I do it through Google
Meet, the Fathom recorder is not
going to kick in.
See what I mean here?
You're going to run into all
these, like, annoyances if you
don't have your ducks in a row
before you actually hire CSM.
So make sure you're aware of your
tech stack.
Make sure that you're aware of,
like, all the, like, ins and outs.
And there's just a small one or
even two minute SOP videos just to
explain the simple stuff.
So client onboarding process, tech
stack tutorials, all these sort of
things.
You want to also give some, like,
different types of SOPs where it's
just you, the founder,
or, again, the head of client
success, whatever it is, just
breaking down, like, you know,
the company history, the missions,
the values, the target market,
competitive positioning.
You know, they should be able to
articulate, like, where you stand
in your market and where you're
currently at.
You want to also explain, you
know, service offering
comprehension, like, quizzes,
assessments, verify understanding.
Like, if you have a Google Form
quiz, anything like that, too.
That's also really helpful down
the line, whether you make it just
even a few minutes before the CSM
takes it.
But it's good to just have this
stuff locked and loaded, ready to
go, you know, before they get
onboarded.
So, again, if they pass the
onboarding process, hey, here's a
Google Form.
It's going to be, like, a quiz on
our onboarding process.
Just run it through there and let
me know what results you get, you
know.
You can see, you know, you'll be
able to see their submission and
their results,
and you'll be able to read and
evaluate their actual knowledge.
You know, again, same for the
onboarding process and client
interaction, kind of, like,
assessments.
Like, small little quizzes and
tests work really, really well.
So, new hires have immediate
access to well-structured
resources.
So, day to one-seventh, they just
want to get the foundational
learning and structure and have a
daily plan.
You know, you kind of want to make
sure, you know, again, sometimes
it's nice to do a one-to-one in
the morning and things like that.
I still like, when I onboard CSM,
to give them kind of, like, a
daily one-to-one.
That's my method because it's good
to get them on a call so they can
go over today's previous
learnings.
They can ask questions.
You can set expectations.
You can focus on what they need to
learn next.
You're just keeping an eye on them
on a day-to-day basis.
You want to make sure that they
have a goal, they have a plan,
they've mapped out, like, a KPI
kind of structure of what they
need to be doing on a day-to-day.
Otherwise, it's not very
beneficial if you're like, here's
all our SOPs, go watch them and
best of luck.
It's like, it's unmonitored, it's
untracked, there's no
communication, there's no
understanding of, like, what
you're expecting them to do in an
eight-hour working day, you know?
And sometimes as well, it's like,
if you give people all these SOPs
and all these videos and it's,
like, 14 hours of content, it's
like, yeah, they'll sit there and
they'll watch them and you'll see
that they watched it.
But it's like, you know, did they
just hear the video and watch the
video or did they actually listen
and learn from the video?
There's a big difference from
that.
So I like one-to-ones just even
for at least half an hour every
day with them just to ensure
quality that they're actually
taking in their attention.
And they're coming to me with
their burning questions that I can
answer for them.
You have to remember every day
that you answer a question for any
of these CSMs, they're getting 1%
better for every question you
answer.
So, yeah, you want to give them
some independent learning, but to
make sure it's structured and, you
know, that they actually have a
goal to get reached and what they
have a goal to actually finish and
get done.
And there's, like, a quiz at the
end of it, which is also very
helpful.
So you can split it in, like, a
morning 30 minutes and an end of
day 30 minutes.
Sometimes I like to just do a one
hour just off the rip because I
know I'm going to have probably
another call with them the next
day or at least the following day.
So you want to just go through,
like, business 101, methodology,
philosophy, case studies,
marketing position.
Like, they just need to learn
where they're at and what they're
doing and what the goal is.
Service offerings and packages,
that's next.
They need to understand, like,
what do we offer?
What's the package?
What's the deal size?
How long do you, what's the
customer contract length?
How long are they going to be here
for?
What's the goal timeline for until
they get their first win?
When should they get their first
win?
When should clients start really
seeing results?
You know, then you can go into,
like, the tech stack,
communications, the tools, project
management softwares, your CRMs,
your workflow integrations, all of
that sort of stuff then.
Now that they have a much better
concept of what it is the business
is trying to do, then all of the
tech stack is going to actually
start making sense.
And then it's going to be
integration and assessment.
Again, this is good time to send
them kind of like a test based off
of business and 101 service and
offering packages and the tech
stack.
So, implement daily feedback to
new CSMs to report their
confidence level with today's
material.
Score below seven indicate areas
of additional focus before
proceeding.
So, again, just ask them simple
things like, hey, out of a scale
of one to ten, how proficient do
you feel like you're in this
section?
The quiz will give you the real
answer.
That's the point.
Days eight to 15, this is like
mock calls and shadowing.
So, this is where you want them to
go through all of your call
recordings and breakdowns and all,
like, you know, watching your
onboarding calls in depth.
You want to send them, like, three
to five recordings.
You're going to ask them to watch
them not just once, but watch them
twice.
Tell them to start, like, planning
and mapping out their questions.
Why did you ask this?
Why did you ask this client this,
not this client that?
You know, you want to start
getting them to sort of really
thinking about it.
Especially if you provide your
service for multiple different
niches and offerings and services.
You know, again, if you're, like,
an ads funnel agency, for example.
Yeah, you do add some funnels for,
like, a lot of different B2B
businesses.
But some businesses are going to
have different funnel types than
other different business types.
Because there's a different market
trend or there's, you know, the
offer is more elite generation or
demand capture versus demand
generation.
Like, again, these little small
nuances here is everything that a
CSM needs to know and understand
to actually be applicable to their
role so they can actually do their
job properly.
You know, another thing that I
really love to do as well is a
live call breakdown.
So, you just get on Zoom.
You share your screen.
You open up a call.
And then you watch the call live
with them.
And then you can pause and break
down and explain why I asked this
specific question.
Why I held them, like, you know,
why I gave them this implication
question.
Why I dig deeper into this pain
point specifically for this client
when they're on the onboarding
call.
Why did I, you know, suggest to
them you should do this instead of
that.
Like, so because these are the
nuances that they're going to
learn and they're going to be able
to break down a lot more
effectively.
So, this is a really, really,
really effective way of teaching
someone live on a call.
And not to mention when that call
is recorded, you also have this
fathom recording.
So, then this fathom recording can
be a great further training, you
know, if the call goes well.
So, you can really start
compounding a lot of your SOPs and
a lot of your trainings.
And, again, through the AI Sys
Agency kind of, like, modules and
things like that as well, you'll
be able to actually start, like,
breaking these down and building,
like, really serious SOPs just
through all of these transcripts
and call recordings.
And then just, like, onboarding
document deep dive.
Like, just breaking down the
document.
Why we ask these questions.
What you need to ask in this
specific category.
How you're going to break down
your onboarding in specific ways.
Like, this is really, really
important, too.
Because they're going to
understand the flow.
They're going to understand, like,
to learn the documentation.
And there's patterns to every
single onboarding document.
There's, like, there's anchors
that I call them.
There's points in the onboarding
process where you need to stop and
take a beat.
Otherwise, you're going to
completely overindulge the client
with so much information that
their brain can't possibly take it
in.
You need to take a break to say,
like, hey, do you have any
questions?
Does this all make sense to you
right now?
Am I going too fast?
Do you need a minute?
Like, these little small moments.
And then there's going to be
potential moments in your
onboarding process where you're
going to upsell a client to a
certain thing.
Or you're going to offer a certain
package to a client.
Or you're going to understand how
they want to be coached and how
they want to be managed as a
client.
So, these types of deep dives are
very, very important as well.
So, they can see it firsthand.
So, first mock call that you're
going to do with your CSM.
It's going to be friendly,
engaged, you know, straightforward
business model.
No major complications.
Just basic flow.
You just want to get them into the
flow of things.
The second mock call is going to
be a little bit more challenging.
Maybe a skeptical or a hesitant
client.
Maybe a client has a certain
personality.
Again, use your own personal
experience from the time you
onboarded a client that was a
little bit maybe nervous.
You know, maybe they have a more
complex business situation.
Maybe they have two founders
involved.
You know, and then you want to
really test them on, like,
handling objections and kind of,
like, building confidence and
building authority onto that call.
Then, the third mock call is you
want to make this really
difficult.
You want to honestly make this
like an onboarding call from hell.
You want them to go through the
worst possible scenario.
You can tell your CSM I'm giving
you the worst possible scenario.
Tell them in hindsight, I'm going
to make this as difficult as I
possibly can for you.
And any mock call that you run
after that, give them that
situation.
You need to set them up for hell.
Because if you give them the most
annoying, heart, soul-crushing,
heartbreaking, like, mock call for
an onboarding that they're
possibly ever going to match,
the likelihood of them ever going
through that situation is actually
pretty slim to none.
But what you're doing them is
you're training them to now take,
like, go to war.
You're training them to go through
the worst possible situation and
how they manage to get themselves
out of that situation.
You want to be aggressive and a
demanding client.
You want to constantly mention bad
previous experiences.
You want to set unrealistic
expectations.
And you want to see how they
de-escalate the situation and,
like, align expectations for that
client.
So that's what you want to do
there.
And you want to just keep making
them more and more and more and
more difficult.
So that way, when they actually do
get a client and they're not
onboarding, it's going to feel
like a fever dream.
After completing the mock call
sequence, CSMs should shadow, you
know, I wouldn't even say at least
one live onboarding.
If you have more, as many as you
possibly can, they should honestly
be shadowing as many calls as they
can in many different scenarios.
Not just onboarding, but now's a
good time to actually now
integrate them into, like, you
know, client meeting calls or
check-in calls,
whatever it might be that you do
for your business.
It's just so they can actually
start seeing it.
And then you kind of want to run,
you know, a Q&A with them on one
of your next one-to-one meetings
of, like, hey, what are your do's
and don'ts?
Like, what are the do's?
Like, do you do this or do you
don't do this?
And just to kind of really start
tracking to see, like, you know,
how sophisticated their critical
thinking is developing within the
company
and, like, how well are they
understanding the product and the
service and the types of clients
that they're serving.
So conduct a comprehensive session
covering critical behaviors.
You know, critical do's always
confirm understanding before
moving forward.
Document everything during the
call.
Set clear expectations.
End with specific next steps.
Never promise the outcomes you
can't guarantee.
Don't skip discovery to rush to
solutions.
Never argue with clients about
their current situation.
Don't end calls without clear
follow-up plans.
Like, again, simple things like
this.
This is just all you're trying to
understand.
So by the end of this, CSM should
be able to demonstrate confidence
on the onboarding call structure,
show competency in navigating the
actual typical scenarios with
clients,
and then they can articulate the
purpose behind each question in
the onboarding process as well.
Again, you shouldn't be asking
questions on an onboarding call
that are not useless to the
onboarding call.
Very straightforward.
It's the same as being on a sales
call.
You wouldn't ask them, like, by
the way, what's your favorite
color?
Like, half which was a sales call
means fucking nothing.
So day 16 to 23, live interaction.
So now they're going to start
taking on some live calls.
Like, now you can actually kind of
start letting your CSM go through
an onboarding call.
You know, if you can, the manager
or the founder, listen into the
call.
Just join the call.
Turn your camera and your
microphone off.
Just sit there.
If you're on Zoom, which you
should be, by the way, you can
then, like, directly DM them.
Tell them to keep their Zoom chat
open so that you can guide them
through the call.
You just be a fly on the wall.
Don't say a thing.
Just pretend you're not there.
And just be there to guide them.
Give them live feedback on the
moment.
Tell them to answer certain
questions.
Ask this question.
Follow up with this.
This, and give them key
information about businesses and
nuances so you can guide them
through that call.
It's really, really effective if
you can do that.
And you're going to make their
first, second, and third
onboarding call much, much easier.
Because now they actually have,
like, a guide with them on the
call.
Don't worry about your client.
They're not going to get that
fucking weird about it.
I've done it many times.
People just go, oh, who's this
guy?
And they can just say, that's
Andy.
He's the head of client success.
He's just here for quality
assurance.
Cool.
No one cares that much.
It's not that deep.
And then, you know, if they can
get a few under their belt and
stuff like that, they're going to,
like, have increased independence.
They're going to now feel more
comfortable.
The first onboarding call is
always the most nerve-wracking.
After they get that done out of
the way, you can give them clear
feedback, instruction, support,
how they can improve, what they
did good, what they did bad, how
you're going to work on your
training in further detail.
Again, at this point, you should
still be doing, you know, at least
a handful of times a week, a quick
one-to-one with these guys, even
for half an hour.
I typically like to do it all the
way for 23 days.
When I hire a CSM, which we call
SSC as in client ascension, I'm on
a call with them pretty much four
days out of the week on a
one-to-one basis having a
conversation with them.
I'm at least on a call with them
where I can ask them, hey, do you
have any questions?
What are you working on?
What are you up to?
You should be having some sort of
call interaction with them all the
way up to day 23.
So it sets that up there, and you
can start working on real,
tackling real, you know, client
problem situations in a real-life
scenario, and it's no longer a
mock call.
They actually now are responsible
for that client.
Now, quality assessment, you know,
they can now do them
independently.
You can leave them to do it on
their own devices.
You know, they can establish
standards, you know, they
understand everything that they're
doing, and then you can go from
there.
So morning planning, review call
clients, client calls, prepare
strategy.
That's also helpful.
Post-call debriefs, you know,
conduct a quick 15 minutes.
What went well?
Maybe they can shoot you a loom,
maybe a voice note inside of Slack
or a quick message.
And then end-of-day reflection,
that's also really helpful there
as well.
If they can give you any sort of
insights, you can do that also in
the end-of-day type form as well,
by the way.
You don't have to worry about that
too much.
I'll explain that in how to manage
a client's success in a later
video.
So, yeah, this is pretty much what
you want to get nailed down after
23 days.
Their technical competency, their
communication skills, their client
management, their business
understanding, and their strategic
thinking.
This is just pretty much one you
want to have nailed down.
Just these five things.
If they can get these five things
nailed down in 23 days, you've
done a phenomenal job.
Even if they're even efficient in
these areas, you've done a great
job.
You know, because if they can get
up and running this quickly in 23
days, they're going to be in a
phenomenal position.
Because client success management
is one of these jobs where you
just have to wear multiple
different hats.
So, your seven-month kind of
mastery timeline here.
This is basically the timeline of,
like, when your CSM should start
hitting, like, all sorts of new
strengths.
Like, they need to get the basic
functions down and competency
down.
They need to get the onboarding
process nailed.
Standard communications in terms
of, like, whatever channels you
use.
Again, just a little heads up.
If your CSM has to text clients,
email clients, WhatsApp clients,
Slack clients, they're going to be
in for hell.
Just try and get all communication
into one channel.
But I'll break that down in
another video.
And basic problem identification
of escalation, they should know
how to, like, basically identify a
problem and, like, know how to
prevent escalation.
They should be able to do good
documentation and reporting.
And they should be able to use all
of the tools.
You know, success metrics,
complete calls without
supervision.
That should be done within 23
days.
Maintain client satisfaction
scores above an 8 out of 10.
You could do this by just actually
DMing your clients as the founder
of the company and saying,
Hey, how's everything going with,
like, Jack, your CSM?
How would you rate them out of 1
to 10?
Handle routines, issues
independently.
And then meet the documentation
and the communication standards
that you've set out for them.
So, month three, months, like,
three to six, they should be more
advanced in their proficiency.
They should have, like, strategic
thinking and client conversations.
They should have complete conflict
resolution and difficult situation
management.
They should be proactive in
problem solving and identification
and prevention of these problems.
They should be cross-selling and
expansion opportunity recognition,
team collaboration, knowledge
sharing.
Handle complex situations,
generate expansion revenue.
They should contribute to team
knowledge, and they should be able
to mentor any new members.
After month seven, I've seen guys
master the role in seven months.
Sometimes it takes a little bit
longer, but typically it's about
seven months.
Like, that's when they should be,
like, really high-level expert, a
genuine strategic advisor.
They should have taught leadership
skills and be able to give you
inputs of what's happening in the
business,
what's happening in the space,
what's happening with clients.
Like, they have a real pulse on
what's happening in the business
that they can give to the founder
to give, like,
opportunities for maybe new
products, new services, new
offerings, new packages, new price
points that we should be
delivering to clients
because, you know, you can be able
to work out and have an honest
conversation about, like,
what's the ROI going to be there
and involving that.
Like, process innovation, they
should be bringing new ideas to
the fold,
and they're actually going to
start having a genuinely really
strong impact into the business in
back-end revenue and retention.
So, yeah, onboarding, process
mastery, communication excellence,
client call execution,
back-end sales understanding,
conflict resolution skills, tough
love delivery as well,
critical thinking development, and
then strategic advisor excellence.
These is going to be kind of
across the board here.
This is kind of the roadmap that
you want to have in terms of your
CSM.
Step one, onboarding mastery.
Step two, communication
excellence.
Step three, client call execution.
Step four, back-end sales
understanding.
Step five, conflict resolution.
Step six, tough love.
Step seven, critical thinking.
And then finally, becoming a full
strategic advisor to your clients
to the point where they don't
really need the founder's input
anymore
because your CSM is doing such a
killer job at giving them good
feedback, ideas, and
implementation strategies
that they're already soaring and
getting a massive ROI.
So, implementation frameworks.
Here's your week one checklist.
Week two, week three.
So, SOPs, past knowledge basis
with, you know, past 90% score,
demonstrate service offering,
master tech, complete daily
one-to-one sessions with you, the
manager.
It says total of 10 sessions.
It should be more.
That's just a mistype on my
behalf.
Document any identifying and
leaning gaps.
Analyze, you know, onboarding
calls, breakdown calls, master
onboarding, successfully complete
all three mock calls
with, like, a decent rating, like,
you should feel somewhat good
about those mock calls.
Shatter at least one of the calls,
complete do's and don'ts Q&A,
conduct a supervised call,
handle client communications,
complete documentation, receive
client satisfaction,
demonstrate readiness and expanded
responsibilities, complete final
assessment.
So, this is all your pre-launch,
tracking and adjustment systems.
And, yeah, this framework requires
significant time investment.
You know, you're looking at, here,
about 40 to 50 hours of intensive
training and practice.
You need to actually put in the
time to train your CSM.
Unless you have a client success
team, unless you have other CSMs.
But if this is going to be your
first CSM, you need to buckle up
and get prepared.
It is going to do it properly and
to have actually set this client
success manager up
for absolute maximum success.
Yes, over the course of, like,
three to four weeks, you're going
to need to invest about 40 hours
into them.
Without a doubt.
Because if you don't, you're
setting them up for fail.
And if they fail, you're going to
get annoyed that they failed and
you lost customers and you lost
revenue
and you didn't get back-end
growth.
Like, it all compounds to the
money at the end of the day.
That's why this role is so
important to so many businesses
and why it really is the epicenter
for a lot of companies.
So don't skip it, your one-to-one
sessions.
Don't rush their interactions
before they're solid.
Don't have inadequate
documentation in your learnings.
And, like, you know, if you feel
like, if you realize that there's
an SOP missing, you need to make
that SOP very quickly.
You know?
And, like, don't, like, you know,
give insufficient practice
opportunities before live client
interaction.
Like, don't skip out on any of
these steps.
Because if you do, you're just
screwing them over.
And if they screw you over,
they're screwing the business
over.
It's very straightforward.
So just make sure that you
actually are willing to put in
this time.
Or you have a team member in the
company that can give them this
time.
So this focus approach eliminates
the trial and error learning
because that's why most CSMs fail.
Master onboarding and kind of go
from there.
So, yeah, accelerated time to
value.
Reduced failure rate.
Higher client satisfaction.
And team excellence and culture.
So, document everything while
you're doing this process, too, so
that you can, like, you know,
include it back in.
Loop it back in for the next CSM.
Refine continuously again.
So after you've, like, onboarded
this CSM, look back.
Give yourself some retrospect
here.
How are you going to improve this
process next time?
You're not going to get it perfect
the first time.
No one ever does.
That's absolutely fine.
But as long as if you can follow
this guide, you're actually going
to be half decent.
You know, how are you going to
extend the approach?
You know, you know, how are you
going to, you need to make sure
that you stick with this for the
seven month timeline.
And then, you know, you need to
measure and celebrate the success.
You know, track key metrics like,
you know, time to productivity and
client satisfaction.
And then just thank them, like,
give them a pat on the back.
Tell them they're doing amazing.
Like, keep encouraging them.
Keep giving them the confidence.
CSMs, when they first join,
especially the first CSM, is very
nervous and is very unsure if
they're doing the job properly or
inadequately in any sort of
capacity.
So, by giving them the reassurance
that they're on the right track
and they're doing all the right
things and giving them that
constructive criticism, but with,
again, the compliment, that's
really, really important.
For every piece of, like,
constructive criticism you need to
give to a CSM or really any
employee, you should also be
bolstering them up with a
compliment.
You need to meet your pair in pair
because if you keep coming to them
with constant criticisms, they're
just going to feel like they're
inadequate at the job and they're
going to already feel like
throwing in the towel because,
like, I'm obviously not a fit in
here.
So, that's pretty much that.
Remember, follow this.
New CSMs must master your
onboarding process.
That's my final tidbit.
Yeah, I hope you found this
useful.
I hope you now understand how to
onboard a CSM.
And this is my personal best way
to do it in 23 days or less.
All right.
See you later in the next video.
Peace.