So, let's talk about the number
one tip for effective email
design.
This is single-handedly the reason
why I'm here today,
being able to teach you about
email design.
It is purely from this, and that
is to steal.
So, don't have any shame in
copying layouts from emails and
brands that you like,
emails and brands that you know
are good at emails,
because if a big brand is sending
a certain type of email,
it's probably because they work.
So, don't reinvent the wheel.
Don't try to be too crazy.
Just stick with what has proven to
work.
Essentially, like, especially when
I was starting,
every single email I made was
literally carbon copy layout from
another email that I liked.
I would pull an image.
I would find an email, put it side
by side with my design,
and just copy the layout, and then
just replace the images and the
colors,
and it served me very well.
So, taken from the great Steve
Jobs,
good artist copy, great artist
steal.
We've always been shameless about
stealing great ideas.
And then, of course, Pablo
Picasso, good artist copy,
great artist steal.
So, I have no shame in that.
Steal, steal, steal.
So, here are 10 great email design
brands that are conversion focused
that you can steal from.
Casely, phone cases, Monk Pack,
they sell snacks.
Kizik sells food.
Duck Camp is clothing.
Magic Mind, they sell little
drinks, like shots of energy.
Magic Spoon, cereal, Olipop, soda,
Dr.
Squatch, men's, like, soap and all
that jazz.
Seed, they sell microbiotics.
And then Breeze, they sell, like,
sodas that are THC-based, and
their emails are super good.
We showed, essentially, all of
these, almost all of these brands
were in this slideshow at some
point.
So, make sure that you subscribe
to the email list, and you can use
these websites such as Milled.
So, Milled is just this massive
database of, like, 90% of
e-commerce brands in literally all
of their past emails.
Like, all of them.
It's pretty ridiculous.
If they go back to, like, 2018,
you can find brands' emails and
look at them and spy at them, and
it's always refreshing every day.
So, if you want to look at any of
these accounts, just go on Milled,
create a free account, and follow
all of these, and you'll just be
updated on as they send emails.
And then you can also just click
on any of them and look at all of
their past emails, all the ones
they've done in 2024, whatever you
want to do.
So, definitely use Milled.
And then Really Good at Emails is
another one where, exactly as it
sounds, it's just a database of
really good emails.
And so, they're just hand-picked
designs of all industries and
categories, so it's super easy to,
like, look at what type of, I can
just show you.
You can see what types of emails
you want, so you can click on,
like, Behavioral, and then go to,
like, Abandoned Cart, and then
you're just going to be shown
Abandoned Cart emails, which is
awesome.
You could look up, like, Industry,
if you want to do, let's talk
about Beverage, then there's a ton
of beverage emails.
So, super, super helpful there.
Really Good Emails is going to be
better for finding, like, specific
emails, like Abandoned Cart.
And Milled isn't going to be as
good at finding those abandoned
carts and industry-specific
things.
So, if you're looking for
something specific, I'd recommend
Really Good Emails.
If you're looking for a brand, I'd
recommend Milled.