Okay, so we have talked about the
microtopics and how we want to
educate the customer and we don't
just want to annoy our list with
discount sales sales sales sales
sales and all this stuff.
So I'm going to give you 29
non-discount email frameworks and
then some examples for a few of
them, about half of them, giving
two examples for each.
So that is what we are doing.
These are things that you can plug
and play and copy.
You could literally just follow
these frameworks and then just
repeat it over and over again if
you wanted to.
But later I'm also going to show
you more ways to get more ideas.
So 29 non-discount email
frameworks and examples.
Let's get into it.
So I already showed this.
I already went over this.
Education plus positioning equals
sales without discounts.
We want to educate the customer on
a problem that they could have a
process that we follow or a
solution that we have to any of
these problems and then position
our product just as that solution.
So educate and then also promote
our product subtly.
So these are all of the campaign
ideas, which you can screenshot
this, do whatever you want, take
the document, which you have
provided for you, and use these
over and over again.
You can lean on some more than
others.
Like there are a ton of different
benefit emails you could do, a ton
of different feature emails you
could do, a ton of different
frequently asked question emails
you could do, all that stuff.
Same as like trending and
testimonials, us versus them,
myths versus facts.
These are all emails that you can
continue to repeat.
So let's break down a few of them,
some of my favorites.
So first one is one benefit.
So that's the whole thing of the
email.
We are focusing on one singular
benefit that our product brings
for the customer.
Right off the top of your head,
for your product, you should come
up with 10 single benefits of like
going with you, going with your
product.
And so let's, you can create 10
emails off of that, just focusing
one by one.
We don't want to show everything
all at once for a lot of our
emails because then the customer
will kind of like forget all of
them.
We just want to drill into their
head one at a time.
Customer doesn't have a big
attention span, so we need to go
one at a time.
So why?
By highlighting the one benefit,
easy for them to know.
So we just want to dive deeper on
our product, whatever it may be,
and earn those trust points.
And so how, just write out 10 of
your, 10 of your benefits and then
just create an email about each
one.
If you want to have a chat GPT
prompt to help you come up with
some of these, you could just say,
we have this product for this
e-commerce store.
Our product is, put as much
information as you can about a
product.
It's verified, you ought to take
information from your website if
you can.
You could say, give me a list of
10 specific benefits about this
product.
So kind of to show you what I
mean, I have a couple examples
here.
So we have this example from Magic
Mind, super simple email, banish
festive fogginess, has a bit of
information, and then just showing
like step-by-step how to use our
product, has cool branding, good
design, releases dopamine.
And that single benefit is just
conquering brain fog.
That's the one benefit they
decided to drill in on.
And then we have this one from
Seed.
Their single benefit is getting
rid of bloat.
All they do is they say 61% of
people experience digestive
discomfort.
The good news, we have strains
that are proven to reduce your
bloating in two weeks.
That's the whole email.
And then we have just like some
testimonials right here.
It's just super duper duper
simple.
This is the benefit.
Use our product.
And ours is like the solution.
So that's just the one benefit
email.
Very nice and simple.
Very similar.
This one is one feature.
So rather than looking at like a
benefit of your product, we want
to focus on a feature of our
product.
Focus on the benefits, not the
features.
You always hear that.
Focus on the benefits, not the
features.
That's a flawed claim that gets
thrown around.
People want to know what's in
their product.
They want to know like the science
behind it when they're making
decisions.
Especially, again, if it's a
health product.
Even if you have a clothing
product, you can do different
features like our pocket.
You can have a whole email on like
your front pocket and how much
space it has in it.
Or your zippers, like how your
zippers work.
You can have all sorts of features
because those have benefits tied
into them.
And so people just love, people
love features of your product.
And so like why do you think that
every software out there has the
word like AI thrown on every
landing page?
They just, if you look at any
software, guarantee, go to their
website, they have AI in like one
of the main points because it's a
feature.
And people like features and stuff
like that.
So like every protein powder will
say the benefit, gain muscle.
But that's just so basic.
We want our features to make our
product like unique.
Because if you were to say like
gain muscle, which is the benefit,
that's the benefit, gain muscle.
But not everyone is going to say
pre-digested whey protein, which
people are going to find unique
and want to buy.
And so that's really what can set
you over the edge.
Your features are what make you
different.
All protein powders, they do the
same thing.
They have the same benefit.
It's all just to build muscle.
But each one has different little
mechanisms and features within it,
which make it special and why
people will end up buying from
them instead.
So how what you may think about
your product is common sense may
be unknown to your customer.
So if you've been in, to go back
to the supplement like protein, if
you've been in the industry for 30
years, you've been lifting weights
for so long.
And some of the stuff you think is
common sense, like for example,
like what creatine does for your
muscles or what instantized
creatine is or why you need to
take creatine every day instead of
just taking it every now and
again.
That could be common sense to you.
But the everyday person who just
found out about creatine last
week, they don't know that.
So how you can do this to really
like understand like your features
is just write out every material
or ingredient or a little feature
like your pockets, write it all
out.
Each one of those can be a
singular benefit that you can
highlight in the email.
So here's some examples.
So for this product, one of their
main ingredients is Tamanu oil.
Never heard of it.
Can't really read this.
Kind of difficult to see.
But it's pretty much just saying
what, like unlock the power of
Tamanu oil.
Hopefully I'm pronouncing that
right.
So you're just breaking down one
feature of your product and what
makes it special.
That's what is going to sell you.
And then, and they even break it
further and say like what are the
features of Tamanu oil.
So that's super effective.
And then also like this one, what
we mean by instantized creatine.
So creatine is instantized.
That's its feature, feature of the
product.
And so you're just breaking down.
What is it?
Usual creatine does this, but
instantized does this.
And that makes it this.
And here's how it can benefit you.
So those are the one feature
campaigns.
Then we have FAQ, which is very
similar to the others.
And you can have a ton of these.
So it's just what we're going to
find a common question from our
customer and then directly address
it.
FAQ emails that are quick.
You can have FAQ emails that
answer multiple questions as long
as they're quick.
But for longer ones, I like to do
a full email out of this.
So again, what may be common sense
to you may not be for your
customers.
So rather than drown out all of
our FAQs and making them all like
kind of random and creating a
super long email,
we just want to focus on one to
really get our point across.
This way, the customer has no
other choice but to agree because
we laid out all the facts.
Just think of yourself as an alien
on Mars who just came to Earth and
found out about your product.
What would they ask?
Gather data from your support
team.
Ask your support like what are
like the emails that we get
questions about the most and then
create emails out of each one.
You can also use ChatGPT.
Here's a prompt.
We have this product and this for
this brand.
Our product does this.
Give me a list of 50 frequently
asked questions about our niche to
customers that may have no idea we
exist.
So look at both of these examples.
When can I expect to see creatines
of X?
That is one frequently asked
question.
How soon can I see results?
Same as this one.
Can teeth whitening harm your
teeth?
Very common question, I'm sure,
for teeth whitening brands.
And so for this one, you're just
going into depth on this is when
you can see it and this is why.
And here are some tips.
And then recommended for you.
Super simple.
Overcome that objection.
And then same thing for here.
The truth behind teeth whitening.
Here's the problem with most.
The thing is like most teeth
whitening, they use this.
So it can be harmful.
But ours doesn't.
We are the solution.
See what I mean here?
By tying your product in as the
solution.
That is what can really set you
over the edge.
And then adding some social proof.
So there's that one.
Now let's go to what's inside.
So if you sell like a package or a
consumable good, explain
everything that comes with the
order.
That's super simple.
For example, your ingredients.
Kind of like we talked about
features.
Let's talk about what's inside and
like what maybe you throw extra
things into your order.
If you have a bundle, explain each
thing that comes in the bundle.
This is a great email that you can
send.
So people just want to know
exactly what they're getting.
It helps clear some of the
uncertainty that someone could
have before ordering.
We want to just clear as much
uncertainty up as possible.
So some brands, for example,
they'll give like free product
guides with every purchase.
That's like a free course with
like whatever.
But then they don't even tell
their customers about it.
That's a nice little bonus to get
somebody over the edge.
Be like, hey, if you order today,
we'll give you this free guide.
And then someone's like, oh, I
want this free guide.
That right there can be included
in like a what's inside email.
Just like, hey, when you order
this, you also get this.
If you sell consumable products,
you can list everything that you
have in it.
People want to know exactly what
they're putting in their body.
So just unpack everything in your
bundle of product and display it
in like a list format.
Just make sure it's skimmable and
easy to read.
So here's like an unboxing for
AG1, massive brand.
This is a great email.
There's so much to look forward
to.
You get this, you get this, you
get a shaker bottle, you get
packs, yada, yada, yada.
Super simple, super easy.
And then this one for supplement
brand.
Here are the seven ingredients
that are in our product.
Just listed out here.
Super easy, skimmable, and easy to
just check out.
Super good email.
Clears up a ton of uncertainty.
Another one is how it's made.
So an email just explaining the
creation process of your product.
Similar to before.
Maybe common sense to you.
Maybe not be for your average
customer.
For example, if you have a
filtration process for like a
certain ingredient like beer.
These aren't emails, but I thought
these were great graphics.
If you have like a filtration
process that like you, the process
takes it through like three
different filters to like make
sure it's safe.
But then you don't tell customers.
They're going to always question
the safety of your product.
But that right there, just by
explaining how it's made, here's
how we take it from here.
It proves the quality of your
product.
And it's also super interesting to
see that laid out.
This also gives your product a
story and adds background to the
product that the customer will
soon have in their hands.
So when they look at their
product, it's not just like this
appeared in my hand.
It has a story.
It went from here to here to here.
And now it's in my hand.
It's a lot cooler.
And it creates a full customer
journey.
So, and then how, just list out
every step of your process from
material gathering to the factory
to warehouse to shipment.
Talk about the process or
highlight parts about it.
Different ones like this.
Like step by step, lay them out so
the customer can see it.
Super interesting.
And then one, how to use.
Again, this is super
straightforward, but super
effective.
So just a step by step product of
how to use your product.
So why?
We just want to be as clear as
possible with our prospects.
Remove as much uncertainty as
possible.
We don't want to leave things to
their imagination because then
they're going to overcomplicate
things.
We all know you love to
overcomplicate things.
So let's remove uncertainty by
explaining how to use our product.
And a bonus if you can explain
like how to get the most out of
your product, which we can talk
about here with this example.
But how?
Just use your product yourself and
share the steps that you follow.
If you have a tough time
explaining it, you can alter this
to be how to get the most out of
your product.
Or if you sell clothing, you could
say like how to style your
product.
Those are all things that you can
do.
So a couple examples, how to pull
a shot of espresso.
So probably a common objection for
this brand is just like I don't
know how to – why would I buy this
product if I don't even really
know how to do this?
And so they have like an article
of doing like how to pull a shot
of espresso.
What's the best recipe?
So people can know how much like
ratio to have different stuff and
how to prepare it.
Super effective in getting people
to realize it's not that hard and
get them to purchase.
And then how to get the most out
of your product.
So even if it's super
straightforward like how to spray
a perfume, that's super
straightforward for like how to
use it.
Just say how to get the most out
of it.
So tip number one, protect your
perfume from direct light.
Avoid the bathroom.
Store in a fragrance in a dry
place.
Keep your perfume in a place with
consistent temperature.
Like these are all tips where it
can prove to people that like it's
just bringing value to them,
building trust points.
You're not heavy selling them.
So those are all very effective.
And then we have back in stock.
So if you have a product back in
stock, create a full email or two
about it.
Just let people know of that.
But even if you don't have a
product back in stock, just get
some new products in.
Maybe put like an extra shipment
in even though you never really
went out of stock.
Just use the angle of back in
stock because it works really
well.
If something is back in stock,
that means it went out of stock.
And if something went out of
stock, that means it's popular.
And that means it may likely go
out of stock again, which is
urgency.
So the back in stock angle mixes
popularity and urgency at once.
So even if a product, again,
didn't necessarily go out of
stock, you'd still use this angle.
So this is one of my favorites to
do.
So keep track of when you get new
products in.
Just create a feature product.
You don't even necessarily need to
do that.
You can just say back in stock
whenever you want.
So here's an example.
The Spidey Suds is back.
This has returned.
You could say limited time only.
That adds urgency.
So then just product feature here.
And then just another example.
The full glass is back.
And it's in this style.
That's also something that you can
do and just feature whatever your
style is.
So just always do back in stock
emails now and again.
And then straightforward trending
products.
Feature email on what products are
performing well on that month.
These work because the customer
just likes to be updated on trends
and popular products, what's going
on.
But one thing that I don't see a
lot of people do too much is doing
future trending.
Not just saying, here's what's
been popular in the past six
months.
You want to say, here's what's
popular this upcoming season.
Or here's, we noticed that this
trend is going to be new and it's
up and coming.
You want to frame it as like,
here's what's going on.
Instead of saying, like for
summer, trending email, you don't
want to say, here's what was
popular last summer.
That was last summer.
Shit changes.
You want to be, here's what's
trending this summer.
Here's like the newest trend for
summer going.
Here's the trend that's going to
take over the rest of summer.
You really can't send too many of
these emails.
They're a great way to make you
stand out.
So just pick a product or
collection you want to highlight,
feature those, and just create
trending off of it.
You could also, bonus points, if
you create like a curated
collection for the customer.
Inside of Shopify or whatever
platform you're using, create a
custom collection for like the
trending or a different category
that you want.
So for this example right here,
this was a special Shopify page.
It was new and trending.
It was checker cases, 2024's
hottest case, number one
bestseller this year, and just
created like a new collection page
for this, just linking people to
that page.
And then they're also saying now
in stock, even though this has
always been in stock.
So that's always angle that you
can use.
And then another example is like
trending.
It's just like green, green for
spring.
This is something where you're
just showing off green products.
These are trending right now.
Also something that you can do and
is very effective.
Reviews and testimonials, probably
one of my favorites, if not the
favorite, just because it's so
straightforward, so easy, but so
effective.
Always is.
But people just don't really send
testimonial emails that often.
Don't know why.
So testimonials just do a few
things.
They prove that you're a legit
brand and you deliver your
products to people, which is going
to overcome some doubt in people.
And two, they also show that other
people are fans of your brand.
And as you know, humans like to
follow the herd.
As hearing others who took the
leap, they made the risk of buying
from you and then they're happy,
customers more likely to.
So it's really important to pull
testimonials that actually address
like an objection that the
customer may have.
General testimonials don't do too
much.
Like this brand is awesome.
That's not going to do too much.
You want to say this brand or you
want to say like, I struggled with
acne for three months and I have
sensitive skin, but this is so
light on my skin, yada, yada.
Find a testimonial like that.
It's worth it.
You can even take social media
comments and integrate them in,
which this brand did, which I
think is awesome.
These are pretty general, but I
think it works kind of like for
the Instagram feel, general
comments.
But you can just throw them in any
email.
Over 30,000 five-star reviews
always feature that.
And then look at, there's only two
testimonials here, but they're
just really good testimonials that
are in-depth and they just prove
that people were passionate enough
to sit down, spend five to ten
minutes writing a review for this
brand.
Okay, they must be good.
So I love that.
And then us versus them.
This is an email just comparing
you versus your customer versus
your competitors or other people
in the industry just clearly laid
out.
So you probably notice this is a
theme with like our emails is just
displaying things super clearly
for the customer.
This is kind of a tougher one to
execute though because you don't
want to beg the customer for the
purchase.
Be like, these guys suck, but
we're great.
You lose frame and that just
increases your sales resistance.
It's kind of like pick me, pick
me.
So you want to be careful.
You just want to display the
facts, show them how you defer,
and then just help the customer
make the decision rather than be
like, you have to buy from us.
So how?
Just use a table.
Just laying out us versus our
competitor.
ChatGPT prompt, super easy.
This is what we use.
We have this product in this
niche.
Our product does this.
Then you just say, I'm creating an
us versus them email.
My brand versus another brand in
the industry.
Give me a comparison list
comparing unique selling
propositions with my brand versus
competitors to make my brand look
superior.
So here's like an example for food
delivery service.
Here's why we shine.
Here's us.
And then here's generic delivery.
And then also this one right here.
Another table.
Us versus them.
Here's us.
And then here's them like
faceless, bland, making us stand
out.
This is just a unique way to show
your benefits of why somebody
should choose you.
And then another favorite as well
is myths versus facts.
So going over common
misconceptions in your industry
versus what the facts actually
say.
So there are plenty of common
misconceptions that people can
have in your industry like we'll
see down here.
Similar to like an FAQ email, we
want to just address them straight
up.
You can ask your support team for
like what are common
misconceptions.
And then, yeah, and the bonus of
the myths versus facts email is
that myths versus facts is like a
cool headline.
That's an intriguing topic.
People like seeing myths versus
facts like did you know this?
This is a myth.
People like knowing that stuff.
So usually overcoming objections,
easy way to make sales.
So just think about your common
misconceptions and compare them
side by side versus the
misconception versus the fact.
So here's a common chat GPT prompt
that you can use.
Again, talk about your product and
then say I'm creating myths versus
facts email campaign.
Give me three myths versus facts
about my industry that I can
include in this email.
Here's an example for the
sunscreen.
Myth, it's impossible to get
sunscreen on my kiddos.
Kiddos love applying this thing.
Thanks to the super fun texture
and consistency.
Sunscreen and sweating don't mix.
And then you could say like our
product does this.
Sunscreen mist always leaves a
white cast.
Nope, we don't.
Same sort of thing here.
Facts and then myths right here.
So super clearly laid out, easy
for the customer to see and read.
And then the blog promo.
So most brands will have a blog,
have some sort of blog.
So all we can do is we can create
an email about this blog.
Now this is going to make sales
because blogs are on your website.
And if you can get people to click
onto a blog, it's super easy for
them at that point to just click
the logo in the top of your
website and then that takes them
to go shop.
So what we really want to do in
this email is like give a sneak
peek on the blog to encourage site
clicks.
So we want to optimize for the
click.
Just get people to click.
Don't give all the information on
the blog just right off the bat.
So it's all about engagement,
moving people down the funnel.
Someone clicks a blog, there's
more likely to go buy.
And also a good blog, if you're
creating good blogs, they're going
to promote your products at the
same time.
So it's kind of like a sales
letter for people anyways and you
get people to view that.
So it's also a nice change of pace
as well for your list to soft sell
them.
And like promoting a blog, it's
like non-salesy, but it's going to
result in a good chunk of sales.
So you're building goodwill, but
you're still making sales.
So how?
Just use a past blog, use an
intriguing headline, and then give
a sneak peek in the email.
Try to really sell the click.
Example right here.
The health benefits of olive oil.
Get the scoop.
You're teasing it right here.
And then there are a few
questions, get all the Q&A
goodness here.
They just give a few, they sneak
peek it, and then you can go read
more on the site, which is on the
blog.
Benefits of the bong.
That's a fun topic.
Are they really better than this?
Learn more.
Button right at the top of the
email in the header section.
And then here's some examples,
again, of educating, giving a
little bit of background, and then
learn more.
And then promoting some bongs down
here at the bottom.
Great example.
And then the last one here is
research study highlight, which
just is going to position yourself
as an authority.
So we just find a research study
published that relates to our
niche and promote it in an email.
So by promoting research studies,
you position your brand as an
industry leader, your thought
leader, you're on top of these
things, all that good stuff.
Now, it doesn't necessarily have
to be about your specific product,
like a research study on your
product, but it could be one just
in your niche or a material in
your product.
One way or another, you can
connect any research study to your
brand.
So you can look up on Google
Scholar or like ChatGPT around
your niche, read the abstract,
read the summary, and then just
create an email about that and
link people to that.
Just, again, you might not make a
ton of sales directly on this, but
you'll make more sales down the
line by telling people about this
study.
So you can say, we have this
product, you can ask ChatGPT to
find this.
We're trying to find a
professional third-party research
study related to our niche that we
can educate our customers about.
Can you provide me with five?
And then you can click through and
find the one that you like.
So new study reveals the soft link
between soft gums and
inflammation.
Soft gums, pathway to
What we found, here's the risk.
And then position your product as
the solution.
So this is linking to the research
study, whereas this, now we're
promoting our product and how we
overcome this.
Same sort of thing here.
Here's a research study.
What does the research say?
Read more, read more, read more.
And we're trying to just get
people to read a little bit more
and position ourselves as that
industry leader and people and
someone that you guys can trust
because we've done the research.
That's really what we're trying to
do.
Oh, actually, we have more.
We have the holiday email here.
So we're promoting a fun, a random
holiday that we can connect to our
niche somehow.
That's the email, the whole email.
So why?
Who doesn't love a holiday?
But we're not using typical
holidays for these emails.
Although you still can.
You can send, like, Christmas,
Easter emails, all that stuff.
But we're using random holidays
because there are random ones
every single day that you can
easily spin up and connect to one
of your products.
And just create a fun email about
it.
Connect it to your product.
Make it fun.
Make it exciting.
So you can use websites like Check
a Day and Blank Calendar Pages to
find holidays.
You can also use ChatGPT to say,
are there any random holidays in
this month that we can create an
email campaign out of?
Here's my product.
So those are always fun to do.
So, for example, this is the day.
It's Irish, National Irish Coffee
Day.
Whether you're in the mood for a
traditional taste, whatever, shop
now.
So it's just promoting their
product, which has this.
Easy way to just promote your
products without being too salesy
and giving people a reason to shop
your item.
Same thing.
National Hiking Day.
View this trail.
And this brand is probably getting
paid for the amount of clicks that
they get.
Same sort of thing.
National Hiking Day.
You can do this for clothing
brands.
If you sell hiking gear.
National Hiking Day.
Shop this.
Okay.
So here are 15 more campaign ideas
that you can use.
Progress update.
So share, like, recent updates in
the brand.
We've seen those perform well.
It really gets people close to the
brand.
Keeps the subscribers informed and
engaged.
You can do a customer
transformation, similar to the
testimonial, but really show,
like, a before and after of
somebody.
That's kind of what we have here,
before versus after.
The effectiveness of your product
before and after being used.
Puzzles and riddles.
That's something that you can do
with, like, brain teasers or
puzzles.
It's a fun break from the usual
content.
Note from the founder.
These absolutely crush it.
Just like, hey, this is X, the
founder of, I just wanted to
remind you of this, yada, yada,
yada.
Gift guide.
No matter the time of the year,
you can create a gift guide.
Like, hey, is it have a friend's
birthday coming up or marriage, a
wedding.
Here's a gift guide.
This is perfect for this person,
yada, yada.
Treat yourself.
Kind of similar.
These perform well.
Hey, you deserve it.
Buy.
Buy for yourself.
You know you want it.
Something like that.
Social proof email, like media
publications, where you've been in
the media, press coverage,
interviews, articles, whatever
like that.
Good form of social proof there.
Behind the scenes.
Take pictures, like, behind the
scenes in your factory or
whatever's happening.
That's an email that you can send.
Tips and tricks is another
valuable one that you can do in
your niche or your industry.
UGC content.
So anybody who's created content
for you, just feature what they've
put together.
You can have a sneak peek for
upcoming products, features, or
content that's coming up.
You can do flashback Friday or
throwback Thursday, like
historical content from the brand.
Like, this was us one year ago.
That's something fun that you can
do.
Staff picks.
So here's what we recommend.
Anything like that.
And then also, like, brand values.
This is a cool email that you can
do where it's just like, this is
what we optimize for.
This is what's important to us.
Are you with us?
Just to remind people of your
message.
So, that was a lot.
This was definitely a longer
email.
But hopefully that gave you
unlimited email content ideas to
choose from.
That's kind of my goal here.
But I'm going to show you how to
get even more for you here in the
next module.
But these are some of my
favorites.
Use them.
Reuse the ones that work.
And you're going to be printing.
All right.
So, I hope you got value from
that.
And let's move on to the next one.
Okay.
So, we have talked about the micro
topics and how we want to educate
the customer.
And we don't just want to annoy
our list with discount sales,
sales, sales, sales, sales, and
all this stuff.
So, I'm going to give you 29
non-discount email frameworks and
then some examples for a few of
them, about half of them, giving
two examples for each.
So, that is what we are doing.
These are things that you can plug
and play and copy.
You could literally just follow
these frameworks and then just
repeat it over and over again if
you wanted to.
But later, I'm also going to show
you more ways to get more ideas.
So, 29 non-discount email
frameworks and examples.
Let's get into it.
So, I already showed this.
I already went over this.
Education plus positioning equals
sales without discounts.
We want to educate the customer on
a problem that they could have a
process that we follow or a
solution that we have to any of
these problems.
And then position our product just
as that solution.
So, educate and then also promote
our product subtly.
So, these are all of the campaign
ideas.
You can screenshot this, do
whatever you want, take the
document, which you have provided
for you, and use these over and
over again.
You can lean on some more than
others.
Like, there are a ton of different
benefit emails you could do, a ton
of different feature emails you
could do, a ton of different
frequently asked question emails
you could do, all that stuff.
Same as, like, trending and
testimonials, us versus them,
myths versus facts.
These are all emails that you can
continue to repeat.
So, let's break down a few of
them, some of my favorites.
So, first one is one benefit.
So, that's the whole thing of the
email.
We are focusing on one singular
benefit that our product brings
for the customer.
Right off the top of your head,
for your product, you should come
up with 10 single benefits of,
like, going with you, going with
your product.
And so, let's, you can create 10
emails off of that, just focusing
one by one.
We don't want to show everything
all at once for a lot of our
emails because then the customer
will kind of, like, forget all of
them.
We just want to, like, drill into
their head one at a time.
The customer doesn't have a big
attention span, so we need to go
one at a time.
So, why?
By highlighting the one benefit,
easy for them to know.
So, we just want to dive deeper on
our product, whatever it may be,
and earn those trust points.
And so, how?
Just write out 10 of your
benefits, and then just create an
email about each one.
If you want to have a chat GPT
prompt to help you come up with
some of these, you could just say,
we have this product for this
e-commerce store.
Our product is put as much
information as you can about our
product.
It's verified.
You ought to take information from
your website if you can.
You could say, give me a list of
10 specific benefits about this
product.
So, kind of to show you what I
mean, I have a couple examples
here.
So, we have this example from
Magic Mind.
Super simple email.
Banish festive fogginess.
Has a bit of information.
And then, just showing, like,
step-by-step how to use our
product.
Has cool branding.
Good design.
Releases dopamine.
And that single benefit is just
conquering brain fog.
That's the one benefit they
decided to drill in on.
And then, we have this one from
Seed.
Their single benefit is getting
rid of bloat.
All they do is they say 61% of
people experience digestive
discomfort.
The good news, we have strains
that are proven to reduce your
bloating in two weeks.
That's the whole email.
And then, we have just, like, some
testimonials right here.
It's just super, duper, duper
simple.
This is the benefit.
Use our product.
And ours is, like, the solution.
So, that's just the one benefit
email.
Very nice and simple.
Very similar.
This one is one feature.
So, rather than looking at, like,
a benefit of your product, we want
to focus on a feature of our
product.
Focus on the benefits, not the
features.
You always hear that.
Focus on the benefits, not the
features.
That's a flawed claim that gets
thrown around.
People want to know what's in
their product.
They want to know, like, the
science behind it when they're
making decisions.
Especially, again, if it's a
health product.
Even if it's, even if you have a
clothing product, you can do
different features.
Like, our pocket.
You can have a whole email on,
like, your front pocket and how
much space it has in it.
Or your zippers, like, how your
zippers work.
You can, all sorts of features.
Because those have benefits tied
into them.
And so, people just love, people
love features of your product.
And so, like, why do you think
that every software out there has
the word, like, AI thrown on every
landing page?
They, they just, if you look at
any software, guarantee, go to
their website.
They have AI in, like, one of the
main points.
Because it's a feature.
And people like features and stuff
like that.
So, like, every protein powder
will say the benefit, gain muscle.
But, that's just so basic.
We want our features to make our
product, like, unique.
Because if you were to, say, like,
gain muscle, which is the benefit.
That's the benefit, gain muscle.
But not everyone is going to say
pre-digested whey protein.
Which people are going to find
unique and want to buy.
And so, that's really what can set
you over the edge.
Your features are what make you
different.
All protein powders, they do the
same thing.
They have the same benefit.
It's all just to build muscle.
But each one has different little
mechanisms and features within it.
Which make it special and why
people will end up buying from
them instead.
So, how, what you may think about
your product as common sense may
be unknown to your customer.
So, if you've been in, to go back
to the supplement, like, like,
protein.
If you've been in the industry for
30 years, you've been lifting
weights for so long.
And some of the stuff you think is
common sense, like, for example,
like, what creatine does for your
muscles.
Or what instantized creatine is.
Or why you need to take creatine
every day instead of just taking
it every now and again.
That could be common sense to you.
But to the everyday person who
just found out about creatine last
week, they don't know that.
So, how you can do this to really,
like, understand, like, your
features is just write out every
material or ingredient or a little
feature.
Like, your pockets.
Write it all out.
Each one of those can be a
singular benefit that you can
highlight in an email.
So, here's some examples.
So, for this product, one of their
main ingredients is Tamanu oil.
Never heard of it.
Can't really read this.
Kind of difficult to see.
But it's pretty much just saying
what, like, unlock the power of
Tamanu oil.
Hopefully, I'm pronouncing that
right.
So, you're just breaking down one
feature of your product and what
makes it special.
That's what it's going to sell
you.
And then, and they even break it
further and say, like, what are
the features of Tamanu oil?
So, that's super effective.
And then, also, like this one,
what we mean by instantized
creatine.
So, creatine is instantized.
That's its feature of the product.
And so, you're just breaking down.
What is it?
Usual creatine does this, but
instantized does this.
And that makes it this.
And here's how it can benefit you.
So, those are the one feature
campaigns.
Then, we have FAQ, which is very
similar to the others.
And you can have a ton of these.
So, it's just what.
We're going to find a common
question from our customer and
then directly address it.
FAQ emails that are quick.
You can have FAQ emails that
answer multiple questions as long
as they're quick.
But for longer ones, I like to do
a full email out of this.
So, again, what may be common
sense to you may not be for your
customers.
So, rather than drown out all of
our FAQs and making them all kind
of random and creating a super
long email,
we just want to focus on one to
really get our point across.
This way, the customer has no
other choice but to agree because
we laid out all the facts.
Just think of yourself as an alien
on Mars who just came to Earth and
found out about your product.
What would they ask?
Gather data from your support
team.
Ask your support.
Like, what are the emails that we
get questions about the most?
And then create emails out of each
one.
You can also use ChatGPT.
Here's a prompt.
We have this product and this for
this brand.
Our product does this.
Give me a list of 50 frequently
asked questions about our niche to
customers that may have no idea we
exist.
So, look at both of these
examples.
When can I expect to see creatines
of X?
That is one frequently asked
question.
How soon can I see results?
Same as this one.
Can teeth whitening harm your
teeth?
Very common question, I'm sure,
for teeth whitening brands.
And so, for this one, you're just
going into depth on this is when
you can see it and this is why.
And here are some tips.
And then recommend it for you.
Super simple.
Overcome that objection.
And then same thing for here.
The truth behind teeth whitening.
Here's the problem with most.
The thing is, like, most teeth
whitening, they use this.
So it can be harmful.
But ours doesn't.
We are the solution.
See what I mean here by tying your
product in as the solution?
That is what can really set you
over the edge.
And then adding some social proof.
So there's that one.
Now let's go to what's inside.
So if you sell, like, a package or
a consumable good, explain
everything that comes with the
order.
That's super simple.
For example, your ingredients.
Kind of like we talked about
features.
Let's talk about what's inside.
And, like, what maybe you throw
extra things into your order.
If you have a bundle, explain each
thing that comes in the bundle.
This is a great email that you can
send.
So people just want to know
exactly what they're getting.
It helps clear some of the
uncertainty that someone could
have before ordering.
We want to just clear as much
uncertainty up as possible.
So some brands, for example,
they'll give, like, free product
guides with every purchase.
That's, like, a free course with,
like, whatever.
But then they don't even tell
their customers about it.
That's a nice little bonus to get
somebody over the edge.
Be like, hey, if you order today,
we'll give you this free guide.
And then someone's like, oh, I
want this free guide.
That right there can be included
in, like, a what's inside email.
Just like, hey, when you order
this, you also get this.
If you sell consumable products,
you can list everything that you
have in it.
People want to know exactly what
they're putting in their body.
So just unpack everything in your
bundle of product and display it
in, like, a list format.
Just make sure it's skimmable and
easy to read.
So here's, like, an unboxing for
AG1.
Massive brand.
This is a great email.
There's so much to look forward
to.
You get this.
You get a shaker bottle.
You get packs.
Yada, yada, yada.
Super simple, super easy.
And then this one for supplement
brand.
Here are the seven ingredients
that are in our product.
Just listed out here.
Super easy, skimmable, and easy to
just check out.
Super good email.
Clears up a ton of uncertainty.
Another one is how it's made.
So an email just explaining the
creation process of your product.
Similar to before.
Maybe common sense to you.
Maybe not be for your average
customer.
For example, if you have a
filtration process for, like, a
certain ingredient, like beer.
These aren't emails, but I thought
these were great graphics.
If you have, like, a filtration
process that, like, you – the
process takes it through, like,
three different filters to, like,
make sure it's safe.
But then you don't tell customers.
They're going to always question
the safety of your product.
But that right there, just by
explaining how it's made, here's
how we take it from here.
It proves the quality of your
product.
And it's also super interesting to
see that laid out.
This also gives your product a
story and adds background to the
product that the customer will
soon have in their hands.
So when they look at their
product, it's not just, like, this
appeared in my hand.
It has a story.
It went from here to here to here,
and now it's in my hand.
It's a lot – that's a lot cooler,
and that's – it creates a full
customer journey.
So – and then how.
Just list out every step of your
process from material gathering to
the factory to warehouse to
shipment.
Talk about the process or
highlight parts about it,
different ones like this, like,
step-by-step, lay them out so the
customer can see it.
Super interesting.
And then one, how to use.
Again, this is super
straightforward but super
effective.
So just a step-by-step product of
how to use your product.
So why?
We just want to be as clear as
possible with our prospects.
Remove as much uncertainty as
possible.
We don't want to leave things to
their imagination because then
they're going to overcomplicate
things.
We all know you love to
overcomplicate things.
So let's remove uncertainty by
explaining how to use our product.
And a bonus if you can explain,
like, how to get the most out of
your product, which we can talk
about here with this example.
But how?
Just use your product yourself and
share the steps that you follow.
If you have a tough time
explaining it, you can alter this
to be how to get the most out of
your product.
Or if you sell clothing, you could
say, like, how to style your
product.
Those are all things that you can
do.
So a couple examples.
How to pull a shot of espresso.
So probably a common objection for
this brand is just, like, I don't
know how to properly.
Why would I buy this product if I
don't even really know how to do
this?
And so they have, like, an article
of doing, like, how to pull a shot
of espresso.
What's the best recipe?
So people can know how much, like,
ratio to have different stuff and
how to prepare it.
Super effective in getting people
to realize it's not that hard and
get them to purchase.
And then how to get the most out
of your product.
So even if it's super
straightforward, like, how to
spray a perfume, that's super
straightforward for, like, how to
use it.
Just say how to get the most out
of it.
So tip number one, protect your
perfume from direct light.
Avoid the bathroom.
Store in a fragrance in a dry
place.
Keep your perfume in a place with
consistent temperature.
Like, these are all tips where it
can prove to people that, like,
it's just bringing value to them.
Building trust points.
You're not heavy selling them.
So those are all very effective.
And then we have back in stock.
So if you have a product back in
stock, create a full email or two
about it.
Just let people know of that.
But even if you don't have a
product back in stock, just get
some new products in.
Maybe put, like, an extra shipment
in, even though you never really
went out of stock.
Just use the angle of back in
stock because it works really
well.
If something is back in stock,
that means it went out of stock.
And if something went out of
stock, that means it's popular.
And that means it may likely go
out of stock again, which is
urgency.
So the back in stock angle mixes
popularity and urgency at once.
So even if a product, again,
didn't necessarily go out of
stock, you can still use this
angle.
So this is one of my favorites to
do.
So keep track of when you get new
products in.
Just create a feature product.
You don't even necessarily need to
do that.
You can just say back in stock
whenever you want.
So here's an example.
The Spidey Suds is back.
This has returned.
You could say limited time only.
That adds urgency.
So then just product feature gear.
And then just another example.
The full glass is back.
And it's in this style.
That's also something that you can
do.
And just feature, like, whatever
your style is.
So just always do back in stock
emails now and again.
And then straightforward trending
products.
Feature email on what products are
performing well on that month.
These work because the customer
just likes to be updated on trends
and popular products, what's going
on.
But one thing that I don't see a
lot of people do too much is doing
future trending.
Not just saying, here's what's
been popular in the past six
months.
You want to say, here's what's
popular this upcoming season.
Or here's, we noticed that this
trend is going to be new and it's
up and coming.
You want to frame it as, like,
here's what's going on.
Instead of saying, like, for
summer trending email, you don't
want to say, here's what was
popular last summer.
That was last summer.
Shit changes.
You want to be, here's what's
trending this summer.
Here's, like, the newest trend for
summer going.
Here's the trend that's going to
take over the rest of summer.
You really can't send too many of
these emails.
They're a great way to make you
stand out.
So just pick a product or
collection you want to highlight,
feature those, and just create
trending off of it.
You could also, bonus points, if
you create, like, a curated
collection for the customer inside
of Shopify or whatever platform
you're using,
create a custom collection for,
like, the trending or a different
category that you want.
So for this example right here,
this was a special Shopify page.
It was new and trending.
It was checker cases, 2024's
hottest case, number one
bestseller this year,
and just created, like, a new
collection page for this, just
linking people to that page.
And then they're also saying, now
in stock, even though this has
always been in stock.
So that's always angle that you
can use.
And then another example is, like,
trending is just, like, green.
Green for spring.
This is something where you're
just showing off green products.
These are trending right now.
Also something that you can do and
is very effective.
Reviews and testimonials, probably
one of my favorites, if not the
favorite,
just because it's so
straightforward, so easy, but so
effective.
Always is.
But people just don't really send
testimonial emails that often.
Don't know why.
So testimonials just do a few
things.
They prove that you're a legit
brand and you deliver your
products to people,
which is going to overcome some
doubt in people.
And two, they also show that other
people are fans of your brand.
And as you know, humans like to
follow the herd.
As hearing others who took the
leap, they made the risk of buying
from you,
and then they're happy.
The customer's more likely to.
So it's really important to pull
testimonials that actually
address, like,
an objection that the customer may
have.
General testimonials don't do too
much.
Like, this brand is awesome.
That's not going to do too much.
You want to say, this brand, or
you want to say, like,
I struggled with acne for three
months and I have sensitive skin,
but this is so light on my skin.
Yada, yada, yada.
Find a testimonial like that.
It's worth it.
You can even take social media
comments and integrate them in,
which this brand did, which I
think is awesome.
These are pretty general, but I
think it works kind of like for
the Instagram feel.
General comments.
But you can just throw them in any
email.
Over 30,000 five-star reviews.
Always feature that.
And then look it.
There's only two testimonials
here.
But they're just really good
testimonials that are in-depth,
and they just prove that people
were passionate enough to sit
down,
spend five to ten minutes writing
a review for this brand.
Okay, they must be good.
So I love that.
And then us versus them.
This is an email just comparing
you versus your customer versus
your competitors
or other people in the industry
just clearly laid out.
So you probably notice this is a
theme with, like, our emails is
just displaying things
super clearly for the customer.
This is kind of a tougher one to
execute, though,
because you don't want to beg the
customer for the purchase.
Be like, these guys suck, but
we're great.
You lose frame, and that just
increases your sales resistance.
It's kind of like pick me, pick
me.
So you want to be careful.
You just want to display the
facts, show them how you defer,
and then just help the customer
make the decision rather than be
like,
you have to buy from us.
So how?
Just use a table.
Just laying out us versus our
competitor.
ChatGPT prompt, super easy.
This is what we use.
We have this product and this
niche.
Our product does this.
Then you just say, I'm creating an
us versus them email.
My brand versus another brand in
the industry.
Give me a comparison list
comparing unique selling
propositions.
My brand versus competitors to
make my brand look superior.
So here's like an example for food
delivery service.
Here's why we shine.
Here's us, and then here's generic
delivery.
And then also this one right here.
Another table.
Us versus them.
Here's us, and then here's them,
like faceless, bland, making us
stand out.
This is just a unique way to show
your benefits of why somebody
should choose you.
And then another favorite as well
is myths versus facts.
So going over common
misconceptions in your industry
versus what the facts actually
say.
So there are plenty of common
misconceptions that people can
have in your industry, like
we'll see down here.
Similar to like an FAQ email, we
want to just address them straight
up.
You can ask your support team for
like what are common
misconceptions.
And then, yeah.
And the bonus of the myths versus
facts email is that myths versus
facts is like a cool headline.
That's an intriguing topic.
People like seeing myths versus
facts, like did you know this?
This is a myth.
People like knowing that stuff.
So overcoming objections, easy way
to make sales.
So just think about your common
misconceptions and compare them
side by side versus the
misconception
versus the fact.
So here's a common chat GPT prompt
that you can use.
Again, talk about your product,
and then say I'm creating myths
versus facts email campaign.
Give me three myths versus facts
about my industry that I can
include in this email.
Here's an example for the
sunscreen.
Myth, it's impossible to get
sunscreen on my kiddos.
Kiddos love applying this thing
thanks to the super fun texture
and consistency.
Sunscreen and sweating don't mix.
And then you could say like our
product does this.
Sunscreen mist always leaves a
white cast.
Nope, we don't.
Same sort of thing here.
Facts and then myths right here.
So super clearly laid out, easy
for the customer to see and read.
And then the blog promo.
So most brands will have a blog,
have some sort of blog.
So all we can do is we can create
an email about this blog.
Now this is going to make sales
because blogs are on your website.
And if you can get people to click
onto a blog, it's super easy for
them at that point to just click
the logo in the top of your
website and then that takes them
to go shop.
So what we really want to do in
this email is like give a sneak
peek on the blog to encourage site
clicks.
So we want to optimize for the
click.
Just get people to click.
Don't give all the information on
the blog just right off the bat.
So it's all about engagement,
moving people down the funnel.
Someone clicks a blog, there's
more likely to go buy.
And also a good blog, if you're
creating good blogs, they're going
to promote your products at the
same time.
So it's kind of like a sales
letter for people anyways and you
get people to view that.
So it's also a nice change of pace
as well for your list to soft sell
them.
And like promoting a blog, it's
like non-salesy, but it's going to
result in a good chunk of sales.
So you're building goodwill, but
you're still making sales.
So how?
Just use a past blog, use an
intriguing headline, and then give
a sneak peek in the email.
Try to really sell the click.
Example right here.
The health benefits of olive oil.
Get the scoop.
You're teasing it right here.
And then there are a few
questions.
Get all the Q&A goodness here.
They just give a few.
They sneak peek it.
And then you can go read more on
the site, which is on the blog.
Benefits of the bong.
That's a fun topic.
Are they really better than this?
Learn more.
Button right at the top of the
email in the header section.
And then here's some examples,
again, of educating, giving a
little bit of background, and then
learn more.
And then promoting some bongs down
here at the bottom.
Great example.
And then the last one here is
research study highlight, which
just is going to position yourself
as an authority.
So we just find a research study
published that relates to our
niche and promote it in an email.
So by promoting research studies,
you position your brand as an
industry leader, you're a thought
leader, you're on top of these
things, all that good stuff.
And it doesn't necessarily have to
be about your specific product,
like a research study on your
product, but it could be one just
in your niche or a material in
your product.
One way or another, you can
connect any research study to your
brand.
So you can look up on Google
Scholar or like ChatGPT around
your niche, read the abstract,
read the summary, and then just
create an email about that and
link people to that.
Just, again, you might not make a
ton of sales directly on this, but
you'll make more sales down the
line by telling people about this
study.
So you can say, we have this
product.
You can ask ChatGPT to find this.
We're trying to find a
professional third-party research
study related to our niche that we
can educate our customers about.
Can you provide me with five?
And then you can click through and
find the one that you like.
So new study reveals the soft link
between soft gums and
inflammation.
Soft gums, pathway to
What we found, here's the risk.
And then position your product as
the solution.
So this is linking to the research
study, whereas this, now we're
promoting our product and how we
overcome this.
Same sort of thing here.
Here's a research study.
What does the research say?
Read more, read more, read more.
And we're trying to just get
people to read a little bit more
and position ourselves as that
industry leader and people and
someone that you guys can trust
because we've done the research.
That's really what we're trying to
do.
Oh, actually, we have more.
We have the holiday email here.
So we're promoting a fun or random
holiday that we can connect to our
niche somehow.
That's the email, the whole email.
So why?
Who doesn't love a holiday?
But we're not using typical
holidays for these emails,
although you still can.
You can send, like, Christmas,
Easter emails, all that stuff.
But we're using random holidays
because there are random ones
every single day that you can
easily spin up and connect to one
of your products.
And just create a fun email about
it.
Connect it to your product.
Make it fun.
Make it exciting.
So you can use websites like
Checkaday and Blank Calendar Pages
to find holidays.
You can also use ChatGPT to say,
are there any random holidays in
this month that we can create an
email campaign out of?
Here's my product.
So those are always fun to do.
So, for example, this is the day.
It's Irish, National Irish Coffee
Day.
Whether you're in the mood for a
traditional taste, whatever, shop
now.
So it's just promoting their
product, which has this easy way
to just promote your products
without being too salesy and
giving people a reason to shop
your item.
Same thing, National Hiking Day.
View this trail.
And this brand is probably getting
paid for the amount of clicks that
they get.
Same sort of thing, National
Hiking Day.
You can do this for clothing
brands if you sell hiking gear.
National Hiking Day.
Shop this.
Okay, so here are 15 more campaign
ideas that you can use.
Progress update.
So share, like, recent updates in
the brand.
We've seen those perform well.
It really gets people close to the
brand.
Keeps the subscribers informed and
engaged.
You can do a customer
transformation, similar to the
testimonial, but really show,
like, a before and after of
somebody.
That's kind of what we have here,
before versus after.
The effectiveness of your product
before and after being used.
Puzzles and riddles.
That's something that you can do
with, like, brain teasers or
puzzles.
It's a fun break from the usual
content.
Note from the founder.
These absolutely crush it.
Just like, hey, this is X, the
founder of, I just wanted to
remind you of this, yada, yada,
yada.
Gift guide.
No matter the time of the year,
you can create a gift guide.
Like, hey, is it have a friend's
birthday coming up or marriage, a
wedding.
Here's a gift guide.
This is perfect for this person,
yada, yada.
Treat yourself.
Kind of similar.
These perform well.
Hey, you deserve it.
Buy.
Buy for yourself.
You know you want it.
Something like that.
Social proof email, like media
publications, where you've been in
the media, press coverage,
interviews, articles, whatever
like that.
Good form of social proof there.
Behind the scenes.
Take pictures, like, behind the
scenes in your factory or
whatever's happening.
That's an email that you can send.
Tips and tricks is another
valuable one that you can do in
your niche or your industry.
UGC content, so anybody who's
created content for you, just
feature what they've put together.
You can have a sneak peek for
upcoming products, features, or
content that's coming up.
You can do flashback Friday or
throwback Thursday, like,
historical content from the brand.
Like, this was us one year ago.
That's something fun that you can
do.
Staff picks.
So, here's what we recommend.
Anything like that.
And then also, like, brand values
is a cool email that you can do,
where it's just like, this is what
we optimize for.
This is what's important to us.
Are you with us?
Just to remind people of your
message.
So, that was a lot.
This was definitely a longer
email, but hopefully that gave you
unlimited email content ideas to
choose from.
That's kind of my goal here.
But I'm going to show you how to
get even more for you here in the
next module.
But these are some of my
favorites.
Use them.
Reuse the ones that work.
And you're going to be printing.
All right.
So, hope you got value from that.
And let's move on to the next one.