Okay, now we're talking about
creating your campaign calendars.
This is going to be more important
than actually creating the
campaigns.
It's always the strategy and the
ideas behind your emails that
generate the most revenue.
It's always the strategy.
That's what carries the load.
So this is super important, but
it's also super duper easy once
you get good at it and
once you just have a ton of topics
that you know are going to
convert.
It's just about filling in the
blanks.
So let's talk about it.
This is the exact process that you
want to use when creating campaign
calendars.
So you have a ton of content to
choose from.
You have your chat GBT prompts.
You have a ton of bullets in the
chamber that you can fire and be
ready to use.
You have those non-discount
examples that I gave you.
All that stuff.
You have the swipe file.
You have everything.
So here's the process for actually
creating your monthly calendar.
So first you want to determine
your important dates and insert
into a calendar.
So I like to start with a blank
calendar.
Get my important dates whether
it's holidays, whether it's
product launches, whether it's
sale deals.
So if it's October, you have to
think like, okay, we have
Halloween and say you have a
product
release that's coming in October.
Awesome.
Put those base dates into the
calendar.
That's first because we need to
work around those.
So those are the main launches
that you want to do or the main
campaigns that you want to
put in.
add your supplementary emails to
those important dates.
So say you have Halloween and
you're running like a flash sale.
Okay.
Let's add in the launch.
Let's add in the reminder for the
sale and let's add in like a
closer for the sale.
So we have multiple emails.
So that's what you want to add.
And then like product launch.
Maybe you want to add a teaser for
the product launch.
Maybe you want to do like a
reminder or a low on stock email.
That's the kind of stuff that you
want to add.
And then at that point, it's just
fill in gaps to send three to four
per week.
Again, you can get away with two
You're going to get more revenue
if you do three to four.
But if you're busy, you can get
away with two.
But then you just fill in the gaps
with the topics that we talked
about and we covered.
And you really don't need to have
too much like you don't need to
spend too much time
thinking about that other than
putting your educational content
in and just keeping your
list nurtured and generating sales
without even really having to put
too much strategy
and time into it.
It's just what are the angles, the
education points that we can hit
and get the customer to
buy.
So step one, step two, step three.
Super easy.
So here's like an example for
Lululemon, which you'll have
walkthroughs.
I'll give a video of me live
adding this stuff for Lululemon
and then also Gymshark.
Those are going to be attached for
you so that you can watch those.
But let me just talk through this
really quick.
So Lululemon, this is March.
So let's look at the main events.
I don't know why this says brand
Nike, but let's look at these main
events.
So St.
Patrick's Day sale, they want to
do 20% off site-wide.
And then there's a new product
drop on Thursday the 28th.
So that's going to be the first
thing that we put in.
So we have the, this isn't
Lululemon.
This is Nike.
Okay, this is supposed to be Nike.
I'm going to fix that.
But, so we have a new product
release on the 28th.
This is hypothetical, by the way.
New product release, Nike Tech
Pants.
And then we've added the
supplementary email just right
here.
So that's step one and two is you
put the main event, Nike Tech
Pants.
You put this.
That's when the release is.
And then also St.
Patrick's Day.
We're running St.
Patrick's Day from the 15th
through the 18th.
Cool.
So we have those in the calendar.
Now let's add the supplementary
emails.
So this is the new release
reminder.
It's testimonials.
So people who have them already.
People who, maybe it's celebrities
who endorse them.
That's a supplementary email as
like a reminder for that.
Then also let's add like a
reminder for the sale.
These are the St.
Patrick's Day favorites.
And then a last chance.
So we have just a general promo,
favorites, and then last chance.
Okay, perfect.
Then after that, it's like, what
can we fill in?
So for something like Nike, you're
going to have a little bit more
product highlights,
a little bit less value.
They're already just like super
established.
But you can see, education-wise,
we have the science behind the
tech fleece.
Like how is it made?
What are the materials of it?
And what's the science behind it?
How does it keep you warm?
All that good stuff.
You also have tips for warming up
to avoid injury.
There's another value-based thing
that you can do.
And then a blog, running outdoors
versus indoors.
What are the things you need to
know if you're running outdoors
versus indoors?
Do you need to prep differently?
Do you need to have different
gear?
All that sort of stuff.
So we're linking to a blog here.
Then we have like a scientific
study outlining something.
So you can just go on, ask
ChatGBT, do you have any, what are
some recent interesting scientific
studies on working out that I can
send for Nike?
And then they'll find like a ton
of stuff like the role of
electrolytes and da, da, da, da.
And then just outline one of that
to bring value and position
yourself as an industry leader.
And then we have something like
the celebrity features.
Nike has a ton of those.
This is kind of like testimonial
and getting the celebrity's
audience.
It's a good way to get trust and
get association with that.
So we have that.
And then we also have just like
general product features in
promoting the product, like March
favorites, promoting what are the
best sellers for March.
Then you also have a restock on
like these shoes.
Restocks work really well because
if something is restocked, that
means it's sold out.
And so it's probably popular.
So those always do well.
So you have a restock.
The best selling tech fleece.
So a specific product.
And then favorite pants, which is,
and then we're doing a favorite
pants.
And then we're also teasing.
It looks like we're teasing these
pants as well.
So doing an email about, hey,
these are like our best selling
pants.
By the way, we have a new release
coming up Thursday.
And so, and then also just added a
free campaign, a hat, added an
extra sale, just like flash
sale of a free hat with orders
above $150.
Something like that is always nice
to throw in on the month to keep
your email list engaged
and giving them a reason to stay
subscribed if they're getting like
secret offers like this.
So that is Nike, the example for
them.
And then we also have Gymshark.
So let's take a look at like main
events that we're doing.
So we have Juneteenth.
This is for June.
And then it looks like one of the,
we have Father's Day as like a
main event.
So Juneteenth and Father's Day.
And then it looks like also a
release for Swim Trunks.
So that's what we're starting off
with.
We're starting off with, okay,
what are the dates we're doing
Father's Day?
What are we releasing at what day?
So we're sending the Swim Trunks
on this day.
And then we also have Juneteenth.
And so let's see.
Let's create the supplementary
strategy.
Let's start with Father's Day.
So we have Father's Day right
here.
Father's Day promo.
We're just, Father's Day is on the
16th.
So hey, get your father some gear.
There's nothing better than, if
you want to show your dad you care
about him, get him some gym gear,
yada, yada, yada.
Transformation Tuesday.
So this is like an educational,
cool community email.
Transformation Tuesday showing
like somebody's, they went from
this overweight to like this, now
they're jacked.
Show one of that, but it's
father-themed.
So go through and find like some
middle-aged men who had like a
great transformation wearing your
gear and feature them.
And then Father's Day last chance
is like, hey, Father's Day is on
Sunday.
It's your last chance to get
something in time for that.
And then having a note from the
founder, just being like, hey,
shout out all the fathers all out
there.
My dad was important to me, yada,
yada, yada.
You guys are what are shaping the
future.
Something like that.
That's very, it's good for the
community.
It's good for your brand.
Then we have Juneteenth, just like
an email for Juneteenth.
Just giving, giving a shout out
and helping with community there
as well.
And then Swim Trunks.
So we have a drop on the 6th for
Swim Trunks.
And so it looks like we're doing
a, we're dropping this tomorrow.
Looks like this, we had a tease.
So we wanted to add like a quick
tease at the bottom of the email.
Just being like, hey, we have Swim
Trunks coming out.
For the summer, be on the lookout.
And then on the 5th, we're fully
teasing them.
Being like, hey, this is dropping
tomorrow.
Be ready.
And then actually dropping them on
this day.
And then doing bestsellers.
So from the trunk drop, these are
the ones that are selling the
hottest.
So summer favorites, we're doing
two variations.
And we're splitting the email by
gender.
So for women, women's summer
favorites.
And then men's summer favorites.
And then let's look at Monday
Motivation as a recurring theme.
So every other week, doing Monday
Motivation.
Of just like a quote, Gymshark is
big on having inspirational stuff
and everything like that.
So doing Monday Motivation as a
recurring theme is a great way to
have your list expect something.
And this was like the NBA finals
were going on at this time.
So doing it from like an NBA
player.
And having another one and another
one here.
And another recurring theme of
Transformation Tuesday.
Which one is Father's Day themed.
And then the other one is just
like a regular transformation.
Which helps with, yeah.
And then we have some others.
So push day inspiration.
Bringing some value in terms of
like workouts.
Like this is what you can do for
your next push day.
And then having something like an
influencer testimonial.
Influencer testimonial for social
proof.
And also just being able to get
recognized with the testimonial.
Suns out, guns out.
Promoting tank tops.
Which is kind of more of a product
highlight email.
So there's less value in this
month.
It was a busy month with like
Father's Day.
And like a release.
And so less of value in terms of
here's how to get the most out of
this.
But a lot of community building
stuff.
Like Monday Motivation.
Transformation Tuesday.
Gym fit of the day.
Note from the founder for Father's
Day.
Things like that.
So this is also another route that
you can go.
But I'm going to drop some videos
for you to watch on me live
creating some calendars.
Okay.
Now we are talking about creating
your campaign calendars.
This is going to be more important
than actually creating the
campaigns.
It's always the strategy and the
ideas behind your emails that
generate the most revenue.
It's always the strategy.
That's what carries the load.
So this is super important.
But it's also super duper easy
once you get good at it.
And once you just have a ton of
topics that you know are going to
convert.
It's just about filling in the
blanks.
So let's talk about it.
This is the exact process that you
want to use when creating campaign
calendars.
So you have a ton of content to
choose from.
You have your chat GPT prompts.
You have a ton of bullets in the
chamber that you can fire and be
ready to use.
You have those non-discount
examples that I gave you.
All that stuff.
You have the swipe file.
You have everything.
So here's the process for actually
creating your monthly calendar.
So first you want to determine
your important dates and insert
into a calendar.
So I like to start with a blank
calendar.
Get my important dates whether
it's holidays, whether it's
product launches, whether it's
sale deals.
So if it's October you have to
think like okay we have Halloween
and say you have a product release
that's coming in October.
Awesome.
Put those base dates into the
calendar.
That's first because we need to
work around those.
So those are the main launches
that you want to do or the main
campaigns that you want to put in.
And then you need to add your
supplementary emails to those
important dates.
So say you have Halloween and
you're running like a flash sale,
okay let's add in the launch,
let's add in the reminder for the
sale, and let's add in like a
closer for the sale.
So we have multiple emails.
So that's what you want to add.
And then like product launch,
maybe you want to add a teaser for
the product launch.
Maybe you want to do like a
reminder or a low on stock email.
That's the kind of stuff that you
want to add.
And then at that point it's just
fill in gaps to send three to four
per week.
Again, you can get away with two
You're going to get more revenue
if you do three to four, but if
you're busy you can get away with
two.
But then you just fill in the gaps
with the topics that we talked
about and we covered.
And you really don't need to have
too much like you don't need to
spend too much time thinking about
that other than putting your
educational content in and just
keeping your list nurtured and
generating sales without even
really having to put too much
strategy and time into it.
It's just what are the angles, the
education points that we can hit
and get the customer to buy.
So step one, step two, step three.
Super easy.
So here's like an example for
Lululemon, which you'll have
walkthroughs.
I'll give a video of me live
adding this stuff for Lululemon
and then also Gymshark.
Those are going to be attached for
you so that you can watch those.
But let me just talk through this
really quick.
So Lululemon, this is March.
So let's look at the main events.
I don't know why this says brand
Nike.
But let's look at these main
events.
So St.
Patrick's Day sale, they want to
do 20% off site-wide.
And then there's a new product
drop on Thursday the 28th.
So that's going to be the first
thing that we put in.
So we have the – this isn't
Lululemon.
This is Nike.
Okay, this is supposed to be Nike.
I'm going to fix that.
But so we have a new product
release on the 28th.
This is hypothetical, by the way.
New product release, Nike Tech
Pants.
And then we've added the
supplementary email just right
here.
So that's step one and two is you
put the main event, Nike Tech
Pants.
You put this.
That's when the release is.
And then also St.
Patrick's Day.
We're running St.
Patrick's Day from the 15th
through the 18th.
Cool.
So we have those in the calendar.
Now let's add the supplementary
emails.
So this is the new release
reminder.
It's testimonials.
So people who have them already.
People who – maybe it's
celebrities who endorse them.
That's a supplementary email as,
like, a reminder for that.
Then also let's add, like, a
reminder for the sale.
These are the St.
Patrick's Day favorites.
And then a last chance.
So we have general promo,
favorites, and then last chance.
Okay, perfect.
Then after that, it's, like, what
can we fill in?
So for something like Nike, you're
going to have a little bit more
product highlights,
a little bit less value.
They're already just, like, super
established.
But you can see, education-wise,
we have the science behind the
tech fleece.
Why – like, how is it made?
What are the materials of it?
And what's the science behind it?
How does it keep you warm?
All that good stuff.
You also have tips for warming up
to avoid injury.
There's another value-based thing
that you can do.
And then a blog, running outdoors
versus indoors.
What are the things you need to
know if you're running outdoors
versus indoors?
Do you need to prep differently?
Do you need to have different
gear?
All that sort of stuff.
So we're linking to a blog here.
And then we have, like, a
scientific study outlining
something.
So you can just go on, ask
ChatGBT, do you have any – what
are some recent interesting
scientific studies on working out
that I can send for Nike?
And then they'll find, like, a ton
of stuff, like the role of
electrolytes and da-da-da-da-da.
And then just outline one of that
to bring value and position
yourself as an industry leader.
And then we have something like
the celebrity features.
Nike has a ton of those.
This is kind of, like, testimonial
and getting the celebrity's
audience.
It's a good way to get trust and
get association with that.
So we have that, and then we also
have just, like, general product
features in promoting the product,
like March favorites, promoting
what are the best sellers for
March.
Then you also have a restock on,
like, these shoes.
Restocks work really well because
if something is restocked, that
means it's sold out, and so it's
probably popular.
So those always do well.
So you have a restock.
The best-selling tech fleece, so a
specific product.
And then favorite pants, which is,
and then we're doing a favorite
pants, and then we're also
teasing.
It looks like we're teasing these
pants as well.
So doing an email about, hey,
these are, like, our best-selling
pants.
By the way, we have a new release
coming on Thursday.
And so, and then also just added a
free campaign, a hat, added an
extra sale, just, like, flash sale
of a free hat with orders above
$150.
Something like that is always nice
to throw in on the month to keep
your email list engaged
and giving them a reason to stay
subscribed if they're getting,
like, secret offers like this.
So that is Nike, the example for
them.
And then we also have Gymshark.
So let's take a look at, like,
main events that we're doing.
So we have Juneteenth.
This is for June, so we have
Juneteenth.
And then it looks like one of the,
we have Father's Day as, like, a
main event.
So Juneteenth and Father's Day,
and then it looks like also a
release for Swim Trunks.
So that's what we're starting off
with.
We're starting off with, okay,
what are the dates we're doing
Father's Day?
What are we releasing at what day?
So we're sending the Swim Trunks
on this day.
And then we also have Juneteenth.
And so let's see.
Let's create the supplementary
strategy.
Let's start with Father's Day.
So we have Father's Day right
here, Father's Day promo.
We're just, Father's Day is on the
16th.
So, hey, get your father some
gear.
There's nothing better than, if
you want to show your dad you care
about him, get him some gym gear,
yada, yada, yada.
Transformation Tuesday.
So this is, like, an educational,
cool community email.
Transformation Tuesday showing,
like, somebody's, they went from
this, overweight, to, like, this.
Now they're jacked.
Show one of that, but it's
father-themed.
So go through and find, like, some
middle-aged men who had, like, a
great transformation wearing your
gear and feature them.
And then Father's Day last chance
is, like, hey, Father's Day is on
Sunday.
It's your last chance to get
something in time for that.
And then having a note from the
founder just being, like, hey,
shout out all the fathers all out
there.
My dad was important to me, yada,
yada, yada.
You guys are what are shaping the
future.
Something like that.
That's very, it's good for the
community.
It's good for your brand.
Then we have Juneteenth, just,
like, an email for Juneteenth.
Just giving a shout out and
helping with the community there
as well.
And then Swim Trunks.
So we have a drop on the 6th for
Swim Trunks.
And so it looks like we're doing
a, we're dropping this tomorrow.
Looks like this.
We had a tease.
So we wanted to add, like, a quick
tease at the bottom of the email.
Just being like, hey, we have Swim
Trunks coming out for the summer.
Be on the lookout.
And then on the 5th, we're fully
teasing them, being like, hey,
this is dropping tomorrow.
Be ready.
And then actually dropping them on
this day.
And then doing bestsellers.
So from the trunk drop, these are
the ones that are selling the
hottest.
So summer favorites.
We're doing two variations.
And we're splitting the email by
gender.
So for women, women's summer
favorites.
And then men's summer favorites.
And then let's look at Monday
motivation as a recurring theme.
So every other week doing Monday
motivation of just like a quote.
Gymshark is big on having
inspirational stuff and everything
like that.
So doing Monday motivation as a
recurring theme is a great way to
have your list expect something.
And this was like the NBA finals
were going on at this time.
So doing it from like an NBA
player.
Then having another one and
another one here.
And another recurring theme of
Transformation Tuesday, which one
is Father's Day themed.
And then the other one is just
like a regular transformation,
which helps with, yeah.
And then we have some others.
So push day inspiration, bringing
some value in terms of like
workouts.
Like this is what you can do for
your next push day.
And then having something like an
influencer testimonial.
Influencer testimonial for social
proof.
And also just being able to get
recognized with the testimonial.
Sun's out, guns out, promoting
tank tops, which is kind of more
of a more of a product highlight
email.
So there's less value in this
month.
It was a busy month with like
Father's Day and like a release.
And so less of value in terms of
here's how to get the most out of
this.
But a lot of community building
stuff like Monday motivation,
Transformation Tuesday, gym fit of
the day, note from the founder for
Father's Day, things like that.
So this is also another route that
you can go.
But I'm going to drop some videos
for you to watch on me live
creating some calendars.