Okay, so we had our campaigns
intro, now let's get into like
actually the strategy of
campaigns.
Again, campaigns, one-time emails
that we're sending to our list.
Okay, so how often do we want to
send our emails?
So I'm going to save you now three
years, over three years of A-B
testing on campaign frequency.
We've tested it all from two per
day for some brands to two per
month.
This is what we found.
So this is the different sending
frequencies kind of like you can
do, grouped in.
So sending one to two times per
week, customer kind of forgets
about you, anything less.
The customer doesn't really
recognize you in the inbox and
it's kind of just more of a shock
to see you in the inbox.
And so they're unable to form that
habit of just consistently opening
your emails.
It's not quite enough and you're
just leaving money on the table.
You get lower on subscribes and
this can be okay, but you're just
leaving money on the table.
We want to get as much money as we
can from our email list.
And so you're just leaving money
on the table.
You're not really getting the
customer too familiar and situated
with you.
And then let's go on the other
side of the spectrum.
Let's say five to seven times per
week where we're sending almost
every day.
You get higher on subscribes.
You get customers that can be a
little bit more annoying.
Dilutes the power of your
messaging.
So anytime you send something, it
holds less weight because you're
sending so often.
And then your revenue kind of
plateaus at a certain point where
you get diminishing returns.
Where sending, you have like a,
it's like an exponential graph and
then it like plateaus after a
certain point.
So the juice just isn't quite
worth the squeeze at a certain
point.
So that's kind of like where we're
at with like the, with sending
five to seven times per week.
Okay.
And then now going to sending
three to four times per week.
Get high revenue.
You're getting more off the table.
You're getting lower on
subscribes.
You stay top of mind with the
customer and every email that you
send is like equal weight and
impact.
Now, this isn't just like an
arbitrary number that I pulled out
of nowhere.
The three to four times per week,
we've tested different lists and
sending one list down,
sending like seven times per week,
another sending once per week, and
then another sending three to
four.
We got the highest revenue, the
lowest unsubscribed, and just like
the best response.
And this was on an eight figure
list.
So this is just what the numbers
say.
Listen to me if you want.
I'm just going off the numbers.
So kind of just like I like to
think of this as just like you're
sending once per week on Monday.
It's just like, what is this brand
doing in my inbox?
A customer is subscribed to on
average like over 40 e-commerce
brands, email lists.
You just get lost.
Whereas like sending four times
per week, you're able to build
that engagement.
You're able to like the customer
can be affiliated with you and see
you and like you.
You've strong branded content and
you're giving them value.
And then it's like, oh, hey, I
know this brand.
I like this brand.
So there's that.
So again, just once per week isn't
going to cut it.
They're exposed to over 70
different e-commerce brands every
day.
Younger audience can be even
double with just the amount of
brands out there like over one
week and the amount of ads people
are seeing.
There's like 490 different brands.
So it's very, very easy for you to
get lost in the mix.
And your engagement and your open
rate will drop as a result of
sending once per week,
which a lot of people don't
expect.
It's just the customer isn't able
to get in that habit.
This was the result from pumping a
client from 2x per week to 4 per
week.
Open rates, crushed it.
Same list.
Click rates, crushed it.
Placed order rates up.
Revenue up.
That's just, it's just what the
numbers say.
I highly recommend that.
But 2x per day, ramming content
down the customer's throat.
They get annoyed.
You want to send a healthy amount.
But more importantly, we want to
send the right content.
So that's what we're going to talk
about next.
If you only send sales-focused
emails at your audience, then
they're going to be annoyed no
matter how much you send.
Even if it's once per week.
They're going to be like, why is
this a sale?
Why is it just this?
But what about giving them value?
Giving them entertainment.
Giving them tips and tricks.
Things like that.
That's just the healthy balance.
If you can find that, you're going
to be able to print cash while at
the same time building a
passionate fan base and not
annoying your list.
So this is what we want our fans
to be.
We want them to be rooting for us.
So what to send?
Again, nobody wants the pick-me
type content.
That's kind of the vibe you give
off when it's just like sales,
sales, sales.
Just like pick me.
Buy from us.
You seem needy.
Nobody wants to buy from someone
needy.
Create sales resistance.
So we want to be altruistic.
We want to avoid asking for sales.
We want to make it seem like we're
better off without the customer.
We want to make them feel special,
but we want to make sure that
there's a balance there.
So by being altruistic and
avoiding asking for sales so
constantly, we avoid annoying our
list with discounts over and over
again in sales, sales, sales,
buyer stuff.
And also you position yourself as
like a sought-after brand who
doesn't need to beg for purchases.
And inherently, that proves to
people that you're legit.
If you're just sending valuable
content, you're sending good
content, just educating on your
product, people are like, huh,
they kind of know their stuff.
So like this is bad content.
You make people mad.
Good content.
Tips and tricks.
Message from the founder.
Watch out for this in your
industry.
Watch out for fluoride in your
water.
I don't know.
Something like that.
Our favorite picks for this.
What does this, what does creatine
mean?
What is creatine?
Stuff like that.
Educational stuff that the
customer will actually enjoy.
So this is where we want to be.
Education plus positioning.
We want to educate the customer
and then position them on our,
position our product as like the
solution.
So the modern customer today, they
want to do their due diligence and
they want to understand what
product they're buying.
We're kind of in like, especially
if you're in the health industry,
people want to know these things.
We're in like a health awakening,
what's the, health enlightenment,
there we go, history class.
So we want to remove as much
friction for them as possible in
that process.
We don't want to have them have to
go look at a ton of different
research studies and whatnot.
We want to give them everything
that they need.
So the content that wins in 2025
for getting sales, it's going to
A, educate the customer on a
problem, a process, or a solution.
It'll educate them.
And then B, it'll position your
product as the solution and as
the, as like the thing that ties
it all together.
And if you can do both, you'll
guide the customer, hold their
hand into making the right
decision, which is going with you
if your product's good.
And also you're going to earn
trust points in the process, which
are needed to make that buying
decision.
So with every piece of valuable
content you give the customer, you
earn trust points and you can cash
in on those trust points when you
ask for sales.
You're going to be able to cash in
on that if they don't buy
automatically.
So product education, promotion,
we want the right balance,
everything like that.
And that's for every email
campaign.
We want to have that balance.
So how we do that is we're going
to use micro topics.
This is something that I made up
that I've seen work the best,
which again, we're going to
continue to talk about.
So micro topics are just little
subtopics of information on your
industry, your process, whatever
it may be, and your product.
Just little subtopics of
information.
So this allows the customer to
digest the information easier
because it's easier to just learn
one little micro topic, get taught
one little thing rather than
trying to learn like 10 points in
one email where we're overwhelming
the customer.
That just doesn't work.
So each email, like we have to
understand also the customer, each
email is getting viewed for a
maximum of three to five seconds.
Nobody's sitting down annotating
their emails being like, oh, it's
time to check my email.
And no, that's just not what's
happening today.
People are checking their email
while they're at a red light.
As bad as it is, people will check
their email while they're driving
like that and just quickly,
quickly skim something while
they're waiting for the bathroom.
They'll just quickly check their
email.
So we just want to focus on one
specific point in each email that
our customer, who's brain dead
right now in that – not that
they're brain dead.
I'm not – just in that when
they're scrolling their phone,
they're brain dead.
They're kind of on autopilot.
So we just want to make it super
easy for them.
If we try to give them too much,
they're not going to get any.
But if we try to give them one
thing, they'll take that one
thing.
So just ask yourself when you're
creating your email, what is the
one thing I want my customer to
know after looking at this email?
One email, one topic, one
takeaway.
That's it.
And that is the micro-topic
philosophy in the campaigns that
you're sending.
And again, we'll go over this.
So customers, like back in the
day, this is like an easy example
that I think of.
It's like, oh, yes, the morning
newspaper.
I can't wait to read all these
long articles.
Awesome.
But now, like, customer, thanks
to, like, all these social media
platforms, they'd rather do weird
things than actually read.
And, like, nobody reads like that
in terms of, like, the younger
audience and people who are on
their phone.
They're not doing that to read.
People like reading, but when they
set time aside to read, the people
aren't setting aside time to read
their email.
So that is kind of the campaign
strategy that we're doing.
We want to educate and position
ourselves by sending good content
and by sending educational
content.
And how we do that is by sending
micro-topics.
And we're sending those three to
four times per week.
So that is the campaign strategy
that we want to follow.
Okay, so we had our campaigns
intro.
Now let's get into, like, actually
the strategy of campaigns.
Again, campaigns, one-time emails
that we're sending to our list.
Okay, so how often do we want to
send our emails?
So I'm going to save you now three
years, over three years of A-B
testing on campaign frequency.
We've tested it all from two per
day for some brands to two per
month.
This is what we found.
So this is the different sending
frequencies kind of like you can
do, grouped in.
So sending one to two times per
week.
Customer kind of forgets about
you.
Anything lasts.
The customer doesn't really
recognize you in the inbox.
And it's kind of just more of a
shock to see you in the inbox.
And so they're unable to form that
habit of just consistently opening
your emails.
It's not quite enough.
And you're just leaving money on
the table.
You get lower unsubscribes.
And this can be okay.
But you're just leaving money on
the table.
We want to get as much money as we
can from our email list.
And so you're just leaving money
on the table.
You're not really getting the
customer too familiar and situated
with you.
And then let's go on the other
side of the spectrum.
Let's say five to seven times per
week where we're sending almost
every day.
You get higher unsubscribes.
You get customers that can be a
little bit more annoying.
It dilutes the power of your
messaging.
So anytime you send something, it
holds less weight because you're
sending so often.
And then your revenue kind of
plateaus at a certain point where
you get diminishing returns.
Where sending, you have like a,
it's like an exponential graph.
And then it like plateaus after a
certain point.
So the juice just isn't quite
worth the squeeze at a certain
point.
So that's kind of like where we're
at with like the, with sending
five to seven times per week.
Okay.
And then now going to sending
three to four times per week.
Get high revenue.
You're getting more off the table.
You're getting lower unsubscribes.
You stay top of mind with the
customer.
And every email that you send is
like equal weight and impact.
Now, this isn't just like an
arbitrary number that I pulled out
of nowhere.
The three to four times per week,
we've tested different lists.
And sending one list down, sending
like seven times per week.
Another sending once per week.
And then another sending three to
four.
We got the highest revenue, the
lowest unsubscribed, and just like
the best response.
And this was on an eight-figure
list.
So this is just what the numbers
say.
Listen to me if you want.
I'm just going off the numbers.
So kind of just like I like to
think of this as just like you're
sending once per week on Monday.
It's just like what is this brand
doing in my inbox?
Because a customer is subscribed
to, on average, like over 40
e-commerce brands, email lists.
You just get lost.
Whereas like sending four times
per week, you're able to build
that engagement.
You're able to like the customer
can be affiliated with you and see
you and like you.
You've strong branded content and
you're giving them value.
And then it's like, oh, hey, I
know this brand.
I like this brand.
So there's that.
So again, just once per week isn't
going to cut it.
They're exposed to over 70
different e-commerce brands every
day.
Younger audience can be even
double with just the amount of
brands out there like over one
week and the amount of ads people
are seeing.
There's like 490 different brands.
So it's very, very easy for you to
get lost in the mix.
And your engagement and your open
rate will drop as a result of
sending once per week, which a lot
of people don't expect.
It's just the customer isn't able
to get in that habit.
This was the result from pumping a
client from 2x per week to 4 per
week.
Open rates, crushed it.
Same list.
Click rates, crushed it.
Placed order rates up.
Revenue up.
That's just, it's just what the
numbers say.
I highly recommend that.
But 2x per day, ramming content
down the customer's throat.
They get annoyed.
You want to send a healthy amount.
But more importantly, we want to
send the right content.
So that's what we're going to talk
about next.
If you only send sales-focused
emails at your audience, then
they're going to be annoyed no
matter how much you send.
Even if it's once per week.
They're going to be like, why is
this a sale?
Why is it just this?
But what about giving them value?
Giving them entertainment.
Giving them tips and tricks.
Things like that.
That's just the healthy balance.
If you can find that, you're going
to be able to print cash while at
the same time building a
passionate fan base and not
annoying your list.
So this is what we want our fans
to be.
We want them to be rooting for us.
So what to send?
Again, nobody wants the pick-me
type content.
That's kind of the vibe you give
off when it's just like sales,
sales, sales.
Just like pick me.
Buy from us.
You seem needy.
Nobody wants to buy from someone
needy.
Create sales resistance.
So we want to be altruistic.
We want to avoid asking for sales.
We want to make it seem like we're
better off without the customer.
We want to make them feel special,
but we want to make sure that
there's a balance there.
So by being altruistic and
avoiding asking for sales so
constantly, we avoid annoying our
list with discounts over and over
again in sales, sales, sales,
buyer stuff.
And also you position yourself as
like a sought-after brand who
doesn't need to beg for purchases.
And inherently, that proves to
people that you're legit.
If you're not – if you're just
sending valuable content, you're
sending good content, just
educating on your product, people
are like, huh, they kind of know
their stuff.
So like this is bad content.
You make people mad.
Good content.
Tips and tricks.
Message from the founder.
Watch out for this in your
industry.
Watch out for fluoride in your
water.
I don't know.
Something like that.
Our favorite picks for this.
What does this – what does
creatine mean?
What is creatine?
Stuff like that.
Educational stuff that the
customer will actually enjoy.
So this is where we want to be.
Education plus positioning.
We want to educate the customer
and then position them on our –
position our product as like the
solution.
So the modern customer today, they
want to do their due diligence and
they want to understand what
product they're buying.
We're kind of in like – especially
if you're in the health industry,
people want to know these things.
We're in like a health awakening –
what's the – health enlightenment.
There we go.
History class.
So we want to remove as much
friction for them as possible in
that process.
We don't want to have them have to
go look at a ton of different
research studies and whatnot.
We want to give them everything
that they need.
So the content that wins in 2025
for getting sales, it's going to
A, educate the customer on a
problem, a process, or a solution.
It will educate them.
And then B, it will position your
product as the solution and as
like the thing that ties it all
together.
And if you can do both, you'll
guide the customer, hold their
hand into making the right
decision, which is going with you
if your product is good.
And also you're going to earn
trust points in the process which
are needed to make that buying
decision.
So with every piece of valuable
content you give the customer, you
earn trust points, and you can
cash in on those trust points when
you ask for sales.
You're going to be able to cash in
on that if they don't buy
automatically.
So product education, promotion,
we want the right balance,
everything like that.
And that's for every email
campaign.
We want to have that balance.
So how we do that is we're going
to use microtopics.
This is something that I made up
that I've seen work the best,
which again, we're going to
continue to talk about.
So microtopics are just little
subtopics of information on your
industry, your process, whatever
it may be, and your product.
Just little subtopics of
information.
So this allows the customer to
digest the information easier
because it's easier to just learn
one little microtopic, get taught
one little thing rather than
trying to learn like 10 points in
one email where we're overwhelming
the customer.
That just doesn't work.
So each email, like we have to
understand also the customer, each
email is getting viewed for a
maximum of three to five seconds.
Nobody's sitting down annotating
their emails being like, oh, it's
time to check my email.
And no, that's just not what's
happening today.
People are checking their email
while they're at a red light.
As bad as it is, people will check
their email while they're driving
like that and just quickly,
quickly skim something while
they're waiting for the bathroom.
They'll just quickly check their
email.
So we just want to focus on one
specific point in each email that
our customer, who's brain dead
right now in that – not that
they're brain dead.
I'm not – just in that when
they're scrolling their phone,
they're brain dead.
They're kind of on autopilot.
So we just want to make it super
easy for them.
If we try to give them too much,
they're not going to get any.
But if we try to give them one
thing, they'll take that one
thing.
So just ask yourself when you're
creating your email, what is the
one thing I want my customer to
know after looking at this email?
One email, one topic, one
takeaway.
That's it.
And that is the micro-topic
philosophy in the campaigns that
you're sending.
And again, we'll go over this.
So customers, like back in the
day, this is like an easy example
that I think of.
It's like, oh, yes, the morning
newspaper.
I can't wait to read all these
long articles.
Awesome.
But now, like, customer, thanks
to, like, all these social media
platforms, they'd rather do weird
things than actually read.
And, like, nobody reads like that
in terms of, like, the younger
audience and people who are on
their phone.
They're not doing that to read.
People like reading, but when they
set time aside to read, the people
aren't setting aside time to read
their email.
So that is kind of the campaign
strategy that we're doing.
We want to educate and position
ourselves by sending good content
and by sending educational
content.
And how we do that is by sending
micro-topics.
And we're sending those three to
four times per week.
So that is the campaign strategy
that we want to follow.