ChatGBT for writing copy, save
yourself the mental bandwidth,
save yourself all the effort
of writing by using ChatGBT to
help you out.
These are the prompts and the tips
that I use to write copy and then
what all of my team
uses.
I'd say it's very, very rare for
our team to just like free ball
off the dome to write
copy.
A lot of times we're going off of
ChatGBT and using it to like help
influence what we're
writing and get ideas.
Now AI isn't perfect, obviously.
It's not quite there yet.
It's easy to tell if something's
fully written by AI and you just
like copy a prompt and
then throw it in and then just use
the copy.
I think we can all agree there.
It's pretty brutal.
ChatGBT isn't going to give you
the finished product where you
just copy and paste and then
you're good to go.
But we want to use it as a guide
and we want to use it as a
framework.
We want to be picking different
parts.
We want to be asking ChatGBT for
different options and then picking
and choosing your
favorites.
It's an iterative process.
Edits, asking ChatGBT to change
things around, all that good
stuff.
This framework that I'm giving you
is a really good place to start.
So there are two steps.
We need a prime ChatGBT with like
all of our brand info and
everything like that.
And then we have the prompt of the
actual, just like write this email
for me.
So we need to give it all the
information and you can create
custom ChatGBTs of like saving
different chats.
So you can have a chat saved where
you give all the information from
your brand.
But this is what I use.
I give it all the information.
This is from me taking things out,
putting new things in that I
noticed like through using
this thousands of times.
But I just say I'm going to give
you all this stuff.
I want you to process it so you
can later write email marketing
copy for me.
My e-commerce brand is this, we
sell this, here's our website,
yada, yada, yada.
Our mission and goal is to do
this.
So you're telling it what to
optimize for, what's important for
us.
Our brand is unique.
So you're giving it why we stand
out from competitors.
Our products are unique, again,
differentiating you from
competitors again.
And then we move to the customer.
My ideal customer is this with
this demographic.
They enjoy this, yada, yada, yada,
yada.
Then you talk about brand voice.
And then goals and aspirations of
the customer.
And then why the customers are
unique, such as like they're
gluten free or something like
that.
And then you just say, are you
ready to write copy?
So here's like an example.
This is for Gymshark.
I did this for Gymshark.
And I'm going through a full
example in this doc with you and
showing you the finished product.
So I'm giving you this.
We're called Gymshark.
We sell high quality gym apparel
meant for working out and also for
leisurely wearing.
It's also important.
Our mission and goal is, I just
took this from the website.
Our legacy was built in the weight
room.
Found it in love for training.
The passion continues into all our
gym clothes today, yada, yada,
yada.
We're unique because of this.
Really talking about the
technology and the quality.
Can't talk right now.
These are our ideal customers,
yada, yada, yada.
For brand voice, this is what they
want.
These are their goals and
aspirations, yada.
They're unique because the gym is
a way of life.
So JackCBT is understanding that
these customers really care about
the gym, okay?
And then the actual prompt for the
campaign, the email that you're
writing.
So this is what I always like to
say for making things clear and
concise and following all
of our principles and not because
sometimes JackCBT will show you
like a text-based email.
It's like 300 words.
I found out that this is the best
way to overcome it.
You say, I'm creating a
graphic-based email campaign with
minimal copy.
I've tried tons of different
variations, longer and shorter
than that.
This is kind of like the happy
medium.
So we're creating graphic-based
email.
This is the topic.
So give us some background.
Using the information on the brand
of the customer, I want you to
write a quick and punchy headline.
Then I want you to write a
slightly longer sub-headline,
which goes into two to three
sentences of body copy leading to
a shop now call to action.
Boom.
Perfect.
That is what we want.
So this is an example for
Gymshark.
Graphic-based email, minimal copy.
The topic is about our
bestsellers.
It's a bestsellers email and how
they are the MVP for you in the
gym.
They're going to make you feel
comfortable and break your
personal records using the
information, yada, yada, yada.
This is what the process was like.
After I gave ChatGPT that prompt
and those campaigns or that
information, here's what it spit
out.
You get the headline and then you
get body copy.
Meet your MVPs, Gymshark's
bestsellers.
That could easily be a headline.
Crush your goals, set new personal
records with a top-selling gear,
design for peak performance,
ultimate, yada, yada, yada.
Gym Companions.
Gear up, push your limits, and see
the difference.
And then it seemed a bit basic for
me.
So I was like, can you make it a
bit more unique?
Unleash your potential.
Gymshark's bestsellers.
Elevate your top pit.
Elevate your workout with our top
picks.
Love it.
Starts with a benefit.
Crafted to be your unique,
ultimate gym allies.
These bestsellers combine
cutting-edge innovation and
comfort.
Amazing.
Ready to transform your training.
That's a really good copy.
So I just said, can you make the
headline more conversational
rather than unleash your
potential?
So ready to meet your gym MVPs.
That is also a banger.
Let's see what I did.
Give me more options for
headlines.
So then it gave me like eight.
So it said, yada, yada, yada.
And so I landed with, your new
go-tos for PR day.
PR day.
So gym-goers would understand PR
day.
It's your personal record day.
So I explained that.
And then I said, amazing.
Give me body copy for that.
And then it said, smash your
personal records, yada, yada,
yada.
And then I said, give me options
for sub-headline.
Because at that point, this body
copy is good to go.
The headline is, your new go-tos
for PR day.
Body copy is going to be smash
your personal records with gear
that's designed to support your
every move.
Our best sellers provide the
perfect blend of comfort and
innovation, making PR day your
best day, ready to redefine your
limits.
Amazing.
And then I was like, okay, I kind
of want a sub-headline.
Give me options.
And then boom.
I have a ton of options here,
which I can implement.
And then here's what this finished
product looks like.
This is where I put the
sub-headline over product images
because I need a product section.
So this is what ChatGPT gave me
from the iterative process.
Your new go-tos for PR day.
Banger.
Smash your personal records with
gear that's designed to support
your every move.
Our best sellers provide the
perfect blend of comfort and
innovation, making PR day your
best day, ready to redefine your
limits.
Shop now.
And then to tie the products, this
is the sub-headline.
PR day dominance awaits.
And then we just copy information
from their website for product
images because we're doing a best
sellers email.
Banger.
ChatGPT helps me with this whole
thing.
I didn't just take the first
option.
Imagine if I took the first option
where it was just meet your MVPs,
Gymshark bestsellers, crush your
goals, and set new personal
records with our top-selling gear.
That's basic.
That's not Gymshark.
Instead of meet your MVPs, crush
your goals, these bestsellers are
your ultimate gym companions.
No.
We're saying your new go-tos for
PR day.
Smash your personal records with
gear that's designed to support
your every move.
Much more powerful.
Much more punchy.
We're going back and forth with
Gymshark.
Choosing what we're like and
taking what we like and getting
rid of what we don't like.
So, that is how you use ChatGPT.
That's the process and the prompts
that we use.
ChatGPT for writing copy.
Save yourself the mental
bandwidth.
Save yourself all the effort of
writing by using ChatGPT to help
you out.
These are the prompts and the tips
that I use to write copy and then
what all of my team uses.
I'd say it's very, very rare for
our team to just, like, free ball
off the dome to write copy.
A lot of times we're going off of
ChatGPT and using it to, like,
help influence what we're writing
and get ideas.
Now, AI isn't perfect, obviously.
It's not quite there yet.
It's easy to tell if something's
fully written by AI and you just,
like, copy a prompt and then throw
it in and then just use the copy.
I think we can all agree there.
It's pretty brutal.
ChatGPT isn't going to give you
the finished product where you
just copy and paste and then
you're good to go.
But we want to use it as a guide
and we want to use it as a
framework.
We want to be picking different
parts.
We want to be asking ChatGPT for
different options and then picking
and choosing your favorites.
It's an iterative process.
Edits, asking ChatGPT to change
things around, all that good
stuff.
This framework that I'm giving you
is a really good place to start.
So there are two steps.
We need a prime ChatGPT with,
like, all of our brand info and
everything like that.
And then we have the prompt of the
actual just, like, write this
email for me.
So we need to give it all the
information.
And you can create custom ChatGPTs
of, like, saving different chats.
You can have a chat saved where
you give all the information from
your brand.
But this is what I use.
I give it all the information.
This is from me taking things out,
putting new things in that I
noticed, like, through using this
thousands of times.
But I just say I'm going to give
you all this stuff.
I want you to process it so you
can later write email marketing
copy for me.
My e-commerce brand is this.
We sell this.
Here's our website.
Yada, yada, yada.
Our mission and goal is to do
this.
So you're telling it what to
optimize for, what's important for
us.
Our brand is unique.
So you're giving it why we stand
out from competitors.
Our products are unique.
Again, differentiating you from
competitors again.
And then we move to the customer.
My ideal customer is this.
With this demographic, they enjoy
this.
Yada, yada, yada, yada.
Then you talk about brand voice.
And then goals and aspirations of
the customer.
And then why the customers are
unique, such as, like, they're
gluten-free or something like
that.
And then you just say, are you
ready to write copy?
So here's, like, an example.
This is for Gymshark.
I did this for Gymshark.
And I'm going through a full
example in this doc with you and
showing you the finished product.
So I'm giving you this.
We're called Gymshark.
We sell high-quality gym apparel
meant for working out and also for
leisurely wearing.
It's also important.
Our mission and goal is I just
took this from the website.
Our legacy was built in the weight
room.
Founded in love for training.
The passion continues into all our
gym clothes today.
Yada, yada, yada.
We're unique because of this.
Really talking about the
technology and the quality.
I can't talk right now.
These are our ideal customers.
Yada, yada, yada.
For brand voice, this is what they
want.
These are their goals and
aspirations.
Yada.
They're unique because the gym is
a way of life.
So ChatGPT is understanding that
these customers really care about
the gym.
Okay?
And then the actual prompt for the
campaign, the email that you're
writing.
So this is what I always like to
say for making things clear and
concise and following all of our
principles.
Because sometimes ChatGPT will
show you like a text-based email
and it's like 300 words.
I found out that this is the best
way to overcome it.
You say, I'm creating a
graphic-based email campaign with
minimal copy.
I've tried tons of different
variations, longer and shorter
than that.
This is kind of like the happy
medium.
So creating graphic-based email.
This is the topic.
So give us some background.
Using the information on the brand
and the customer, I want you to
write a quick and punchy headline.
Then I want you to write a
slightly longer sub-headline,
which goes into two to three
sentences of body copy leading to
a shop now call to action.
Boom.
Perfect.
That is what we want.
So this is an example for
Gymshark.
Graphic-based email, minimal copy.
The topic is about our
bestsellers.
It's a bestsellers email and how
they are the MVP for you in the
gym.
They're going to make you feel
comfortable and break your
personal records.
Using the information, yada, yada,
yada.
This is what the process was like.
After I gave ChatGPT that prompt
and those campaigns or that
information, here's what it spit
out.
You get the headline and then you
get body copy.
Meet your MVPs, Gymshark's
bestsellers.
That could easily be a headline.
Crush your goals, set new personal
records with a top-selling gear,
design for peak performance,
ultimate, yada, yada, yada.
Gym companions, gear up, push your
limits, and see the difference.
And then it seemed a bit basic for
me.
So I was like, can you make it a
bit more unique?
Unleash your potential, Gymshark's
bestsellers.
Elevate your top pit, elevate your
workout with our top picks.
Love it.
Starts with a benefit.
Crafted to be your unique,
ultimate gym allies.
These bestsellers combine
cutting-edge and innovation and
comfort.
Amazing.
Ready to transform your training.
That's a really good copy.
So I just said, can you make the
headline more conversational
rather than unleash your
potential?
So ready to meet your gym MVPs.
That is also a banger.
Let's see what I did.
Give me more options for
headlines.
So then it gave me like eight.
So it said, yada, yada, yada.
And so I landed with your new
go-tos for PR day.
PR day.
So gym goers would understand PR
day.
It's your personal record day.
So I explained that.
And then I said, amazing.
Give me body copy for that.
And then it said, smash your
personal records, yada, yada,
yada.
And then I said, give me options
for sub-headline.
Because at that point, this body
copy is good to go.
The headline is, your new go-tos
for PR day.
Body copy is going to be smash
your personal records with gear
that's designed to support your
every move.
Our bestsellers provide the
perfect blend of comfort and
innovation.
Making PR day your best day.
Ready to redefine your limits.
Amazing.
And then I was like, okay, I kind
of want a sub-headline.
Give me options.
And then boom.
I have a ton of options here,
which I can implement.
And then here's what this finished
product looks like.
This is where I put the
sub-headline over product images.
Because I need a product section.
So this is what ChatGPT gave me
from the iterative process.
Your new go-tos for PR day.
Banger.
Smash your personal records with
gear that's designed to support
your every move.
Our bestsellers provide the
perfect blend of comfort and
innovation.
Making PR day your best day.
Ready to redefine your limits.
Shop now.
And then to tie the products, this
is the sub-headline.
PR day dominance awaits.
And then we just copy information
from their website for product
images.
Because we're doing a bestsellers
email.
Banger.
ChatGPT helps me with this whole
thing.
I didn't just take the first
option.
Imagine if I took the first option
where it was just meet your MVPs,
Gymshark bestsellers.
Crush your goals and set new
personal records with our
top-selling gear.
That's basic.
That's not Gymshark.
Instead of meet your MVPs, crush
your goals.
These bestsellers are your
ultimate gym companions.
No.
We're saying your new go-to's for
PR day.
Smash your personal records with
gear that's designed to support
your every move.
Much more powerful.
Much more punchy.
We're going back and forth with
Gymshark.
Choosing what we're like and
taking what we like and getting
rid of what we don't like.
So that is how you use ChatGPT.
That's the process and the prompts
that we use.