Okay, so we are talking about copy
here and we're talking about core
copy principle number
one, which first principle in my
eyes is skimmable, which we are
going to be talking about right
here.
So SCE, these are kind of the
three main pillars, the copy
principles that we like to follow
at my agency, which has served us
pretty well, which are skimmable,
clear and concise, and
then engaging.
So first one is what we're talking
about in this video, which is
skimmable, which is the
ease at which someone can briefly,
briefly skim your email.
So let's talk about it.
Time is money.
The customer is not sitting down
every morning and reading their
emails in depth like they
would like the morning newspaper.
It's just not what the modern
customer is doing today,
especially since most of the sales
that
are coming are going to be people
under the age of 50 and those
people aren't really reading
the newspaper and have the
attention spans like some other
older demographics would.
So we really only have a couple of
seconds of our customer's
attention.
Everybody, they're just quickly
opening their email and briefly
going through it.
So we need to understand that if
people cannot skim your email,
they're not going to bother
reading it.
So we need to optimize for the
skim and not the read.
Very, very important.
So how do we do that?
There are a couple main things
that we want to do.
First is we want to avoid blocks
of text.
Blocks of text just scare people
off.
They are terrified.
Inside it is the modern customer's
kryptonite is blocks of text.
So it's very difficult for the
eyes to like make out and process
blocks of text when we
only have a couple seconds of the
person's time.
So this just results in people
skipping past any type of block of
information.
So we really want to shorten our
copy or split it up in our text
with like line breaks in
different forms of graphics.
So when you're outlining your
emails like as far as like copy,
you really want to make sure
that you're splitting things up
for the designer.
So here are like two examples.
These could have been put in like
blocks of text.
But look, they're listed out.
One, two, three, four, five.
You can easily skim this.
Five ways nature supports mental
health.
Reduces the stress.
That's bolded.
Improves mood.
Improve attention and memory.
That's bolded.
And you can see it's just not
blocked out.
It's just clear, easy to just for
your eyes to follow.
Same thing as right here.
Easy for the eyes to follow.
We're not using blocks of text.
We are just separating things out
into like our different points and
then bolding like the
main stuff or putting it up clear
up top so that if somebody wants
more information, they
can read down here.
But if they just want to skim,
they can look at this.
So avoid blocks of text.
That's the real main first thing
that you want to do.
The other thing that you want to
do is you want to bold all of your
main points.
Most of your audience will not
read any of your copy, but they
will read the bolded main
points as they're skimming your
email.
So use body copy to support your
main points, kind of like I
mentioned before.
Some people might read it.
People might do that.
But other people are just going to
read the main points.
And I mean, look at what I've done
with this guide and all the other
guides in these modules.
I put, if you want to read all
this stuff, you can.
I've attached the links to
everything.
But really what we're doing is
we're highlighting the main points
so people can get the gist of it
if they just want to skim it.
So a really good example is this
guide and what I'm doing here.
The main points allow the readers
to get the full picture.
Then the body copy is used for the
further justification and proof
you have about that.
So right here, here's an example.
Accept the seasons of life.
Relationships are rarely 50-50.
Striving for your goals is
underrated.
And remember, you always have
choices.
And so you can see justification
in backing the information up is
in this text.
And you can read more if you want.
These are like kind of blocks of
text, but not like too big.
This is like kind of the situation
where you can sometimes have like
quick blocks of text for different
points.
But as long as you bold like your
main points, then people can
easily skim that.
Here's a good example number two,
comparing others versus your
brand.
Rather than have everything just
in like single points without
bolding the top, you have or that
would be tough to read.
But instead, we bold just the main
points.
And if people want to have further
information on that specific
point, then they can.
Empty monthly versus daily.
If you want to read more and say
at any time empty after dozens of
cycles, perfect.
Then you have that information.
But you can just easily see all
the main points here.
That's one of the other keys.
And then also, just keep it short.
We'll touch on this in all of our
principles, but we really want our
copy to be short.
The shorter it is, the more
skimmable it is.
If there's a lot of stuff, you're
not going to be able to skim it.
So that's very, very, very
important.
And these are just kind of the
three main things to make our copy
skimmable.
And we're going to be talking a
lot about this and then using
infographics.
That's kind of like the main thing
I'm trying to tell, trying to say
like with these copy modules is
don't focus less on the copy and
focus more on infographics like
this.
So avoid blocks of text, highlight
your main points, and keep your
copy nice and short.
We only have a couple seconds of
our customer's attention, so we
have to be really intentional with
what copy that we are using.
Okay, so we are talking about copy
here.
And we're talking about core copy
principle number one, which first
principle in my eyes is skimmable,
which we are going to be talking
about right here.
So SCE, these are kind of the
three main pillars, the copy
principles that we like to follow
at my agency, which has served us
pretty well, which are skimmable,
clear and concise, and then
engaging.
So first one is what we're talking
about in this video, which is
skimmable, which is the ease at
which someone can briefly, briefly
skim your email.
So let's talk about it.
Time is money.
The customer is not sitting down
every morning and reading their
emails in depth like they would
like the morning newspaper.
It's just not what the modern
customer is doing today,
especially since most of the sales
that are coming are going to be
people under the age of 50,
and those people aren't really
reading the newspaper and have the
attention spans like some other
older demographics would.
So we really only have a couple of
seconds of our customer's
attention.
Everybody, they're just quickly
opening their email and briefly
going through it.
So we need to understand that.
If people cannot skim your email,
they're not going to bother
reading it.
So we need to optimize for the
skim and not the read.
Very, very important.
So how do we do that?
There are a couple main things
that we want to do.
First is we want to avoid blocks
of text.
Blocks of text just scare people
off.
They are terrified.
It is the modern customer's
kryptonite is blocks of text.
So it's very difficult for the
eyes to like make out and process
blocks of text when we only have a
couple seconds of the person's
time.
So this just results in people
skipping past any type of block of
information.
So we really want to shorten our
copy or split it up in our text
with like line breaks and
different forms of graphics.
So when you're outlining your
emails like as far as like copy,
you really want to make sure that
you're splitting things up for the
designer.
So here are like two examples.
These could have been put in like
blocks of text.
But look, they're listed out.
One, two, three, four, five.
You can easily skim this.
Five ways nature supports mental
health.
Reduces the stress.
That's bolded.
Improves mood.
Improves attention and memory.
That's bolded.
And you can see it's just not
blocked out.
It's just clear, easy to just for
your eyes to follow.
Same thing as right here.
Easy for the eyes to follow.
We're not using blocks of text.
We are just separating things out
into like our different points and
then bolding like the main stuff
or putting it up clear up top so
that if somebody wants more
information, they can read down
here.
But if they just want to skim,
they can look at this.
So avoid blocks of text.
That's the real main first thing
that you want to do.
The other thing that you want to
do is you want to bold all of your
main points.
Most of your audience will not
read any of your copy, but they
will read the bolded main points
as they're skimming your email.
So use body copy to support your
main points, kind of like I
mentioned before.
Some people might read it.
People might do that.
But other people are just going to
read the main points.
And I mean, look at what I've done
with this guide and all the other
guides in these modules.
I put, if you want to read all
this stuff, you can.
I've attached the links to
everything.
But really what we're doing is
we're highlighting the main points
so people can get the gist of it
if they just want to skim it.
So a really good example is this
guide and what I'm doing here.
The main points allow the readers
to get the full picture.
Then the body copy is used for the
further justification and proof
you have about that.
So right here, here's an example.
Accept the seasons of life.
Relationships are rarely 50-50.
Striving for your goals is
underrated.
And remember, you always have
choices.
And so you can see justification
in backing the information up is
in this text.
And you can read more if you want.
These are like kind of blocks of
text but not like too big.
This is like kind of the situation
where you can sometimes have like
quick blocks of text for different
points.
But as long as you bold like your
main points, then people can
easily skim that.
Here's a good example number two.
Comparing others versus your
brand.
But rather than have everything
just in like single points without
bolding the top, you have or that
would be tough to read.
But instead, we bold just the main
points.
And if people want to have further
information on that specific
point, then they can.
Empty monthly versus daily.
If you want to read more and say
at any time empty after dozens of
cycles, perfect.
Then you have that information.
But you can just easily see all
the main points here.
That's one of the other keys.
And then also, just keep it short.
We'll touch on this in all of our
principles.
But we really want our copy to be
short.
The shorter it is, the more
skimmable it is.
If there's a lot of stuff, you're
not going to be able to skim it.
So that's very, very, very
important.
And these are just kind of the
three main things to make our copy
skimmable.
And we're going to be talking a
lot about this and then using
infographics.
That's kind of like the main thing
I'm trying to say with these copy
modules is don't focus less on the
copy and focus more on
infographics like this.
So avoid blocks of text, highlight
your main points, and keep your
copy nice and short.
We only have a couple seconds of
our customer's attention, so we
have to be really intentional with
what copy that we are using.