And now we're talking about core
copy principle number two which is
clear and concise so going
back here to our main graphic of
skimmable clear and concise and
then engaging those are our three
principles we already went through
skimmable clear and concise ties
into that for sure but
we want to make sure that we have
one takeaway kind of like in our
emails that we want to be
the driving force of our emails so
clear and concise the customer's
iq is dropping by about
50 the second they open their
email they're just in zombie mode
and if we aren't clear on what
we're giving them they're just not
going to understand and so if we
aren't concise they're
not going to bother giving us time
so this kind of ties it into
keeping our copy short which is
definitely a principle with clear
and concise is keeping it short
but also less scatter with your
copy just make sure you're clear
on what you're giving away so
short and sweet that's the main
thing the shorter your email is
the better we only have a few
seconds your email should not be
longer
than one to two scrolls in most
cases now we want to make sure
we're mixing things up for
audience but
look at like these short and sweet
emails benefits beyond the gut
this is the whole email and then
this button right here it's the
whole email nobody's reading an
essay they don't have to worry
about
these like crazy crazy emails that
they have to read short and simple
and then look at this email
we're texting you for one thing we
want to be in your shower just
being honest and we're just trying
to get
people on the text list we're not
spending so much time going over
like each benefit we're just
keeping
it short and sweet and to the
point so the customer isn't
overwhelmed and you know it's just
clear and
concise what we're giving away and
then also really important which
not a lot of people talk about is
one takeaway per email that's
really what we want to do for 90
75 of our emails we want it to
have
one specific takeaway the odds of
having our customer remember one
takeaway that we're trying to
drive home is
much higher than the odds of them
taking like three plus different
takeaways we're trying to tell
them
so many different things they're
not going to be able to they're
not going to it's then each one
gets
like 33 of their attention we want
100 of attention when people are
in zombie mode so the more concise
the better like look at this email
enhancing the benefits of caffeine
they're not talking about how
you also get like brain benefits
your memory improves when you use
this product and how it adds 1500
years to
your life no it's just this will
enhance the benefits of your
caffeine and that's literally
the whole entire email short and
sweet and it's just talking about
one takeaway they just want their
customer to know that you can pair
this with coffee to get more out
of like your caffeine whatever
that
may be same here super short and
sweet email maximizing growth
potential tackle hair loss with
doctor
trusted treatments personalized to
you we're just talking about the
one benefit we're maximizing our
growth
potential super easy super simple
to understand we just want the
growth potential and so then
just right here they're talking
about like specific things just
like adding a little bit of
support and
so that really is all you need to
focus on for clear and concise um
i really am simplifying all this
down
for you trying to be clear and
concise we really just want to
focus on as little takeaways per
email
as possible try to have one main
point that you're trying to drive
home you can have like smaller sub
points but we really just want one
main takeaway in our emails we
want to make sure that they're
short
and sweet and you're going to be
all set with being clear and
concise and now we're talking
about core
copy principle number two which is
clear and concise so going back
here to our main graphic of
skimmable
clear and concise and then
engaging those are our three
principles we already went through
skimmable
clear and concise ties into that
for sure but we want to make sure
that we have one takeaway
kind of like in our emails that we
want to be the driving force of
our emails so
clear and concise the customer's
iq is dropping by about 50 percent
the second they open their email
they're just in zombie mode and if
we aren't clear on what we're
giving them
they're just not going to
understand and so if we aren't
concise they're not going to
bother giving
us time so this kind of ties it
into keeping our copy short which
is definitely a principle with
clear and concise is keeping it
short but also less scatter with
your copy just make sure you're
clear
on what you're giving away so
short and sweet that's the main
thing the shorter your email is
the better
we only have a few seconds your
email should not be longer than
one to two scrolls in most cases
now
we want to make sure we're mixing
things up for audience but look at
like these short and sweet
emails benefits beyond the gut
this is the whole email and then
this button right here
it's the whole email nobody's
reading an essay they don't have
to worry about these like crazy
crazy
emails that they have to read
short and simple and then look at
this email we're texting you for
one
thing we want to be in your shower
just being honest and we're just
trying to get people on
the text list we're not spending
so much time going over like each
benefit we're just keeping it
short and sweet and to the point
so the customer isn't overwhelmed
and you know it's just clear and
concise what we're giving away and
then also really important which
not a lot of people talk about is
one takeaway per email that's
really what we want to do for 90
75 of our emails we want it to
have one
specific takeaway the odds of
having our customer remember one
takeaway that we're trying to
drive home
it's much higher than the odds of
them taking like three plus
different takeaways we're trying
to tell
them so many different things
they're not going to be able to
they're not going to
it's then each one gets like 33 of
their attention we want 100 of
attention when people are in
zombie
mode so the more concise the
better like look at this email
enhancing the benefits of caffeine
they're not talking about how you
also get like brain benefits your
memory improves when you use this
product and how it adds 1500 years
to your life no it's just this
will enhance the benefits of your
caffeine and that's literally the
whole entire email short and sweet
and it's just talking about one
takeaway they just want their
customer to know that you can pair
this with coffee to get more out
of
like your caffeine whatever that
may be same here super short and
sweet email maximizing growth
potential tackle hair loss with
doctor trusted treatments
personalized to you we're just
talking
about the one benefit we're
maximizing our growth potential
super easy super simple to
understand
we just want the growth potential
and so then just right here
they're talking about like
specific
things just like adding a little
bit of support and so that really
is all you need to focus on for
clear and concise um i really am
simplifying all this down for you
trying to be clear and concise
we really just want to focus on as
little takeaways per email as
possible try to have one main
point
that you're trying to drive home
you can have like smaller sub
points but we really just want
one main takeaway in our emails we
want to make sure that they're
short and sweet
and you're going to be all set
with being clear and concise