Okay, and moving on to core
principle number three,
which is engaging, not having
boring, boring copy.
So engaging is just like the
entertainment of the content
that you're sending to your list.
So the customer is craving
dopamine.
That's where we are at in this
world.
You need to have dopamine at all
times.
People are scrolling TikTok,
they're scrolling Instagram all
day, every day.
They're eating sugar all day,
every day.
If we're not gonna be able to give
them dopamine,
they're not going to want to read
our stuff.
So we need to give that to them.
We want our emails to be engaging
enough
to trigger dopamine in the
customer's brain.
This is gonna lead to a positive
association with our brand
and then results in future opens
and sales.
If we give them dopamine one time,
they're much more likely to keep
coming back.
So that's super, super key.
So the first thing that we wanna
focus on
is having our copy be punchy.
A punchy email with punchy copy is
short, but full of power.
You can tell with the strength of
the words
that it's just like, it's just
like one, two, boom.
It's just very punchy.
It evokes emotion and the
information is very, very dense.
The below examples do a great job
at injecting their information
into small amounts of space.
Small amounts of space.
So having ton of information in
short little areas.
So here's an example.
Don't just buy shit, invest in
yours,
which is a banger email.
So right here with two daily
capsules containing 53 billion, I
think.
Or is that trillion?
No, it's billion.
53 billion.
You give the whole body benefits
of all this stuff.
Short, punchy, to the point, has a
lot of information.
And then right here, you will
spend 92 days or 2,200 hours of
your life on the toilet.
Want to make that time feel
smoother.
Look at that.
That is nice and punchy.
That engages me.
That's what keeps me engaged.
When every single line that I'm
seeing,
every single line is giving me
tons of information.
And it's giving me stuff to like
keep reading.
Same thing right here.
Nice and punchy.
Every little word packs a punch
here.
Sugary cereal is delicious for
many reasons.
Added sugars, empty carbs, and
more.
That's why we recreated your
childhood favorites.
Tastes just as good.
But now with ingredients we're
proud of.
Amazing.
Packed with protein.
Zero sugar.
Magic Spoon helps you power
through the day with less cravings
and more energy.
Cut back on added sugars and
processed carbs.
Perfect for the keto lifestyle.
This is short, punchy, 100%
gluten-free and grain-free.
That's right.
No corn or wheat around here.
It's just punchy to the point.
Has some life.
But it's not like too much.
Impressed?
Honestly, we still are.
That is what keeps people engaged.
That is what gives them dopamine.
That's what creates engaging copy.
We're not rambling on and on about
stupid little things.
No.
Short, punchy, to the point.
Also, informational.
So we talked about punchy, putting
things, making things powerful.
Now we want informational.
You don't need to be Shane Gillis
or just Dave Chappelle.
For copy to be engaging, that's a
big misconception.
People think for copy to be
engaging, you need to be funny.
You need to be cracking jokes.
No, you don't.
That's not everybody's brand.
Not everybody's brand is cracking
jokes like Dr.
Squatch.
Informational is another way you
can keep your copy really
engaging.
People love to learn and they want
to be able to make an educated
decision in the purchasing
process.
If you can give people facts,
people will engage with your
emails more often.
They want to know information.
They like learning.
My favorite book growing up was
fact books.
I loved reading fact books and
there wasn't like fun and nothing
fun about that in terms
of like it being funny.
But if someone learns something
new every time they open your
email, you're in a good place
because they know they're
benefiting from being on your
email list and they're going to
keep
reading.
So keep your copy as informational
as possible.
So heard about golden root
talking, educating people.
Have you heard about this?
Known for centuries in older Asian
and European mountains for its
ability to yada, yada, yada,
yada, 140 active compounds.
It's just one of the amazing.
Look at how informational that is.
I just learned something golden
root and it's called Rhodiola Rose
and it's in this product.
So it ties things in.
Amazing.
Super informational.
And then this example right here,
informational.
Five ways nature supports mental
health.
Spending just 20, 30 minutes
outside reduces the stress hormone
cortisol.
Exposing yourself to natural light
can improve mood.
Improve attention and memory up to
20%.
I'm learning stuff from this
email.
I'm going to keep it.
I'm going to keep engaging.
And this email is engaging.
It keeps me interested.
What's the next point?
What's the next thing I'm going to
learn?
And then another thing is keeping
things entertaining, which we
talked about.
You don't need to have it like be
funny necessarily, but you can
really spice things up by making
it entertaining with jokes, puns,
puzzles, et cetera, all that stuff
and keeping things punchy.
The worst thing that you can do is
be repetitive.
That's kind of like the main thing
that I want you to understand is
for things to be entertaining.
You can't just send the same thing
over and over and over again.
We need to mix it up.
That's how you keep things
entertaining.
So a good example here, super
funny email from Dr.
Squatch.
How to last longer, last longer,
shower harder, have more fun.
It's like a butter pill for your
soap.
So that's super funny.
And then tips to last longer.
Obviously, guys are going to perk
their ears up or perk their eyes
once they see this email.
That's super funny.
Same thing here.
This is entertaining.
Look at this flow chart.
Work bag, ready, go.
Follow the prompt.
So this is kind of like copy
that's engaging, keeps me
entertained, and it feels custom
to me.
So these are great ways to keep
your emails entertaining.
And then infographics.
That's how you can keep things
entertaining, engaged, and tie
this all together is with
infographics, which we're talking
about in the next module.
Okay, and moving on to core
principle number three, which is
engaging.
Not having boring, boring copy.
So engaging is just like the
entertainment of the content that
you're sending to your list.
So the customer is craving
dopamine.
That's where we are at in this
world.
You need to have dopamine at all
times.
People are scrolling TikTok.
They're scrolling Instagram all
day, every day.
They're eating sugar all day,
every day.
If we're not going to be able to
give them dopamine, they are not
going to want to read our stuff.
So we need to give that to them.
We want our emails to be engaging
enough to trigger dopamine in the
customer's brain.
This is going to lead to a
positive association with our
brand and then results in future
opens and sales.
If we give them dopamine one time,
they're much more likely to keep
coming back.
So that's super, super key.
So the first thing that we want to
focus on is having our copy be
punchy.
A punchy email with punchy copy is
short but full of power.
You can tell with the strength of
the words that it's just like,
whop-ah, it's just like a one-two,
boom.
It's just very punchy.
It evokes emotion, and the
information is very, very dense.
The below examples do a great job
at injecting their information
into small amounts of space.
So having a ton of information in
short little areas.
So here's an example.
Don't just buy shit, invest in
yours, which is a banger email.
So right here with two daily
capsules containing 53 billion, I
think?
Or is that trillion?
No, it's billion.
53 billion, you give the whole
body benefits of all this stuff.
Short, punchy, to the point, has a
lot of information.
And then right here, you will
spend 92 days or 2,200 hours of
your life on the toilet.
Want to make that time feel
smoother.
Look at that.
That is nice and punchy.
That engages me.
That's what keeps me engaged.
When every single line that I'm
seeing, every single line is
giving me tons of information, and
it's giving me stuff to, like,
keep reading.
Same thing right here.
Nice and punchy.
Every little word packs a punch
here.
Sugary cereal is delicious for
many reasons.
Added sugars, empty carbs, and
more.
That's why we recreated your
childhood favorites.
Tastes just as good.
But now with ingredients we're
proud of.
Amazing.
Packed with protein.
Zero sugar.
Magic Spoon helps you power
through the day with less cravings
and more energy.
Cut back on added sugars and
processed carbs.
Perfect for the keto lifestyle.
This is short, punchy, 100%
gluten-free and grain-free.
That's right.
No corn or wheat around here.
It's just punchy, to the point,
has some life, but it's not, like,
too much.
Impressed?
Honestly, we still are.
That is what keeps people engaged.
That is what gives them dopamine.
That's what creates engaging copy.
We're not rambling on and on about
stupid little things.
No.
Short, punchy, to the point.
Also, informational.
So we talked about punchy, putting
things, making things powerful.
Now we want informational.
You don't need to be Shane Gillis
or just Dave Chappelle.
For copy to be engaging, that's a
big misconception.
People think for copy to be
engaging, you need to be funny.
You need to, like, be cracking
jokes.
Like, no, you don't.
That's not everybody's brand.
Not everybody's brand is, like,
cracking jokes like Dr.
Squatch.
Informational is another way you
can keep your copy really
engaging.
People love to learn, and they
want to be able to make an
educated decision in the
purchasing process.
And so if you can give people
facts, people will engage with
your emails more often.
They want to know information.
They like learning.
Like, my favorite book growing up
was, like, fact books.
I loved reading fact books.
And there wasn't, like, fun and
nothing fun about that in terms
of, like, it being funny.
But if someone learns something
new every time they open your
email, you're in a good place
because they know they're
benefiting from being on your
email list, and they're going to
keep reading.
So keep your copy as informational
as possible.
So heard about Golden Root.
Talking, educating people.
Have you heard about this?
Known for centuries in older Asian
and European mountains for its
ability to yada, yada, yada, yada.
140 active compounds.
It's just one of the amazing.
Look at how informational that is.
I just learned something, Golden
Root, and it's called Rhodiola
Rose, and it's in this product, so
it ties things in.
Amazing.
Super informational.
And then this example right here,
informational.
Five ways nature supports mental
health.
Spending just 20 to 30 minutes
outside reduces the stress hormone
cortisol.
Exposing yourself to natural light
can improve mood.
Improve attention and memory up to
20%.
I'm learning stuff from this
email.
I'm going to keep engaging, and
this email is engaging.
It keeps me interested.
What's the next point?
What's the next thing I'm going to
learn?
And then another thing is keeping
things entertaining, which we
talked about.
You don't need to have it, like,
be funny necessarily, but you can
really spice things up by making
it entertaining with jokes, puns,
puzzles, et cetera, all that
stuff, and keeping things punchy.
The worst thing that you can do is
be repetitive.
That's kind of, like, the main
thing that I want you to
understand is for things to be
entertaining, you can't just send
the same thing over and over and
over again.
We need to mix it up.
That's how you keep things
entertaining.
So a good example here, super
funny email from Dr.
Squatch.
How to last longer.
Last longer, shower harder, have
more fun.
It's like a butter pill for your
soap.
So that's super funny.
And then tips to last longer.
Obviously, like, guys are going to
perk their ears up or perk their
eyes once they see this email.
That's super funny.
Same thing here.
This is entertaining.
Look at this flow chart.
Work bag, ready, go.
Follow the prompt.
And so this is, like, kind of like
copy that's engaging, keeps me
entertained, and it feels custom
to me.
So these are great ways to keep
your emails entertaining.
And then infographics.
That's how you can keep things
entertaining, engaged, and tie
this all together is with
infographics, which we're talking
about in the next module.
Thank you.