Let's talk about it.
Number one, we're going to talk
about ease of click.
So when customers are
opening our emails, they are in
zombie mode.
Any friction in the ability for
someone to click
on our button to go to our site
will automatically lead to churn
if there's any friction at all.
So we need to literally hand them
the click on a silver platter.
So you can do this with having
buttons above the fold, which
we'll talk about, which is
essentially having your button
high up
in the email so the customer
doesn't have to scroll, spun above
the fold, and then you want
to make sure your buttons are very
large so that somebody, even with
small thumbs, even
a blind person could click it.
And that's how big you want your
buttons to be.
And then you
want to make sure they're clear.
So there's nothing around them.
It's just, this is like
the focal point of the email and
make those buttons.
And then also you want to make
them
centered.
So these are all about the button.
The button is the most important
part about
your email.
You need to make sure that it's
super clear and all of these
things will do
that for you.
But again, just to touch on
customers are just in zombie mode.
They're not sitting
down, annotating their emails and
just waiting to that they're
getting up to go to the bathroom.
They're opening their email for
three seconds.
So we need to make it very, very
easy for them.
So let's talk about button above
the fold.
So the above the fold section is
the section of
your email that is viewed without
scrolling.
So if you go to this example, I
just opened up
my email and immediately when I
open, this is the above the fold
section.
This is stuff that
is viewable.
Now I could scroll and look at the
other part of the email, but in
this above the
fold section, you can see, I can
see the logo.
There's a headline, some body copy
and a button
all above the fold, which is
amazing.
So not every customer will scroll
your email.
So there's
always going to be a drop off.
Some people just open and leave.
So you want to make sure that you
have a button available in the
hero section so that 100% of the
people who open your email
will see a button.
So including a top button in your
email designs is an easy, low
hanging fruit,
and that's going to automatically
improve your click rates
guaranteed.
Now let's talk about large
buttons.
You want to make sure your buttons
are big.
So an iPhone screen is 2.75
inches.
That's not a
lot.
Unfortunately, sorry, all the lads
out there, but 2.75 inches is not
a large space.
So the larger your
button is, the more surface area,
the easier it is to click.
Pretty obvious.
So this actually has a
massive impact on conversions.
So we can look at this bad example
here from Nike.
Look at how small
this button is.
It's about like half an inch if
it's on a phone screen versus this
button here,
which is like two inches wide.
Even a blind person could click
this.
So easy.
It's just,
it doesn't compare.
And you would have to be, even a
blind person could click it.
As simple as that.
So that's going to be a lot more
clear that people can click it and
you're subconsciously going to get
people to click it more and have
their eyes just gravitate towards
it.
That applies as well to clear
calls to action.
So the goal of an email obviously
is to get somebody to click.
And so your button should
be the easiest part of your email.
And there should be no ability for
someone to click over a button or
to view over a button.
You just want it to be super
clear.
Here's the button.
So avoid distracting
backgrounds and contrasting colors
to get your CTAs to stand out.
So here's like a bad example.
Like you can't even really see it.
If I'm just like opening my email
and quickly scrolling,
I'm not even going to see this
button.
A very bad example versus
something like this,
where it's, there's nothing around
it.
There's enough space between the
title and the picture.
They're not putting the button
like over top this picture
slightly.
It's clear.
It's in its own,
it's in its own space and nobody's
going to miss it essentially.
And then we also want to have our
buttons centered.
So let's go back to this Nike
example.
So
the thing about buttons and having
your button on the left side of
the screen is that think about
holding your phone in your right
hand.
Most everybody holds their phone
in the right hand
because we're not weirdo lefties.
I'm kidding.
Sorry, all the lefties.
But you actually have to like
stretch your thumb to reach
buttons on the left side,
especially if your button's at the
top of your
email, you've top left of your
email, you have to like stretch.
And that actually really impacts
conversions as well.
So we even did that for not a
button that was at the top left,
but just in the
middle, but to the left versus
centered.
And we noticed a different in
place to order rate of 6.6%
or 7.5% of 15 K to 19.9 K.
And then about a 10% increase in
clicks here, despite having less
opens,
a lot more revenue.
So that's just like an example of
like AB test we did there.
And it's pretty ridiculous how
much something like stretching
your thumb can have on your
conversions.