We just covered ease of click, now
we are going to talk about skim
ability.
We want to make sure that people
can skim our emails.
So, like we said earlier, nobody's
sitting at their desk annotating
their emails.
They're checking their emails as
they're getting up to go to the
bathroom,
they're on a quick break, they're
waiting for their kids at soccer
practice just in between drills.
I don't know, but on average you
really only have two to four
seconds to get your email across.
It's just, that's just the reality
of the situation,
and you need to optimize for the
skim and not the read.
So, you really just want these
factors.
You want to have simplicity,
simplicity, simplicity.
You want to have clear sections,
as minimal copy as possible,
and clear headlines and the main
points just like so somebody can
quickly look at it and boom, we're
good to go.
So, those are the main factors
we're going to talk about.
First, we're talking about
simplicity.
Simplicity will always win.
Adding too much complexity in your
emails will overwhelm the
customer.
So, that's the first thing.
If you throw a whole bunch of
stuff at a customer right when
they open their email,
because, again, they're in zombie
mode.
They don't want to sit down and
read and go through like three
minutes looking through your
email.
They don't want to read a blog
when they're checking their email.
So, if they do open your email and
there's so much going on,
they're just going to leave
because they're like, I don't want
to deal with this right now.
So, too much complexity will
overwhelm.
And then, more importantly,
complex designs will distract from
the whole purpose of the email,
which is to sell.
Took that from David Ogilvie.
But, essentially, if you have so
much going on, you're just
distracting from the bigger point
of the email,
which is to click and make it easy
for someone to click.
If you're giving so much stuff,
that's distracting from it.
So, keep it simple so you just can
easily just skim and understand
the contents of the email.
When possible, also, shorten your
email as much as possible.
So, this is a bad example.
There is just so much going on.
So, I am going, in 2024, I am
going to, and then there's a
sticky note with different font.
And then, there's this, a weird
button that's a different shape.
And then, you have a different
section, which is hack the habit,
keys to success.
And then, all these different
icons and crazy colors and all
this different stuff.
There's just too much going on
here.
The colors are distracting.
There's just a lot.
I'm too overwhelmed to read it.
Whereas, like this, this is the
whole email.
Right here.
That is perfect.
Nobody's going to be scared of
looking at something like this
with calm colors.
It's just almost sold out.
This is what it is.
Grab this best-selling crisp and
refreshing color.
You can just let the product do
the talking a lot of the time.
And so, it's just super simple.
Someone can easily open this.
And in two seconds, while they're
getting up to go to the bathroom,
they can get this.
And they may as well click because
it's that easy.
So, make sure that you're keeping
things as simple, simple, simple
as possible.
Now, another one, which is kind of
underrated, is clear sections.
So, the human brain just likes
when things are organized and
clear.
So, we want to be smooth with our
sections, but we want to be clear
when we're differentiating.
So, we let our brain kind of like
process things differently.
So, this way, people can clearly
see two to three sections,
categorize it in their head, and
then skim with ease.
So, the below example, not below,
the below example is how
unprofessional of me, makes it
clear what is the intro and what
is the product section.
So, you should have clear.
This is obvious.
This is the header.
And then this is obvious.
This is the product section.
They're not doing anything crazy.
The colors are a little bit much,
but it's kind of clear.
It's a little bit smooth.
It's smooth here.
And it's the same.
The background is the same color
as this button.
So, it kind of flows a little
better.
It ties together.
And you just know that these are
two different sections.
So, that's a good example here.
You wouldn't want it to be like a
flat, like blocky thing with a
different color because then it
would look awkward.
Like if this was a gray and it was
just cut off.
Like, no.
We want it to be a little bit
smooth.
We want to make sure it flows and
matches the email and you're at
least clear with the different
sections.
So, good example there.
And then, probably the most
important, as minimal copy as
possible.
So, the customer is only going to
be on your email for three-ish
seconds and nobody is going to be
reading an essay.
One, it's going to overwhelm them.
And two, nobody wants to read it.
And nobody is going to read it.
So, if you're spending all this
time on your copy, it's just going
to be wasted because no one is
reading it.
So, more copy, least overwhelmed.
No one will read it.
It's wasted space.
So, optimized for the three-second
viewers.
Quick and punchy.
So, let's look at this bad example
with just way too much copy.
When you open this email, like, I
can almost guarantee, I can
guarantee, not a single person
read every single word of this.
Guarantee it.
Everybody is just reading, Gorilla
Bars arrived, 2023, enhanced each
bar's flavor, available at Gorilla
Mine.
Okay.
That's what the whole process was.
And you have these great icons,
this great graph, but you're just
taking up so much space.
Because now the customer has to
scroll, like, three times to even
get to the bottom and see this.
It's just way too much, and it's
just causing problems and making
it hard for the design to flow.
Whereas, this is an awesome
example.
So simple.
Look at how simple this is, and
the design makes it where, even if
there is a little bit of copy,
it's displayed simple, and it's in
just this simple table.
Look at how simple this is, so
little copy, amazing.
How will I feel?
Find your perfect dosage.
And it's just overcoming an
objection of, like, what's it
going to feel like?
And then this is the blend, the
active parts of it, and then the
effects.
Amazing.
Perfect.
Copy and design go together with
email.
That's why I included this.
So, 100%, this is probably the
most important aspect of making
things skimmable.
But also very important, headlines
and main points.
This is necessary.
You can see in this body copy,
there's no headlines or main
points.
So, this person is just going to
scroll through the bottom and not
get anything from it.
Whereas, if you have something
like this, they're going to get
these.
So, talking about the headlines
and main points, very few people
will read your body copy in full,
but they will read, skim, all your
headlines and sub-headlines.
So, if we only have three seconds
of our customer's attention, we
need to make it loud and clear
what the main points and the
takeaways are.
So, I've attached two good
examples here.
You can see here, for this brand,
it's just a new standard in
probiotics.
And then, you have bolded.
You just know it's clinically
validated.
It's engineered to survive, so
stay with you.
And then, it's superior science.
So, you just know, like walking
away from this email, you know,
okay, this is like a legit product
because of these points.
And if you want to learn more
about them, there's one, two
sentences about it.
That's perfect, easy to take away,
little copy, and it's just clear
what the takeaways are.
And then, this right here as well.
You can see, cheers to crunchy
beginnings.
So, that just kind of like you can
feel the crunchy in your mouth
when they said that, so that's a
good copy.
So, clear headline, you have some
body copy, and then you have your
sub-headlines here.
So, it's very clear that protein
packed, sugar smugger, so there's
no sugar, and then it's vegan and
gluten free.
Like, somebody could skim this and
easily get the point.
So, they open the email, cheers to
crunchy, it's protein packed, no
sugar, and then it's vegan.
Cool, I'm vegan, and then they
buy.
It's just that simple.
Everything's clear, so you don't
even need to read the body copy,
and you get the point of the
email.