And then the other point, so we
have skimmability and then we have
the simplicity and then last we
have branding.
So I won't go too much in this as
it is pretty self-explanatory.
A design can be
really beautiful, but unrelated to
a brand.
And so in order to strengthen your
brand and keep up
your positive associations, you
need to make sure that all
channels are the same.
So this is going
to promote your longer term
conversions as you build up these
associations.
So make sure your
graphics are branded, you have the
correct fonts, you have congruent
styling and the colors are all
the same.
And that's going to kind of be it.
So just make sure when you're
working with a brand,
you get all the brand styling
guidelines, looking at the past
emails, you're relating everything
to
the site.
And it really is that simple.