Hello hello so in this video i
just wanted to give you just a
brief look around as to figma
some of its main features and
really just the main stuff you're
going to use to be quite honest
like
you're just way better off just
exploring yourself and messing
around inside of the platform but
i
just wanted to give you some of
this just to show you around like
some of the main stuff that you
will use so all i did was i went
to figma and then i clicked create
new design file and this is
exactly the page that it took me
to so this is your figma design
file it is as simple as this so
this is essentially where you are
designing this central area you
have like your file where it's at
and then you have like all this
stuff and then you have all this
stuff and then this stuff so
essentially
what we have here on this left
side these are like your layers so
once you start inputting designs
into
this area they're going to show up
here so let's just run you through
an example so if i go here
these are different shapes that
you can use and you're going to be
using a lot of shapes more often
than not you'll be using something
like a rectangle so if i add a
rectangle and i put the size right
here you'll notice that a layer
went over here on the left side so
and you will see this is over here
so if i were to copy this and
duplicate it now we have two
layers and each one if i click on
it it's
going to reference a different
layer so this is exactly like
where everything will show up here
on the
left left and this helps with
organization for example you could
say rectangle um cool and then
this one
could be rectangle not cool i
don't know why i went with those
names but you know what i mean you
have these so you'll also notice
that with a shape you have this
stuff here on the right side so
this is
where you can do a lot of the
customization with your stuff so
kind of the main stuff here is you
have
width so if you don't want to do
this yourself you can adjust this
and you'll notice the width will
adjust
as well as height you can do that
and adjust those if you want to
adjust things where they're locked
in proportion like say i wanted to
keep this exact shape but i wanted
to increase it as a whole like
maybe i wanted to double it you
can lock these two together so you
could lock this and if i wanted to
make this 400 the height is going
to move in proportion so that's
something cool that you can
do and then you can unlock it by
doing this so it's one thing that
you can do of course you can
change
colors here mess around with your
colors you can even do some cool
stuff over here like if you add
this section like a gradient you
can make a gradient and you can
mess around there i won't go too
much
into that stuff but there's
gradients there that you can do so
that's what you can do over here
you have
things like you can add like a
stroke like you can add um like a
border to it for example so you
can
see here's like the color of your
border the opacity so how
see-through you want it to be
that's what
these percentages are um you can
add inside outside whatever you
want you can change the width of
it so
if i wanted it to be 20 then it's
a lot thicker of a border so i'm
just going to undo that so let me
undo
that there we go and then i just
want to remove this you can change
all sorts of different stuff with
it
you have things like effects so
you can add a shadow you can add a
layer blur so you can see
like the corner got layered you
could add a background blur if you
have a background you can
add an inner shadow so you can see
on the top there there's like a
little shadow and then say you do
choose one of these let's do an
inner shadow you can adjust it
even further by clicking here and
then
changing like the coordinates of
it whatever you want to do a lot
of this stuff is advanced and you
really won't really use it so
let's just delete that you can do
like layers so if you want your
layers
to adjust in any sort of way you
can do this all this fancy stuff
add different filters but
again like i rarely use that and i
create emails all day every day so
that's some stuff that you can
do and then you have these layers
so some stuff that you are going
to do however is you're going to
like
group stuff and put them together
so one thing that you can do let's
say this is all going to be part
of
like a cohesive design we go here
change this and let's say we
wanted to group these together
you can just click on both of them
just by holding down shift and you
can just left click and you can
group so a few different options
here you can group them you can
frame them so if we just click a
group
then we have a group here and if
you down to this then they're
together and now it's together
you can also turn any group into
what's called a frame so kind of
frame is like a level up from a
group so you can have groups
inside of frames so that's kind of
as far as it goes you have frames
then you add groups and then you
can add multiple different groups
underneath them you can name this
group rectangles so typically when
we're talking about email design
we're going to be using a frame as
a singular design so your designs
are going to be frames whereas you
have groups within your frames
so you have groups within your
emails which is frame so let's
just name this frame let's just
say email
number one so we have an email
here and typically for your emails
you want to be 600 width so i'm
just
going to change that and now this
is our frame so we are going to
create a frame let's make it 600
wide and
then let's make it like 800 tall
now this is our frame so some
different stuff you can do with
frame
so we can even i'm just going to
remove these from the group and
you'll see it from the frame and
you
can see that the frame is now
lonely so typically like when you
have your emails you want a
specific
background for your emails so you
can add a fill to your frame and
have this be like the background
to
your email so for example let's
add like a logo section i'm going
to create a new rectangle i'm
going to
put you like this and then i'll
adjust the width to be 600 so it's
the full width of the frame and
then
let's make you like 100 tall and
then we can just slide this in and
adjust it and then now we have we
can just imagine this is a logo
and then right here we can name
this logo section and that right
there
is like a logo section so some
cool stuff you can do there and of
course you can add images in so
let's
say for our email we wanted to add
like a hero image all you have to
do to add any sort of image
is you can just go right up here
to left you can go to file and
place image so i'm just going to
go
place an image oops okay so here
we go i just grabbed an image just
my logo and you can place your
image wherever so let's just place
you right here for now and it's
going to change to the size it was
thousand by a thousand so here it
is and then we can adjust this so
i have these locked let's change
it to like
five let's see if this is 600
width maybe we'll have this be
like 400 width so it can take up
this
whole section and then we can
center it here and then boom now
we have an image but we want to
make
sure that it's inside of the frame
so if it's ever not in the frame
and you want it to be you can just
drag it in and we'll go right here
so boom now we have our main image
and then boom now we have a full
frame and you can create groups
within them so we also have this
text text feature which of course
you
can add text of any kind we could
say this is a sub headline and
then just like it's a google doc
you
have all your information here so
let's center it we can make this
bigger we can go like 24 and then
we
can bold it and then boom we have
a sub headline let's say we wanted
to add body copy i'm just going
to copy and paste this and then
let's change you to like 18 take
you bolt take you off bold and be
like
this is the body copy of my email
and what we can do within this so
let's just extend this out
and then center you then we have
body copy here if you want to just
for organizational purposes you
could group these together even
further so click here shift boom
and then group and then we could
say
this is like a copy section wow i
spelled that wrong and then boom
now you have this
that's really the extent of what
you use in figma you use shapes
here and there you upload a lot of
images and you can organize them
within them and then you can
create all sorts of different
emails so
let's just copy and paste this if
we want to create another you'll
see another frame came out we
can rename that email too oh i
changed this one to email too let
me undo that i want this one to be
emailed too if i change this name
it's going to go here and now we
have two emails you can collapse
stuff as you go so i'm just going
to delete that and then boom now
you can see we have two frames for
emails here and here and that is
kind of the extent of what you use
you have you can create frames up
here you can create sections which
are a little bit different but we
don't even really use them but if
you
ever want to create a frame you
can just create it just like this
and that is pretty much the extent
of what you want to do all sorts
of different stuff but this is
just very base what you want you
have
all sorts of stuff that you can do
here you can view like this is
just your edit properties if you
want
to add plugins these are plugins
that i use so these are like apps
built on to figma so if you want
to create gifts and whatnot you
can do that here um screenshots to
designs whatever you want to do
and then there are widgets which
are which are also like little
tools that you can create you can
do
all sorts of different stuff
alignment but again i don't even
really use those so all sorts of
different
shapes that you can use uh the
slice feature is what we'll talk
about later this is helpful for so
essentially what a slice does is
you can slice any anything you
want and essentially just be able
to
export just a slice so if i did
that and i wanted to export the
slice the slice is just taking
that piece and
then you can export the slice over
here you can export it however you
want and that's how we are
going to be uploading emails but
for now i'm just going to delete
this slice let's see is there
anything
else i'm missing not really you
have a pen and pencil if you want
to use those uh if you want to
comment
that's this comment feature you
could be hey at max this is
terrible um let me just make sure
it actually
tags me so i know that this is
terrible and then boom you have
comments like this then you can
resolve
comments say somebody leaves a
comment and it's resolved you just
click this check mark and it'll
go away of course you can share
your file and all that good stuff
with whoever you want um but that
is
pretty much the extent of what you
need in figma the main stuff
you're going to be using is
creating
your frames adding in shapes
adding in a ton of photos and all
of that good stuff you can even
adjust your
photos however you want you can
change your photos um we don't
need that let me undo what i just
did
there we go um you can do whatever
you want but again you really
don't really use any of this and
just like we could with frames you
can add different strokes like if
i wanted to add a border around
this
picture i just added a border so
highly recommend you just mess
around with this and kind of
experiment but
this is just like the general
overview of figma and the main
features that you'll use and kind
of
just inside my head as i'm
navigating figma i just wanted to
get you just a live video of me
doing this
hello hello so in this video i
just wanted to give you just a
brief look around as to figma some
of its
main features and really just the
main stuff you're going to use to
be quite honest like you're just
way
better off just exploring yourself
and messing around inside of the
platform but i just wanted
to give you some of this just to
show you around like some of the
main stuff that you will use so
all i did was i went to figma and
then i clicked create new design
file and this is exactly the page
that it took me to so this is your
figma design file it is as simple
as this so this is essentially
where you are designing this
central area you have like your
file where it's at and then you
have like
all this stuff and then you have
all this stuff and then this stuff
so essentially what we have
here on this left side these are
like your layers so once you start
inputting designs into this area
they're going to show up here so
let's just run you through an
example so if i go here these are
different shapes that you can use
and you're going to be using a lot
of shapes more often than not
you will be using something like a
rectangle so if i add a rectangle
and i put the size right here
you'll notice that a layer went
over here on the left side so and
you will see this is over here so
if i were to copy this and
duplicate it now we have two
layers and each one if i click on
it it's going
to reference a different layer so
this is exactly like where
everything will show up here on
the left
left and this helps with
organization for example you could
say rectangle um cool and then
this one
could be rectangle not cool i
don't know why i went with those
names but you know what i mean you
have
these so you'll also notice that
with a shape you have this stuff
here on the right side so this is
where you can do a lot of the
customization with your stuff so
kind of the main stuff here is you
have width so if you don't want to
do this yourself you can adjust
this and you'll notice the width
will
adjust as well as height um you
can do that and adjust those if
you want to adjust things where
they're
locked in proportion like say i
wanted to keep this exact shape
but i wanted to um increase it as
a
whole like maybe i wanted to
double it you can lock these two
together so you could lock this
and if i
wanted to make this 400 the height
is going to move in proportion so
that's something cool that you can
do and then you can unlock it by
doing this so that's one thing
that you can do of course you can
change
colors here mess around with your
colors you can even do some cool
stuff over here like if you add
this section like a gradient you
can make a gradient and you can
mess around there i won't go too
much into
that stuff but there's gradients
there that you can do so that's
what you can do over here you have
things like you can add like a
stroke like you can add um like a
border to it for example so you
can see
here's like the color of your
border the opacity so how
see-through you want it to be
that's what these
percentages are um you can add
inside outside whatever you want
you can change the width of it so
if i wanted
it to be 20 then it's a a lot
thicker of a border so i'm just
going to undo that so let me undo
that there we go
and then i just want to remove
this uh you can change all sorts
of different stuff with it you
have things like
effects so you can add a shadow
you can add a layer blur so you
can see like the corner got
layered you could
add a background blur if you have
a background you could add an
inner shadow so you can see on the
top there there's
like a little shadow and then say
you do choose one of these let's
do an inner shadow you can adjust
it even further
by clicking here and then changing
like the coordinates of it
whatever you want to do a lot of
this stuff is
advanced and you really won't
really use it um so let's just
delete that you can do like layers
so if
you want your layers to adjust in
any sort of way you can do this
all this fancy stuff add different
filters
but again like i rarely use that
and i create emails all day every
day so that's some stuff that you
can
do and then you have these layers
so some stuff that you are going
to do however is you're going to
like
group stuff and put them together
so one thing that you can do let's
say this is all going to be part
of like a cohesive design we go
here change this and let's say we
wanted to group these together
you can just click on both of them
just by holding down shift and you
can just left click and you can
group so a few different options
here you can group them you can
frame them so if we just click a
group
then we have a group here and if
you down to this then they're
together and now it's together you
can also
turn any group into what's called
a frame so kind of frame is like a
level up from a group so you can
have groups inside of frames so
that's kind of as far as it goes
you frames then you add groups
then you
can add multiple different groups
underneath them you can name this
group rectangles so
typically when we're talking about
email design we're going to be
using a frame as a singular design
so your designs are going to be
frames whereas you have
groups within your frames so you
have groups within your emails
which is frame so let's just name
this
frame let's just say email number
one so we have an email here and
typically for your emails you want
to be 600 width so i'm just going
to change that and now this is our
frame so we are going to create a
frame
let's make it 600 wide and then
let's make it like 800 tall now
this is our frame so some
different stuff
you can do with frame so we can
even i'm just going to remove
these from the group and you'll
see it from
the frame and you can see that the
frame is now lonely so typically
like when you have your emails you
want a specific background for
your emails so you can add a fill
to your frame and have this be
like the
background to your email so for
example let's add like a logo
section i'm going to create a new
rectangle i'm going to put you
like this and then i'll adjust the
width to be 600 so it's the full
width of the frame and then let's
make you like 100 tall and then we
can just slide this in and adjust
it and then now we have we can
just imagine this is a logo and
then right here we can name this
logo
section and that right there is
like a logo section so some cool
stuff you can do there and of
course
you can add images in so let's say
for our email we wanted to add
like a hero image all you have to
do
to add any sort of image is you
can just go right up here to left
you can go to file and place image
so
i'm just going to go place an
image oops okay so here we go i
just grabbed an image just my logo
and
you can place your image wherever
so let's just place you right here
for now and it's going to change
to the size it was thousand by a
thousand so here it is and then we
can adjust this so i have these
locked let's change it to like
five let's see if this is 600
width maybe we'll have this be
like 400
width so it can take up this whole
section and then we can center it
here and then boom now we have an
image but we want to make sure
that it's inside of the frame so
if it's ever not in the frame and
you
want it to be you can just drag it
in and we'll go right here so boom
now we have our main image
and then boom now we have a full
frame and you can create groups
within them so we also have this
text
text feature which of course you
can add text of any kind we could
say this is a sub headline
and then just like it's a google
doc you have all your information
here so let's center it we can
make
this bigger we can go like 24 and
then we can bold it and then boom
we have a sub headline let's say
we wanted to add body copy i'm
just going to copy and paste this
and then let's change you to like
take you bolt take you off bold
and be like this is the body copy
of my email and what we can do
within
this so let's just extend this out
then center you then we have body
copy here if you want to just
for organizational purposes you
could group these together even
further so click here shift boom
and
then group and then we could say
this is like a copy section wow i
spelled that wrong and then boom
now you have
this that's really the extent of
what you use in figma you use
shapes here and there you upload a
lot of images and you can organize
them within them and then you can
create all sorts of different
emails
so let's just copy and paste this
if we want to create another
you'll see another frame came out
we
can rename that email too oh i
changed this one to email too let
me undo that i want this one to be
email too if i change this name
it's going to go here and then now
we have two emails you can
collapse
stuff as you go so i'm just going
to delete that and then boom now
you can see we have two frames for
emails here and here and that is
kind of the extent of what you use
you have you can create frames up
here you can create sections which
are a little bit different but we
don't even really use them but if
you ever want to create a frame
you can just create it just like
this and that is pretty much the
extent
of what you want to do all sorts
of different stuff but this is
just very base what you want you
have
all sorts of stuff that you can do
here you can view like this is
just your edit properties if you
want
to add plugins these are plugins
that i use so these are like apps
built on to figma so if you
want to create gifts and whatnot
you can do that here um
screenshots to designs whatever
you want
to do and then there are widgets
which are which are also like
little tools that you can create
you can do all sorts of different
stuff alignment but again i don't
even really use those
so all sorts of different shapes
that you can use uh the slice
feature is what we'll talk about
later
this is helpful for so essentially
what a slice does is you can slice
any anything you want
and essentially just be able to
export just a slice so if i did
that and i wanted to export
the slice the slice is just taking
that piece and then you can export
the slice over here you can
export it however you want and
that's how we are going to be
uploading emails but for now i'm
just going
to delete this slice let's see is
there anything else i'm missing
not really you have a pen and
pencil
if you want to use those uh if you
want to comment that's this
comment feature you could be
hey max this is terrible um let me
just make sure it actually tags me
so i know that this is terrible
and then boom you have comments
like this then you can resolve
comments say somebody leaves a
comment
and it's resolved you just click
this check mark and it'll go away
of course you can share your file
and all that good stuff with
whoever you want um but that is
pretty much the extent of what you
need
in figma the main stuff you're
going to be using is creating your
frames adding in shapes adding in
a
ton of photos and all of that good
stuff you can even adjust your
photos however you want you can
change your photos um we don't
need that let me undo what i just
did there we go um you can do
whatever
you want but again you really
don't really use any of this and
just like we could with frames you
can add
different strokes like if i wanted
to add a border around this
picture i just added a border so
highly
recommend you just mess around
with this and kind of experiment
but this is just like the general
overview of figma and the main
features that you'll use and kind
of just inside my head as i'm
navigating figma i just wanted to
get you just a live video of me
doing this