All righty.
So in this video, I'm going to be
showing you how to take your email
designs from
Figma over to Klaviyo, exactly how
to upload them and how to make
sure that they're optimized so
that you're getting good
deliverability and everything is
all like squared away.
So this
is the email in question.
Just an example.
I didn't put the footer in.
We're going to do that
inside of Klaviyo, but typically
you want to have your footer in
here as well, just so you can
reference it.
So this is our like fake email.
For example, imagine that this is
a logo.
You can
see my layers over here.
It might be a little bit cut off
here on the side, but this is our
email.
So the thing with this is in your
slicing is for example, if I just
uploaded, so essentially we're
exporting image files, we are
exporting images rather than doing
HTML.
You really don't need
In fact, it limits you.
And when you use HTML, that means
like sections built directly
inside of
Klaviyo where it's showing up as
native text inside of the
recipient's email inbox.
So if somebody like
actually sent an email, that's
HTML because those are actually,
you can like highlight all of the
words there.
So a lot of people will tell you,
you need designs with HTML.
You don't, because there are
some things that you can overcome
it inside of this video, inside of
this tutorial that I'm going to
show you.
But essentially we are just
exporting everything as image
files and we're uploading a bunch
of
images into Klaviyo.
So the thing with that is we need
to make sure that our images are
also optimized.
And so they're not massive files.
Cause if you have a massive, like
two megabyte, three megabyte
photo in your email, that's going
to take a long time to load in the
customer's inbox.
And then also
it can be kind of spammy in the
eyes of inbox providers.
If you're just attaching massive
files
to a ton of people.
So this is exactly what you want
to do.
Um, again, you don't necessarily
need to
know all these reasons you could
just follow this guide and it's
going to give you everything that
you need, but figured I'd let you
know.
So essentially we're just
exporting image files.
So what we're going to do is
inside of figma, we have these
tools here.
And what we want to do is we
want to use the slice tool.
So when you click the slice tool,
you're going to get this and you
just want
to highlight the different
sections of your email.
So since we're doing image files,
say, for example,
we just wanted to slice this whole
entire thing and we have this full
thing and we just wanted to
export this, go to export.
We wanted to export this.
The problem with that is that
there are different
products here and these need
different links.
The logo section should just click
to the homepage.
Um,
this product sections should link
to that specific product.
This product should link to that
specific
product.
And if we just have one image, you
can only attach one link per
image.
So we need to separate
them.
So instead of making this slice,
we want to have a slice per link.
And then also we just want
to make sure that our slices
aren't too big.
If you have a massive slice, your
file size is just going
to get big.
So I recommend having a maximum of
800 or so.
Um, even then that's a bit much,
maybe more like
700 or 600.
So our first slice that we're
going to do is we're just going to
do the logo because when
somebody clicks on the logo, we
just want to take them to the main
home screen.
So here's what I always
recommend.
So you slice, we have this section
and it's going to capture that and
let us export it.
I always export in two X because
if you export in one X, if you
have like a high resolution photo,
it's going to become grainy.
I like to always do two X and
change this to JPEG because it's a
slightly
smaller file.
So we can export slice one.
We can just name it slice one.
You can name it logo,
whatever you want.
We are going to, it looks like we
already have that.
So we're going to say logo one
and then boom, we created that.
Now we can create another slice
for this different section.
We're going to do this one.
So I'm just going to copy and
paste this slice.
So now I have slice two and I'm
going to move it down to the edge
of this one.
Let's make sure it's lined up.
There we go.
And then let's change the size to
go all the way down
to here.
So we can do that.
We're going to export this second
slice and then we're all set
there.
Now let's keep doing the same for
the different sections.
Now I'm not going to have a 600
size here
because I want this section to be
linking directly to this product.
So I'm going to copy and paste
this
slice again, move this one down,
have it line up perfectly to this
one.
Let's see.
There we go.
Just like that.
And then we are going to have it
end right here.
So we're slice three, slice three
test.
And then let's just do the same
for the other products, copy and
paste, line these up, move you
here, export slice for test.
And then let's do the last one.
Move you here.
Get you right to the edge and then
right there.
Slice five test.
Boom.
So now we have
all our slices.
Awesome.
Let's upload that in Klaviyo.
Not.
So when you export like 2x, you're
going to
have massive file sizes.
So we need to use an outside
platform to compress our files for
us.
So I'm going
to pull that up right now.
So this is a website called
iloveimg.com.
It's great for compressing
your images.
So we can go to
iloveimg.com/compress image.
And this is where you upload your
files and
it'll automatically compress them.
So I'm going to upload these right
now.
Alrighty.
There we go.
Here
are all the slices in their order.
And then just going to click
compress.
Then we'll see how much file
size we fit, we save.
So the slices were three megabytes
before pretty much.
And then we lowered
it to 600 kilobytes, which is
pretty awesome.
So I'm just going to download
this.
It's going to put
it in a zip file and then we can
open it.
And then boom, we have this and
now it's in there and we can
upload that to Klaviyo.
So now I'm just going to go
straight to Klaviyo over here and
you, maybe you're
familiar with Klaviyo, maybe you
aren't, but we're just going to
create like a fake campaign and
upload this.
So we're going to create a
campaign, which is just one of our
emails or emails.
Let's
go into the whole list.
Let's name this test for video,
the date.
That's fine.
We're just doing email,
continue, select your list
newsletter.
Um, we can, you can do whatever
you want with settings.
Um,
now let's go to content subject
line, SL preview text, PT, well,
copy, whatever you need to do.
And we're just going to do a drag
and drop because we're dragging
our images in.
So we can just start
blank or you can go off template,
whatever you want.
I'm just going to create a blank
email here.
And it gave me this.
So cool.
Let's just delete this.
Let's delete this.
And then we already have a
footer in for us.
Usually you're going to want to
create your own footer.
So now we literally just
want to upload our image files.
So I'm just going to drag image
here and then we can upload our
images.
So I'm just going to duplicate
this.
So we have, I believe it was five
and I'm just going to go here
and I'm going to upload these
images.
So here we go.
Just going to go first to this
logo file and then
boom, our logo comes in and then
let's do the rest now.
And it should be, if you have just
the correct
widths should just be super
coherent and look exactly as it
was in your Figma.
Now, typically if you just sent
these, um, if you just sent like
these images with no HTML,
then you could have some issues
with deliverability.
If you're just sending just like a
ton of images,
but I'm going to show you how to
overcome that right now.
So we have, well, in just a
second.
So here we are, here's our email.
We have our logo, this main
section, and then our different
sections here looks awesome.
And then we have our footer.
So now we want to put our links.
So let me
move you over here.
So you can see here there are alt
text.
You can do alt text.
If you want,
you don't need to necessarily.
That's pretty much just going to
show up.
If somebody's browser isn't
showing the images, it'll show an
alternative text, like logo.
It'll just say like logo.
Um, but you can
add your different links here to
each separate image.
Um, so this would be like my main
site and this
would be like to the product in
the picture.
This would be to this product.
This link would be to this
product and so on.
So now this gets to where we want
to overcome kind of the, we want
to add some
HTML to our email so that we are
showing inbox providers.
Okay.
There's actually text in this
email.
It's a mix of text and images.
So we're not just like blasting a
ton of emails to people.
So we have our footer here.
We have social links.
And so we have that.
And then we have,
this is actually HTML.
This is what I mean by HTML.
It's custom text inside of the
platform.
And so
kind of to improve our
deliverability to prove we're not
just doing a ton of images.
We're going
to add a bunch of HTML in our
footer.
So all I'm going to do is I'm
going to drag this.
I'm going
to drag a new text box here and
then we can add a bunch of text.
So I'm just going to go to my
website
and take a bunch of text here.
Can I even copy and paste this?
Okay.
Let me,
I'm going to take this.
You can get a free guide if you go
to my site, but I'm just going to
take some copy.
So I just got the copy from my
site.
I can delete this and then just
paste it.
And then boom, now I have a bunch
of text, but this sucks.
This doesn't look good.
And so what we can
do is let's make this very small
because nobody's going to be
reading this.
And I'll show you why
we can make this like five where
it's super small.
Let's change the line spacing.
So it's like,
I don't know, 10, you can do that.
And then even further, we're going
to just change the text to be the
exact same color as the
background.
So we make it white and then boom,
look at that.
Doesn't look
too much out of place.
If we want to cut out some of the
copy, um, in this, we can let's
just delete.
Can't even see this, make it a
little bit smaller and then boom,
then that looks good.
And then we have
a ton of HTML.
This is like a whole essays worth
and nobody can see it.
But in the eyes of the inbox
provider, it's a ton of HTML data.
And so that right there is going
to overcome any of the issues
that we could have.
Uh, everything's just right here
and we have this HTML and then
everything looks
good.
Trust me.
I've sent thousands of emails.
This has never been a problem.
So if anybody does try to
say it's a problem, they don't
know what they're talking about.
Um, I consistently get 60% opens
by doing this.
And then you're all set.
So it's always smart to preview
your email in your inbox so you
can preview
it, whatever it is, uh, whatever
your email is, you'll send a test
email and then you can check
the links, make sure everything is
good.
Everything looks good.
And then you can go on to sending
the
email.
So hopefully you found that
helpful and make sure you do that
and make sure you add some HTML
and you are good to go.
Alrighty.
So in this video, I'm going to be
showing you how to take your email
designs from Figma over to
Klaviyo, exactly how to upload
them and how to make sure that
they're
optimized so that you're getting
good deliverability and everything
is all like squared away.
So this is
the email in question.
Just an example.
I didn't put the footer in.
We're going to do that inside of
Klaviyo, but typically you want to
have your footer in here as well,
just so you can reference it.
So this is our like fake email.
For example, imagine that this is
a logo.
You can see my layers over
here.
It might be a little bit cut off
here on the side, but this is our
email.
So the thing with this
is in your slicing is for example,
if I just uploaded, so essentially
we're exporting image
files.
We are exporting images rather
than doing HTML.
You really don't need HTML.
In fact,
it limits you.
And when you use HTML, that means
like sections built directly
inside of Klaviyo,
where it's showing up as native
text inside of the recipient's
email inbox.
So if somebody like
actually sent an email, that's
HTML, because those are actually,
you can like highlight all of the
words there.
So a lot of people will tell you,
you need designs with HTML.
You don't, because there are
some things that you can overcome
it inside of this video, inside of
this tutorial that I'm going to
show
you.
But essentially we are just
exporting everything as image
files and we're uploading
a bunch of images into Klaviyo.
So the thing with that is we need
to make sure that our images are
also optimized.
And so they're not massive files,
because if you have a massive,
like two megabyte,
three megabyte photo in your
email, that's going to take a long
time to load in the customer's
inbox.
And then also it can be kind of
spammy in the eyes of inbox
providers if you're just attaching
massive
files to a ton of people.
So this is exactly what you want
to do.
Again, you don't necessarily need
to know all these reasons.
You could just follow this guide
and it's going to give you
everything
that you need, but figured I'd let
you know.
So essentially we're just
exporting image files.
So what we're going to do is
inside of Figma, we have these
tools here.
And what we want to do is we
want to use the slice tool.
So when you click the slice tool,
you're going to get this and you
just
want to highlight the different
sections of your email.
So since we're doing image files,
say for example,
we just wanted to slice this whole
entire thing and we have this full
thing and we just wanted to export
this,
go to export.
We wanted to export this.
The problem with that is that
there are different products
here and these need different
links.
The logo section should just click
to the homepage.
This
product section should link to
that specific product.
This product should link to that
specific product.
And if we just have one image, you
can only attach one link per
image.
So we need to separate them.
So instead of making this slice,
we want to have a slice per link.
And then also we just want to
make sure that our slices aren't
too big.
If you have a massive slice, your
file size is just going to get
big.
So I recommend having a maximum of
800 or so.
Even then that's a bit much, maybe
more like 700 or 600.
So our first slice that we're
going to do is we're just going to
do the logo because when somebody
clicks on the logo, we just want
to take them to the main home
screen.
So here's what I always
recommend.
So you slice, we have this section
and it's going to capture that and
let us export it.
I always export in two X because
if you export in one X, if you
have like a high resolution photo,
it's going to become grainy.
I like to always do two X and
change this to JPEG because it's a
slightly
smaller file.
So we can export slice one.
We can just name it slice one.
You can name it logo,
whatever you want.
We are going to, it looks like we
already have that.
So we're going to say logo one
and then boom, we created that.
Now we can create another slice
for this different section.
We're
going to do this one.
So I'm just going to copy and
paste this slice.
So now I have slice two and I'm
going to move it down to the edge
of this one.
Let's make sure it's lined up.
There we go.
And
then let's change the size to go
all the way down to here.
So we can do that.
We're going to export
this second slice and then we're
all set there.
Now let's keep doing the same for
the different
sections.
Now I'm not going to have a 600
size here because I want this
section to be linking directly
to this product.
So I'm going to copy and paste
this slice again, move this one
down.
have it line up perfectly to this
one.
Let's see.
There we go.
Just like that.
And then we are going to have it
end right here.
Let's go slice three, slice three
test.
And then let's just do the same
for the other products.
Copy and paste, line these up,
move you
here, export slice four test.
And then let's do the last one.
Move you here, get you right to
the edge.
And then right there, slice five
test.
Boom.
So now we have all our slices.
Awesome.
Let's upload that in Klaviyo.
Not.
So when you export like two X,
you're going to have massive file
sizes.
So we need to use an
outside platform to compress our
files for us.
So I'm going to pull that up right
now.
So this is a website called
iloveimg.com.
It's great for compressing your
images.
So
we can go to iloveimg.com slash
compress image.
And this is where you upload your
files and it'll
automatically compress them.
So I'm going to upload these right
now.
Alrighty, there we go.
Here are all the slices in their
order.
And then I'm just going to click
compress.
Then we'll see
how much file size we fit, we
save.
So the slices were three megabytes
before pretty much.
And then
we lowered it to 600 kilobytes,
which is pretty awesome.
So I'm just going to download
this.
It's going to put it in a zip file
and then we can open it.
And then boom, we have this and
now it's in there and we can
upload that to Klaviyo.
So now I'm just going to go
straight to Klaviyo over here and
you, maybe you're familiar with
Klaviyo.
Maybe you aren't, but we're just
going to create like a fake
campaign and upload this.
So we're going to create a
campaign, which is just one of our
emails or emails.
Let's go into the
whole list.
Let's name this test for video the
date.
That's fine.
We're just doing email,
continue, select your list
newsletter.
Um, we can, you can do whatever
you want with settings.
Um, now let's go to content
subject line, SL preview text, PT,
well, copy, whatever you need to
do.
Then we're just going to do a drag
and drop because we're dragging
our images in.
So we can just start
blank or you can go off template,
whatever you want.
I'm just going to create a blank
email here.
And it gave me this.
So cool.
Let's just delete this.
Let's delete this.
And then we already have a
footer in for us.
Usually you're going to want to
create your own footer.
So now we literally just
want to upload our image files.
So I'm just going to drag image
here and then we can upload our
images.
So I'm just going to duplicate
this.
So we have, I believe it was five
and I'm just going to go here
and I'm going to upload these
images.
So here we go.
Just going to go first to this
logo file and then
boom, our logo comes in and then
let's do the rest now.
And it should be, if you have just
the correct widths should just be
super coherent and look
exactly as it was in your Figma.
Now, typically if you just sent
these, um, if you just sent like
these
images with no HTML, then you
could have some issues with
deliverability if you're just
sending
just like a ton of images, but I'm
going to show you how to overcome
that right now.
So we have, well, in just a
second.
So here we are, here's our email.
We have our logo,
this main section, and then our
different sections here looks
awesome.
And then we have our footer.
So now we want to put our links.
So let me move you over here.
So you can see here there are alt
text.
You can do alt text.
If you want, you don't need to
necessarily.
That's pretty much just going to
show
up.
If somebody's browser isn't
showing the images, it'll show an
alternative text, like logo.
It'll just say like logo.
Um, but you can add your different
links here to each separate image.
Um, so this would be like my main
site and this would be like to the
product in the picture.
This would be to this product.
This link would be to this product
and so on.
So now this gets to
where we want to overcome kind of
the, we want to add some HTML to
our email so that we are showing
inbox providers.
Okay.
There's actually text in this
email.
It's a mix of text and images.
So we're not
just like blasting a ton of emails
to people.
So we have our footer here.
We have social links.
And so
we have that.
And then we have, this is actually
HTML.
This is what I mean by HTML.
It's custom text
inside of the platform.
And so kind of to improve our
deliverability, to prove we're not
just doing
a ton of images.
We're going to add a bunch of HTML
in our footer.
So all I'm going to do is I'm
going to
drag this, I'm going to drag a new
text box here, and then we can add
a bunch of text.
So I'm just
going to go to my website and take
a bunch of text here.
Can I even copy and paste this?
Okay.
Let me,
I'm going to take this.
You can get a free guide if you go
to my site, but I'm just going to
take some
copy.
So I just got the copy from my
site.
I can delete this and then just
paste it.
And then boom, now I have a bunch
of text, but this sucks.
This doesn't look good.
And so what
we can do is let's make this very
small because nobody's going to be
reading this.
And I'll show
you why we can make this like five
where it's super small.
Let's change the line spacing.
So it's like,
I don't know, 10 can do that.
And then even further, we're going
to just change the text to be the
exact
same color as the background.
So we make it white and then boom,
look at that.
Doesn't look too much
out of place.
If we want to cut out some of the
copy, um, in this, we can, let's
just delete.
Can't
even see this, make it a little
bit smaller and then boom, then
that looks good.
And then we have a ton
of HTML.
This is like a whole essays worth
and nobody can see it.
But in the eyes of the inbox
provider, it's a ton of HTML data.
And so that right there is going
to overcome any of the issues
that we could have.
Uh, everything's just right here
and we have this HTML and then
everything looks
good.
Trust me.
I've sent thousands of emails.
This has never been a problem.
So if anybody does try to
say it's a problem, they don't
know what they're talking about.
Um, I consistently get 60% opens
by
doing this and then you're all
set.
So it's always smart to preview
your email in your inbox.
So you
can preview it, whatever it is,
uh, whatever your email is, you'll
send a test email and then you can
check the links and make sure
everything is good.
Everything looks good.
And then you can go on to
sending the email.
So hopefully you found that
helpful and make sure you do that
and make sure
you add some HTML and you are good
to go.