Okay, so now let's talk about
subject lines and preview text.
I get asked about these a lot,
subject lines and preview text,
and so let us talk about them and
break them down and give you some
simple frameworks to use for this
to make them as easy as possible.
Now, I am under the belief that
your subject line and your preview
text should not matter for getting
opens.
A lot of times people are using
the subject line and preview text,
like if you have bad opens, you're
like, oh, it's a subject line and
preview text.
Disagree completely.
Your content in your emails should
be so good and your cadence just
like so consistent that you're
sending emails on like this
consistent cadence and the content
is so good every time that the
customers are conditioned to open
every email no matter what.
We want them to open our emails
based off our sender name rather
than off of the subject line and
preview text.
For example, maybe there's like
probably not a lot of people out
there, but there might be some
people out there who watch all of
my YouTube videos not because the
title is extremely relevant to
them,
or the description is super
important.
They just see it's a video from
me, they like my content, and so
they're going to watch every video
or at least click on it and check
it out.
It's going to be the same thing
for your email list.
This happens for a lot of my
favorite brands.
I'm opening because of it's this
brand.
I don't care what the subject line
and preview text says.
I'm just going to open their email
and see what's inside because
their brand I like, their content
is always good, I'm getting
information from their emails, and
they're constantly sending to me
so it's not a surprise that I'm
seeing them in my inbox.
I'm just conditioned no matter
what.
When I see this brand, I open
every email.
So I really look less at the
subject line and preview text for
opens, and I think that subject
lines and preview text are quite
overrated.
If you have a strong brand,
subject lines and preview text
won't matter too much.
But the real purpose of subject
lines and preview text is going to
be for sales.
That's all we care about in
marketing.
We want more sales.
So different subject lines and
preview text are going to change
the frame of your email and prime
the customer for sales in
different ways.
So if somebody sees an email, like
for example, you have a
bestseller's email, if you just
say, these are the bestsellers
versus bestsellers low on stock,
those are going to have different
views in the customer's eyes.
They're going to open the email
differently.
They're going to be thinking about
the products through the email
differently based off what we
said.
So we've had some subject lines
and preview text generate
literally 3x more revenue than
others.
Same copy and design.
Any A-B tests.
Test your subject lines based on
revenue and less about opens.
Let's look at this example.
Same exact email right here.
These are the same email but
different subject lines and
preview text.
This had less opens.
Less open rate.
Much higher click rate.
And a 3x in revenue.
Place to order rate.
Just from subject line.
We changed the frame at which
somebody opened that email.
I believe it was an abandoned cart
email.
And it said like, this one said
like, finish your order.
And then this one said like, your
order is ready to ship.
Or something like that.
To really prime it in the
customer's head that like, you
have an order.
It's ready to go.
We're ready for you.
Just make the move.
Rather than like, you left
something behind or something like
that.
Just completely changes the frame
of the email and gets different
results.
So really test off your revenue.
Think of your subject line as your
headline.
Preview text is your sub headline.
You don't want to give away all
your information in your subject
line and preview text.
We want to give people a hint.
But in order to really know what
we're saying, they need to open
the email to find out more.
So that's really the main thing to
make sure that we're getting like,
enough opens is give them a hint.
Don't tell them the full story.
It's just the headline and the sub
headline that's teasing the open.
So this is a simple subject line
framework that we use most often.
It looks clean.
It builds intrigue.
And will prime your customer for a
purchase.
This is for subject lines.
And then we'll go into preview
text next.
So typically what we're doing is
two to five words.
And again, don't overthink subject
lines of preview text.
There's really no right answer for
all of them.
But just do spend a little bit of
time on them.
But this is like typically what we
use most of the time.
But it's important to always be
mixing it up.
So two to five words in length.
Nothing too long.
We don't want to write a whole
sentence because that's going to
get cut off.
And it's going to scare people
off.
Two to five words in length.
It's short and sweet.
And it builds intrigue just having
a shorter headline.
Title case.
Like this sentence.
I always think it looks more
official.
Adds more legitimacy to the email
rather than having it be sentence
case.
Builds curiosity.
So we're selling people to click.
It ends with one to two emojis.
This is optional.
Good to do every now and again.
So let's look at these examples.
Title case.
Two to five words in length.
Builds curiosity.
Ends with an emoji.
A taste of sunshine.
Ooh, what does that mean?
Builds your curiosity.
Myth busted.
What myth is busted?
What?
Builds curiosity.
They're finally here.
What's finally here?
It's literally this easy.
What's this easy?
It builds curiosity.
It looks clean.
It looks official.
And then the emojis are just like
an added touch.
Which you don't want to do every
single time.
But you want to do a good amount
of the time.
Let's include emojis.
They work.
And then a preview text framework.
Do not overthink it.
Preview text.
Just build off the subject line
and create more curiosity.
That's all it is.
Do not overthink it.
So here's a framework that feeds
off of the subject line that I
like to use for the preview text.
So we want the preview text to be
one full sentence long.
Regular capitalization.
So we're not capitalizing each
thing.
Just regular sentence case.
It's going to add support to the
subject line.
And every now and again, like a
good tip that I like to use is end
with dot, dot, dot.
Really builds your intrigue and
kind of like leaves the customer
like unfinished.
And so some examples.
This wasn't supposed to be made,
but now it's a bestseller.
Dot, dot, dot.
That dot, dot, dot just really
builds your intrigue.
And you're like, uh.
And so builds off of like the
subject line.
For example, that would be like a
taste of sunshine.
With the subject, with the preview
text, this wasn't supposed to be
made, but now it's a bestseller.
And it's a taste of sunshine.
Holy cow.
Like what is this?
What does this mean?
So another one, it's available,
but the last drop sold out in 24
hours.
Same thing here.
You could say for one that's like,
you could do that for a taste of
sunshine as well.
It's available, but the last drop
sold out in 24 hours.
If you want the cold, hard facts,
we got them, dot, dot, dot.
That would be for like myth
busted.
That is a banger.
Myth busted.
If you want the cold, hard facts,
we got them, dot, dot, dot.
Oh my goodness.
I'm smashing that email.
I'm smashing to open that.
No one is talking about this, but
it will make you more money.
That could go with, it's literally
this easy.
Banger.
Builds on the subject line.
Looks good.
It's a full sentence.
Ends with dot, dot, dot.
That's how you get people to
click.
Again, don't overthink it.
If your email content is good,
people are going to open your
emails no matter what.
No matter what your subject line
and preview text.
You have good designs, you have
good copy, you have good branding,
all that good stuff.
People will just continue to open
your emails and start to open your
emails based off the
sender name and not the subject
line and preview text.
So don't overthink it.
Don't get too caught up.
Focus more on your content.
And the opens will take care of
themselves.
Okay, so now let's talk about
subject lines and preview text.
I get asked about these a lot.
Subject lines and preview text.
And so let us talk about them and
break them down and give you some
simple frameworks to
use for this to make them as easy
as possible.
Now, I am under the belief that
your subject line and your preview
text should not matter for
getting opens.
A lot of times people are using
the subject line and preview text.
Like if you have bad opens, you're
like, oh, it's a subject line and
preview text.
Disagree completely.
Your content in your emails should
be so good and your cadence just
like so consistent that
you're sending emails on like this
consistent cadence.
The content is so good every time
that the customers are conditioned
to open every email
no matter what.
We want them to open our emails
based off our sender name rather
than off of the subject
line and preview text.
For example, maybe there's like
probably not a lot of people out
there, but there might be
some people out there who watch
all of my YouTube videos, not
because the title is extremely
relevant to them or the
description is super important.
They just see it's a video from
me.
They like my content.
And so they're going to watch
every video or at least click on
it and check it out.
It's going to be the same thing
for your email list.
This happens for a lot of my
favorite brands.
I'm opening because of it's this
brand.
I don't care what the subject line
and preview text says.
I'm just going to open their email
and see what's inside because
their brand I like.
Their content is always good.
I'm getting information from their
emails and they're constantly
sending to me.
So it's not a surprise that I'm
seeing them in my inbox.
I'm just conditioned no matter
what.
When I see this brand, I open
every email.
So I really look less at the
subject line and preview text for
opens.
And I think that subject lines of
preview text are quite overrated.
If you have a strong brand,
subject lines and preview text
won't matter too much.
But the real purpose of subject
lines and preview text is going to
be for sales.
That's all we care about in
marketing.
We want more sales.
So different subject lines and
preview text are going to change
the frame of your email and prime
the customer for sales in
different ways.
So if somebody sees an email, like
for example, you have a
bestsellers email.
If you just say these are the
bestsellers versus bestsellers low
on stock, those are going to have
different views in the customer's
eyes.
They're going to open the email
differently.
They're going to be thinking about
the products through the email
differently based off what we
said.
So we've had some subject lines of
preview text generate literally 3x
more revenue than others.
Same copy and design.
Any A-B tests.
Test your subject lines based on
revenue and less about opens.
Let's look at this example.
Same exact email right here.
These are the same email but
different subject lines and
preview text.
This had less opens, less open
rate, much higher click rate, and
a 3x in revenue.
Placed order rate.
Just from subject line.
We changed the frame at which
somebody opened that email.
I believe it was an abandoned cart
email and it said like this one
said like finish your order
and then this one said like your
order is ready to ship or
something like that
to really prime it in the
customer's head that like you have
an order, it's ready to go,
we're ready for you, just make the
move rather than like you left
something behind or something like
that.
Just completely changes the frame
of the email and gets different
results.
So really test off your revenue.
Think of your subject line as your
headline, preview text as your
sub-headline.
You don't want to give away all
your information in your subject
line and preview text.
We want to give people a hint but
in order to really know what we're
saying,
they need to open the email to
find out more.
So that's really the main things
to make sure that we're getting
like enough opens is give them a
hint,
don't tell them the full story.
It's just the headline and the
sub-headline that's teasing the
open.
So this is a simple subject line
framework that we use most often.
It looks clean, it builds
intrigue, and will prime your
customer for a purchase.
This is for subject lines and then
we'll go into preview text next.
So typically what we're doing is
two to five words and again, don't
overthink subject lines of preview
text.
There's really no right answer for
all of them but just do spend a
little bit of time on them.
But this is like typically what we
use most of the time but it's
important to always be mixing it
up.
So two to five words in length,
nothing too long.
We don't want to write a whole
sentence because that's going to
get cut off and it's going to
scare people off.
Two to five words in length, it's
short and sweet and it builds
intrigue just having a shorter
headline.
Title case, like this sentence, I
always think it looks more
official, adds more legitimacy to
the email rather than having it be
sentence case.
Builds curiosity, so we're selling
people to click.
It ends with one to two emojis,
this is optional, good to do every
now and again.
So let's look at these examples.
Title case, two to five words in
length, builds curiosity, ends
with an emoji, a taste of
sunshine.
Ooh, what does that mean?
Builds your curiosity, myth
busted.
What myth is busted, what?
Builds curiosity, they're finally
here, what's finally here?
It's literally this easy, what's
this easy?
It builds curiosity, it looks
clean, it looks official, and then
the emojis are just like an added
touch,
which you don't want to do every
single time, but you want to do a
good amount of the time.
Let's include emojis, they work.
And then a preview text framework.
Do not overthink it.
Preview text, just build off the
subject line and create more
curiosity.
That's all it is.
Do not overthink it.
So here's a framework that feeds
off of the subject line that I
like to use for the preview text.
So we want the preview text to be
one full sentence long.
Regular capitalization, so we're
not capitalizing each thing, just
regular sentence case.
It's going to add support to the
subject line.
And every now and again, a good
tip that I like to use is end with
dot, dot, dot.
Really builds your intrigue and
kind of like leaves the customer
like unfinished.
And so some examples, this wasn't
supposed to be made, but now it's
a bestseller, dot, dot, dot.
That dot, dot, dot just really
builds your intrigue and you're
like, oh.
And so builds off of like the
subject line, for example, that
would be like a taste of sunshine
with the subject.
With the preview text, this wasn't
supposed to be made, but now it's
a bestseller and it's a taste of
sunshine.
Holy cow.
Like what is this?
What does this mean?
So another one, it's available,
but the last drop sold out in 24
hours.
Same thing here.
You could say for one that's like,
you could do that for a taste of
sunshine as well.
It's available, but the last drop
sold out in 24 hours.
If you want the cold, hard facts,
we got them, dot, dot, dot.
That would be for like myth
busted.
That is a banger.
Myth busted.
If you want the cold, hard facts,
we got them, dot, dot, dot.
Oh my goodness.
I'm smashing that email.
I'm smashing to open that.
No one is talking about this, but
it will make you more money.
That could go with it.
It's literally this easy.
Banger.
Builds on the subject line.
Looks good.
It's a full sentence, ends with
dot, dot, dot.
That's how you get people to
click.
Again, don't overthink it.
If your email content is good,
people are going to open your
emails no matter what.
No matter what your subject line
and preview text.
You have good designs, you have
good copy, you have good branding,
all that good stuff.
People will just continue to open
your emails and start to open your
emails based off the
sender name and not the subject
line and preview text.
So don't overthink it.
Don't get too caught up.
Focus more on your content and the
opens will take care of
themselves.