Okay, so before we really get into
what makes good copy, you're
probably already writing copy,
and you could be making these
mistakes.
So I want to first talk about what
to avoid in your copy
so that we can be clear on what we
need to have.
Sometimes it can be better to just
go over what
not to do, and that tells you what
to do.
So let's talk about what to avoid
in your copy.
So as we
went over, 2024, 2025 customer is
different than the past.
Their attention spans are shorter
than
ever.
We really need to understand that.
If you look at tracking on
websites and on ads and whatnot,
it just keeps on shrinking.
The average watch time just keeps
on going down.
Same thing applies to
emails.
So we need to understand that.
Our time, we're on the clock with
having people's attention.
So we really need to make the most
of it.
So we need to make sure that we
are avoiding this.
So
first thing to avoid, unnecessary
information.
You always hear it, copy, keep it
nice and concise.
We really, really, really, really
need to live up to that with our
emails.
A lot of the copy that I
see in emails is literally just
fluff.
That is unnecessary.
Unnecessary.
For example, when somebody
joins a newsletter, they know that
when they join, they enter their
email for like a discount, they
know
they're going to get like
exclusive access, sneak peeks,
insights, community, and they kind
of know that
those are fluff words and you kind
of just like say that.
So there's no need to waste space
talking about
that.
Because every, every extra
sentence that you add increases
the barrier of entry for a
customer to like
read that and they get more scared
with the more words somebody sees,
the more scared they get and the
more
likely they are to leave.
And so we really just want to
focus our time on useful
information that can be used by
the customer, such as your brand
unique selling propositions, your
social proof, all that.
A lot of the
branded stuff that you might want
to include, a lot of the exclusive
access stuff that you want to
include
just isn't necessary and you
shouldn't use it.
I always find that it hurts
conversions to include
that stuff.
So every sentence that you're
adding, literally every sentence
that you're adding to your
copy, just ask yourself, does this
push the customer closer to a
sale?
That's all you need to know.
So like look at this example.
This whole section is complete
wasted space.
At this brand,
we're all about elevating your
driving experience one mod at a
time.
As a subscriber, you're now part
of an exclusive community of car
enthusiasts.
We appreciate style, performance,
and quality.
Here's
what you can look forward to.
Exclusive offers, expert insights,
products, sneak peeks, yada yada.
To kick
things off, here's a 10% off
discount.
This is all the person cares
about.
All of this stuff is just
masking and hiding the discount
code that they want.
The discount code, which was right
under.
That's, you could delete all this
and just say, welcome to this.
We're excited to have you.
To kick
things off, here's 10% off.
That's going to convert a lot
better.
I guarantee it.
All this stuff is just
fluff.
Don't need all of it.
People are just there for the
discount.
I'm sorry.
People don't care as much
about you.
They care more about their
wallets.
And so that's just what they're
doing.
So that's just
completely unnecessary.
And then another one.
So I tie in design and copy very
closely.
I think they
should be hand in hand.
And we're going to talk about that
close.
We're going to talk about that
in the future.
But another thing on top of like
unnecessary information, maybe you
have good
information, but you can't have
too much in your emails.
Too much copy just increases
churn.
Even
if you have the helpful info, just
nobody's going to read it.
The shorter your copy is, the more
likely
someone will actually take the
time to read it.
This is an example.
This copy is actually
good copy.
It's talking about like what
everybody, what they changed about
like these new bars or
whatever.
It's not letting me zoom in, but
it's talking about it.
You can, this doc will be attached
for you and so you can read it.
It's a great copy, but nobody's
reading it.
If they just did like this
line and this line, then people
would read it.
But when somebody sees all this
copy, they're just going to
skip over it, go down here.
These little icons did 10x more
the effectiveness and readability
for someone.
It's just these icons.
People prefer that sort of stuff.
And that's what we're going to
talk about and what we need to be
doing with our copy.
We can't just list blocks and we
can't have information too long.
People aren't going to read that.
They're going to see that and get
scared.
Another thing is too many points.
So the customer is very,
very, very, very, very easy to get
overwhelmed.
So if you try to give your
customer five different
takeaways, like we are the best,
we have this, we also do this, and
you can also get this, and you can
also get this, they're not going
to remember any of them.
Each takeaway would get 20% of
their
attention.
If you split 100% divided by five,
20%.
Whereas if you try to just point
on one thing,
such as our product does this
specific benefit, in one takeaway,
much more likely that they're
going
to be able to remember it because
that's 100% of their attention.
This below example is great in
terms
of like talking about benefits for
the customer, but there are just
too many benefits to the point
that the customer isn't really
going to take any of them away.
It seems kind of productive to
leave
out benefits, but we found it
immensely to increase conversions.
Like right here, they're talking,
so
they're talking about the meter
block right here, and they're
saying perfect results, no strings
attached, durable construction.
It has a cook estimator, cook
graphs, cooking alerts, multi view
cook, all
this stuff.
We kind of just want to focus on
one and then meter two plus meter
and then meter block.
Like this is all way too much that
all this information is on the
landing page.
We want to get people
to click.
So we want to tease some stuff,
give them one of the benefits such
as you have, you get
perfect results because you remove
guest work, because you're
tracking like on your phone,
whatever it may be.
Then you could have one that's all
about no strings attached.
There are no strings.
It's all mobile and wireless so
that you can take it anywhere.
This could be split into like six
different emails and it would just
be way better for the customer to
take everything in.
So that's kind
of the philosophy there.
And then also boring.
Avoid being boring in your copy.
No one wants to buy
from a lame brand.
They want to buy from brands they
like.
So that seems obvious.
If a copy is lame
and they're not, you're not giving
them dopamine, they're not going
to come back.
And so include
powerful words, include puns and
cute humor and then information.
Also, if you can give valuable
information, then people will
enjoy that.
People like to learn.
People like to see that sort of
stuff.
And so this is an example of just
lame copy.
Maximum coverage and comfort in a
lightweight
performance fabric that blocks UV
rays and dries in a flash.
Like, come on.
We can make that better.
The finest con tees on earth.
Cool comfort for trail and town.
Like, it's not the end of the
world,
but you just get higher on
subscribes when you're not
entertaining people rather than
like,
um, rather than like sun's out,
sun's out, surf screen.
I don't know.
So something that can be a
little bit more fun.
Just put, put it in a chat.gbt and
say, make this more fun.
And that'll give you
everything that you need.
You can't be lame, uh, with the
customer today.
They need to be entertained.
And then lastly, no value for the
customer.
You want to avoid providing no
value.
You need to provide
value in some way, whatever it is
for the customer, such as an
exclusive offer, some useful
information,
or an engaging story that
entertains them.
If you don't have a clear value
proposition,
value you can bring the customer,
you're going to fail to capture
and retain their interest.
So
the below copy doesn't explain the
value of having travel sized
products, which makes it very
unclear
and not effective.
It's just saying, elevate your
journey, indulge in, uh, Darfin's
travel bag,
skincare essentials.
Why?
Like that doesn't, that doesn't
tell me anything rather than
like, um, um, get, uh, airline
approved.
Never worry about never get your,
uh, never get your
skincare lotion confiscated at the
airline ever again, or what, what,
something along those lines
where it's talking about the
benefit, uh, take these on the go,
never have to worry about picking
up
whatever your skincare stuff at
the store on, on your vacation
spot.
That could be worded a lot
better, but you get the point.
Elevate your journey.
That isn't, that isn't telling me
anything.
indulge in our travel bag
essentials.
That isn't telling me anything.
I need to know
what is the benefit for me, such
as never, such as being able to
take this on the go, um, and not
get it confiscated.
So that's like the, that's like
the value that we need.
Um, so that I just
accidentally, um, clicked off, but
okay.
So that is what to avoid in your
copy.
You want to make sure that
you're giving value.
You have to avoid being boring.
You have to avoid too many points
and
sharing too many points.
You have to avoid being too long
with your messaging.
You need to avoid
unnecessary information.
So that is it for this one.
Now let's get into what we want to
do.
Okay.
So before we really get into what
makes good copy, you're probably
already writing copy
and you could be making these
mistakes.
So I want to first talk about what
to avoid in your copy
so that we can be clear on what we
need to have.
Sometimes it can be better to just
go over what not to do.
And that tells you what to do.
So let's talk about what to avoid
in your copy.
So as we went over
2024, 2025 customer is different
than the past.
Their attention spans shorter than
ever.
We really
need to understand that.
If you look at tracking on
websites and on ads and whatnot,
it just keeps on
shrinking.
The average watch time just keeps
on going down.
Same thing applies to emails.
So we need to
understand that our time we're on
the clock with having people's
attention.
So we really need to make the
most of it.
So we need to make sure that we
are avoiding this.
So first thing to avoid
unnecessary
information.
You always hear it copy, keep it
nice and concise.
We really, really, really, really
need to
live up to that with our emails.
A lot of the copy that I see in
emails is literally just fluff.
That is
unnecessary.
Unnecessary.
For example, when somebody joins a
newsletter, they know that when
they join,
they enter their email for like a
discount.
They know they're going to get
like exclusive access,
sneak peeks, insights, community,
and they kind of know that those
are fluff words and you kind of
just like say that.
So there's no need to waste space
talking about that because every
extra sentence
that you add increases the barrier
of entry for a customer to like
read that and they get more scared
with the more words somebody sees,
the more scared they get and the
more likely they are to leave.
And so we really just want to
focus our time on useful
information that can be used by
the customer,
such as your brand unique selling
propositions, your social proof,
all that.
A lot of the branded
stuff that you might want to
include, a lot of the exclusive
access stuff that you want to
include
just isn't necessary and you
shouldn't use it.
I always find that it hurts
conversions to include
that stuff.
So every sentence that you're
adding, literally every sentence
that you're adding to your
copy, just ask yourself, does this
push the customer closer to a
sale?
That's all you need to know.
So like look at this example.
This whole section is complete
wasted space.
At this brand, we're all
about elevating your driving
experience one mod at a time.
As a subscriber, you're now part
of an
exclusive community of car
enthusiasts who appreciate style,
performance, and quality.
Here's what you can
look forward to.
Exclusive offers, expert insights,
product sneak peeks, yada yada.
To kick things off,
here's a 10% off discount.
This is all the person cares
about.
All of this stuff is just masking
and
hiding the discount code that they
want.
The discount code, which was right
under.
You could
delete all this and just say,
welcome to this.
We're excited to have you.
To kick things off,
you're 10% off.
That's going to convert a lot
better.
I guarantee it.
All this stuff is just fluff.
Don't need all of it.
People are just there for the
discount.
I'm sorry.
People don't care as much
about you.
They care more about their
wallets.
And so that's just what they're
doing.
So that's just
completely unnecessary.
And then another one.
So I tie in design and copy very
closely.
I think they
should be hand in hand.
And we're going to talk about that
close.
We're going to talk about that
in the future.
But another thing on top of like
unnecessary information, maybe you
have good
information, but you can't have
too much in your emails.
Too much copy just increases
churn.
Even
if you have the helpful info, just
nobody's going to read it.
The shorter your copy is, the more
likely
someone will actually take the
time to read it.
This is an example.
This copy is actually
good copy.
It's talking about like what
everybody, what they changed about
like these new bars or
whatever.
It's not letting me zoom in, but
it's talking about it.
You can, this doc will be attached
for you and so you can read it.
It's a great copy, but nobody's
reading it.
If they just did like this
line and this line, then people
would read it.
But when somebody sees all this
copy, they're just
going to skip over it, go down
here.
These little icons did 10x more
the effectiveness and readability
for someone.
It's just these icons.
People prefer that sort of stuff.
And that's what we're going
to talk about and what we need to
be doing with our copy.
We can't just list blocks and we
can't have
information too long.
People aren't going to read that.
They're going to see that and get
scared.
Another thing is too many points.
So the customer is very, very,
very, very, very easy to get
overwhelmed.
So if you try to give your
customer five different takeaways,
like we are the best,
we have this, we also do this, and
you can also get this, and you can
also get this,
they're not going to remember any
of them.
Each takeaway would get 20% of
their attention.
If you split 100% divided by five,
20%.
Whereas if you try to just point
on one thing, such as
our product does this specific
benefit, in one takeaway, much
more likely that they're going
to be able to remember it because
that's 100% of their attention.
This below example is great
in terms of like talking about
benefits for the customer, but
there are just too many benefits
to the point that the customer
isn't really going to take any of
them away.
It seems kind of
productive to leave out benefits,
but we found it immensely to
increase conversions.
Like right here,
they're talking, so they're
talking about the meter block
right here, and they're saying
perfect
results, no strings attached,
durable construction.
It has a cook estimator, cook
graphs, cooking alerts,
multi-view cook, all this stuff.
We kind of just want to focus on
one, and then meter two plus
meter,
and then meter block.
Like this is all way too much.
All this information is on the
landing page.
We want to get people to click, so
we want to tease some stuff.
Give them one of the benefits,
such as
you have, you get perfect results
because you remove guest work,
because you're tracking like on
your
phone, whatever it may be.
Then you could have one that's all
about no strings attached.
There are no
strings.
It's all mobile and wireless so
that you can take it anywhere.
This could be split into like six
different emails, and it would
just be way better for the
customer to take everything in.
So that's
kind of the philosophy there.
And then also boring.
Avoid being boring in your copy.
No one wants to
buy from a lame brand.
They want to buy from brands they
like.
So that seems obvious.
If your copy is
lame and you're not giving them
dopamine, they're not going to
come back.
And so include powerful
words, include puns and cute
humor, and then information also.
If you can give valuable
information,
then people will enjoy that.
People like to learn.
People like to see that sort of
stuff.
And so
this is an example of just lame
copy.
Maximum coverage and comfort in a
lightweight performance
fabric that blocks UV rays and
dries in a flash.
Like, come on.
We can make that better.
The finest
quantities on earth.
Cool comfort for trail and town.
Like, it's not the end of the
world, but you just get
higher on subscribes when you're
not entertaining people rather
than like,
rather than like sun's out, sun's
out, surf screen.
I don't know.
So something that can be a little
bit
more fun.
Just put it in a chat GPT and say,
make this more fun.
And that'll give you everything
that
you need.
You can't be lame with the
customer today.
They need to be entertained.
And then lastly,
no value for the customer.
You want to avoid providing no
value.
You need to provide value in some
way,
whatever it is for the customer,
such as an exclusive offer, some
useful information or an engaging
story
that entertains them.
If you don't have a clear value
proposition, value you can bring
the customer,
you're going to fail to capture
and retain their interest.
So the below copy doesn't explain
the
value of having travel sized
products, which makes it very
unclear and not effective.
It's just saying
elevate your journey.
Indulge in Darfin's travel bag,
skincare essentials.
Why?
Like that doesn't, that doesn't
tell me anything rather than like,
um, get, uh, airline
approved.
Never worry about never get your,
uh, never get your skincare lotion
confiscated at the
airline ever again.
Or what, what, something along
those lines where it's talking
about the benefit,
uh, take these on the go.
Never have to worry about picking
up whatever your skincare stuff at
the
store on, on your vacation.
That could be worded a lot better,
but you get the point.
Elevate your
journey.
That isn't, that isn't telling me
anything.
Indulge in our travel bag
essentials.
That isn't
telling me anything.
I need to know what is the benefit
for me, such as never, such as
being able
to take this on the go, um, and
not get it confiscated.
So that's like the, that's like
the value
that we need.
Um, so that I just accidentally,
um, clicked off, but okay.
So that is what to avoid in
your copy.
You want to make sure that you're
giving value.
You have to avoid being boring.
You have to avoid too many points
and sharing too many points.
You have to avoid being too
long with your messaging.
You need to avoid unnecessary
information.
So that is it for this
one.
Now let's get into what we want to
do.