Okay, okay, that all makes sense
in theory.
Yes, we want a high-converting
pop-up,
but how exactly do you make an
effective pop-up form?
That is what we are going to be
going over
in this very, very, very, very,
very important doc here.
Lots of jam-packed information
here.
So these are the steps you want to
do
when creating a pop-up form.
First, we want to establish the
offer.
Choose what incentive you're going
to be giving the recipients.
The stronger your incentive, the
higher your opt-ins,
but again, you want to be able to
balance it
so that you're not giving like 90%
off your products
because obviously that's a bad
look for your brand
or you're giving somebody,
everybody who signs up gets a free
Tesla Cybertruck.
No.
So first, we want to establish our
offer.
What do we want to do?
And then we want to choose what
form type you want.
So I'm giving you five different
form types
and then pick a starting point.
I'll give you recommendations.
Three, we want to create our form
in Klaviyo or Amped.
Use my tutorial guides,
which I'm going to show you for
your form
and your desired platform.
Then four, run your form through
my checklist,
which I will show you,
the high-converting form
checklist,
and then set up your A-B test and
test from there.
So number one, establish your
offer.
Your offer is the most important
part
in terms of getting conversions.
So we want to really try off,
try different offers based on our
margins
and then what opt-in rates we're
getting.
Like obviously if you don't have
good margins,
don't be given like $500 off your
first order.
So a great test to ask yourself
is,
if I was given this offer,
would I exchange my email for it?
So make sure you're testing all
these different styles.
Do percent off versus dollar off.
So this is a great test to do.
Typically if your average order
value
is below $100, you want to do
percent off.
If your average order value is
above $100,
you want to do dollar off.
Because say your product sells
for,
say your product is $50,
that's your average order value.
You could either say, so 10%,
say you want your offer to be
around like 10%.
So 10% of $50 is $5.
So you're telling people, hey, $5
off.
That doesn't sound as good as 10%
Would you rather have $5 off or
10% off?
Probably 5% off.
Meanwhile, if your average order
value is $500,
10% would be $50.
Would you rather say, hey, do you
want 10% off
or do you want $50 off?
Do you want a $50 bill?
That sounds a lot better.
So make sure you test those,
but that's just a way to start.
A mystery discount is a great way
as well.
Say no matter what,
you want to give somebody 10% off,
you could just frame it as a
mystery discount
and then be like, open your email
for your mystery discount.
That can work well.
You could do a free X with like
your order.
So get a free pair of socks with
an order of pants,
something like that.
You could do free shipping.
You could do like a giveaway
entry.
Like every month you do a giveaway
for Cybertruck.
It doesn't need to be that crazy.
You can do a giveaway, sign up for
a giveaway.
You can do a free guide,
like how to do XYZ in X amount of
days,
or you could do like early access.
That's something that you could
do.
If you don't want to offer any
discount,
you could just say, hey, sign up
to our email list
for like early access on all this
stuff
or something.
You just want to make sure that
it's enticing
because typically sign up to our
newsletter
for free tips and content.
That's not really enticing enough.
So you really want to make it,
you want to make sure there's a
value prop in there.
So make sure that you do that
if you're not doing a discount.
So now that you have your offer,
we want to choose what type of
form that we want.
So different forms are going to
have
different effectiveness based on
your audience.
Depends on like how the form loads
and all that good stuff.
It's important to give all of
these forms a shot
and see what resonates best
because truly you don't know.
It doesn't matter what you think.
What matters is the numbers.
What do the numbers say?
So start with one and then test
from there.
Your best bet is going to be the
classic
or the micro commit.
So here's what the classic looks
like.
It's literally just a simple,
hey, take this off your order
or whatever it is
and then they enter their email
and then you're good to go.
Then you also have the micro
commit,
which is just an extra step
before the enter your email.
So the micro commit,
just before the email,
you say, do you want this
discount?
And this works really well.
A lot of times this performs
better on mobile
for some reason.
It's just the commitment bias.
That is the reason.
It's a psychology trick,
which essentially this seems
a very low barrier to entry for
somebody.
It's just 10% off.
Yeah, I want 10% off.
So they click it
and then they've already committed
something.
So they're already like down the
funnel.
So they're like,
I might as well just enter my
email.
So that works a lot better.
In some cases,
depends on the audience.
You have the quiz here.
So you could be,
you could gamify it a little bit.
So you say,
hey, you've got this discount.
You just have to tell us this.
And then it really,
it's the same sort of thing.
They don't know
that they have to enter their
email
and they're much more likely to
enter it here.
Then also it feels like
they earned their discount.
It's like, oh, okay,
I gave them this information
in exchange for this discount.
I'll claim my discount
because I earned it.
So that works really well.
And you also get information
about the customer this way,
which is very, very good.
You also have the spin to win,
which is only available
on some platforms.
Just spin to win,
get this discount.
In most cases,
in all cases,
you just have it land
on like whatever the discount is.
Make it the highest offer though.
So spin to win,
win this,
congrats,
you won it,
enter your email to claim it.
Then you also have something
like the uncover your discount
where it's a little bit more
gamified.
This isn't going to work
for all brands
in terms of like branding,
but just like choose this
discount,
uncover your,
or choose a box,
uncover your discount
and it's a lot more engaging
for somebody.
So those are the different
options.
Typically,
you're going to go
with like one of these two
in 90% of cases,
that's just what you're going to
do.
Three,
we need to create your form
in Klaviyo or Amped.
Klaviyo and Amped
are different pop-ups platforms.
So Klaviyo is just,
hopefully you're using that
for your email marketing.
And then Amped
is a separate pop-up platform,
which is a different,
it's a separate cost for you,
but it's really,
really good.
I love Amped.
We see a lot better results
on Amped for our clients
and so I would highly recommend
it,
but it is an extra cost.
The ROI is like worth it always.
If you have a 10% form on Klaviyo,
a lot of times you can get it
to like 15% on Amped.
So tutorials will be provided
in a future module.
Four, you want to run your form
through this winning checklist
in terms of how it is laid out.
We only want to ask
for one input per step,
so we don't want to ask
what's your email,
what's your phone number,
what is your birth certificate,
I don't know.
You don't want to ask anything
besides just one thing.
If you want to get multiple things
like email and phone number,
ask for email first
and then phone number
in the next step.
So that's going to drastically
improve your conversions
because if somebody sees
so many inputs,
they're just going to X out.
They're like,
I don't want to do all that.
If you do it one by one,
you at least get some information.
So we also want to make sure
the time delay is 4 to 12 seconds
because we don't want
to fire it right away.
It's going to hurt
the customer experience.
We want to give it a little delay.
We also want the form
to load instantly
after the delay.
So say it's four seconds,
we want the form
to just pop up instantly
and not like load in.
Usually that's going to happen
like if your image files
are too big
so you'd want to compress it.
So you want to make sure
that it loads instantly
with no lag.
We want our form
to cover at least 75%
of the screen.
The bigger the form,
typically the better it performs.
We want it to have
under 10 words of copy.
Don't try to give somebody
a ton of information.
Just trust me.
You can test it yourself.
Put a bunch of information
on what somebody gets
in the email list
and then just have one
where it's just like,
you're 10% off.
And I can almost promise you
it's going to perform better.
We want to make sure
the offer is the largest
aspect of the form
so that like 10% off
isn't a small part of it.
We literally want it
to be 10% off
so somebody literally
can't miss it
so that even a blind person
could see it.
And then also,
this is a bonus,
but there's no X button,
but rather like a
closed form button
underneath the submit button.
So rather than putting
like an X
in the top right corner
of your pop-up,
everybody's conditioned
at this point
to just right when
they see a pop-up,
they just go to the top
right corner and click it
without even looking.
So if we can put the X
somewhere else
or just have a closed form button
underneath like the submit button,
it forces somebody
to look at the offer
and then close from there.
So highly recommend doing that.
Then five,
we want to set up
our A-B test.
So no form's going to be
perfect on the first go.
You must be setting up tests
at least weekly
to slowly inch up your form.
So just to really help you
understand this,
for every 1% increase
in conversions
that you're able to get,
which is very easy
on pop-up forms,
on 10,000 visitors,
that's an extra 100 subscribers.
Imagine 100 people
standing in a line.
Literally just from
a little A-B test,
that is what you can get.
So make sure that you're
setting up your A-B tests.
And these are the top 7 A-B tests
that you should be running
on your form.
We have the offer,
highest level that you can test,
try the different offers
outlined above that I showed,
and even try doing
the mystery offer,
even if you want to give $10 off,
have your pop-up be,
hey, sign up and get
a mystery offer.
Sometimes that can perform better.
Two, we want to test
different form types,
so it's another very large lever,
so try the different form types
that I went over.
Try micro commit,
try regular,
try doing a quiz,
try doing a spin to win.
You can even test out things
like doing a pop-up
versus like a full page
versus like a fly-out,
which are all settings
inside of Klaviyo.
Three, our closed form
functionality,
so try using the closed form
button
versus the X in the corner,
see if that performs better,
try an X in the other corner.
Try saying closed form,
try saying no thanks,
I don't want this discount.
That's something that you can do.
Time delay,
so we want to make sure,
so you can do four seconds
versus 12 seconds,
we just want to make sure
that we're maximizing
and choosing the winner
based on the total number
of submits,
because, for example,
if you have a 60-second delay
on your pop-up form
and you're running that
versus like a four-second delay,
usually if somebody's been
on your site for 60 seconds,
they're going to take a discount,
so you might have
a really high conversion rate
on that pop-up.
Somebody's been looking
at your website for a while
and so maybe you have
like a 10% conversion rate
on a 60-second delay.
The problem with that
is how many people
are on your site for 60 seconds?
Not a lot,
versus compared to
like how many people
are on your site
for four seconds.
So maybe you have
a 5% converting form
at four seconds
and a 10% converting form
at 60 seconds,
but the total submits
is going to go
to the four-second
because a lot more people
are seeing it
and so I'd rather have
5% of 10,000
rather than 10% of 1,000.
So make sure
that you're looking at that.
Five, you can test
different photos
and photo content,
kind of like the design
overall look of your pop-up.
You should test
the placement of your photos
also, either like in the form
or like as the backdrop
so test photo content.
You can test the copy
so you can try
unlock my offer
versus unlock this offer,
claim this offer
and then colors.
Not a massive lever
but it can make a difference.
Typically the less colors
you have the better.
Try different shades,
try white,
try black,
try different colors
and these are all
in order from
highest effectiveness,
highest levers
to lowest levers.
So make sure
that you test these out
and then you can have
some great form.
So that is the fifth step
is to test