All right let's talk about the
thing that most people F up and
that is list growth.
That is what
this next module is going to be
on.
How do you grow your list?
How do you get more people on
your list?
And how do you do it effectively
to where you're getting the most
out of like the
site traffic that you're bringing?
So let's talk about it.
So there are four methods of list
growth,
four main methods.
We have pop-up forms, we have
post-purchase opt-ins, we have
sign-up pages,
and sign-up embeds.
Now kind of in this order is
typically how people come in in
terms of like
numbers.
Like most people are going to come
in from pop-ups, then
post-purchase opt-ins,
sign-up pages, and then sign-up
embeds.
So let's just talk real quick.
Who is more likely to make
more money this year?
So we have brand A.
They currently have 10,000 email
subscribers but they
also gain 2,000 subscribers a
month.
In brand B, they have 20,000 email
subscribers but they gain
250 subscribers a month.
Huh?
What do you think?
I'm going with brand A because the
value of new
subscribers is just much higher
than old subscribers who are
probably, you have 20,000 current
email
subscribers, probably only 5,000
of them are still engaged.
And then for this, there's
probably only
like 4,000, 3,000 people that are
still engaged.
And you're gaining 250 a month.
It's going to be
very hard to convert people right
off the bat and get sales right
off the bat because there's kind
of that honeymoon phase.
After somebody signs up within
that first like 6 to 12 months,
that's a
honeymoon phase where somebody's
probably going to place multiple
orders with you if you can make
the
customer experience correct.
And also, subscribers will just
naturally churn.
Over time, people will
naturally lose interest to your
brand and your emails.
Like you can't, you can't expect
somebody
to be a part of your brand forever
unless you're like Starbucks.
Like people will move on and
that's
just part of the game.
So you always need to be
replenishing your active
subscribers at a higher
rate than you're losing them.
If you lose 100 subscribers a
month, you should be gaining at
least
200.
So in this situation, this, these
current email subscribers are
probably slowly going to be
falling off.
Same as here, but we're getting
2,000 a month extra and we're
getting, we're gaining 250
subscribers a month.
Now they're probably just going to
be flatlining.
If you're gaining 250,
they're probably getting like 250
unsubscribes a month.
So that's why I am taking brand A.
So
let's talk about people need
content to convert.
So again, there are thousands of
econ brands in your
niche that are out there and just
people need info about your brand
to convert.
And people just don't
trust you right off the bat.
They've seen one ad from you.
They're not going to trust you.
So it's just
very rare for somebody to go to
your site and buy the first time
they see you and just buy right on
the spot.
So you need to get their email.
That's the importance of email is
to send these people
content, nurture them to get them
over the edge, to get them to
trust you.
Rule of seven, somebody needs
to see your brand seven times in
order to trust you enough to
purchase.
That's the whole basis of
everything here.
And email is the cheapest way to
do this.
So the value of a new subscribers,
new subscribers
are just worth more than past
subscribers.
They just opted into your list and
they're probably ready to
buy.
They're in the honeymoon phase.
There's fresh interest.
They're probably going to buy
within the
next couple of weeks.
They're probably, they probably
have a strong need for your
product and
they're looking at you versus a
couple other competitors.
I was looking at getting an ice
bath
recently.
And so I opted in, I went to a few
different sites, got offered
discounts, joined their email
lists.
And then I was kind of in this
phase where I was going to buy
from one of them.
And I ended up going with
the one that I had the best
relationship with and I thought
they connected with me the most.
And so
that right there, value of a new
subscriber.
Whereas old subscribers, you could
have a hundred
thousand people on your email
list, but five thousand of them
may only be active.
And so that's why we
really need to focus on these
fresh subscribers.
So it's as simple as more people
joining your list,
the more money you make.
If a brand getting 20,000 email
subscribers new a month, it's
going to make
more than a brand getting 10,000.
So it's really just that simple.
It is that simple.
Get more people on
your list.
If you double your list growth
over the long run, you're going to
be doubling your revenue
because twice as more people to
market to.
So make sure you dial this in and
that's what we are going
to be going over in this module.