All right all right what's up guys
so first off this is going to be
probably the most in-depth
click funnels tutorial that many
of you guys have really ever gone
through so at the same time we're
gonna be talking about you know a
lot of best practices as well for
building funnels in general
landing pages and stuff like that
plus you guys of course are going
to get some of our templates
that you can plug and play into
click funnels 2.0 and just go
ahead and utilize so if you don't
know
click funnels has essentially 1.0
as it stands right now it is
august 28th 2025 and we have click
funnels 1.0 and we also have click
funnels 2.0 this is 2.0 so
personally i like building on 2.0
you
can still build on 1.0 a lot of
the stuff looks kind of similar on
the back end but there are some
some key major differences
especially on this dashboard here
and everything but
honestly they're starting to
support 2.0 obviously a lot more
that's what they're trying to push
they
say they're still they say that
they're still maintaining 1.0 but
at the end of the day it's
a legacy product so a lot of the
new features are getting rolled
out on 2.0 and overall the coding
language react that click funnels
2.0 uses is just very very user
responsive very clean looks great
and overall this is our choice for
funnel building um at our agency
so without further ado we're just
going to go over in this first
video just this overall like setup
here what it what what happens
when you first land um on this in
click funnel so first off this is
your dashboard if you are
selling if you are selling stuff
through click funnels which you
can do um you will have you know
all of
your stats right here a lot of our
campaigns are just lead gen stuff
but if you're doing like a low
ticket funnel or something and you
integrate um click funnels with
payments ai it's called it's
their gateway to stripe um you'll
be able to see some of the stats
here and stuff like that you could
also of course see leads like form
fills and all that there too this
will be uh sales now down here
they have this whole kind of setup
wizard stuff you can click on that
if you want to do the whole
customize my funnel thing and
follow their stuff they also have
a bunch of like ai templates and
um you know their whole of course
he's got his one funnel away uh
weekly coaching and challenge
stuff
um on there i don't ever really
touch that stuff i also don't
touch this smart funnel builder
um mainly what you're going to be
doing is either hitting create a
funnel if you want to create
something
from total scratch or you're going
to take one of the share links
from one of our funnels that we
have
whether you're doing a call funnel
webinar low ticket challenge
whatever it is you're going to
take that template paste it up
here in the search bar hit enter
and it's going to populate that
template right inside of your
account and then you will go
inside of funnels here which is
our next
section and you'll be able to see
that funnel right there so this is
all of our funnels we do have
some that we keep for our clients
in our account we have other ones
that we share to them
and basically run them from their
account but essentially here this
is where you see all of
your funnels you can see archived
ones you can see imported ones so
again the imported ones are the
ones that you essentially imported
from another account which will be
the ones that you uh you see that
we
share to you and right here let's
just go into one of our funnels so
if you look at the actual line
here you'll be able to see the
amount of steps the amount of
pages in the funnel unique
visitors page views
opt-ins sales orders and then
you'll be able to see analytics
open it in a new window so you can
actually just open the page itself
then you'll also be able to
duplicate that funnel so say
you're an
agency and you just run the same
sort of VSL call funnel structure
over and over and over again you
just
go here and hit duplicate funnel
and that'll duplicate it and then
you can also click here and edit
the master
settings for this funnel now this
is very key i did show this in
another video but um you want to
of
course make sure that your domain
is connected and we'll go over
that in a second i'm going to open
this tab but you want to make sure
the respective domain is connected
to that actual funnel itself
into your click funnel account
overall i like to switch the
favicon image favicon i don't know
how to
pronounce it but favicon image
here and i'm just going to slap
that logo there so in the corner
it'll
actually look like this and not
the click funnels logo that's
where you solve that there
you could also set up style sheets
which we'll go over later that's
going to be universal style sheets
for a certain client and then
whenever you want to go and paste
your meta pixel code this is where
you're going to paste it in the
head code the main pixel code you
grab when you create your pixel on
meta
will go in here it's not going to
go in the header section of each
and every page it will go in here
okay and you have your footer code
there if you do want to put stuff
there i always toggle this off i
don't
want to have the click funnels
badge showing up on things and
then if you want to share your
funnel
to a client or some someone else
you click generate funnel link
share funnel link you can have the
affiliate code attached if you
want and then hit generate a share
or generate a funnel share link
and
then you'll just send them that
link that it gives you after that
make sure to scroll down if you
make
any changes and click update
funnel and you'll be good to go so
that is the funnel settings now
let's go over to domains so
domains is very easy right i have
done their whole free domain thing
so
their whole get a free domain
through ionos.com i think it is
whatever registrar that they use
for
domains i've noticed that it's
very annoying to log in again
after that so personally i just
use godaddy
that's it it's very easy just grab
your domain on godaddy or if you
have a different registrar where
your domain is at or a different
provider you know totally cool um
i just like to do add existing
domain after i've purchased that
domain enter it here and then
follow their setup wizard it's
very very
very easy very straightforward
they tell you what to copy and
paste what to do for the dns
records and
everything like that um if you
can't figure it out it's they have
a ton of different things on their
their site too for you know just
type in like click funnels 2.0
godaddy domain setup right
and it's going to tell you right
there so very easy straight and
straightforward on that front so
now going back into just the
overall general builder and
everything here if you want to
essentially create a funnel from
scratch you can go to create
funnel
and you can do a squeeze funnel
which is essentially like a normal
lead funnel a summit funnel
book funnel cart funnel challenge
funnel product launch webinar
funnel video sales letter funnel
application funnel and all these
other funnels right so if you want
to pick a template of theirs
you can do so or you can just
start from complete scratch up
here if you do want to say you
want
to take one of their vsl funnels
here they got a nice little video
here with uh good old russell
telling you what it is telling you
the actual whole steps of it and
everything and then you could
preview a few of the templates and
then click here to select it and
import it but again we give you
proven templates for a reason but
if you're like hey i just want to
experiment on my own and try
something you know else or new
whatever you can go here and click
that just know that uh if you're
selling to a lot of internet
marketers i've seen these
templates all the time i know
exactly what they look
like and i immediately i'm like
yep that's a click funnels
template uh so it just doesn't
show any
originality and creativity so just
keep that in mind if you do that
i'm just setting a note too
their support is halfway decent
it's okay i click this chat bubble
in the bottom and you'll be able
to get support from them but um
yep and then if we go over to
analytics you can see again if
you're doing
actual like sales through a funnel
you'll be able to see that here
you can toggle by date up here
and you can see by each page step
all these different metrics here
like opt-ins if you have
opt-ins so opt-ins will show if
you're using a click funnels form
a click funnels embedded input
form so
where you put name phone number
and email you pull it from the
actual click funnels widget bar
and toolbar
so using their in-app stuff not if
you're like embedding a hubspot
form or an active campaign form
or whatever it is it will not show
up here so most of the time when
we're doing analysis for our
clients we're going to pull just
unique page views right here from
these sheets or from the from this
section here that's what we go off
of so that essentially is the
funnels tab very straightforward
and easy if we go to products
you'll be able to see all products
collections and inventory so this
is
where if you actually want to make
a product you can so you can go
there and create a product here
you can
also click here to set up payments
and that's going to again have
their gateway payments ai set up
it'll
pop up the whole wizard and
everything and you'll connect that
to your stripe account for direct
payment processing so if you do
want to run like a low ticket
product funnel or a challenge
funnel you
want to sell directly through this
totally good just click set up
payments and then when you go to
create product you can do physical
if it's like a book funnel book or
something like that or you're
sending
something physical have it you
know be there if it's a digital
just do that we'll do like test
test
great product you can do if it's a
payment plan one-time subscription
one-time product sorry or a
subscription so let's just say
it's a one-time thing for you know
hundred bucks do you set price you
can
add an image to it you can add
another price variant you can do
some tags for it if you'd like so
if I want
to do like I don't know you know
low ticket funnel ads something I
can make a tag there I can add it
to
collections and then you can add a
skew if you want just keep track
of things that's if you have
like a ton of products and then if
you do want to host different
courses and stuff like that on
here
in different digital assets you
can you just click that and then
add the asset I personally never
do
that so I usually just use kajabi
for courses and stuff or whatever
I noticed that click funnels
essentially their whole course
section and all that and they're
you know they're basically their
education portal is not too hot so
I personally don't do that but if
you want to do that you can
click there on whatever hit create
course and begin doing that and
you can also edit the SEO
so if you want to like label it
differently if it is shared there
you go and always make sure as
well
to toggle it on online store and
customer center for some reason if
those aren't toggled on it won't
show up properly inside of the
actual inside of the actual
checkout page I don't know why but
anyways
then if you go to customers over
here you have a bunch of different
things you can see all your
individual contacts and you're
able to go here and just filter
out by all these different things
so you can filter out by different
contact attributes contact
activity products broadcasts and
some
custom stuff so I always like to
do like opting in on funnel step
and I'll pick you know a certain
funnel step for example you know
pick like that whatever funnel
step here apply more it'd probably
be like
like our our webinar one right you
can pick that and pretty much the
funnel step is the actual page
itself so if you have like one
funnel with multiple different
opt-in pages and you want to see
okay
who opted in through page one I
want to export that list you go to
opt in on funnel step and just
pick that
up that page essentially but very
self-explanatory in this part too
nothing too crazy a bunch of
different
options for you if you do want to
filter through through there and
then you'll be able to see all
your orders subscriptions all that
fun stuff on this side as well
this is their you know learn and
connect
kind of section with different
courses and training materials and
their community all that fun stuff
you want
to dive through it I haven't been
through it I just get my hands
dirty in this and start building
stuff a couple other things too is
they do a great referral program I
can lie so if you are an agency
like myself like we don't make a
ton of money off this but whatever
it pays for half my car I have a
fun car so it's dope just like
send it to clients and stuff have
them sign up they're gonna sign up
anyways site and blog this here is
if you're having like a full-blown
website this is where you'll go
not
funnels so you know you do want to
play with that go for it but just
like a different building area
analytics is where you'll be able
to see overall analytics and some
more deeper reporting stuff like
that so you can do all funnels you
get click different funnels and
all that fun stuff sort by date
range
automations is we'll do a couple
workflows now some of the
automations here are very bare
bones so like
most of the time we're just doing
hey if we have this person that
opts in on this page here so event
type
opt-in on this funnel on this page
we toggle it on I want them to you
know get a tag added or something
and other times especially if
we're using like hubspot or
something we'll go over to here
it's just a normal
workflow builder it doesn't have a
lot of functionality most of the
time like 99% of the time we have
to use a beer
for stuff but sometimes you'll be
able to just go here click
third-party integration and they
do have
a lot of integrations here but
I've noticed that there's not a
lot of capabilities like even if I
go
to hubspot there's not a lot of
things that I can do essentially
probably not going to go and won't
won't do that one now but anyway
so there's like a couple things
you can like add to list or add a
tag
in hubspot or create the contact
in hubspot there's not a lot of
functionality so I default to
if I need to create some sort of
automation between you know click
funnels if I'm doing an opt-in on
click funnels to my CRM then what
I'll just simply do is use Zapier
just to connect the two so it's a
lot
easier from what I've noticed and
community no idea what that is
honestly landing pages here I
honestly
have not ever dove into this here
but it looks like it's just simply
the individual pages for each
one of our funnels something that
you can do that I'm actually just
realized now that I need to have
our team do is just go in here and
like relabel these individual
landing pages because sometimes
when you're doing zaps like this
is what's going to show up like if
you have hey if they opted on this
landing page or this funnel step
you know send them basically like
pull that information off and fire
them
through the into the CRM and it'll
show up like this when you go for
your selection you'll know
what I mean when when this when
you actually go to do this if you
do so you know you can go in here
and just change up the actual name
of the landing page which is
pretty cool so that's an overview
of everything and really just
other than that I mean you have
workspaces or sorry the workspace
settings
here so a bunch of other things
this is where you like add people
to it under collaborators
you can add different
administrators and users this is
where you connect your domains and
all that fun
stuff email settings email
templates if you do want to send
out emails with them I personally
don't like
i said i use like hubspot ghl
pretty much anything else so um i
don't really default to that and
um
yeah other than that we'll get
into more of this later but this
is where you can create
actual style sheets so if you have
a client for example like we have
this client here uh adfluent
we can name the actual style sheet
there but what's really cool is if
we go to customize design so this
is where like say for example you
want to essentially keep a client
all their pages looking really
like
well branded and almost exactly
the the same in terms of like the
font that's used the color codes
that's
used and all that stuff you can
make what's called a style sheet
um right in here so this is where
you
go and you say all right for this
client's entire funnel all the
landing pages the conference pages
the vsl page any additional pages
that i do whatever this is what i
want the headline font to be this
is
what i want the sub headline to be
this is what i want the base font
to be and stuff like that this is
what i want the colors to be for
light background lightest
background colored background dark
background darkest
background it's just setting
universal style sheets and then
you can go to shadows and set that
there
so sometimes we'll do this
whenever we're like hey we want to
make this like super easy for a
designer
or one of our page developers to
essentially just make all the
pages look very congruent and
styled
the same we'll go through and make
a style sheet like this and i'll
show you guys where in the builder
that we actually use these style
sheets to just automatically make
all the headlines and you know
fonts and
everything and all the colors look
exactly the same so that's
essentially the quick overview of
the
initial stuff here inside of good
old click funnels and let's dive
into an actual page and i'll show
you
guys literally every single thing
that you need to know inside of
the page builder to know how to
make
some high converting funnels and
landing pages peace