All right guys so this is part two
i'm going to go into an actual
live client funnel right now and
we're just going to break down
everything from a to z i'm going
to click around show you guys all
these different buttons show you
guys hey if i had a blank page
this is exactly what i would do
to basically start developing from
top to bottom and also of course
make sure that it's mobile
responsive that's super key a lot
of people forget and just don't
simply do so let's dive
into it right now so we'll go to
funnels we're going to pick this
client right here
so i typically like to because
we're an agency keep there's
probably a better way to do it but
look i like to do it this way we
have 12 pages in this funnel now
we have multiple different funnel
types we're running for them we're
running a high velocity opt-in
funnel for them which is literally
just an opt-in we're also running
a free training funnel for them
which is basically a lead magnet
plus a call funnel so i keep
everything here inside of this
whole entire funnel that's just
personally how i like it like
right here is the free training
funnel here's the replay page for
it
here's the qualified and
unqualified confirmation page
after they actually booked through
that
respective funnel here's the high
velocity opt-in page here is the
beginning of the call funnel and
everything like that so i like to
keep it all just in one funnel
right this is what they call a
funnel
this right here all the pages
right and then you have funnel
steps that's what they refer to it
as
which funnel steps are essentially
just individual landing pages
within a full funnel okay so and i
just
want to let you guys know that
because like sometimes their
support will ask you these things
and you're like i don't i don't
know what the difference is like i
thought a landing page was
a funnel it's not but like the
funnel is the full thing landing
pages are here within it so
don't mind my coffee too we're
ripping y'all know it anyways so
uh basically just make sure that
you go to
the actual settings of the funnel
initially select your domain
change name now this one here just
note
this is your master url now the
master url is going to begin the
first step so when you look at
this funnel
technically it's like step one
step two step three step four step
five step six that's how they
really
like processed it and made it um
again we don't really follow that
logic but
basically like this all you need
to know is this is your master url
so if you're running some sort of
split test between these two pages
like we were here you would need
to use this url here because
it's going to go depending on what
you set this percentage to be on
the split test it's going to
divvy up the traffic between these
two pages right now it's set to
100 going to this page but if i
was
doing you know if i clicked on
this and dragged it to 50 50
essentially it would drive 50 of
the traffic
here 50 of the traffic here and
that's how i did a that's
basically how i do a split test
right and you
essentially would just click here
and this is your master url and it
would split the traffic between
these two so if you're going to
run ads use this url up here okay
if you're doing like some sort of
split test if for whatever reason
you just want to drive traffic
only to this page just click there
and you'll be able to copy that
individual landing pages url put
it into your ads manager and run
it so
other things too i always turn
this to uh to live once we launch
even if we're not doing payments
this is the overall funnel path
right so this one up here
make sure you hide this make sure
the head code is good if you do
want to select that style sheet
that's where you're going to
select it right here you can
override it on the actual landing
page level like
if you have the style sheet you
can change the font still but this
will just make sure everything is
just by default fitting that style
sheet which we went over in the
first video a little bit and i
showed you guys what it looks like
then if you want to tag it you can
tag it but there we go so
let's dive into the page itself
cool so a couple things to note
all right first off at the the top
here so what you're going to see
is over here so drag and drop or
sorry not drag and drop you can
move to different funnel steps if
you
want to over here or different
landing pages but essentially
let's go from left to right here
so this
is help if you need it this will
show you any errors and warnings
this is essentially just a
overview of all the different
sections rows columns because
sometimes
you might like have something
that's uh basically like you just
can't pull it up or you can't move
it
for whatever reason um you know
sometimes there's just glitches
within click funnels so if you
want to
like move a headline around or a
row or something you can basically
just drag that and move it uh this
way if
you uh if you care care to then
from there this is where you can
start to add sections so they have
a
ton of different you know
universal sections so ton of
different headers ton of different
you know
stacks and product stacks and all
that ton of different templates so
we have used like some of these as
inspiration but uh most of the
time we're still developing from
like scratch or using one of our
templates like i said we're going
to share with you guys but if you
do find something you're like okay
cool this product stack could be
pretty interesting let me go and
do that you can just grab this and
just
slap it into the uh slap it into
the funnel so other than that you
also have your saved sections
which
most of the time if we have some
sort of like value stack section
or features section that we like
to
do and transfer across clients
we'll just save it and you can
just go and basically you know pop
it here
if you want to save a section very
simple you just hover over the
section because essentially when
you
think about click funnels it's
built in sections then you go to
row right there and then you have
the element
within the row okay so you have to
make sure you hover and it's the
green section here hit save and
then
you can basically save it and if
you want to save it under like a
folder or something like you know
this would be like estimate
mastery all right our our client
there you can save that if you
want to
have like different sections and
rows and stuff like that and
elements saved to different uh
different
clients you can do that different
folders so you can save like i
said a headline here or an element
all right you can save a video
element you could save a row you
could save a section whatever you
want to do you just got to do that
and click save if you delete it
you can click delete there if you
want to use some custom code which
that's beyond the scope of what
we're going to go over here you
can
click there clone settings which
we'll get into in a sec that's all
the settings on that you know
respective section and if you want
to move it you can just grab it
and start moving it or of course
you can go
here and just move things around
so if you want to do a pop-up
hover here click show pop-up make
sure
when you when you actually go to
uh you know edit pop-ups that you
also edit on a mobile by the way
big mistake i've made before make
sure to do that then from there
you can do the edit the settings
of
the pop-up so which will get into
a bunch of the settings here but
this is where you can basically
toggle
with the margin at the top the
margin at the bottom you can you
know have it to where it triggers
on
exit or not you can have it to
where it triggers on page load or
not i hate i hate that i hate both
them honestly um you can have the
backdrop color you can change that
around which essentially is this
backdrop over here so you'll see
like it can make it darker lighter
all that fun stuff left and right
padding so you can make it smaller
and bigger you can make it wider
even more too you can add some
more padding so padding
essentially will add like
basically just that padding to
whatever you know
whatever element or row or section
you're essentially trying to uh
you're essentially toggling it on
so
by the way too whenever you see
this computer icon that means you
are editing that element in its
desktop
view in format if you want to
switch to mobile you can click
here or you can go into mobile
only view
and then click the element there
but go back here bottom we'll
change padding there padding there
left
and right we'll change padding
there then if you want to change
background for example on the
pop-up
you go here you can do an image
with your image library and you
just upload a new image there
you can do image style so we
usually do you know essentially
like full center we just kind of
like
toggle it till it looks good image
fit if you want it to be placed
this way that way this way that
way
we always do mainly center just
leave it blank don't really
overthink that part and then if
you want
to change the background you can
do that here you could also use
style guide which style guide by
the way
is from the style sheets so for
this client style sheet in the
settings from section one we set
up
all these different colors that
these are their brand colors so i
can just easily go here and say oh
i know
that this blue is their respective
blue for their their this client
right i can go there and make it
blue if
i want you know border this
essentially just the the border
here shadow if i want to add a
shadow it'll add
that there corner if i want to
basically add a corner it's right
there now again these are the
styles from
your style sheet okay so in the
style sheet in that main settings
we went and started to toggle
around
some things so if i have like
three types of corners basically i
can set them there if i want to
edit it
further i just click this button
here and it allows me to custom
override that style sheet that's
pretty
universal for any element in any
section if you go to advance um i
really never touch this stuff
not gonna lie like ever touch this
stuff so not even gonna go over it
and we built a lot of pages
uh let me just make sure i didn't
have some crazy stuff that i added
no cool so uh another
thing too with click funnels just
because it was on my mind make
sure you save your stuff
frequently
okay make sure you click this
little save button over here quite
frequently because it is a
nightmare
at times especially like if you
get a little blip in your internet
or whatever like i've edited page
while pages while i'm traveling
and you know on a plane and you
get like a little blip on the
internet
and it dies out and unfortunately
unlike some other page builders
click funnels does not save your
progress even if it's offline for
a little bit of time so
essentially it just wipes out all
of your
work so usually i will just make a
note to like every 15 minutes just
try to like hit save or if i just
edit a big section i'm going to
hit save and stuff like that so
yeah that's an overview of
everything
guys um right here now the next
video we're going to dive into
just each element each section and
all
that but um really from there very
simple stuff you can go here and
change like the typography of the
entire page same with the body
displays and stuff like that
honestly i never really check any
of this
stuff here's custom code sometimes
if we want to make like right here
a uh you know we want to highlight
something if we do a strikethrough
like we want to make this one to
do the strikethrough element
we'll uh we'll do that with custom
code so it's very easy with chat
gpt
right there basically just ask
chat gpt hey i'm making something
in click funnels 2.0
i want to make it to where it is
this color if i do a strikethrough
um how do i basically do that
and it will tell you exactly how
to do that and then by the way
again with the actual pixel or the
sorry the standard event code not
the pixel um for meta you will
have to place that in the footer
for
click funnels 2.0 not the header
like a lot of people tried to do
it does not work in the header
just the footer so i'll see you
guys on the next video and we'll
dive in deeper