All right guys so I have a page
open here this is video number
three and I'm
literally gonna go over every
single button inside of the editor
for you guys
so first off again we have
sections the hierarchy of elements
inside of click
funnels is sections and then rows
are essentially contained inside
of sections
and then elements aren't contained
inside of rows and there's all
different
elements that you can have there's
headline sub headline bullet list
paragraph
links all this stuff right images
video audio all these different
things are
elements that you can place inside
of rows okay now inside of the
section say for
example I want to go and add a
section right here I go to add
section and I
basically can pick blank section
flex or I can do some sort of
template that they
have on the section level or I can
pick the saved or universal
essentially
flex I don't really use it too
much but it's just a little bit
more of like a
flexible section that you can move
it and adjust it some more I
always like to just
go here blank section by default
and then rows is where you can do
one column two
three four five six or flex so if
I pick six rows here or six
columns in the row
essentially you create you know a
bunch of different ones this is if
you want to do
like an icon list or like a bunch
of bullet point sections or
something like
that you can essentially just
build that out there most the time
though I'm doing
like one or two maybe three you
know if we're doing something like
I don't know if
this page has one but right this
is like a three row right here
with elements
inside of it an image element a
headline element sub headline
element and then a
bullet point element right and
then this is a row here and then
this section is
contained around it so if we go to
let's just say add a row it's
going to add a row
there and then we can pick an
element let's say we want to just
do you know this
right here and when I add a
headline so let's do a headline so
this page does
have a style sheet by the way I'm
just kind of keep that in mind it
does have an
overall style sheet already
selected onto it whoops I don't
know what was going on
there anyways settings if I click
here on this headline element and
go to settings
this is going to open up
essentially my just editor wizard
there's so many things
that you can do within 2.0 on this
I'm starting with you know adding
some custom
code to this headline element if
you want to do that you can do
that click here and
it's going to open this for you
but essentially if you want to
just edit real
quick you can go highlight and
then on this toolbar that pops up
on any text
element you can do bold you can go
italics you can go underlined
strike through move
it to the side move it to that
side move it to the middle or you
can hyperlink it add your
hyperlink you can also change the
color of the hyperlink here and if
you want to do
like telephone so it's a click the
call right you do something like
that big mail to is that if you
want to do mail like an email and
then other than that we go over
here to settings and if I
want to add some top margin
basically move that whole element
down as you can see right here
like
watch this okay it moves the whole
element down okay padding if I add
padding it's going to add padding
within that element okay if I want
to add padding to the bottom or
remove it I do that if I want to
add padding to the left and right
sides I do this that's what I want
to make this element you know
tighter or smaller so if I want to
for example make like this
headline here you know tighter I
can like
add that if I want to like stack
it in the middle for some reason
right so let's go back to here and
look at some more settings on the
actual headlines and text so again
if I want to override the actual
style sheet that I have I can hit
override and do that now again
this funnel is set to the style
sheet of
our ca our client here play
capital so I can go here edit
style and this will edit the
Blake's play capital
group style sheet okay if I click
anything there you know our style
guide as they call it right so I
can
click there and edit the style
guide this will change everything
on the page that has this style
guide and
style sheet basically active for
it and if you click that override
button that'll override that
specific
element so if I go here and I
change the headline font here this
will change it on all of the ones
all of the headlines that have
this style sheet applied to it if
that makes if that doesn't make
sense to you please let me know in
slack I'll be able to help you out
but it's pretty pretty simple
default or pretty simple there so
if I want to override it and say I
just want to edit this L this
headline
element standalone I can go to
here and I can change the font so
like let's make it for photo let's
make
it big right and this is on
desktop keep in mind we're on the
desktop editing so we're only
editing
desktop here if I want to add
letter spacing I can do that if I
want to add line height so say I
have two
lines let's type punch stuff words
words words words misspelled words
but hey it's all good it always
defaults like 125 percent or so or
135 I don't know why I think it
looks kind of weird I usually go
to
like 110 or like 105 and it'll
shrink that there as you guys can
see so we'll keep it there for you
for now if I want to change the
color now this is the color if it
is not bolded so as you can see
right now it is actually
hyperlinked so I need to
unhyperlink it and the way to do
that is just
basically exit out of it or
basically on whoops there you go
right here you can unhyperlink it
like that
now there's a couple different
color settings on the font so you
have your default color if it is
not
bolded and you have your bold
color right there then you have
your hyperlink color so if it is
hyperlinked you can edit it there
so right now this is not bolded
right if I go to bold it I can
click
there and I'll be able to change
the color now if it's bolded and
you can also do the actual font
weight so you can make it thin
make it super dark medium regular
headlines I usually like to do
like
semi bold or bold I think it looks
pretty good so we'll keep it a
nice semi bold there but let's do
like this is a headline let's go
let's go bold cool and as you can
see it is not on bold right here
so
what I like to do sometimes like
say I want to make headline
something different I'll hit bold
and I'll change the color of the
bold element so it's like
emphasizes a word it's pretty cool
next
some other things you can do the
text casing if you want everything
to be capitals you could do that
if
you want it to be mixed you can do
that lowercase only the first
letter capitalize you can do that
decoration underline strikethrough
you got that I've never used that
before so I don't know what
that is but never used it
positioning positioning here you
can make it the opacity you can
change that
right and if you want to add to
this element the full box element
here okay so all of this not just
this okay if you want to add a
background to that element what
you can do is you can do the image
here you can select you can select
the image style there like we
talked about before I can go here
and
make this whole element red right
see how the whole element does
this again the hierarchy sections
rows
elements now if I go here say for
example I just want to have like
the red extended here for whatever
reason I just go left to right I
can drag this you know a little
bit more there or another thing
that I
like to do is there you go I'll
basically make the width of the
row smaller if you want to like
condense the amount of red
highlight if you're putting some
background in an element that's
the way to do
do to do with the undo button and
go back let's get rid of this ugly
as heck background there toggle it
off
if I want to do a text shadow you
can do that and make it glow kind
of like how we have up here in the
eyebrow so it looks like that
looks pretty cool and if I want to
remove it you go there if I want
to
I add an icon before the headline
you can do that and they have
their icon library there you can
select
from you can change the size of
the icon you could change the
color of the icon you can add some
margin
to the left of it you can add some
margin to the right of it delete
and then same thing for icon after
now something to note is the
visibility settings so if you only
want something to basically be
shown on
desktop you have to go here and
click desktop only if you want it
to be visible on both desktop and
mobile you'll click all if you
want it to be visible on only
mobile you'll click mobile only if
you want
to hide it from all devices you'll
click this eye here if you want to
remove it from all devices and
just
delete the thing you'll click
remove
right there so
Sometimes as you're developing
right like this this just looked
terrible on mobile there is no way
to
You know make this like compressed
and make it look good on mobile
So what we did was we went and we
just designed a mobile only
version
Which you're gonna have to do
sometimes when you develop
something first on desktop and
that's what we do by the way
So we will develop the page
initially and build it initially
on desktop view on the desktop
version, so we'll create that and
After that is done then we'll look
at mobile we'll go over here and
toggle over and we'll start to
optimize mobile
So, you know
We'll go here and we'll change the
font size on mobile a little bit.
We'll change the line height on
mobile
We'll start just tweaking things,
you know add some more margin on
mobile because look once you
design something on desktop
And you try to optimize it on
mobile or you just open the mobile
view
It looks terrible most of the time
like you need to kind of develop
them
independently from each other so
sometimes we'll do
Like the whole page pretty much
we'll go to each section and
Duplicate it out.
So like hey for example, I wanted
this section to be only on mobile
I would duplicate it out and I
would make
one section desktop only
this main one and
Then I would go here and make this
section mobile only and I would
edit them irrespectively of each
other if I choose to do so
Um, but most of the time we'll
just develop it on desktop first
entirely build the full page on
desktop
Entirely first and just worry
about desktop optimization
Once that is complete then I will
go over here to the mobile view
and be like, okay, cool
Uh, you know this logo is a little
too close to the top.
Let's just add like a little bit
of margin there
Cool.
That looks better.
All right.
This is lining up really well
And this headline could be a
little bit
Smaller so let's go here and like
tweak it down a little bit
Right, you're just going step by
step
You're going section by section
element by element row by row and
just trying to adjust things
So they look clean on mobile and
if there's anything where like for
example
Let me just show you guys like
what this
Looked like, right
So i'm going to clone this
Settings
I'm going to show you what it
looked like initially when we
developed this on desktop
And i'll show you why we made an
independent one for mobile.
Okay, so look at this
And this i'm just going to change
it.
So we know
mobile
Or look at me
Right, it just didn't look clean.
I'd wanted to like center this and
stuff to be fair
It didn't look too too bad, but I
wanted to really center this and
if I centered it here
It would also center it on
desktop.
So it just didn't look good.
So all we did very simple
Was we duplicated out this
section.
We made one for desktop.
We made one for mobile
And we just had the mobile one
right here that we
Simply centered the the headline
and just developed it like that
So sometimes you'll have to do
that sometimes you'll have to make
some sections and elements desktop
only and mobile only
And in and basically edit them
independent of each other.
So if I were to edit, you know
this
section right here
Right say I change this word
It's only going to change it on
the mobile only version
Okay, because this is the only
thing
multifamily because this is the
Mobile only version of this
element just keeping that very
clear.
So
You know if that confused you guys
like I said just know that there
are ways to edit
elements on desktop as well as
mobile
And you just have to know like
okay
First i'm sitting down i'm
developing the desktop version and
then if there's anything that I
see once I switch to mobile
That I need to optimize around and
I can't really just get it
Without kind of screwing up how it
looks on desktop
I duplicate out the section the
element or the row make one
desktop only
Optimize it for desktop and I make
another one mobile only and
optimize it for
mobile
Okay
So that's pretty much all the
sections or the settings for the
actual like text elements
You know, there's a lot of other
things that we like to do
On click funnels like obviously we
have video as something that we
Really push all the time.
So we'll embed like wistia or
youtube traditionally wistia is
what we're going to do
And we always have auto play off.
I don't really like adding auto
play on
I think it's very annoying when
you land on the page and it's just
bam
There's a video starting to play
the audio is on.
I don't like that
Lazy loading if we're having
trouble getting this to load fast.
We'll turn on lazy loading
We don't do the block pause and
here you can add you know padding
on the video itself, right?
padding there
Can add some padding left and
right if you want to shrink it
within that frame
And then I was like adding a
border so as you can see is a
little thin line of blue around
that video
I think it looks very clean and
custom branded
So I always add a border and if
you want to change the settings of
the border
You can do that here
You know if you don't want it to
be at the top
You just take that off see how it
got rid of this blue border up
here at the top
I want to add it back on i'll do
that
If I don't remove it from the
bottom for whatever reason I can
do that
If I want to add the stroke size
and make it bigger I can do that
I like to add a nice little thin
one there
Nothing too big if I want to have
it like dotted I can do that
I want to have it look like a
bunch of little dots there
You know whatever you want to do
shadow if you want to add a shadow
This is how we do it so it looks
cool
You know
And corners if I want to
Make the corners like super super
round
You can do that want to make them
blocky just get rid of them there
And something I like to do as well
on some pages have a background
image
So we'll toggle on background
unless this is where you're using
the style sheet
So if you're using like universal
styles
On that you can select these
whichever background you want
If you want to override that
You just go here toggle on
background
And you could pick you know your
color if you want a different
color
You can choose your image
So we have an image of the car
wash in the background
Which is the thing they're trying
to get people to invest into
And I have the foreground set
Basically at 93% on the alpha
Because I don't want it to look
like this because it's hard to
read
It's very hard to read so
I go all black and I crank that up
so it's a nice fade that we have
in the background
So it still looks really clean
But in the background it's like
hey, I see it.
There's a car wash very
interesting
so
This is an faq section where it's
two rows essentially that we have
and then these are
a bunch of little just flex boxes
so
This one was you know pretty
simple to make we're going to have
this in the template for you guys
But basically if you want to add
some new ones
All you got to do is just
duplicate out these
And you could add some of them and
then these are just text box that
are inside of the faq
drop down element so
Let's go element here
You could also like add an image
inside of these boxes if you'd
like
You know click funnels really at
the end of the day.
It's just a big old
drag and drop builder, okay
You're gonna have to get your
hands dirty a little bit just
editing these things our templates
again make it
Super easy to use very simple to
to just plug and play slap into an
account and and go from but um
overall, you know
You're able to like do a lot of
cool stuff like dragging these
accordion features into there
Which are just drop downs
essentially for faqs and you just
have to like visualize it a little
bit in your mind of what you want
And then from there
It's just like dragging and
dropping different blocks and
elements.
That's really it.
So
Button styles is something i'll go
over real quick to you.
So button text
That's what you're gonna put there
if you want to have like a sub
button
You know text
You can have that there
Keep that there because i'll show
you guys how to edit
Now the button actions
This is pretty key
So if you want to go to a website
after they click that or some
other page after they click this
button
Do go to and then put the actual
don't worry about this too.
This is uh, something we're
testing, but
Um, you can click that and from
there
It'll go to a page, right?
So if I wanted to do google.com
whatever that's a stupid thing
But if you want to like drive it
to a scheduler page or something
like that
You would just put the scheduler
page url there
You can select if you want it to
be opened in a new window or not
and then some other things you can
do
Is I don't know why anyone would
put nothing happens, but hey
You know if you have a use case
for it go for it
Submit order or form so this is
where if I for example would have
a bunch of click funnels inputs
So if I had the input elements
here like
You know full name
Which I'll show you guys how to
add these in a sec
Phone number
Email I could have it as submit
form and it will submit whatever
information
Has been placed into these fields
here and then it will move on to
the next step.
So
The next step in the actual funnel
And I can hit this thing here that
says enable redirect override
because here's the thing
If I were to have this checked off
and I basically had a page that
collected name phone number email
and it had submit form as the
button
It would drive me to the next page
in the funnel automatically
If I want to send them somewhere
else after they submitted that
form
I would click here and I would put
whatever url that is right here
And that will send them over after
they submit the form and after
they click this button
Basically after they've entered
their information and click this
button will send them to that page
that I select or put right here
And you can also have something
where once they click on the the
button here and it's starting to
you know submit their stuff
Like there's that little loading
time in between whenever they
submitted the actual thing click
the button and when they land on
the next page
You can just have a message pull
up there
Size and spacing very simple
stuff, but if you want it to be
full width
Which means full width of the
actual row it's contained in you
can have it there if not
You just do disabled and
You can from there
You know kind of like pad the
sides of it and stuff
I usually like to do
Enable for the most part and if I
want to shrink this section, I'll
just shrink the whole row here
And something fancy I like to do
too is say for example
I wanted this button for whatever
reason to be you know half the
size of these input fields what I
could do is go add a row
knowing that you know my hierarchy
Is sections rows elements and then
I can go here
Kill the padding at the top kill
the padding at the bottom and then
I'll shrink this
You know to whatever it is there
obviously I'll need to go in and
go over to here override my
button style
Looks like shrink this
And there you go looks ugly, but
yeah, if I wanted to do that, you
can do that so
If you want to delete some just go
there delete it
But anyways
Let's keep going on here
So again, if I wanted to override
the button style
So if I want to override what it
looks like on hover what it looks
like when it's pressed
So hover is just when you're
hovering over it like this with
your mouse
You can change that
I mean you could have a different
color you can have the text change
colors different font so you can
go crazy with it
I'll usually change the the hover
hover color of the actual button
itself so the background of the
button
And also with press I'll have like
three different you know shades of
blue or something in this case
when this one's blue
So maybe like a darker one on
hover when it's pressed
I'll like change it to I don't
know like a really dark blue or
something or a super light blue
Something like that.
It's just kind of fun.
I don't really overthink it
honestly
And button font right here.
You can change the button font
You can make the font on the
button extra bold.
We can make it medium
Semi-bold whatever it is you
change the font size here again.
This is desktop.
I switched to mobile.
I can then change it on mobile
Uh letter spacing if I want to
change the spacing of the letters
there you go
And if I have multiple lines, I
could change the line height
So text casing we already covered
that earlier
Primary text shadow if I want to
add a shadow behind this text I
can do so there
And then subtext if I do have
subtext right here this little sub
headline thing I can increase the
margin I can change the uh
There's increase the margin.
I could change the button font the
weight
font size
Letter spacing
Crazy, right?
Yeah, that's that's wild usually
like invert it
line height
text casing
Decoration so just adding some
different things to it and if I
want to add like a subtext shadow
I can do that too
If I want to add a border that's
more, you know
aggressive or something like that
to the actual
Button itself I can do so there
Corners I can pick to change it
here
Separate edges if I want to like
make the top left like
You know cornered I can do that
there
Maybe only the bottom left and
like the top left.
I want to do something like that
Don't know why but there you go
And then if I want to have an icon
before so here's one before and
after which we will do a lot of
the times honestly
It looks pretty cool.
Um, we'll just go here and uh
select
whichever one we want
And we'll just make sure the sizes
match make sure the margin matches
and you are good to roll on that
so
Now a couple things on the input
fields, right?
So we have multiple different
input types
So an input field is essentially
just like a form field.
That's really that's literally it
Okay, it's a form field on click
funnels
So we have you know full name
first name last name email phone
shipping address shipping city
State country zip and custom type
So usually we're doing like full
name or we're doing first name and
last name
Then email and phone and maybe
we'll do custom type to ask like
one other thing from them
But basically if you go full name
for example, you can change the
label here.
So like full
name
You can have the label be on the
border up here plus in there.
You can have it just be default
within there for you
And you can also
change the actual like font of the
label itself
By clicking there the letter
spacing
Like label there change the actual
font too like I said
And we got to change the color to
actually see it.
There we go.
See now we can see it.
I saw the wondering where it went
You change there you can make it
bold and we're looking at this
thing here
Full name, right
Make it all caps
Shade it up a little bit
That text shadow
You guys see how it's all the same
stuff over and over again really
And you know you can change the
the width of the actual input
fields itself
You can add more padding
There you can add more padding
here
You can put the input in the
middle
Alignment within its actual
You know container itself
Add some corners to it
Add a border if you want
All these different things
Then from here just make sure that
you know if you want to toggle it
on as required or not required you
do so here
And then if you do have like a
full name first name last name
email phone number input or
whatever
I'm just like the right one here,
right
And one that we'll do like I said
is a custom type.
So we'll go here custom type
And say I want to know if they're
a business owner or not.
So like business owner
required
So
We could do
Are you a business
owner
And that could be you know they
essentially like type it in but
let's do
This would be again an input one
is where they type in stuff so
they would type in yes here
If you want to add something like
a drop down you would go to
Form
And you could have like a big old
text area by the way too you can
do that
I never really do that
You could have a freaking survey
As well
Which is super in-depth
Just individualized fields here
Which I again have never done
You can go
To checkbox input so if it's like
sometimes the ATP stuff will be
like you do like ATP
required
You know you go here and then you
can edit this and be like
Check here
The box here to subscribe to SMS
notifications
Sometimes you have to have like
the ATP stuff
Then you can change like the check
color if you want
You could change you could keep it
start checked if you'd like so
whenever they land an actual page
It's already checked off
And stuff along those lines
And some other ones that we can do
and the forms
Is a select box
So if you want to do
Countries you can do that but I
usually do custom options here so
are you a business owner
And I put it like this because you
can't it this is the string and
the output
That it shows this will show up in
like automation
So if you're doing automations,
it's you just have to know that
like they can't there can't be
spaces here basically
So yes
Yes
No
I am not
No, I am not you also make it
required or not
Change the whole background of the
input and
You know if we were to go to
preview
See if it shows it or if I have to
make it live or not
Yeah, I'll have to make it live
But definitely don't want to make
it live just a live page for a
client
But anyways you essentially would
click here and it would drop down
yes or no
And from there you could also
again make it required or not
So that is pretty much overall all
of the uh
elements within an actual
You know click funnels page itself
and if you don't want to save any
of the things that you just did
Guess what you got to do click
over here
It shows you everything will be
lost hit okay and you're good to
roll so that guys is an overview
of
Literally every single button
within click funnels and now it's
up to you to take the templates
And essentially just build and
combine these elements and makes a
match and really you're just going
to get super good at click funnels
just by playing around
Honestly, that's at the end of the
day what
What it is playing around and
trying different elements and
looking through their library and
being like oh this thing could
look kind of cool
What if I like made the padding a
little bit bigger here change this
font or bolded this one here?
Or you know added a strike through
here and stuff like that
Maybe if I broke this into two
rows
So let's add two rows instead of
one row in the section and see how
that looks a lot of different cool
things you can do
Let me know if you have any
questions peace