All right guys so real quick we're
just going to go in to click
funnels and I'm
just going to make a new funnel
from scratch it's pretty pretty
easy and
everything so we're going to go to
funnels right here create funnel
I'm
just going to create one from
totally scratch I'm not going to
use their
templates and let's do test funnel
make sure if you want to change
the URL you
can there so now we're going to
add our first step so we're going
to go here
we're going to create a page you
could also create a split test and
also have
conditional logic based upon these
right there so let's just go to do
see if they
have a new page test test and this
is again where you can select the
style
sheet I'm just going to use
default but if I wanted to use a
style sheet I created
you know over here for a client or
a certain funnel type that's right
there
you could have selected it now
let's go to edit and we're just
going to build a
quick like headline sub headline
and slap a VSL so initially you're
going to have
to add a section so we're going to
go blank section we could pick a
template if
we want but we're just going to go
blank section we're going to add a
row and let's
say we want to put a sub headline
here so let's do you know eyebrow
fine technically an
eyebrow headline then what I want
to do is I'm going to add a let's
add a little
headline right there this is our
big line and I don't like that
font so let's
override everything with these
three dots let's do pick something
random poppins
yeah there you go I want to make
it extra bold to make it a big
headline I also
don't like this spacing here so
I'm going to shrink that spacing
on the headline and
I think there's a little too
spacing with the eye too much
spacing with the
eyebrow too so I'm going to pull
that there pull that there cool I
don't like the
spacing at the bottom too so a lot
of times you're going to be
playing with like
padding and stuff like that as you
add elements but you'll get you'll
get used to
toggle in between that let's do
this is a sub headline that
supports the big design above
all right let's toggle that up a
bit hmm looks a little too close
so you know I made everything a
little too close so let's go five
below to a five above five and
that looks pretty
clean there we go so a nice even
spacing with the padding on the
headline looks
pretty good now what I'm going to
do is I'm going to add a VSL so
let's go video
here tons of spacing at the top of
it I don't like that let's pull
that up some
more and I also want to make the
VSL smaller the actual video
itself so what I'm
going to do is I can't change it
on this level but I can shrink the
entire row this
is why I made the row essentially
its own element that's why I did
not sorry that's why I did not put
the video
here within this row I made a new
row for this video because then on
the row column
or in the row settings I can sit
here and shrink the width of the
entire row and change the actual
sizing of the video so let's do
that there and we can add a
another row toss a button here
so much padding on it by default I
don't like that we also have some
weird margin on the actual button
element itself there we go looking
good now this is obviously a very
ugly page guys but I'm showing
you you know how quick and easy it
is to uh you know spin something
up even like all right we have
a lot of kind of spacing between
the actual video and the
sub-headline so let's find out
where
there's some padding we can shrink
all right we can shrink that there
shrink that there
there we go and let's say we just
want to change the background for
whatever reason here
let's say we want to add a
gradient let's do that so let's do
this side of the gradient
feel like red or something see
this side of white looks terrible
but that's how fast you can spin
something up right um so yeah
that's essentially I just want to
make a quick video five ten
minutes
going over just literally the
hierarchy of everything and it's a
lot of just playing around with
spacing too
like even here like all right you
know it's a little bit too much
padding at the top so let's
like try to shrink this a little
bit to like ten there we go we
pulled it above the fold a little
bit and then let's go to mobile so
mobile we want to obviously shrink
so if you want to change the
text you go to button style here
oh actually sorry mobile you just
go down here button styles on
desktop
all right let's shrink that there
a little bit let's make the big
headline bigger on mobile so we'll
go
there make sure you're toggling on
this big headline let's shrink the
line spacing a little bit
and there you go uh so if you want
to go and edit a pop-up you click
show pop-up you can see it on
mobile and desktop so you go here
column add a headline right enter
your info below and then from
there just
like i showed you guys in another
step we start to just layer on our
input fields and everything and
slap another button on down there
but i would have to make sure that
i change this to open pop-up
if i were to do a pop-up so that
is just a quick one quick build
obviously again it's very ugly but
if you want to start from scratch,
that's what you got to do.
Peace.