Hey guys i just wanted to clear up
style sheets a little bit more for
you so what you're going to
want to do if you're on the main
dashboard is go to workspace
settings styles and then here's
where
you can make a style sheet so you
can make a new one here i'm going
to go into an existing one
and typically what we do is once
we have one style sheet we like
then we're going to just
duplicate it out change some
colors and fonts per client or per
you know funnel that we're trying
to
make so for example let's click on
this company's style sheet here so
a style sheet is essentially a
universal style that you can
essentially just place onto a
funnel so if you have a client
that their
color schemes are these colors
here their backgrounds are
typically these backgrounds here
their fonts are typically these
fonts here with these sizes you
can essentially do that you can
also set
all right i want the colors for
this page to look like this based
upon their branding i want the
fonts to look like this based upon
their branding and essentially
what you can do once you designate
the fonts the colors the shadows
the border style even the button
style this helps a lot honestly in
the corner
style for different elements on
one particular style sheet then
what you want to do is go
over to the funnel so once i have
that style sheet created right
like i made this one here
for this client i go into funnels
i find their designated funnel i
click settings and then i can
select the style sheet so now
whenever i go to make the
the funnel by default the colors
will match what i put in the style
sheet so it'll match the branding
the fonts
will match what i put in the style
sheet so it's a lot easier just to
start building from you know
square one
essentially on these funnels so
that's style sheets and you know
very simple it's a universal style
sheet for
or whatever funnel you essentially
just selected on.