All right, what's up guys, so just
going to do a quick overview of
the opt-in page.
So this is basically at your
disposal if you want to have an
opt-in page where people submit,
typically just name, phone number,
and email, sometimes one qualifier
question before the
actual VSL page where they have
the application, the calendar, all
that fun stuff.
So I did leave some copy on here.
This is for a cold email kind of
setup offer.
You guys probably all know that
type of offer.
And I left a copy on there in this
section mainly, as well as this
section that we like to have,
just to again, give you guys some
like context on everything and
what you should be essentially
putting in these sections.
And other than that, I love having
the get pricing and details as the
actual CTA and the button.
And these, we have a pop-up that
goes, so you can change the color
of the pop-up.
Remember if you go here, you can
change the backdrop.
So the opacity there, you can
change the color of the backdrop.
I usually just do like kind of
this faded out black there.
I toggle these off.
So trigger on exit, trigger on
load, I toggle that garbage off.
And you know, you can change the
width of the pop-up.
You can change the background of
it here.
So if you go to background, you
want to make it black.
You can do that.
Just make sure that you also have
to change the rows and the section
backgrounds.
If you are to do a different
background, just make sure to
match them, right?
Let's go here.
It's going to change that.
So you kind of got like two
sections to change the background
color if you choose to do so.
And of course, if you want to
change up any of the font styles,
you can go here, swap them up to
whatever you really deem fit.
Just make sure it's congruent
across the whole funnel.
You know, make sure that like
you're not switching fonts from
the VSL page over to the
confirmation page, the opt-in
page, all that stuff.
So just going to exit out here.
And if you do want to add in some
more form fields, again, you go
there, clone it out.
Of course, make sure that looks
clean on mobile and everything
looks good, especially with
pop-ups.
You're going to want to actually
test on your phone.
I don't know why people don't do
that, but go on your actual phone
and test to see how the pop-up
looks.
Test to see how all these sections
look, like make sure the spacing
is good here.
All those sorts of things, right?
So this is the opt-in page.
I love to put case studies down
here as well and just a bunch of
CTAs to get pricing and details of
the pop-up.
This section also, whenever I heat
map these pages, stops the scroll.
It's a pattern interrupt, right?
You have this nice black
background everywhere and then
bam, you get exactly what you get
with the system.
You could also talk about benefits
from here, like the outcomes.
You can talk about features,
really whatever you're trying to
convey.
You can split test different
pieces of copy there.
So yeah, this is the page.
And then after they hit submit,
you want to route them over to the
VSL page.
So if you do have this as the
first step in your form and or the
first step in your funnel and they
click this,
they're going to automatically go
over to, uh, to that next page
right there.
So you can also do a redirect
override.
If you want to send them to a
different URL, you just go there
and paste that URL.
And if not, again, if this is step
one in my funnel here, once I
click submit form, I'm going to go
over to the next step in the
funnel.
Basically in my click funnels log
machine.
So, uh, yeah, let me know if you
guys have any questions.
And of course, if you want to like
drop the spacing there, you can do
so all this fun jazz and just
very, uh, very easy.
It's really just at the end of the
day, making these funnels is
testing different things, seeing
how it looks or Hey, going onto
your phone and looking and seeing
how it looks on your phone, trying
it on desktop, trying it on
mobile, all that stuff.
So, uh, this is a structure there
for a opt in page.
And let me know if you have any
questions.
Peace.
All right.
So real quick, I forgot to also
mention that something we like to
do sometimes on the opt in pages
above the fold is we'll
essentially do a gift.
So I know this is like a video
thumbnail of a VSL, but
essentially we'll do a gift of the
VSL sometimes where if they click
that gift, so we'll embed it
usually right around here under
the sub headline.
Um, sometimes we'll also put the
button above it.
So we'll have it like right
between this section, this main
fold section and this content
section, but we'll basically have
a gift of like a section of the
VSL and a little play button.
And we'll click on that and it'll
have a popup.
Um, so it basically would be kind
of like a, this and gift version
and you click this and it would
have the, the popup.
So that whole image would
essentially be clicked to pop up.
So just a little trick we like to
do if you're like, I can't get
this thing looking too clean.
I want to like split test an
element, uh, like a visual element
above the fold.
You can pull out again, a gift of
a section of your VSL.
That's pretty attractive and cool.
And you can just slap it up there
above the fold.
That does work pretty well
sometimes.
So peace.
All right guys.
And just something real quick to
note.
If you are using the, uh, VSL call
funnel template at the bottom here
is the opt-in page.
So all you're going to want to do,
if you're going to essentially
want to use the opt-in page is
just grab it here, pull it up to
the top and put it as the first
step.
If you do not want it, you can
either go here, remove it, or if
you just want to keep it in the
template or essentially in your
funnel,
simply grab it here and place it
there.
Good to roll.