All right what's up everybody so
real quick i just wanted to go
over some of the templates here
so i'm just gonna do like a quick
sweep of them but again these are
in 2.0 um so starting with
the call funnel here so we have
our confirmation page and then we
have our vsl page i'll open up
these individually uh just make
sure you know you go in here and
you know rename stuff change
the urls whenever you go live hit
live and then hide the uh lovely
click funnels badge you can
add your tracking code there for
whatever ad platform you choose to
do so um to utilize this
on but yeah basically here
anything can be edited okay now
this is just like our best
practices on
these templates and the ones that
we've seen work the best so a lot
of the spacing is very strong now
obviously as you add more words
and stuff or you start to add
images and different elements
you're
going to want to test live on
different devices like i don't
know why people sometimes whenever
they're launching a funnel uh and
they're editing mobile they only
use like the mobile editor here
and they don't actually like look
at the freaking link on their
phone and see like oh that
actually
looks good or that looks bad right
so like make sure you're actually
like looking at these pages live
especially before they go live um
as you edit them right so each one
here is uh you know very very
simple right so some of the stuff
here i tell you what to
essentially like write and you
know like
here's a section talking about
like articulating the problems
that your customer experiences
articulating how you solve the
problem why your system works and
stuff like that break down your
deliverables add some case studies
so if you see these these are like
videos that you can add
and um if sorry if some of mine
are in here uh you could just go
there and delete them um basically
yeah yeah so some of them will
potentially have some of our case
study videos there so you can
delete all this stuff like this
and add your own but um anyways so
also have some faqs things like
that and then um also most of
these like this one here has a
pop-up for example so you'll want
to go
here and embed your own type form
if you if you're utilizing type
form there and then just like
delete
stuff here like some things as
well as you edit you'll see like
you know delete this element
before
publishing right so uh just make
sure to follow those instructions
and then our confirmation page
right here too same structure i
tell you you know here's these
video topics and faqs you want to
add
in down here if you choose to do
so that on your confirmation page
and then the other one that i want
to go over
is the low ticket and challenge
funnel so this is definitely the
most intense funnel that we have
in here
the most intense template so this
is one that we launched for one of
our clients and this performs
super super super well um so i did
leave on this template some of the
images that we utilize so if
you want to have like a graphic
designer replicate them like this
product box matrix and this stuff
like
that you can do so um and then i
also left some of the copy down
here for you guys to look at
and uh same with some stuff like
this some of these little images
and whatnot now like i said this
one
is no no joke like a challenge
funnel of this scale and a low
ticket product funnel this can be
utilized
for both is a beast right there's
a lot of stuff a lot of copy a lot
of sections and feel free to add
and take away some but i left a
lot of the copy here so you guys
can read through and see like what
i did
for each section so that is you
know intentional there and a
couple things too if you see this
uh this highlight this is actually
a custom uh code so i'm gonna show
you guys what to do for that but
basically it's a strikethrough
that turns gold it's pretty cool
um not a lot of people you know
do a lot of custom stuff with
click funnels we love doing it so
what you guys can do for that
is go to show code here and
basically all i did was i just
asked gbt i'm like hey i'm using
click
funnels 2.0 i want to make this
strikethrough a highlight can you
give me the css code for that so
all you want to do if you want to
change like the gold to something
else just find the color code you
want to do here and just change
this this background color and
that's really it so then if again
if you
want to add some sort of uh code
some of these will by default
already have uh some standard
event
code on there like uh let's see if
the footer code has any i don't
think so no but like this one here
we made like a glowing button um i
don't even think it's active
though to be honest but um you
want to
use uh utilize some of that code
you can go for it it's a little
bit more advanced if you have any
questions on custom code just like
let me know um transparently i am
not a coder i just use chat gbt
and it tells you exactly what to
do so uh you just like paste it in
there and it's good to go
so yeah the low ticket one will be
a beast um you know there's some
elements here like we have to do
a lot of custom like formatting
like even this image behind you
right you have to like try to find
it
right right there if you want to
edit the image you have to play
with the padding to make sure it
looks
good and we like edited these
sections out here um so yeah it's
a beast but it converts very well
so
um yeah then we have the checkout
page for that one too an oto page
here for you guys
and a scheduler page and then for
the webinar one right here very
similar to the call funnel one
there
are two sections i just want to
show you guys real quick if you
choose to i put like a little
description here right so like
make sure to read some of these
descriptions as you go through if
you
choose to not have like a vsl you
just want to have a headline and
do a pop-up for registration you
can do so there if you want to
have a nice little mini vsl
explaining what's about you know
what's in
the webinar what you're going to
go over you know answer some
questions stuff like that you can
choose
to do so there and then have the
form visible there um i also added
this extra like qualifier field if
you want to see how we do those
sometimes we'll just do name phone
number email to register for a
master class or webinar other
times we'll also conditionally
logic and route out people based
upon what
they answer in this uh field here
and then um yeah so let me know if
you guys have any questions as
you go and edit these uh again
there's a lot of copy sections
that are guidelines and especially
on
the call funnel and the uh webinar
funnel and then on the challenge
funnel like i left a lot of this
stuff here so you guys can like
see what i'm writing for your
product or for you know past
product and
stuff so peace y'all let's crush