Hey, what's going on, guys?
My name is Nick Abraham, and today
I'm going to show you how you
can properly scrape Sales
Navigator.
So I get this question all the
time.
Nick, what's the
safest way to scrape Sales
Navigator?
How can I get my Sales Navigator
search to get me business
emails?
And tons of questions from people
hitting me up on Twitter and
YouTube.
So I thought I would
make a video on this specifically.
And if you don't know who I am, my
name is Nick Abraham,
like I mentioned before.
I run Libra.io and a other
plethora of SaaS companies in the
cool
outreach space.
And we're pretty good when it
comes to scraping Sales Navigator,
enriching our
data with business emails and so
forth.
And so I want to kind of give you
a quick overview on how
to properly scrape Sales Navigator
and kind of talk about the pros
and the cons of Sales Navigator.
So Sales Navigator, believe it or
not, is what all the big B2B
databases use to kind of build out
their database, right?
The only issue is that it does not
provide business email.
So on Sales Navigator,
you can apply filters, find a
whole bunch of leads that fit your
ICP, but typically they're
not going to have a business email
unless they include it in the
profile.
And so that's where,
you know, data sources like
Apollo, ZoomInfo and so forth do
really well is because they'll
actually provide the business
email, right?
But they're basing all their data
off of Sales
Navigator.
And typically they're just doing
permutations and other sources to
actually get
the business emails, but that's a
whole other topic.
So just to kind of recap, in Sales
Navigator,
you do not get the business emails
for the leads, but that's okay.
I'm going to show you how to get
them.
And then when it comes to Sales
Navigator, the search results are
actually very inaccurate.
And this is one of the biggest
issues with Sales Navigator and
why I hate using it.
It's because
no matter how you apply the
filters, whether you do Boolean
searches or not, your search
result
typically on average is only going
to be 33% accurate, right?
So, you know, you may say,
hey, I only want people that are
in the United States and it's
going to have leads that are from
India, from all the countries and
so forth.
And so you really do need to build
a filtering mechanism
to kind of make sure that your
search result that you're getting
is accurate to the filters that
you
applied.
So that's, that's one thing I'll
kind of speak about and how to
automate that later in this
video.
The other thing about Sales
Navigator, this is typical in most
B2B like lead gen databases is
that they only show you a select
few amount of the leads that are
compared to your total results.
So what I mean by that is, you
know, if your search result comes
back with a hundred thousand
contacts, typically you're only
going to actually see 2,500 total
leads.
And so it's going to show
you 25 results per page and a
total of a hundred pages.
So 2,500 total leads per search.
And so,
you know, if you're wanting to
scrape your entire TAM, right?
So let's say your TAM is a hundred
thousand contacts.
You're going to have to break down
your search result.
It's a tiny batches of 2,500.
And I'll show you like the most
effective way of how to kind of
think about this using the
slice spread method.
So I did not come up with the
I'm not even sure where I
learned from, and I don't even
know where I got the spreadsheet
from, but the spreadsheet's
outdated,
so it doesn't work, but you can
take that same exact process and
build out these tiny search links.
So basically what this spreadsheet
does is like, you're coming in
here and you're basically applying
all the geographies that you can
apply, the IDs, right?
And so like, you know, let's say
you want
to get everyone in the UK.
So you want to split the search
because it's too big.
It has a hundred
thousand contacts and you need to
break them into batches of 2,500.
Easiest way is probably doing
geography and just doing and
breaking each, like your total
search.
It's a tiny little batches,
just by the geography, right?
And so you come in here, you can
apply all the different geography
IDs.
I just copy and paste in the same
thing, but you get what I'm
saying.
And then it builds out the
search link over here.
And then you could just, you know,
input this search link into your
tools
and scrape it.
But this is the process of like
breaking down your search.
You want to break it
down.
Like you're still like, let's say
you're still targeting marketing,
advertising, and managing
directors at these companies,
right?
But now you're just breaking it
out down into tiny little batches
so that you get everyone, right?
Because Sales Navigator only shows
2,500 total searches per
source.
That's why you got to have to use
the sliced bread method.
So I just want to kind of quickly
touch on that and explain how that
works.
But the two methods for scraping
Sales Navigator are using
Chrome extensions or a headless
browser tool, right?
So I'll kind of talk about this
and the pros and
cons of it.
The con of using a Chrome
extension is that it is very risky
profile.
So LinkedIn will
ban you if they see that there's,
you know, unusual activity coming
through your account.
And a lot of
these Chrome extensions are
cheaply made and can get your
account banned.
I've never ran into that
situation.
I haven't really used a Chrome
extension in a while, but LinkedIn
is very sensitive
nowadays.
So if you're in an industry where,
or you have a profile that's
really built up with a lot
of followers and stuff, it's
definitely not worth the risk of
using a Chrome extension,
right?
And so if you do use a Chrome
extension, I recommend that you
use like an avatar.
So there's
a website called get AIA, get
A-I-A dot I-O that allows you to
rent out profiles.
And, you know,
these are throwaway profiles that
you can put a Chrome extension on
and not have to worry about it.
So that's something I would
recommend if you're wanting to use
a Chrome extension.
The thing about a
Chrome extension as well is that
typically the outputs are pretty
basic.
So, you know,
you're just getting first name,
last name, the title of the
person, their company name,
maybe their company website, their
LinkedIn URL, sales navigator URL,
leads location, summary,
and headline.
Just the basic information.
And then you typically just take
that, you know,
CSV export that you just used off
of Chrome extension to scrape and
put it into drop contact to go
find
the business email.
That's the simplest way to do it.
I just don't prefer this method
because,
you know, you're leveraging your
profile.
I don't want to have my profile
banned or just,
you know, deleted or anything of
that sort.
So I don't like using a Chrome
extension,
but it's different for everyone.
Right.
And free plug for myself.
I own this tool called
Golden Leads.
I'm a partner here.
And what we do is we actually use
our own network of accounts
so that you don't have to use your
own account.
Right.
And so, you know, once you get
your search
result from sales net, you just
literally input that search result
into our platform.
And we're going
to run the scrape through our
accounts.
Right.
So we don't use your account.
And then we do a lot
more than the average Chrome
extension could do.
And I'll kind of explain some of
the stuff as well.
So, you know, we can get all of
this data very easily, but we do a
lot of really cool things on
our own.
So one thing that we do is we're
actually getting the activity of
the profile.
Right.
So
we'll get your sales net search
and we can even see if it's an
active profile, meaning has,
you know, have they been active in
the last 30 days?
And typically what we've seen is
we're
running any kind of LinkedIn
campaign.
If we target the active profiles,
we see a much higher
response rate, connection
acceptance rate, and everything of
that sort.
Right.
We'll even check
if the lead has an open profile so
you can run in-mail campaigns to
them.
And then we'll go even
further and grab the industry that
was applied and specific to their
sales net result, company
description, you know, their start
date, how long they've worked at
the company, their company
page, LinkedIn URL.
If you want to do some stuff
instead of clay, company location,
company
employee count range, and then
we'll even do advanced filtering.
So I kind of want to show
you that.
Right.
So this is kind of what the CSV
looks like when you pull it from
golden leads.
And the cool thing is, is that on
the very right of your
spreadsheet, we'll basically see,
okay,
hey, does your title actually
match what you inputted inside of,
you know, your search result?
Yes or no.
Right.
Is the industry matching?
Yes or no.
Is the region matching?
Is the company
headcount matching?
Yes or no.
Because these are the typically
the areas where we see the most
inaccuracies when it comes to
using Sales Navigator.
And so by doing so, we're able to,
you know, make
sure, hey, you know, in this
search for this client, having the
title as yes only is very
important,
right?
We can't have any no's because
they can't target outside of this.
So, you know, let's only
target the people to yes.
So we can kind of get our search
result to be a lot more accurate
and relevant
to what we want.
So this is kind of like the
outputs that we can give you.
And then past that, we also do
a lot of extra stuff that most
creepers can't pull.
So a great example is company
follower URLs.
So this is probably some of our
best performing campaigns that we
had.
We can actually grab
everyone that follows Zoom Info,
for example, or everyone that
follows Apollo, for example,
or, you know, go find one of my
competitors and scrape everyone
that follows their company page.
And the reason why this is so
important is because it's like
intent data.
Because if anyone's following
Zoom Info on LinkedIn, they're
probably interested in have
knowledge of like B2B, lead gen,
lead sourcing,
and things of that sort.
So if I'm selling anything within
that realm, it's like the best
campaign to
run because you could basically
say something up the lines of
like, hey, I saw that you're
following
Zoom Info on LinkedIn and thought
I'd reach out to see if you're
interested in my lead gen
solution,
XYZ, that does XYZ.
Like that's a game changing
campaign.
And so that's
one of the things that you could
scrape using all the leads.
The other one is kind of similar,
like a LinkedIn event attendees.
So, you know, if you find an event
that has tons of people within
your space, you can go grab
everyone that attended it, same
similar situation, run a campaign,
saying something up the lines of,
hey, I saw that you attended this
webinar by XYZ.
You know,
we help people do XYZ.
Would you be interested?
Whatever it is, right?
Totally depends on how you
want to run it.
And we can also scrape group
members inside of a LinkedIn
group.
So you can
find groups that, you know, have
your ICP.
We could pull everyone in there.
And then we could also do
a lot of other advanced search
features that are coming out soon.
So like, let's say you have a
list of LinkedIn URLs and you want
to, you know, identify which ones
have open profiles or active
profiles.
Or if you have like a list of
accounts that you need to search,
we have all of these advanced
search features coming out onto
our platform golden leads.
And what I'm most excited for is
we're going
to build something called a sales
nav breaker.
And so what we're going to do is
actually on our end,
instead of you having to do the
slice spread method, we're going
to break the sales nav search into
tiny little batches so that we
could scrape more than 2,500 at a
time.
And we'll be the only platform
in the entire world that can, you
know, be able to do this where,
you know, if you're like, hey,
I want to, you know, just get
everyone on this list as a hundred
thousand people on it.
And I don't want to do this
tedious process of doing the slice
spread method that I explained
earlier.
You know, you can put it into
golden leads.
So we'll be able to do that.
Can't do it yet,
but we will vary, you know,
probably in like the next 30 to 60
days.
But yeah, that's kind of like
an overview of how to scrape sales
navigator.
And like I mentioned before,
right, if you want to get
the business emails, all you need
to do is run the LinkedIn profile
URLs into drop contact or pretty
much
any enrichment tool and you'll be
able to get the business email.
And so that's a quick overview
on how to scrape sales navigator.