What's going on guys in this video
i'm going to walk you through how
you can build a list of
lookalike domains for your lead
list so that you can build super
targeted just like you can inside
of tools like ocean.io and so this
is very very very important when
you're trying to build lead
lists for clients that need that
sniper precision and the keywords
that you're applying inside of
sales nav or inside of apollo just
aren't cutting it so let's kind of
back up real quick what is a
lookalike lead list so if i put in
leadbird.io the output is going to
be a list of domains that are
similar to lead bird and lead bird
is a b2b region agency so i would
get an output of domains or pp
region agencies and so there's two
ways of grabbing it you can use
the pioneer in the space that
built
this kind of technology and use
case which is ocean.io they're
more of an enterprise solution
so they are a little bit more
expensive they have annual plans i
think that start in that 12 to 16
thousand dollar range we use them
very early on and they're amazing
but they are a little bit more
on the expensive side so if you're
more of a startup then there's
another tool on the market called
export list io they basically will
get you almost the same results
that ocean will do for 75 dollars
per search so you can try to you
know test this out use it as
needed and not really worry about
paying like an enterprise solution
like ocean and so that's a pretty
good tool to go through and then
when it comes to finding and
getting like really good results
whether you use ocean or export
list
is you need to identify a domain
for like your ideal icp that is
rich with keywords so what i mean
by
that i mean that the website isn't
just like a one pager with barely
any keywords and maybe doesn't
have
any traffic behind it like what
they're doing is they're basically
scraping the website identifying
keywords and then going and trying
to find other websites with
similar keywords and so you need
to find
something that you know talks a
lot about the process talks a lot
about like b2b legion or whatever
it may be
that identifies you know that
specific website and so let's kind
of walk through the entire process
so this is export list.io you can
just go to the ai lookalike and
then we could put in just a name
for
this order so i'm just gonna call
it testing and then let's do
leaper.io so if i once i input
that i
just submit the order and then i
can go into orders and you'll see
that i have this right here and
i'm
just going to open it up so i
already downloaded it and in the
csv there is tons of information
in it but
the main thing that we are looking
for is just the domains and to see
how accurate this is we can kind
of just start opening up a couple
of the domains to kind of see what
it looks like so i inputted
leaper.io bbgen agency and so
everything in here should be sales
and leads orientated and you can
see that this says is your sales
cycle yawn and lacks the mojo so
that makes sense but it caused me
books 25 to 30 meetings in a day
and let's just kind of keep going
down to see if we can find
something
else conversion calls so this is a
call center so bbbgen at the same
time so you can see that the
ai lookalike does pretty good
results but now we need to go from
list of domains to actual people
and then to emails so if i copy
the list of domains i can head
into apollo and then click uh
company
include list of companies and then
paste this in there and click save
and search and now what we're
telling apollo is like okay hey
everyone inside of these websites
i need to go find the people that
work
there so this is the 2500 people
that work at all of the domains
that we have in here and i believe
we were able to get a total of
1145 and now i can apply the
filters to go find my icp so let's
go
ahead and say you know we just
want the owner the founder and
c-suite let's just say that's the
icp
that we want what i can do then is
just copy this search url come
back and export and then i can put
this here and so this has a total
of about 1100 contacts so i'm just
going to order 2000 and then call
this linkedin testing and then
order this and now they're going
to actually go ahead and pull
the emails from the contacts that
are right here almost immediately
right that's i think a better
pricing than what apollo gives and
so that's how we go from building
the lookalike and then being able
to actually find the emails of the
people we want to hit and then
when it comes to actually writing
the
cold email campaign since we have
a hyper specific lead list we want
to get hyper specific with the
call
out of the lead list so you know
if i'm running a campaign to b2b
agent agencies i need to be able
to say hey first name we've been
working with other b2b agent
agencies i wouldn't just say hey
we're
working with other agencies so
that's the benefit and then
whenever you're able to get hyper
specific
with the outreach like that you
typically have a higher response
rate just because it doesn't look
like it's a mass blast like some
of our other campaigns do so
that's how you go from start to
to finish on how to build a
lookalike legalist and then
building a campaign around it.