What's going on guys?
In this video, I'm going to walk
you through one of the many
playbooks that we
use at Leadbird to generate high
quality leads for our clients.
My name is Nick Abraham.
I'm the
founder at Leadbird.
We generate leads for our clients
on a pay-per-lead basis.
And this is our
playbook called LinkedIn Jobs
Scraping.
So I'm going to walk you through
how we use LinkedIn
Jobs to generate leads for our
clients.
So this is super important if you
are a recruitment agency.
So as a recruitment agency,
specifically if you are
specialized in certain job roles
that you can
fill, imagine finding all the open
job posts for that role and the
hiring manager that's involved
and their email address so that
you can run super targeted cold
outreach campaigns.
That's what I'm
going to walk you through in this
video.
And you can do the same thing if
you're a service-based
business, right?
A lot of times a business isn't
ready or needs a full-time hire.
And so if you're
able to kind of come in and pitch
your solution, your outsourced
solution that isn't, you know,
having them to, you know, have to
pay a full-time salary, all the
benefits and being able to manage
to do all that in-house, like you
can really come in and be the
alternative solution to their
full-time
hire.
And so that's kind of the two
strategies that I want to walk you
through if you're a recruiter
or if you're a service-based
business on how to basically run
this LinkedIn Jobs playbook.
So the first thing you want to do
is open up LinkedIn Jobs.
And what you can do is just put in
a role that is, you know,
something that you can fill or
something that is related to what
you sell.
So Leadbird, like I mentioned
earlier, we're a B2B Legion
agency.
We do what an SDR does, generate
leads,
generate meetings for our clients,
right?
So I can come in here and say,
hey, let me find all the open
job posts for SDRs in the United
States.
And, you know, I want to see all
the ones that are in the past
24 hours that are offering remote
jobs.
There's about 563 results.
And you can see from this first
result, there's a hiring team
that's involved.
Brandon Lewis is the direct person
that's responsible
for hiring the SDR.
So let me show you how I would go
about running and getting his
email address at
scale.
The easiest way is this internal
tool that we actually built called
Leadbird Recruiter.
If I could get back to the screen
right there, there we go.
If you go to leadbird.io slash
recruiter,
all you need to do is take this
search URL that you've composed
from using LinkedIn jobs,
put it into the scraper.
And now you're going to get an
email back with a link to download
the list
that you just, you just uploaded
or not uploaded, but requested to
scrape.
It's going to come back
within five to 10 minutes.
And what we've seen from, you
know, running a lot of these
scrapes is that
20 to 30% of every search that you
have will have a direct hiring
manager associated with the job
post.
There are some posts on LinkedIn
where there isn't a hiring team
attached to the actual job
post, which is fine.
I'll show you how to find who is
there and take a really educated
guest.
But
basically, if the hiring manager
is not associated with the job
post, what you can do is kind of
make
assumptions, right?
If the company is smaller, wants
50 headcount, it's typically going
to be the owner,
founder, CEO that is directly
responsible for the hiring, right?
And you know, if the company
headcount is 50 plus, we like to
use ChatGDP.
So I'll literally come into
ChatGDP and say, hey,
at a tech company with over 50
plus employees, who is responsible
for hiring the SDRs?
And they're
going to kind of give me some
roles.
Sales managers, sales operation,
those are probably where I'd want
to
start.
And since the CV that I get from
the email is going to have
everything from the actual job ID,
the job URL, the title that I'm
hiring for the job description,
the company name, I can kind of go
in
and find these people.
But more specifically, you'll see
that this list has in total about
75 results,
because it's very targeted, small
one that I wanted to do.
You'll see that this has already
about 25
people from that 75.
So roughly about 33% of this
search is there with a hiring
manager, which I can
leverage to go find and do true
targeted outreach.
So two strategies whenever you do
have the actual
hiring manager is, you know, hit
them up on email.
So the best way to find their
email address is upload
your CSV that you get from us and
to find email or drop contact, and
they will get you their email
address.
You're seeing a 40 to 50% match
using find email, very
recommended.
Best in class when it comes to
enrichment percentage, validation,
and price.
And if you don't want to do cold
email campaigns,
I would recommend using the
profile URL of the hiring manager
that you'll get.
So you'll see in this post
right here that we have the hiring
manager's profile URL.
And so you could run really
targeted campaigns via
media or expandee from link to
connector campaigns and saying,
hey, first name wanted to connect,
saw your job post,
saw that you're the hiring manager
for this, wanted to connect,
whatever, right?
So that's kind of how you run the
actual scraping of this and
getting the data.
So now let's talk about the actual
cold email angles that you can use
to generate the leads.
So if you're a recruitment agency,
this is what I recommend.
This is some of the stuff and some
of the copy that we use
for our clients, where it's simply
saying, hey, first name, saw that
you're the hiring manager for the
SDR job role.
I can help you find qualified
candidates that would be happy to
send over some open CVs that we
have for SDRs
that make sense to connect, right?
Very simple cold email campaign.
And it has high intent because it
shows that you did
some level of research by pulling
that data in.
And then similarly, if you're a
service-based business, being able
to say,
hey, first name, I saw that you're
the hiring manager for SDRs at
Leadbird and wanted to reach out.
Have you considered?
And then you want to pitch your
alternative solution.
Have you considered using an
outsourced to manage an agency
that works on a performance basis?
Question mark.
Like imagine getting that email
and you're the hiring manager.
You're like, oh, you know, might
want to see what this is about.
And so those are two different
angles that I like to use
for the actual campaigns when we
have them running.
And then last but not least, just
want to kind of talk
about the different things that
we're going to do for this
internal tool that we're
releasing.
So our goal
in the next 30 days is to be able
to be able to provide more than a
thousand results per search.
So similarly to SalesNav, LinkedIn
Jobs does this thing where they
only show you a certain amount of
results per page.
And they only show you in total a
thousand results and in general.
And so we're going
to scrape more than a thousand
results per search coming soon.
And then we're also going to just
go ahead
and directly integrate with my
email to retrieve the hiring
manager's email for you.
So you don't have
to run that process.
And then we're also going to build
this super cool solution where you
could
get a recurring list sent to you
weekly.
So let's say, you know, you're
filling in SDR job roles.
You could get a recurring list of
all the new job posts that are
submitted every week on LinkedIn
so that you could keep running
outreach, keep having that system
built out, keep seeing, you know,
what's coming out in the market
and running campaigns.
So that's, that's basically what
we're
doing on the LinkedIn job scraping
tool that we built,
Libra.io/recruiter.
So yeah, that's,
that's basically the entire
playbook.
Nothing too crazy, super simple,
short video,
just a very targeted way of kind
of, you know, standing out in the
inbox from the typical cold email.
So if you want us to do this on a
pay-per-lead basis and your, your,
your business that's doing over
50K a month that wants to
outsource this out, hit us up, go
to Libra.io,
book a call with our team and we
can walk you through this and many
of the other playbooks
that we use.
If you want to test this out and
do this on your own, we built a
very cheap internal
solution that I kind of mentioned
in this video, Libra.io/recruiter.
And you could go run this exact
campaign on your own.
So that's basically it for this
video.
If you liked this video, do me a
favor,
like, comment, and subscribe, and
we'll catch you on the next one.