All right, in this video, I'm
going to show you how to build a
list of leads for your clients or
for your own campaigns
Because you're probably saying
where in the world do I get
5,000 email addresses of people
that I want to work with with
tools like list kit pulled up in
front of me
Disclaimer, this is my software
company.
I'm a co-founder at this business
It's the only tool that I use to
get lists of leads if you would
like to use other tools on the
marketplace
No hard feelings at all.
I just don't have the expertise
necessary to teach you about it
so for the sake of this video, I'm
going to show you how to use list
kit
To get a list of emails to
actually reach out to with the
email machine that you're
building.
So
let's say you want to reach out to
first of all, um, think of any
company in the world and
Realize that they can be
categorized based on a few things
industry.
Are they marketing?
Are they restaurants?
Are they hotels?
Is it a software company you
filter based on industry first?
Then you filter by how many
employees are at the company
because your client might want to
target small businesses big
businesses
Medium-sized businesses and then
where are they located if you have
a client who only works with
florida companies?
You're going to need to select
florida as a filter
Inside of this of the data tool
And then to finish it off you can
filter based on job title.
Do you want to reach out to ceos
owners founders?
chief marketing officers
Operations managers hr all of
these filters are possible with
list kit and other data tools
So let's dive in right.
Let's say for the sake of this
video.
I want to reach out to companies
that are in
hospitality
hospitality industry
In the u.s
But let's say you have a client
that does marketing for
hospitality companies
Okay, great we have
Hospitality companies in the u.s.
And let's say we specifically want
hotels so hotel
I would type in and as a keyword
This is going to filter out any
company that is not listed as a
hotel
inside of our database
And we're left with eight hundred
thousand people at fourteen
thousand companies
Which just means that most of the
companies in here have a lot of
employees?
So let's also add in a filter of
one to two hundred employees
you're basically
Building a pot.
You have a bunch of puzzle pieces
out in front of you.
You have to construct the puzzle
in such a way that
You get the exact list of people
that you want to reach out to for
yourself or for your clients
So now we have a list of hotels
pulled up in front of me
Hospitality recruitment agency
would actually don't want that
Great accommodation hotel looking
for best and cheapest place to
stay in los angeles home page
Okay, so basically all of these
companies given there's always a
few outliers that aren't fitting
The search that we want that's
just the nature of data in general
But bottom line we now have a list
of hospitality companies
to reach out to
In the hotel sector specifically
and what we want to do is finish
off with
Job titles so ceo owner founder
Cmo
chief marketing officer head of
marketing
Marketing vp of marketing right so
like whatever your client
specifies
For the targeting it the the type
of people that they want to reach
out to
You come into a tool like list kit
and build that list for them
Up until the point where okay,
this looks like a good list
All this is looking good owner
president marketing manager
president co-founder
Great, this is looking good.
Let's go ahead and export the list
I want
10 people per company so I can
reach out to several people at the
same company
And then you enter how many leads
you want if you want 5,000
Let's say you want 3,000.
Okay, great 3,000 leads redeem
credits
You're good to go.
You're going to get a list of
email credits
You know 3,000 people deep if you
only want 50 like i'm going to do
here to give you guys a quick
example
Redeemed credits my list is being
built
And once it's ready I get sent a
csv file to my inbox that looks
like this
Let me open it real quick
Where is it?
And here is an example of what
this list
Looks like here.
We go ready
We get their email their name
their linkedin profile
Job title company name
So like in the earlier videos when
I was showing you the company
underscore name text replacement
It just pulls in the name of the
company from this csv file
So it'll say circa divine
birdine's current marin ralph and
russo
Like it'll pull in the name of the
actual business that you want to
reach out to
um
So it seems more personalized and
more relevant to them, but
In a nutshell, this is how you get
a good list of leads for your
client at scale
Um sent right to your email and
you can just plug in this csv file
into
The sending tool right so like in
the last video
I was showing you what the actual
campaigns look like when you're
running them
And if I go here
Import leads like all I would do
is just drag and drop my csv
Into this box and i'm good to go
right i'm not going to do it here
because that would mess up my
actual campaign
But you draw you literally
download the csv file drag and
drop it into this
And all of the leads are uploaded
into your sending tool
You throw in the copy that you
wrote that we've gone over in the
in the past couple videos
And the campaign is ready and good
to go
Okay, so that's how list kit works
There'll be more info on how to
sign up for list kit down below
I'll go through the website real
quick basically
What you can do with any data
company that you work with is
charge your clients
This subscription fee so like bake
in the cost of a subscription to
list kit
into the
Pricing that you charge your
clients like let's say you sign a
client and you charge them a
thousand dollars up front
This
297 a month can be baked into that
pricing that you charge your
client
So they're the ones paying for
list kit and you get access to our
tool so you can then go ahead and
build a list of leads
um
There's plenty of other tools out
there like if you look up
B2b databases
Best b2b data providers you will
get an entire list of other
companies that you can pull from
Obviously, you know
I would love for you to use list
kit because we have the most
expertise with list kit and
um
We'll be able to give you the most
amount of support because it's our
tool
If you go to another tool for
their data not going to take it
personally
um
You know feel free to pull data
from wherever you want if you want
to go to linkedin and pull people
one by one you can also do that
but
um
Like if you literally wanted to
pull this guy's email one by one
You can do that
But with the volume that you're
going to be doing for yourself and
your clients you're going to want
to use a tool like
list kit
or
a similar database tool to get a
list of leads so
um
Not to go super in depth
with everything but
What you're going to want to do is
get really good
At building a list from scratch
based on what industry the company
is in like let's say construction
And then let's say you want
Contractor home builder
Home builder right
You have to be able to come into a
tool like list kit and build the
exact list of leads that your
client is looking for
So for example, I have contractors
and home builders
searched up in the us
And then let's say your client
only wants to work with the owners
and founders you would have to
come in here and select
CEO owner founder
And get a list of leads that way
Right, so like just like writing
copy is a skill that you have to
master writing messaging
Building a list of leads is also
going to be a skill that you need
to master
So you get the right list for your
clients because the last thing you
want is to reach out to the wrong
contacts for your clients
And have them be upset when
they're not getting in touch with
the people that they want to get
in touch with so
That is how building a list of
leads works
I'm going to drop a ton of
resources down below going over
the best practices when you use
list kit
Um, but yeah guys at this point
you basically know how to
Write a good cold email set it all
up in a sending tool like smart
lead or list kit
um
Get a good list of leads the last
thing i'm going to wrap up with
for now is
What how do you actually like get
the technology behind a good cold
email campaign because you need to
set up
domains and inboxes
For your campaigns and this is the
Most labor-intensive part of the
entire process, but i'm going to
show you how to do it in one sec
So let's get into that video and
then we'll wrap up