All right.
In this video, I'm going to go
over email account settings plus
deliverability KPIs,
deliverability checklist, and how
to troubleshoot deliverability on
your cold email account.
So
first I'm going to cover the
setup.
So first you're going to go inside
smart lead, you're
going to press email accounts, and
then here's where you can
configure settings.
If you go to
the email account section, you can
bulk select it and do this.
So you select multiple people at a
time.
Like if you go here and you just
select a bunch, you can do that
there.
So let's talk
about settings.
First thing, when you set up an
email account, you're going to
want to go to the
general settings.
Also, I want to preface this and
say your exact settings depend on
the setup you're
using.
There are a lot of different ways
you can set up cold email
accounts.
And so I'm giving you
like a general setup.
I like to set up one inbox or two
inboxes per one domain.
And so this is what's
working again as of December 2024.
If you're using a different
provider, maybe like a mail reef,
a
hyper tide, a who knows what
you're using at this point.
And so if there's a different
setup,
consult with the people that
obviously set up your stuff.
This is relevant to Google and
Microsoft
setups where I set up one domain
and two email accounts.
If you set up in a different way,
there's probably some wiggle room.
So I'm just giving some rough
general settings and also refer
to the doc in this video for the
most up-to-date stuff.
So the exact setup depends or the
exact
what's it called?
Settings.
Depends on the setup.
So this is typical settings I
have.
Minimum messages per day.
It can be anywhere from, I say 15
is about an average.
I like to start at 10
and then like ramp up to like 15,
20, and up to 25 even in some
cases.
But let's just split the
difference and say 15.
I'm just trying to keep this
simple, but you can ramp it up.
Minimum time gap,
at least 14 minutes.
I just did 15 arbitrarily in this
case because sometimes I just
press different
numbers for different reasons.
But you want to have, I like to
extend out the time gap between
the
email sent.
Warmup settings.
I like to have a 25 total amount
of warmup email sent, randomized
between
15 and 25.
This email account was imported
from a different lifetime.
So that's why this is disabled.
But typically you're going to want
to have a five email per day ramp
up and then randomized between
15 and 25.
I like to set my warmup reply rate
to 50%.
Now I have it set to 100% because
in reality,
what ends up happening is if you
check out the warmup email sent,
you can see I have it set to
100% and smart lead for whatever
reason only wants to reply to 10%
of them.
So I just jack it up over
the top.
But I've seen, depending on the
actual smart lead account that
you're using, sometimes I've seen
it respect it and I don't know why
maybe my account is just tweaking
out.
So that's why I have it set to
100.
But typically 50%, I'd like to
have the auto adjust a warmup
sending ratio off.
And then the rest of
the stuff you can just leave blank
or it doesn't really matter.
So those are the actual settings
on
the email accounts typically.
And I say typically because it
depends on your setup and a lot of
other
factors.
If you are sending like a lot of
really, really high quality
emails, you can probably ramp
it up.
If you're seeing good metrics, you
can probably ramp it up.
If you're sending really poor
emails
that get you reported as spam a
lot, then you're actually going to
see, you know, terrible results,
even with these settings because
people were reporting to spam.
So diving to the next level,
what are the things you can do to
make sure that your emails have
high deliverability?
Here's a rough
checklist.
Number one, make sure you have a
relevant email and audience.
Like this is really the biggest
factor in email deliverability is
your spam compliant rate.
So you could have all your stuff
on paper,
perfectly set up.
But if everyone's reporting your
emails to spam, you are going to
land spam.
You could
have everything else set up
perfectly.
The spam report means a lot.
So if, like I said before,
you could send, if you're saying
super, super high quality messages
and everyone's replying to them
and you're seeing no issues at
all, you can keep scaling your
email sent per day and you're not
going to see issues.
This is why, you know, people can
send tons and tons of emails off
of, you know,
one domain and not see any issues.
But when you're sending cold
emails, typically some percentage
of
people are going to report your
emails to spam because they're
cold and some people just hate
cold emails.
So the best thing you can do is
have a relevant email, have a
relevant audience, make sure that
the people you're sending the
emails to actually are responding
well to them generally.
And that's
going to do like the most of your
deliverability.
But aside from that, plain text
emails.
So make
sure you don't have any links,
images, any garbage in your emails
that could help increase the odds
of
your landing and spam.
Have open rate tracking turned
off.
Have your bounce rate low, less
than 4%.
4% is
kind of the high end.
You ideally want like less than
2%.
And then warm up your email
accounts for minimum of two weeks.
Those are the high level things
you should do.
Now, how to monitor
and make sure your deliverability
metrics are doing well.
Your warmup score is not a be all
end all
metric, which you can see here in
the email accounts section.
You can see your reputation.
It's not a
be all end all metric, but it can
roughly equate to how your email
accounts are doing.
You want to see
95% plus on these.
Typically, if I see like lower
scores than that, there's usually
an issue with
deliverability.
Reply rates and campaigns.
I cover this in a different video.
But if you're seeing less than 1%
replies on emails sent, there's
typically an issue.
Again, there's a lot of nuance
here.
This is why we want to
collect all these different
metrics.
And then placement tests.
These are really good.
So smartly include the smart
delivery thing.
And so you can see, you can run
placement tests and see where your
emails are actually
landing.
Now, I don't care about personal,
so it doesn't really matter.
But you can see on professional
emails, 60% of the outlooks are
inboxing, 40% are in spam.
And then the G suites, these are
inboxing really well.
And so you can take that at face
value.
And if most of your emails are
landing
an inbox, that's awesome.
Those are the KPIs.
Those are the checklist action
items.
Those are the
settings.
Now, if something's wrong.
So how do you actually fix this?
If something's wrong,
if something's wrong, you either
need to lower your sending volume
to compensate for your results
going down.
You need to send more warm-up
emails and less cold emails to
basically try and tell the
system, hey, most of my emails are
doing pretty well.
That's what the point of warm-up
emails are,
is to get responses that signal to
providers like, hey, I'm not
reporting this guy's spam.
Get this guy in the inbox.
Or just set up new accounts, which
is what I like doing.
If you just set up
new accounts, it's the easiest way
to make sure that your
deliverability is doing well.
And so those
are the two action items.
So hopefully this is a quick
video, how to set up your email
accounts, KPIs,
settings, all that type of stuff,
deliverability stuff, and how to
troubleshoot issues.
So if you
have any questions, hop on one of
my calls or shoot me a DM.