All right, in this video, we're
going to be covering how you can
set up your cold email
campaigns.
I'm really just going to lay out a
quick roadmap here, showing you
all the different steps you
need to take.
And in the other videos in this
training and throughout the client
ascension modules, you'll
see how to tangibly do all these
things.
By first, want to lay out a
roadmap so you know what you're
getting into.
It looks a lot more complex than
it actually is.
And once you see how things are
done, all you have to do is just
click the buttons, go
step by step.
And if you have any questions, you
can reach out to me or one of your
student success coaches
or any one of the other cold email
experts in here.
So first, I'm just going to do a
quick roadmap to have it in a
little bit more digestible
format of the things you need to
do to actually get your campaigns
up and running.
So the first thing you're going to
have to set up your tech.
That's what a majority of these
kind of intro modules are.
It's purchasing the domains.
You're going to go to a domain
registrar, Porkbun, GoDaddy,
Cloudflare.
They all kind of do the same
thing.
And you're going to purchase the
actual domains you're going to
host the email accounts on.
From there, you're going to
connect them to an admin panel,
account, tenant.
They all kind of mean the same
thing through Google or Microsoft.
And so you can host your email
accounts where you can actually
send and receive emails from.
We have trainings on how to do
both of them.
I recommend if you want to have
the most safe and resilient
solution, you do a little bit
on both.
You can set up 10 inboxes on
Google, 10 inboxes on Microsoft,
or 20 on Google, 20 on Microsoft.
It doesn't really matter.
Or you can do it all on one or the
other.
If you want an exact
recommendation, I would just say
do 50-50 on both.
But you can do all on one, all on
the other, or a split of both.
Then you're going to add your
records to the DNS settings.
So your records, it's just like
the backend settings for the
domain stuff.
It's a lot of copying and pasting.
I'll walk you through and show you
how to do that.
Then you're going to create the
inboxes, a couple clicks of a
button.
You're going to connect it to
SmartLeads so that you can
actually start sending the emails,
receiving the emails, and using
the automations there.
Then you're going to scrape your
leads, write your emails, launch
campaigns, and book meetings.
And there's plenty of modules and
plenty of trainings on all of
that.
So that's basically the high-level
roadmap.
It's a lot more digestible when
you just see it in this quick
nine-step bullet point section
here.
And so all the videos are going to
cover this.
I'd highly, highly, highly
recommend watch through all the
videos the first time over.
Just take notes, digest it a
little bit.
And then whenever you go back to
actually execute on it, then you
can go back and start
to pause, replay, do the things in
the videos, just so you can have a
digest, or you can digest
the content and have a little bit
of a feel for it.
So those are all the steps.
I'm going to have a training here
on how to set up the Google
accounts.
Andre already has a training on
how to set up the Microsoft
accounts.
And then, yeah, if you have any
questions, feel free to let me or
any one of the other student
success coaches or cold email
coaches know.
So appreciate you guys a ton and
excited to get you some help on
getting these cold email
campaigns launched.