All right, in this video, I'm
going to cover how you can set up
a cold email campaign inside of
Smartlead.
It is really not that complicated.
It does not take that long.
It just requires you to
press a few buttons.
So first off, we're going to hop
into Smartlead, go to the email
campaign
section and press create campaign.
Now you're going to be prompted
here to import leads.
So
you can drag these in from
wherever you are dragging them in
from.
This is a list I made
for my boy Evan Siege here in
Client Ascension.
Shout out Evan.
So I'm just going to upload this
as an example.
Now it's going to ask you for
settings here, import leads, even
if they're
in the general or in the global
block list.
I like to respect that, not import
the leads
if they're in the block list, not
import the leads if they're in the
unsubscribed list.
I do like to ignore this because
Smartlead's global bounce list is
not super accurate in
our experience.
And then ignore leads that exist
in other campaign.
That's up to you.
I only
enable this if you have leads in
other campaigns you want to filter
out.
This depends on your
exact circumstance.
You could leave this off or on
depending if you want to import
leads
exists in other campaigns to
yours.
The next step you're going to do
here, you can name
the campaign however you'd like.
I like to name it, you know,
whatever campaign this is.
So
let's say Hormozy followers and
then 12, 15, 24.
So like what the date is.
Now here's where
you're going to map the fields.
You're going to add your first
name, your email, all the
different
fields.
Typically you're going to have
first name, last name, company
name, email, any custom
variable, custom variables.
You'll have a company name and
LinkedIn profile and a few others
website.
So this is where you're going to
map it.
You're just going to want to tell
Smartlead
like, Hey, in the Google sheet, it
says first name.
We're going to map this to first
name.
Same thing with email and all the
other stuff you want to pull in.
Now, if I want to include
their follower count as a custom
field, I can just press the custom
field button here and
then import that.
So we're going to, I'm going to
make sure the settings are set up
properly.
So I'm just going to upload this
as a sample.
This takes anywhere from a few
seconds to a few
minutes, depending on how big your
list is.
So you're going to let this upload
and wait a couple
seconds here for this to load.
While this is loading, you're
going to want to make sure that
you have your email script already
set up and all the other assets
ready.
Now you can see here,
this is all the stuff that
Smartlead uploaded.
So you can see, here's all the
stuff.
I don't like
to validate inside Smartlead.
I like to validate externally.
And so we're going to continue and
upload.
Now, now that we're in the
sequences section here, here's
where you can write the email.
You're going to put your subject
line, all your different email
contents.
Writing this is pretty
straightforward.
So you're just going to insert
what you put as a subject line.
If you want variables,
like the stuff in your sheets, all
you have to do is press this
variable button.
So I could say like,
hi, first name.
This is obviously not a good
script.
Hi, first name.
Sometimes it does that like
undefined thing if you press
enter.
So just keep that in mind.
Hi, first name.
I want you to book
a call.
Okay.
That's how you type stuff in.
If you want to make split tests,
this is where you add
variant.
You can have your split tests.
If you want to add extra steps to
the campaign, like
other emails.
Let me move this loom thing here.
You just press add step, add
email, and then plug in
your next email here and you can
keep going.
You can keep adding split tests
and do all that
stuff here.
This video is not on copywriting,
but this is where you paste your
copy.
If you want to add
images, links, which in 99% of the
scenarios, I don't recommend it.
You can do that here as well.
Now, moving on, we're just going
to press save it next and go
through this very quickly.
That's where
you write your sequences.
Again, pretty straightforward.
You're just copying and pasting
your stuff into
here.
And then if you want variables,
you can insert those through the
variable button.
Now, moving on to the setup.
Oh, one last thing I'll cover here
is Spintax.
So Spintax is a good
thing to have.
Generally, Spintax is basically
like randomization of stuff in
your email.
So
if you want your email to say hi
in half the cases and hello in the
other half the cases like
this, all you have to do is make a
curly open embrace, put whatever
you want one randomization
to be, put a line, put your other
randomization, and then close it
out.
So if you want half the
emails to say A and half the
emails to say B, if you set up
this Spintax, it will show us
that.
So the reason why you do this is
because you want your emails to
appear not as like copy and paste
templates and have some
randomization.
So in this case, you know, half
our emails will say hi,
half our emails will say hello,
and this is useful for
deliverability reasons.
Now, if you're trying
to like split test something to
see which result will perform
better, that's where you're going
to want to use the A/B split
testing feature.
If you want to just include micro
variations in your
email to help improve
deliverability, this is where
you're going to want to use
Spintax.
You can say,
hey, instead of I want you to book
a call, I want you to schedule a
meeting, right?
And it's not
half our emails.
It'll say, I want you to book a
call.
And the other half, it'll say
schedule a
meeting.
So that's how you set up Spintax.
Spintax is basically just
randomization your email,
and it helps improve results for
deliverability.
So that's how you set up Spintax.
That's how you
set up your emails.
Now moving on to the next step,
the setup section.
Choose sender accounts.
This is
where you can add the emails that
you want to be associated with
this campaign.
I like to just add
all the emails that are relevant,
you know, included in this
campaign.
Some people like to chop them up
into separate campaigns, but
smartly, smart enough to know to
like respect your daily sending
limits and
not over send on those email
accounts.
I just add them all in here.
Schedule campaign, pick your time
zone, pick the days you want to
send.
You can send on weekends if you
want.
I know people that crush that do
that.
For your time of day that you're
sending, again, this depends on
your time zone and who you're
sending to.
But I like to send from like seven
in the morning to like 2 p.m.
ish because I'd rather
send earlier and they see it
during their workday than send
close to when most people's
workday is up.
An email will be sent every X
minutes.
I like to make sure that this just
adds up to whatever your
email sending limit is.
So if you're sending 15 emails per
account per day, you want this
number
to be 15 or greater, which it is
by default.
But if you want it to be, you
know, exactly the same
as what you have it for your email
accounts, you can keep playing
with the numbers until it's like
that.
As long as this is above what your
email sending limits are, then
that's fine.
Email
account start date.
If you want to schedule a
campaign, you can do this 99% of
the time.
I don't do
that.
For the max number of new leads
reached per day.
Again, this doesn't really matter
because
smartly to smart enough to know to
say like, hey, if your email
account, if you have 10 email
accounts sending 50 emails per
day, 1515, that means you're going
to send 150 emails a day.
Now, if I put anything higher than
150, smart leads are not going to
go over that because you
have email account limits.
So it doesn't matter as long as
it's above the number that your
email
account, like your amount of email
accounts times the amount sent per
day of the email account.
So
you can just set this to a really
high number.
I like to set this to like a
thousand or whatever
higher number you could possibly
think of because your smart lead
account will respect your email
account sending limits.
By the way, I know I'm breezing
through this really quickly.
Um, there, if you want to rewatch
this video, I'd recommend it just
to solidify the settings,
but this is to mainly be a quick
start guide.
And again, you can DM me if you
have any questions,
time zone, pick your time zone,
pretty straightforward, press
save.
So I'm going to put New York here,
New York.
Awesome.
Cause I want EST.
Cool.
So now that's set up, um, schedule
campaign center
settings.
We have that all set up campaign
These are, um, where you can put
your kind of more
important settings here.
So if you want to optimize email
deliverability, which I always
recommend,
this is basically saying, Hey,
smart lead, don't send any
additional baggage in my email.
So, um,
my emails land in the inbox as
much as possible.
I always have this ticked now
force plain Texas
content type.
What this basically means is like
some email providers won't like,
you'll say, Hey,
I want to send this to the plain
text email and they'll like
reformat it.
You can force your emails
plain text.
I haven't seen the like actual
results on deliverability, but I
typically don't have this
enabled because sometimes it
messes up the formatting.
So your mileage may vary here.
You can split test
this right now.
I just believe this unchecked
since you have this ticked, it's
not going to let
you track email opens or link
clicks, which is what we want
because again, that reduces
deliverability.
Now prioritizing sending pattern.
Uh, I like to set this just 50% of
emails go to new leads and 50%
go to follow-ups pretty
straightforward.
If you want results to be quicker,
you can send it all to new
leads that way.
Um, you're hitting new people as
fast as possible and new people
typically respond
better than follow-up.
So you can do that.
Um, company level auto pause.
I always have this disabled
because there's been plenty of
times where I reach out to two
people from the same company.
One person
says no.
And one person says yes.
And what this feature does is if
person a response, your email,
then it also pauses person B if
they are belong to the same
company.
So I don't have this enabled
enhanced email sending.
This is like, if you have outlook
accounts, it'll route them to
outlook accounts.
If you have Google accounts, it'll
route them to other Google
accounts.
Your mileage may vary here.
I usually leave this off.
Uh, and in some cases sending
across providers
and say if instead of the same
providers performs better, I
usually leave this off.
Um, isolated
sending provider matching.
So right now, as of December,
2024, a lot of outlook accounts
reject emails
at a lot higher rate.
So if you're like, Hey, I don't
want to reach out to outlook
accounts.
I only want to do the Gmail.
Then you can just take this box.
This depends if you want to filter
out certain providers, but in a
lot of cases, you just want to
send to all intelligent AI
categorization.
This is basically telling smart
lead to like, Hey, whenever we get
replies, let's tag them as certain
filters, um, which can be useful
for inbox management.
I like to have this on.
And then I like to include,
um, do not contact out of office,
interested, not interested, um,
and meeting a request that pretty
much
gets the job done.
I have a bunch of extra stuff
inside my smart lead, uh, for
custom tags, which
you don't need to have.
Um, so that's why you might see
different stuff than what I have
here.
Um, ignore auto categorize out of
office from the reply rate.
I like to include it as part
of the reply rate.
So I leave this in and then
automatically restart AI
categorize out of office
from lead returns.
This is basically saying someone
says, Hey, I'm out of office until
January 15th.
It'll pause them for now.
And then in January 15th, it'll
resume them, which is pretty cool.
So I have this enabled high bounce
rate auto protection.
This is basically saying like,
Hey,
if our bounce rate goes above 4%,
pause this campaign so that you
don't, you know,
ruin your email account
reputation.
I like to have this on, uh, email
accounts.
This is where you can select the
email accounts again, just in a
different view.
If I want to select all of my
3,800 accounts, I can do that
here.
Um, and so that's where you can
set that up.
Now, last section here, final
review in the final review
section.
This is where you can see
what your emails look like.
And so this is great.
If you want to see what, if like
your spin tax is
working.
So you can see a high, hello,
first name.
I want to schedule a meeting, book
a call.
So you can see, and some of these
will say, hello, first name.
And some of these will say,
um, Oh, looks like it, this did
not save.
Hold on.
So in some of these emails, it'll
say hi,
first name.
And some of them, it'll say hello.
So hello.
Hi, hi, hello.
This is for deliverability
reasons.
And you can see some say schedule
a meeting, book a call, book a
call, schedule a meeting.
Right.
So the point of this is to add
randomization to make your emails,
uh, land in inbox better.
I always recommend saying a test
email before you run your
campaign.
So you can see what it looks like
in the inbox.
And then if you want to see what
your email to looks like, this is
where, if I had an
email to, which I'll add super
quick, you'll be able to see what
this looks like in your sequences.
So before you push it live, always
send a test email to make sure it
looks good.
Always double check
your spin tax looks like, or it
looks right in the editor, because
what you see in the editor is what
your recipients will see, and then
also send a test email so you can
see your email signature to make
sure that shows up right.
For whatever reason, your email
signature does not show up in the
final
review section.
So again, I sped run this super
quick to go over like quick start,
how to make
sure your campaign settings are
right.
That's basically everything you
need to know, how I like to set up
my campaigns, how I like to set
up, um, everything from there.
And then when you're ready to go,
you can just launch your email,
um, campaign.
It says select email accounts
because I didn't actually
save one, but if I press this
account, I press save, you'll see
it'll let you just launch the
campaign
here.
So that's a quick start guide, how
to set up email campaigns.
I went through that super quick,
but if you have any questions,
reach out to me in Slack, reach
out in the outbound channel,
and we will help you out.
Appreciate you.