What's going on y'all in this
video i'm going to be showing you
how to audit a cold email campaign
so basically taking all the
responses you've got so far and
showing you how to optimize them
for
more results based on what you've
already been seeing working so
step number one go to your gmail
inbox itself and click on this
little gear icon here and all
you're going to do is type the
subject
line of the cold email you're
sending it might be quick question
it might be something different
into the line that says subject go
down to search and go to inbox
instead of all mail and then click
search and what you're going to
have here is all of your replies
from prospects right and all
you're
going to do is okay i actually
made this a little bit trickier
than i had to because i want to
get rid of
hwr whoops mwr
okay so all of these are replies
that we've got from prospects
right and all you're going to do
is go through every single cold
email that got a reply not
interested skip
intrigue feel free to send the
video thanks so this is a positive
reply we're going to star it to
make
it easy to find and you're
basically going to go through
every single positive reply that
you've
got and you're going to star them
all until you get to the end of
the inbox and you have every
single
reply start right because all this
is going to do is make a really
easy crm for you to go into
and see all these positive replies
right so um doesn't have mwr
because mwr is like the warm-up
emails so all them were showing up
but here we go right all the
positive replies are here um so
all
you're going to do is whenever
there's a positive reply go to the
email that you sent over to them
was researching cannabis brands
and came across your website based
on your website i think your
products
would go viral and all you're
going to do is go over to the cold
email
scripts that you wrote up i don't
know where you might be keeping
track of it maybe it's notion
maybe
it's trello um but all you're
going to do go into the place you
keep your scripts and find the
exact
angle that got the positive reply
um which i think is this one right
here and you're going to put a one
next to it right and you're just
going to keep tallying up all the
angles that you get positive
replies from until you're at the
end and then you're going to see
like for example this one is
already
fully tallied up because i went
through every single one of these
angles found which angle got the
reply
and marked it up over here so
you'll see right email 1a had four
positive replies 1b had 11 and a
half
positive replies 1c had seven
replies seven and a half nine and
a half and you might be wondering
where's the half coming from if
the response is to a follow-up
like if email three got responded
to
i give half a point to every angle
that was sent before that so
whatever email two angle got sent
i
give a half a point and whatever
email one angle got sent i sent i
give half a point so at the end
you're going to have all these
tallies and you're like what do i
do from here well you optimize the
campaign based on which angles are
actually working in your outreach
right so for example in this one
this has 11 and a half responses
what email 1b email 1c only has
seven and then email 1a has four
i would get rid of 1a it only had
four which is way less than 11 and
a half right and then all you're
going to do is run email 1a and
email 1b as your next round of
campaigns right so you went from
three
angles to two um these ones are
pretty even nine and a half and
seven and a half and that's the
only
other ones with the test but yeah
it's pretty simple really
elementary stuff tally up all your
positive replies as you get them
see which angles got the best or
most amount of positive replies
optimize the campaign by
eliminating the losing angles and
go from there so pretty simple
straightforward
that's how you optimize campaigns
for what's already working i do
this once a month for my clients i
really recommend that every single
month you do it for your client as
well and you'll get them more
results moving forward because
they're going to double down on
what's already working so thanks