What's up squad all right today
we're gonna walk you through rev
reply how to get your account set
up and kind of show you all the
bells and whistles so what you're
seeing here is my account this is
my actual live account i'm going
to go ahead and use zoom as an
example one that is most relative
to a lot of people as you can see
we have revton labs rev reply kind
of a wide range of other
campaigns in here as well but for
the sake of the example when you
log in here just you'll see the
ad bond in the center we are
working on a dashboard that will
be released very very soon so
you'll be
able to see that up front as well
with some light metrics at least
for a v1 just some options on here
real quick edit duplicate trash
right active not active auto
respond we'll go through that in a
second as well and how that works
let's go to go into edit manager
so i can at least show you a few
things here now when you come in
obviously naming it it's going to
be defaulting to inbox manager one
inbox manager two and so on you
can feel free to customize it
however you see fit you see this
accordion view here all of these
are fields that we will need in
order to activate that the most
amount
of time it will be spent under
profile configuration and we go
ahead and dive into that here now
if you are
using a lead and you're using the
signature sound which looks like
this right and you want to leave
the name blank you could
definitely do so you know i went
ahead and put my name as if i am
working for
zoom and my company url zoom.com
now this is a pretty cool feature
that people love that we launched
very
recently is if once you put the
domain in here click auto general
profile give that about 10 seconds
it's
going to search the web it's going
to search the site and pull up
whatever it can about zoom there's
an additional box as that loads up
there's additional box that's
going to be available for
yes are there any additional
insights about the company's
offering links whatever may be
pricing
details whatever may be feel free
to engage with that if you like
you are limited a thousand
characters
per each of these boxes trust me
that's more than enough we used to
have 500 and we almost used to
have
one box but people kept on asking
for more so we loaded up both
these with a thousand characters
some ideas for here what you could
do just pretty much think of it as
a prompt for for the autoresponder
anything you wanted to keep in
mind right if there's information
to pour over here go ahead and put
that in
there if not i'm going to feel
free to tell anything else you'd
like to and if done that you just
keep
that off but some examples here
people like we have clients who
just hey don't use the word
synergy
right or sound like a millennial
or you know anytime you book a
meeting make sure to ask for the
mobile
number before you know when you
send the last email any little
details like that could be
important for
how you want to engage whether
it's about pricing or any specific
details about your offering make
sure
go ahead and include that in there
next section is going to ask you
if there's any case studies
any videos any white papers any
ebooks whatever may be just go in
and put the description here what
it
is put the link here and that will
be able to read and pull that in
if the context deems to to reply
with that information now look
majority of the people here are
looking to book a meeting that is
the objective of most sales reps
and most inbox managers but there
are other cases where the
objective is to perhaps send them
to a landing page have them sign
up for an account or you know we
have
a client who like just does or
manufactures door frames and just
works with contractors and so
their
objective is other and they put
please collect width length and
height of door frame so they can
just send
them a quote they don't even want
to talk to people right which is
perfectly fine but for the most
part people are gonna are gonna be
setting a schedule a meeting and
what that's gonna allow you to do
is
fill out all the other meeting
scheduling preferences now select
your time zone obviously you want
to let
the autoresponder understand where
you are so he knows what times to
suggest as well as what time zone
you can go ahead and include
weekends or include weekends most
people do exclude as you can
imagine but
in the event you do want to
include weekends go ahead and
remove that that is for when you
want to schedule
the other section here is going to
be meeting scheduling preferences
now you could see here
the question is would you like the
autoresponder to connect to your
calendars this is just available
days and times now you can go
ahead and do so by clicking
clicking on a connect to google
calendar
which will then have this pop-up
or you could go ahead and click on
connect to your outlook calendar
which that will have a different
pop-up for microsoft right so once
you connect those either one or
both or however many
you want they will populate in
here now as you can see i have
quite a few here and i could
select as
many as i like let's just say for
example i want to schedule with
damien and i wanted to schedule
one
pablo and i want to add one on my
other calendar and i want to make
sure it's all available for
everybody
in order to suggest any specific
time between the hours of 7 a.m
and 8 p.m pst so if you want to
include multiple people think
about how many calendars you want
to check then go ahead and include
that
on there now in the event that you
have a client you're working with
or you want to connect somebody
else's calendar obviously i'm
going to ask you know pablo or
damien hey what's your username
and password
don't want to get that personal
but what i could do is click send
email link so i could input the
email address of the person whose
calendar i want to connect to this
inbox manager click send they'll
receive an email asking them to
connect their calendar now the
other questions you'll ask is if
you have
multiple calendars selected for
example let's just say i do
because like pablo here it's going
to ask you
which mailbox do you want to send
the calendar invite from in this
case i'm going to go ahead and
keep it myself if you want to
include anybody else on the
calendar invite that would be this
section
here let's just say i want to
include anybody else at this point
then you go ahead and input it
there
click enter and that will populate
next question is would you like
the calendar booking sorry would
you
like the autoresponder to include
a calendar booking link so if you
have a calendar or whatever it may
be
feel free to include that there
again the more the merit that
would be very helpful as now
you're
going to be providing more options
than just two available times plus
a calendar link if you want
the autoresponder to send out
calendar invite definitely include
a google meeting link or a zoom
or other zoom or others pretty
much any static link that you have
for conference call link so if you
are
doing zoom just make sure it's
your static link one one quick
thing to highlight here on this
section for
meeting schedule preferences if
you do have your calendar
connected what it's going to do
it's
going to suggest two available
times both of the times will going
to are going to be hyperlinked so
you
click on them to actually book a
meeting automatically or the
person could respond back saying
hey great
tuesday at 2 sounds good the
autoresponder will automatically
recognize that and send out
calendar invite
if you do have a calendar booking
link it's going to go hey does
tuesday at 2 or wednesday at noon
work
well for you if not here's my
calendar booking link now if you
don't have this connected and you
have only a calendar booking link
here whatever it may be in that
case what it's going to do is just
send a calendar invite oh sorry
calendar booking link and if you
only have this and no calendar
booking link and you have a
calendar connected here it's going
to go hey here are my available
times
does that work for you it's never
going to suggest a calendar
booking link so make sure to pick
your
poison here how you like to get
that set up and i highly suggest
setting up either google meet or
zoom or
whatever may be that you have
because in the event that you want
to send a calendar invite unless
you're
trying to collect some other
pieces of information like a
mobile number or something like
that i would
make sure that have that part
filled and include one of those
now the next section after the
profile
configuration is going to be
mailbox settings for mailbox
settings you see i have it
connected to gmail
obviously connected outlook smart
lead instantly we have many other
connections coming up as well if
you
are connected mailbox same pop-up
is going to happen just like the
mailbox you want allow and i'll
pop
play in here now if you're
connecting smart lead or instantly
it's going to pop up asking you
for
username password as well as your
api if you are using a white label
version of smart lead and you want
to for example i actually could
show you this so that way you can
see what i'm talking about if you
are using the white label version
for any reason
you want to include that you could
go ahead and include your api key
email password and then the white
label
redirect for example ours is this
so i'm going to go ahead and put
app.revor.com click sub once i put
my
credentials and i'll be good to go
let's go ahead and go back to the
zoom account and continue with
that
example and go back into the
mailbox settings that's where it's
at so right now i have my gmail
connected
because i want to show you guys
some examples of how that looks
trigger activation controls this
is
probably where people usually get
stuck this is a new thing right
it's not like an outreach a sales
loft in apollo or any other
sequencing tool out there it is
completely new and this is what
you just need
to comprehend that this is where
the autoresponder will decide what
to trigger on or what not to
trigger
on i say that because you notice
here it says hashtag zoom with me
these are the trigger activation
controls so this is what the
autoresponder will look for in
order to decide whether or not to
reply to
that specific email so this needs
to be unique this is an and
statement not an or statement and
it needs to
be in the first email so if it's
in other emails it will still
catch and that would not be good
though you
don't want to do that so you want
to make sure it's in the first
email again this is an and
statement
i have here hashtag zoom with me
for example i will show you what
that looks like on my initial
email
here in this example i'm selling
zoom here's a subject here is my
verbiage but here is my little
trigger word
it's zoom with me partner now this
trigger word can be in the subject
line anywhere in the body or
anywhere in
the body or both it could be a
subject line or body so just keep
that in mind when you send this up
again it's an end statement some
popular stuff that i've seen
people do and we do ourselves is
www-company-com hashtags as i
showed you here forward slash and
forward slash company like that's
your
linkedin page right whatever may
be those things can tend to work
pretty well because they don't
include
a domain it's a little different
it's not consistent and
specifically unique very very much
to you in this case
let's say i have multiple people
running this campaign maybe i want
it to be triggered for ramsey
and i'm going to duplicate this
inbox manager and do another one
for john do another one for sam do
another one for mary and so on
right and so i'll say mary zoom in
zoom with me zoom with me right
whoever maybe so that's how i
would manage it if you had
multiple inbox managers for
multiple different
people as well now after the
trigger activation controls you're
going to get into additional
settings look at this as like more
advanced settings it's where
you'll be able to select your tone
exactly how you want it to engage
and additional settings that will
you know use more credit to be
honest with you right so how much
of that do you want to use and how
much more engagement do you want
is ultimately up to you obviously
we like to maximize this we've
noticed a lot of success from
making
sure to do no thanks follow-ups
and so on and i'll show you what
that is all about inbox manager
tone pretty self-explanatory our
default is professional and
standard length but my co-founder
picks laid back and brief so i
don't think he's a brief type of
guy either i think he's a more
standard
type of guy but it's whatever your
heart desires all right so this
section here is the no thanks
section
so what we believe is like look
somebody responded and took the
time to tell you not interested in
no
thanks they took the time to do
that have a little courtesy
respond back to them and confirm
that hey
receive your no thanks appreciate
it and it's also a great
opportunity to throw in some leave
behind
materials so what a great way to
go hey by the way here's some case
studies or hey by the way we also
do linkedin engagement if email
outbound campaigns are not for you
let me know or else reach back out
to
me if you're ever interested a
great way to provide another
offering or throw an article add
some
value so if you want to reply to
no thanks or not interested our
autoresponder will recognize that
sentiment and respond back
accordingly now we've also added
some restrictions if you like some
people
like hey i only want you to
respond the first email and that's
it or one two three punch and
that's
it i want to take over right uh i
don't want it to go have a
conversation going back and forth
9 10 12 times
whatever it may be i want to be
able to have control of that and i
want to get notification of it
absolutely you can connect slack
that'll get pushed forward or if
you just have gmail connected
don't
get drafted and sitting in your
inbox or draft box but as you can
see we don't have that turned on
but
in the events you want to do that
you're more than welcome to
follow-up settings this is also
something
to point out in this that gets a
little tricky is it will only
respond to the last email that rev
reply
sent reason is let's just say rev
replies engaging with a prospect
of yours and let's say it's done
through smart lead or whatever it
may be but all of a sudden you hop
in and start chatting well it's
gonna know why am i gonna follow
up and see if i could get that
meeting booked if you know ramsey
or
somebody else had actually stepped
in so you know as you know 25 35
percent of your time is spent just
trying to convert somebody to get
a meeting so it is a good check of
time once even somebody engages
with you it doesn't mean the
meeting is booked you're trying to
get continue pushing for that
lean on rev reply for that so one
two or three follow-up it will be
very context specific as well
and i'll pick that up so however
many days apart you want them i
want one one day after the last
auto response two days after the
last auto response maybe i want
this to be and maybe i want to
wait a
little bit and i want to space
this out a little bit more one
three five so day two technically
day
five and day ten ultimately right
and day after the last auto
response um adaptive templates
think of
this as like something that would
you would give the auto responder
with some some guidance like you
want to actually give it hey i
anybody that's a positive
sentiment any of these interested
information
requests being a request i want
you to tell like hey you know what
i absolutely love to buy you a
guitar
and sing you a song and tell you
more about your questions but
first let's put together a poem
right
whatever maybe you want to tell
this thing it will grab that
whatever context you want to give
it
and whatever context it pulls in
from the email thread it will
combine it and will adapt it
accordingly to
the email so you could pick and
choose however you'd like to see
that fit and now for the finale
automatic sending options so you
see here you have two options full
auto right i'm going to go hey
let's just go ahead and run with
it no matter what i want rev reply
to respond to everything of every
category automatically if you
don't want that the other option
is custom and you'll have to
integrate slack
so what slack allows you to do is
you could pick the sentiment and
you can imagine positive
is anything that's information
request being a request interested
follow-up is anybody that says hey
circle back with me a different
day and time not interested no
thanks not interested and all that
right so you can pick and choose
which one you want on automatic
which one you want manual review
and
i'll show you how that looks in a
second in this case i typically
like to keep follow-up and not
interested no thanks all those
full automatic i do not want to
touch those out of sight out of
mind
i completely trust rev reply on
the sentiment analysis that's able
to pick up and just let
it do its thing i don't need to
spend time doing that but maybe i
want to review the positive
responses
just you know maybe in the
beginning i highly recommend it in
the beginning so you can see and
feel confident with what we're
able to do and you can edit it and
guide it a little bit more if you
need to and train it and i'll show
you how to do that in a second so
typically start out you know
i suggest starting out something
like this you can pick and choose
whichever slack channels you want
most people have three different
slack channels depending on which
one but some people actually
have one and all go into one
channel we'll still able to be
distinguished you'll still be able
to
distinguish the difference between
which message is what so let's go
ahead and jump into how that looks
all right so zoom here's an
example of one of the first
messages i had sent out and i will
show you
how it kind of ends up running
through this what nine responses
back and forth to get to where
it's at
so in this example i shared with
you earlier that saying hey mark
trying to pitch on zoom
and here's a trigger word zoom
with me partners so the
autoresponder said i'm sorry the
the prospect
said how do you compare to google
meet it's free you're expensive
autoresponder came back and said
mark great question while google
me offers basic free service zoom
offers blah blah blah right in the
end
we'll push it and say i'd love to
discuss this further and address
any specific needs you might have
here are a couple available slots
and i'll suggest both these times
if you're picking the time that
works for you or suggest another
time you could also use my
calendar booking link that you saw
in the
profile best ramsey mark goes eh
no thank you no longer interested
so what happened is this turned
from
a positive sentiment to a negative
sentiment right so i went from yes
interested to no thanks not
interested
sent a no thank you email as you
can see here with customer success
stories and then shortly after
mark had a change of heart 10
minutes later after he saw the
case studies and said actually
wait those
are some impressive case studies
so i guess i am interested what's
your cheapest plan autoresponder
is
actually also able to handle that
right like hey thank you for
renewed interest it recognizes
went from
yes no yes no i'm glad you found
the case studies impressive our
most affordable plan starts at 15
a month and if you probably saw
there's nothing actually mentioned
here that says 15 a month pretty
magical isn't it so it's able to
pick up on previous learnings able
to pick up on anything online as
well
it will pick up on whatever it can
to ensure the answer is as solid
as can be if you'd like to discuss
further or have any questions feel
free to book a meeting via my
calendar link and that goes to my
calendar
booking link right so mark comes
back says actually i'm only
interested if you give me 80
discount
and give me a love poem right now
depending obviously on the
sentiments that you pick you could
actually you know because i put if
you recall professional and
standard if i had more of
enthusiastic or laid back perhaps
you know the autoresponder might
give him a little love poem
but instead i said while i can't
quite offer an 80 discount or
write a love poem i appreciate
your
interest in the sense of humor so
it's talking about zoom it throws
it one more time and it still
pushes out to discuss how zoom can
be best for you here are a couple
available time slots
now if in the event just to show
you an example you notice these
are hyperlinked that's because
i'm my calendar connected and it's
suggesting a calendar booking link
because i have that provided
as well to the inbox manager but
you see here are two options i
could definitely click on and what
will
happen is it will go to this page
and show you that you're
confirming the calendar invite for
this day and
time now i could confirm it
through there or if i was mark i'd
go hey sounds good let's put
although
this day has passed now at 12 30
p.m sent right so that mark is
gonna mamsie is gonna get an email
seeing confirmed autoresponder is
going to recognize that and that's
automatically going to send that
calendar invite for 12 30 on
tuesday but now we'll probably see
this pop up thing is this is in
the past
so it's gonna tell hey mark sorry
that time don't look available how
about this day and time
so let's go show you how this
looks in slack now this is my
dummy account here so i have a lot
of
tests going on so excuse the
little mess that we've got going
on but as you could see once a
response
comes in and this is the sentiment
analysis here this is what you get
i'll show you that inbound email
it'll show you the rest of the
email you could also see more tell
you it's a positive sentiment if
it's
not a positive sentiment it'll
tell you it's a follow-up or if
it's a no thanks for example
soft no it will that one's change
one will tell you no thanks right
so it will happen as this pops up
you also have ability to approve
again remember this is a manual
scent you have ability to edit so
i could
go right in and go you know what
yeah i don't like the fact that it
says learning more you know i
don't
want it to say learn more how
about we say thanks for your
interest i don't want it to say
it's setting
up me obviously they know whatever
maybe update and then i come in
here and click approve and it will
send automatically now if i wanted
just to stop it all all of a
sudden even though it's unmeaning
review
i don't want it to go back and
forth i don't want to generate any
more responses i'll take over
i can go ahead and click i'll take
over and what you'll see here is
let me show you a different
example this pop-up will happen
i'll say stop thread and that will
pop up now some other things
you'll
see as well is link to thread if
you are using white label for some
smart lead it will take you to
that
white label link that's the
beautiful part you do have an
option to turn this off in the
additional
settings and then you have ability
to thumbs up thumbs down it so
this is where the autoresponder
is going to get smarter so in this
case let me show you one that i
have yet to click on it will show
you a thumbs up a thumbs down and
that will automatically train the
autoresponder as it goes
you need about 20 plus for it to
really start getting more of an
expert and be a mirror of your
voice so i highly recommend you do
that if you like the message if
not edit it and then thumbs up
so that way it learns the
differences and what you've put
together so i hope this helps at
least
guide you through that and as you
can see even from the follow-ups
for example um it is intuitive
enough
if somebody says hey i'm out this
not not i'm out right now i'm
traveling or reach back out to me
next
week what it's going to go ahead
and do in this example i said hey
ramsey i'm traveling right now
in portugal won't be back in the
country until the end of next week
reach back out to me until i
return
and blah blah blah and you know
the autoresponder said hope you're
enjoying time in portugal i'll
reach
out to you the week after next
once you're settled back in please
let me know if there's any
specific
daytime that works best for you
now this was sent yesterday guess
what not next week
by the week after it's going to
come back it's automatically going
to send a follow-up
now one thing i'll also share with
you guys about the sentiment
analysis that's pretty unique
is our sentiment analysis actually
supersedes smart leads what i mean
by that is you know smart lead
does have the ever going issue of
marking something out of office or
not having to be categorized so
what our sentiment analysis will
do is it actually is able to pick
those up and it's able to correct
the correct sentiment because we
use about four different four five
different ai models to be
exact and they obviously all talk
to each other and more of an
objective approach so it is far
more
accurate so therefore it will
update it to the current center
the correct sentiments and if
there's
uncategorized it will put it in
the right category for you as well
so anyways that's the walkthrough
of
rev reply free to kick the tires
around you're gonna see a
dashboard coming up very soon beta
is just
very you know it's very light it's
not meant to be anything robust
just so you can see all the
messages
your inbox managers your user
settings all that stuff is right
there for you if you have any
questions
please reach out to us through uh
email support at rev reply.com or
through chat as you can see we're
always in here and happy, happy
hunting.
Thank you.