Okay, so this video is going to
show you how to set up the
infrastructure necessary to run
mass outreach cold email
campaigns.
As you can see, you cannot send
cold emails at scale from a single
domain.
You need to set up brand new
domains specifically for the
function of running cold email
campaigns.
And we have over a thousand of
these.
For starters, you'll probably need
about 50 email inboxes to run
outreach at scale.
We have literally a thousand
because we send a lot, a lot, a
lot of volume with our email
campaigns.
But either way, here's how you
actually go ahead and set up, you
know, a bunch of domains and
inboxes.
And this kind of stuff is even
confusing to me.
I'm a marketer.
I don't like the technical stuff.
So let me explain it to you in
very simple terms.
If you work at a business and you
have an email address at that
business, Christian at list
kit.io, right?
Christian at list kit.io is my
main business email for my work
communication at list kit.
You probably have, if you're
watching this, an email
specifically for the job you work
at or the university you go to or
the university you went to that is
set up specifically for that
purpose.
Think of this like setting up
hundreds of new email addresses
like the one you already have but
just for cold email because if
your main business email goes to
spam and doesn't send emails
anymore as a result of a cold
email campaign, you will not be
able to email your coworkers, your
clients, your boss, or anything,
right?
So this is why we set up dozens if
not hundreds of brand new email
accounts for cold email.
And there's a two-step process.
First, you have to buy the domain,
right?
List kit.io is our business domain
and Christian at list kit.io is an
inbox on that domain.
So you have to purchase a ton of
different domains from a tool like
GoDaddy or Porkbun.
Most of you have probably heard of
GoDaddy, right?
They used to have famous ads with
girls in them and I don't know.
They had really good marketing for
a domain registrar, which is
hilarious.
But Porkbun is a tool that we use
most of the time to set up these
domains for the campaigns, right?
And here's a good example.
Like let's just say
GetAgencyServices.com.
This is probably taken, but let's
see if it's not.
Okay.
It is available.
GetAgencyServices.com.
Then I would try
GoAgencyServices.com.
Available.
So I would sit here and literally
purchase 25 domains.
This is what you need to do.
Sit in a tool like Porkbun and
purchase 25 different domains and
then check out and purchase them.
And they're $11 each for a year,
which, you know, at first is
expensive,
but then you don't pay for it for
a whole nother year.
And once you have all 25 domains
ready to go, you purchase them and
they are now yours.
So the first part of the process
has been set up
where you have the domains
necessary to run campaigns.
What you don't have is the inboxes
yet.
So what you need to do is go into
Google Admin Panel.
And honestly, I hate doing this
stuff on my own.
So if I butcher this, I'm sorry
because I haven't done this
process in five years and I'll
show you why in a second because I
have people doing it for me.
But basically what you need to do
is go into because think of it
like this.
You have your 25 domains purchased
and ready to go, but you don't
have the email accounts ready to
go.
And where do you send emails from
Gmail?
Gmail is a Google business.
So you need to go into your Google
Admin account, which it looks like
I can't even get into, and set up
Google email inboxes.
Like to set up multiple inboxes in
Gmail, navigate to settings,
select inbox type.
Like you just have to go into the
Google Admin panel and build these
inboxes out using the domains that
you just purchased.
Because once you have the inboxes
created, you now have both pieces
of the puzzle with the inbox and
the domain set up and ready to go.
So you can then connect it to a
tool like Smartlead and have these
inboxes in this dashboard that
you're sending emails from.
Because we only, so for
simplicity's sake, let's say I
have 100 domains.
I can only send 11 emails a day
per domain before my account's at
risk of going to spam.
If you send it any more than 11
per day per domain, you're
probably going to go to spam and
your whole campaign is toast.
So like I said, you have to set up
a lot of different email inboxes
so you can send a ton of volume
without sending a lot of volume
per inbox.
Right?
So once you purchase the domains
from a tool like Pork Bun, once
you set everything up in a tool
like Gmail or Outlook, you now
have your email inboxes.
And then you just hook them up to
this tool called Smartlead and go
from there.
In the description, I'm going to
link a video from my partner Andre
where he basically sets up an
inbox from scratch doing this
whole process manually.
And you will see it is a massive,
massive pain in the ass that
nobody wants to handle or deal
with.
Nobody wants to deal with.
Right?
You don't want to sit here and set
up 15 domains, 30 inboxes for each
of your clients.
The reason why I said earlier that
I haven't done this in years is
because our tool, ListKit, has
basically a cold email set up in a
box where you come to us and you
say, hey, I need 30 domains and 60
inboxes.
You pay us $691 a month to manage
everything and we build it all out
for you where you get the domain
set up, the inbox is set up, and
you have the ability to send 660
emails a day for your clients.
Right?
So you can do this process
manually using the link below this
video.
It's from my partner Andre.
It basically shows you how to
properly set up an inbox.
If you're, you know, just starting
out, you're balling on a budget, I
would highly recommend doing it on
your own and just sucking it up
for a few hours.
If you want us to do it for you,
you go through a tool like ListKit
just like you would do for the
data, except this time you come to
us for the inboxes and the
domains, and we will build this
out for you for a monthly fee.
Right?
There is a monthly fee either way
because you have to pay for
inboxes and domains, or you can
just use the monthly fee and put
it towards a ListKit build out
where we handle all this for you
so that you log into a sending
tool and you have 60 email inboxes
warmed up and ready to go so you
can start emailing from them so
you can launch a campaign that
reaches out to 10,000 people a
month.
So that is the manual process of
setting up inboxes and domains.
It's not fun.
Nobody wants to do it, but it is
necessary to get results.
So, at this point, you have now
learned how to set up inboxes, how
to write good copy, how to build a
list of leads.
Everything is all ready to go, and
I've shown you real examples of
different campaigns built out and
ready.
So you basically now have a very
basic beginner knowledge of how to
do cold email and get actual
results from them.
So, there's going to be a ton more
videos in here going over
different subsectors of issues
you're going to run into and
things you need help with, but
this is the basic gist of how to
do cold email.
So, hopefully you enjoyed, there's
going to be questions and
concerns, and you guys are going
to have things that you need help
with.
I know, and I'm aware of this, and
I'm looking forward to hearing
from you so I can help you out,
but hopefully this was valuable,
and congrats on kicking off your
journey of running your very own
cold email business.
Thanks.