What's going on guys, in this
video, we're going to finish off
the deliverability section
of the cold email setup guide
updated for 2023 and SmartLead by
starting the warmup process
in SmartLead for each of the new
email accounts we've now connected
to our new SmartLead account.
And so right within SmartLead in
the email account section, you
should have 10 email
accounts added here and you're
going to go into each individual
one, take note of what
the domain or email account it is,
and you're going to start in
general.
The first thing we want to do is
set up a custom tracking domain.
And so turn this on and then we're
going to have to go back to
domains.google, back to
the registrar, and then we're
going to have to go to this
specific domain.
So this is clientascend.com right
here.
We're going to go back into
manage.
We're going to go into DNS and
then we're going to manage custom
records and we're going to
create a new record after DMARC.
And the value here is just the
host is email tracking, just
spelled that way.
The type is going to be CNAME.
This can stay the same.
And then the domain name is
open.sleadtrack.com.
So email tracking, CNAME, this
stays the same,
open.sleadtrack.com.
You're going to save that.
So it should show up exactly like
you see here.
And then back in Smart Lead, the
way you're going to set this up is
like it says here.
Or where does it say?
So it's basically just going to be
HTTP, right, like this, slash,
slash, and then email tracking
dot.
And then it's going to be your
domain.
So clientascend.com like this.
And then you can verify CNAME.
And then it should be verified
successfully.
Okay.
And then click save in the bottom
right.
And it'll be saved successfully.
And you could go off the email
account and back into the general
settings.
Let's see if it wants to load.
I think we might have crashed the
system.
No, we're good.
So go into general settings and
this should show up this way.
So HTTP, dash, dash, email
tracking, and then the domain
name, dot, the domain name, right?
So that's all set up exactly like
we just showed.
And then now for the actual
warmup, first, we want to actually
enable warmup in the bottom right.
Okay.
And then, so this should be
enabled.
And then the total number of
warmup emails per day should be
40.
The ramp up should be four.
And then the randomized number
should be 25 to 40.
And then the reply rate should be
45.
Okay.
Everything else can say the same.
And then we can enable auto adjust
warmup setting ratio and then
update.
So these are the warmup settings.
It should be enabled.
This number should be 40.
Ramp up should be four.
Randomizer should be 25 to 40.
Reply rate percentage should be
45.
This can stay the same.
And then this should be toggled on
and enabled.
And that's it.
So you want to just go back to all
the email accounts and that should
be enabled for each of them.
So when it says warmup enabled,
all of them should say yes.
And we're going to leave that on
for 14 days.
So from the moment you complete
this step, which brings us to the
end of the deliverability section,
you're going to be able to launch
your campaign 14 days from today.
So that gives you 14 days to go
and complete the targeting and the
messaging sections of the program.
It also gives you 14 days to do
your landing page and your VSL.
And so make sure to use these 14
days very strategically so you're
not wasting any time.
On day 14, you want to come in
here, follow the rest of the steps
in the launch campaign videos,
which are at the end of this
section after targeting and
messaging, which we'll do next.
And follow those steps to actually
launch campaigns.
But for now, where you should be
at is you should have all 10 of
your new domains and email
accounts registered via Google
domains.
You should have your smart lead
account set up.
You should have all your email
accounts connected in your smart
lead account.
And you should have the warmup
process enabled for each of your
email accounts with the custom
tracking domain set up with these
settings.
40 is the total number with a wrap
up of four, with the randomization
of 25 to 40, with the reply rate
of 45% with this setting enabled.
And from there, we're going to be
able to jump into the targeting
section next and then the
messaging section.
And then we're going to be able to
launch campaigns 14 days from
today.