What's up guys, Lucas here.
So this is actually one of my
favorite flows that I've made
simply because this is one that I
know is highly requested.
We have a lot of e-com email
marketing guys inside Client
Ascension
and one of the things I regularly
get is questions about copywriting
and how do they replace
copywriters
and how do they write their email
flows and stuff with AI
and now this automation does all
of that for them completely, 100%.
So let's take a look at how this
works.
As usual, let's start off by
saying what you need to have set
up.
You need to have your open writer
set up.
You need perplexity for a research
You will need your Google Docs
OAuth 2 for your MD2 Docs,
Google Drive, and Slack.
Aside from that, we are good to
go.
So the way this works is it is a
form.
The form asks for the brand name.
This is of course about the brand
you're creating e-com emails for.
So the brand name, their website,
the industry niche they're in,
are they an existing client,
and any personalization notes you
might have about them you want to
add.
Then our brand research agent is
used perplexity to do detailed
research on the brand.
As you can see, it comes out with
a very detailed thing on this
brand.
This is a brand that I used to
work with a long time ago,
so I already kind of knew a bit
about them.
I could verify that everything you
got was correct.
After that, we take that
information and we write seven
flows.
The welcome flow, the cart
abandon, the checkout abandon, the
browse abandon,
the post-purchase, site abandon,
and the win back flow.
And these are all super detailed
based on Max Durdvant's writings
and his training.
And it creates the full sequence
for each of these.
Then the MD2 Docs creates Google
Docs for all of them.
Then we have some code nodes
running here that essentially are
an aggregate node
that essentially are putting all
of these Google Doc IDs together.
Then we check and see if they are
an existing customer or not.
So on the form, if you say that
they are, then they'll go to the
true branch,
which will search for their client
folder inside of your client's
folder,
as well as always need a Google
Drive folder named clients.
And if they're not, it'll create a
folder for them.
Then we've got some more
processing with the code nodes to
do with the IDs and the documents.
Then we're moving the files from
the seven files we created to the
correct folder
before finally sending a very
nicely formatted Slack message
that says, hey, new client setup
is complete
and includes a link to their
client folder, which will look
like this.
That will be named whatever you
put the brand name at the
beginning of the form
along with all the different
flows.
So if we have a look, these are
what the flows look like.
So as you can see, it gives the
subject line options, preview
text, email layout,
gives all the copy, email too.
It goes all the way through.
Same for all of these.
These are card abandoned, six to
eight email sequence, the checkout
abandoned flow,
the post-purchase flow, the win
back flow, the site abandoned
flow, and the browse abandonment
flow.
As you can see, they're all very
detailed.
It goes through the full breakdown
of what you should do.
You can give some notes on things
like the Clavio setup and
personalization
and things like that, depending on
what the flow is.
So this is super detailed.
This is something that the
e-commerce email guys and site
client essentially have been
asking for for quite a long time.
To get this set up, again, all you
need to do is make sure that you
modify anything you need to modify
here.
It really should be nothing.
It's just setting up really your
different account details, such as
your open router, your perplexity,
getting your Google OAuth for the
MD2 docs, and the Google Drive and
Slack setup.
Once that is done, then you are
good to go.
You simply just turn it to active
and then get your production URL
for the form.
Anytime you have a new client, you
just input the information into
the form,
and you will, within a few
minutes, have all of their flows
written, ready to go in Google
Drive for you.
Now, you don't have to hire a flow
copywriter.
You are good to go.
So, next we're working on is going
to be campaign ideas and things
like that.
So you can, again, put out any
copywriter whatsoever and have
everything handled by AI.
But this is going to get you 90%
of the way there for one of the
most important parts of becoming a
marketing,
which is the flow creation and
setup.
After this, you've got to design
the emails and put the copy and
you're sorted.
So, hopefully, this was helpful
and I will see you in the next
one.
Peace.