What's up guys, Lucas here, and
this one I'm going to be showing
you our content calendar
generator.
This is for creating your content
calendar for an e-com email
marketing agency.
Again, like a lot of other forms,
it's a calendar input form.
For this, you will need to have
set up your Perplexity API key,
your OpenRouter API key,
your Google Sheets, and your
Google Drive and Slack.
We've been over had to do all
these in other videos.
Check them out if you are not
sure, but it's very simple.
For most of these, it is simply
just inputting an API key.
And then for Google Sheets, you
will do the usual Google Sheets.
So just log in with Google and
you're good to go.
So the way this works is there is
a campaign request form.
You can put brand details below to
generate a comprehensive email
content calendar.
So you need to put in the brand
name, the brand website, the
industry and niche,
are they existing clients, any
personalization notes you might
have.
For instance, any specific product
launch date or anything like that.
Upcoming key dates and that's it.
So once you do that, then our AI
agent immediately generates a
fully detailed content calendar
for you.
Our code nodes here are just
formatting data for us and parsing
the data that's output.
We then create a spreadsheet.
We create a sheet inside that
spreadsheet called calendar.
And we create another sheet called
summary.
Then we prepare the data for this
by splitting the rows, just
preparing the data here.
And then we populate the data onto
the sheet.
Then we aggregate those results
back together.
We check, are they a returning
client?
If they are, then we search for an
existing folder and move the sheet
to that folder.
If not, we create the folder and
move it to that folder.
Then finally, we send a nice Slack
notification saying, hey, it's all
done.
Here's a link to the calendar
ready to go.
And what the calendar looks like
is this.
So as I said, there's two sheets,
calendar and summary.
The calendar one obviously has all
the details.
There's the date, day of week,
campaign type, the subject line,
the preview text, primary goal,
content theme, key message, CTA,
segment priority, notes, and the
brand.
You can see it's super, super
detailed.
So this handles that for you.
And then the next thing we have is
the summary that goes over the
campaign mix, the total number of
emails, the key dates
incorporated, the strategic notes,
and when it was generated.
So this generates a full content
calendar for you, ready to go.
Very, very easy to use.
Again, when you're ready to go
live with this, you will simply
get your production URL from up
here, and then you will set it to
live, and you are ready to go.
So that is how this works.
Very simple, as you can see, and
very useful because, you know,
planning out these campaign
calendars can be very, very hard.
This makes it very easy for you to
get it set up in seconds versus,
you know, planning out over the
course of, you know, a few hours,
having to do, even having to
create, like, custom graphics for
it or whatever.
Now you've just got a spreadsheet
where it's got everything in there
ready to go.
So I hope this is helpful.
Any problems, feel free to hit me
up, and I will see you in the next
one.
Peace.