What's up guys, Lucas here, and
this one will be showing you
our e-com email campaign generator
agent.
This one is pretty
straightforward, but pretty cool.
So essentially what this does is
like a lot of the others,
it's a form submission workflow.
So we have a form and on that
form, all you have to submit is
the brand name,
the brand website, industry and
niche, choose their existing
client.
You can add some personalization
notes.
You also could put some details
here about any specific campaigns
that you want
to create, you know, say civic
data or product launch coming up.
And then choose from a dropdown,
the campaign types you want to
make.
Uh, there's multiple you can
select from on there.
Uh, if I scroll down here, you can
see a few, as you can see, it's a
lot here.
So choose the ones that you want.
They're a checkbox and then we are
good to go.
After that, we have our brand
research agent, um, that goes and
researches
everything about the brand reason
perplexity.
Make sure you got perplexity set
up.
Make sure you get open writer set
up, make sure you got Google drive
set up.
I make sure you got slack set up.
Those are all the ones we're
using.
Uh, then we have a campaign idea
agent.
And this actually creates the
ideas for your campaigns.
So, uh, it takes the information
you put into it, uh, next to
research and then create some
really, really nice campaigns.
And then we write five of them
that we actually have a different,
uh, AI agent writing each
of the campaigns to make sure
they're as detailed as possible.
And then at the end, we aggregate
all this information together.
Google docs, send your Google, uh,
docs OAuth to set up for MD2 docs
creates a nice Google
document for us.
And then as usual, we run through
the, are they using client?
Yes.
Then searches for the existing
folder, moves the folder and sends
you a slack notification.
Now the campaigns themselves or
the document actually looks like
it gives you the subject
line, the preview text, the
headline, the body copy, uh, goes
into full detail on the campaign.
It gives you the CTA, uh, goes
through the whole thing.
So it is super in-depth it, uh,
does a very, very good job of
writing, uh, the full campaigns
seven pages worth of campaigns in
here.
And, uh, it is, uh, everything you
need to automatically create new
campaigns for your
clients on autopilot, uh, super
easy to, to, to run again, all you
need is that input form.
Uh, make sure you've got your
perplexity API key in there and
make sure you get your open
writers set up and make sure that
you have your Google drive and
your Google docs or MD2 doc set
up.
Uh, again, all this is doing is
taking the information,
researching the brand, uh,
creating campaign ideas, sending
those ideas to our campaign
writer.
This code node just spits out the
different campaign ideas.
And then we take all the
information, put it all together,
prepare the document data,
create the document to MD2 docs,
and then send you a slack
notification.
Just saying, Hey, new campaigns
created.
We're all done.
Uh, you know, uh, the client, the
status document, each campaign
strategy created the
campaign focus.
Um, and then the strategy
highlights.
Now in the ages themselves, these
are actually built very, very
heavily on max.
Um, uh, campaign, uh, methodology.
Uh, you can see here actually in
the, in this one, up here we go.
Uh, we're actually saying create
five high converting emails.
Using max has proven, uh, 40
million methodology.
Um, and then, uh, same for our
system message.
Uh, we sell it the micro topic
mastery education positioning.
We go through all the different
things it's got to include.
So, uh, this goes super in depth,
uh, make sure that, you know,
everything that is being,
um, out, uh, output by max here
is, uh, everything's output is
based on max's training.
And, uh, you know, guarantees that
you are getting really, really
solid campaigns.
Uh, I use an existing brand that I
knew about for this.
So we were able to get actual real
information or real brand.
Um, obviously put in the brand
that you're working with.
If you give it the, the, the brand
website, it helps a lot.
And, uh, again, any
personalization notes, you just
put it in the presentation, those
box.
And, uh, you'll get some kind of
extra context and it'd be, you
know,
kind of tailored a bit more to
whatever kind of information that
you give it.
So that's how this works.
Uh, super straightforward.
Again, all you need to do is get
the, uh, production URL here and
then set your flow live.
And you will be good to go.
All you gotta do is input the
information form and you're
flying.
So this is great for, you've got
a, if you're running an e-commerce
agency,
you've got some campaign managers
that we were doing, you know, uh,
more in detail things,
handling clients, stuff like that.
Now they can actually just write
campaigns pretty much on autopilot
as well.
And you're good to go.
So I'll be helpful.
And I will see you in the next
one.
Peace.