What's up guys lucas here this is
probably one of my favorite
automations that we've done
uh this is an ai product photo
shoot generator and uh essentially
i think i should show you guys
the the results before anything
else because they turn out really
cool but uh these are entirely
ai generated using google's nano
banana uh image generator which
released only recently
and does an absolutely phenomenal
job of following uh product
dimensions and uh copying things
from
one image to another look at the
detail on that absolutely insane
uh you see logos and everything
are all perfect text all perfect
uh super super nice uh this is
absolutely perfect if you are
creating uh product photo shoots
or you need them for email designs
anything like that so the way
this works it looks complicated
but it's pretty simple uh there's
actually i'll start off with
saying the two things we're going
to need to set up you will need to
get an api from imagebb.com
now just type in imgbb.com and uh
once you are in imagebb and you're
signed up you are going to
i'm going to my website to show
you guys you're going to go to
about and you're going to click
api
here you'll get your api key
simply take that api key and you
are going to double click this one
here
this is the upload original image
to imagebb one and where it says
key paste in your key here
and that's it and then the other
one you're going to need is going
to be file ai so go to file.ai
sign up or actually you can see me
log in right now so i'm going to
just continue with google
i'm going to choose my account
continue
and when you're in file to ai
again i'm just going to go back to
the main home page so you see
exactly
what i see you're going to just
click your name up here and click
account and then api keys i just
think api is available from
beginning so api keys and add key
and once you have that there's
going to be a
few here you're going to add it to
it's going to be over here create
image you are going to choose a
new header auth so you're going to
do uh header auth create new
credential type in authorization
and then paste your key here and
that is it you are done so that is
it that's what you're going to do
do it for that do the same then
once that's created you'll uh
select obviously header auth as
your file ai one forget status
double click and just set it as
file ai forget url image header
auth file
ai and get file image uh we're
going to set that to actually you
don't need that at all that's fine
you just leave get so it's just
for uh these three create image
get status and get url image
you're
going to set file ai you also need
to set up uh your google drive
your slack uh perplexity uh open
router and we actually will need
an open ai key for the analyze
image uh to do that you're just
going
to go to uh i think it's
platform.openai or openai uh yeah
platform.openai.com slash settings
uh log in obviously let's log in
continue with google
then once you're logged in you're
just going to go down to api keys
and you're going to create a new
key and copy and paste it then
into uh your account settings
under open ai account api keys
paste it in there and then you're
good to go so the way this works
you have a form as usual you'll
put in a brand name the brand
website the brand niche the photo
shoot
goals any additional context are
they existing client yes or no and
you will upload a product photo
pngs
are preferable so upload a product
photo um then what this will do is
it will immediately upload the
image
image to image bb and it will send
it to open ai to analyze the image
and say what's in it
then we have a photo shoot
research agent that does detailed
research on conducting a photo
shoot and
comes up with five different
scenes for the photo shoot after
creating our five scenes we split
those
out and then we send it to a loop
and the loop basically creates
those five scenes so it sends
it to file ai to generate the
image it waits 60 seconds then it
gets the status if it's completed
then we get the url of the uh
image if not then we wait in our
60 seconds and we get the file
image
and then we upload the file to
google drive uh it'll loop over
these so they're done we'll have
five
files it'll upload the files to
google drive aggregate those
together then we'll check if
they're a returning
client client and if they uh are
not in this case it'll create a
client folder and then we will
loop
over moving the files uh the five
different files into that folder
and then send a notification same
deal if they are existing client
we just loop over moving the files
into the folder then send you a
notification and as i showed you
this is the sort of result you're
going to get uh looks really
really
good um i think this is my
favorite one just having
incredibly detailed and uh like
close up that is
and uh yeah absolutely perfect so
this is everything you would need
then to create everything from ads
to uh really really good um email
designs uh you know throughout
your uh your email campaigns
so that is how that works again to
get this live all you're going to
do is you're going to click the
active button up here and then you
will get your uh production url
here input the form and you will
automatically end up with a slack
notification with a link to the
files in your google drive folder
so
that's how that works a really
cool one probably one of my
favorite one so far um hope this
is helpful
and i will see you in the next one
peace