What's up, boys?
I want to make the topic of this
video, exert shit out into the
world, right?
This is basically about building a
social following and why you
should do it.
Just listen
to what I'm saying here, right?
So the person actively, the person
on the journey actively
narrating it is as interesting as
a person who has already
accomplished it, right?
Building a
social following is infinite,
right?
I'm going to get to this in a
second, but you need to chase
the infinite over the fast, right?
So building a social following is
about making relationships
with people, right?
If you have a service or you're
selling a particular thing, what
you're
doing with the social following is
permanently associating your name
with what you do, right?
So cold email, you think of cold
email wizard, SEO, I think of
Caval on Twitter, Google ads,
I think of Colin Schmelbeck,
right?
VSL, I think of Steven Trister,
It doesn't matter
if there's competition.
What you're trying to work, your
audience, the people by
happenstance,
you have found to follow you or
engage with, or they're just in
your sphere in some capacity,
you're trying to work them, right?
There is infinite shit here,
right?
It's not about like,
there's no market of like, oh,
this is just the SEO market.
There's who you have.
It's who you have.
You need to take those people and
over time, just associate who you
are with that thing permanently
inside their head.
Where they think of that, they
think of you, just automatic,
right?
So I want to
talk about this real quick.
Fast, cheap, infinite.
Ads, fast.
They're not cheap.
They're not infinite,
right?
Cold outreach, fast and cheap,
Not infinite though.
You stop doing outreach, you stop
getting leads for that.
Social following is cheap and
infinite, but it's slow, but it's
infinite.
It's the
only one that is infinite.
You own it.
It's there forever.
Like you've, there's a category of
people
who you've permanently associated
your thing, right?
So there's a group of people.
I'm going to talk
about this.
It's a group of people who like
over time, you offer some service
and some percent of
them will eventually need it at
some point and you become the de
facto option, right?
There's no reason
on earth why any, any person
shouldn't be building and
following you.
This is, I want to express to you
guys.
You just need to be doing Twitter.
You need to be doing LinkedIn.
You need to build something
infinite, right?
It needs to be there.
And this is the function of why,
but kind of sensitive is so
long.
Why want you guys to be in here
for so long?
Cause you need to build the
infinite, right?
You're
here cause you knew Cody, my
wizard, or you knew Andre and you
were in our, you were in our
infinite.
You need to make your own
You need to have something with an
infinite return that's there
permanently, right?
It's so important, right?
There's no ad spend.
There's no, there's no,
there's no, it's just there
forever.
You own it, right?
And if we were, if we were to look
at like
how this kind of works out, where
it's like, first thing I did with
Cody and the wizard was sell Cody
on mastery.
And this is how this worked out,
right?
Look at nothing.
Three months, like basically,
basically nothing, right?
Three months, like total of like
four grand.
You're going to do something
for three straight months and make
like a total of, this isn't even
four grand.
It's like, you're going to do
something for that long.
And then just to get here, that's
what you're looking for.
You're just trying to get there,
right?
You need to do this for
so long.
Cause it's, it's the compounding
effect.
Nothing happens for so long.
And then it all
happens at once.
Like this is look at that fucking
growth, right?
This is nothing.
This seems like
nothing.
When you look at it from the
outside, Oh, three months, that
isn't that long until
you're inside of the three months
and you give up, right?
You need to keep going.
You need to,
you need to fucking get past that.
You need to achieve the infinite.
You need to chase that,
right?
It's so important, right?
And here's what I did on Twitter.
It's so easy.
This is what I did
just consecutively forever.
Like I just did all seven of these
months.
This is what I did,
right?
It was at least three tweets, at
least 10 comments, outbound
comments.
You find someone,
someone else's shit.
You comment on it, right?
Reply to every single comment you
get in your post.
You reply to every single DM,
right?
This is, that's it.
Like, it doesn't seem so simple
until
you're in like week six and you're
like, Oh, this isn't doing
anything.
And then you give up.
It's because you didn't wait.
You didn't do it long enough.
You didn't get here.
You gave up.
So you can't do that.
It's consecutive.
It needs to be every single day.
Every consecutive day you do
it.
You pull the goal forward seven
days.
Every day you skip, you just
pushed it back seven,
right?
It's amplified.
It's amplified on either end.
You need to do it every single
day.
Actually zero off days, right?
You just need to get here.
You just need to get to 120 days.
Like you,
you need to get the infinite,
right?
And this is so easy if you really
just think about it.
30 minute block every single day,
right?
Writing content, right?
45 minute block every day,
responding to all the comments,
making outbound comments, replying
to DMs, right?
Nothing happens
for so long that you went all at
once, right?
And do you have the mental
fortitude to withstand this work
while absolutely nothing happens
while you're in month one, in
month two, in month three,
where fucking nothing has
happened, right?
Will you make it to month four?
Will you keep doing this in the
face,
of it seeming completely fucking
pointless, right?
Can you do that?
Right?
How much effort will you exert to
achieve the infinite, right?
But you just need to stick with
it.
You need, in this concept, you
need to exist so hard.
And what I mean by that is you
start
building an audience.
Is when you send a comment on
Twitter, it shows up on your
followers timeline,
bam, reminder that you exist,
right?
When you reply to comments, they
leave, it shows up as a
notification for them and on the
timeline for everybody that
follows you, bam, reminder that
you exist to them and everybody
else, right?
When you send a tweet, it shows up
on your followers
timeline, bam, reminder that you
exist, right?
When somebody DMs you and you
reply, bam, reminder
that you exist, right?
You need to permanently exist
every single day.
Your followers need to get on
Twitter.
You need to see something from you
every fucking time.
Like your frequency is like they
see
you like at least twice a day,
right?
You just need to exist so hard for
so long.
You just need to do
that, right?
You need to always be there.
And then we start talking about
conversion windows.
Every person
has their own conversion window,
right?
You offer as an example, video
editing services, right?
Not
everybody is making videos right
now, but by existing so hard for
so long, the moment they
need video services, they're going
to think of you, right?
Because you, you've existed so
hard for so
long, right?
So 1% of the people are buying
right now.
Assume you have 10,000 followers
over the course
of a year, 15% of them are going
to fall within the category of
possibly needing video services in
the
future, right?
So 20, 15% of them, it's 1500
people.
1% of those people are going to
need any,
any given month.
That's 15% of people per month
that need video editing services
over a rolling
period, right?
Because you're not acquiring all
10,000 immediately.
It's a rolling period.
It's up,
up, up, up, up, up, up, up.
It just keeps going.
And it, you never hit that if you
don't exist so hard
for so long, right?
This is how this works, right?
You need to talk about longevity,
right?
You need to
be doing the same thing
consistently for so long.
It's through the persistent and
constant existence
of yourself associating with the
thing that you do, results follow,
right?
You just need to do it,
like just always, right?
You need to exert shit out into
the world.
Post on Twitter, engage.
Post on
LinkedIn, engage.
Post on YouTube when you have
audiences here, right?
Cross-post to Twitter and
LinkedIn, engage with the
comments.
Give people attention.
As much attention as is feasibly
possible,
right?
Make people like you and be who
you are hard, right?
So like you don't emulate
somebody,
you become you.
You become you intimately, right?
You might, you might like the way
I speak.
You
might like the way Sam Owens,
Russell Brunson, Alex Becker
talks.
You need to find your voice
and figure out what your voice is
and do it so hard, right?
There's no way I can kind of
describe what
that's like until you just start
doing it and you start getting
used to it.
But so I can't, I can't
actually express to you like how
important this is to, to do this,
right?
Like you need to have
something that is infinite.
And this, this is like, you think
it's so simple and you're like, it
can't
be that simple.
This is all you do.
This is literally the only fucking
thing you do.
There's,
there's no secret, but there's no
secret behind this.
This is what you do.
I did it.
I'm not some,
there's not some magic shit I did
to like grow my Twitter, but
there's no thing I did that.
It was
like, Oh, I did that.
That's it.
But if you just do that for four
months, it's fucking impossible.
You're not just having an
astronomical amount of inbound.
There's literally no way this,
this,
there's no way this doesn't work.
It's impossible.
So you guys need to do this, but
you just need to
have a sit, you need to be doing,
you need to do LinkedIn or Twitter
or both.
You need to do
one of these.
You need to have something that's
infinite, right?
Some stuff fucking around.
Like
we need some real shit here.
Comment below this and like, let
me know your thoughts on this.
Cause
like we fucking go time, baby.