So when Andre asked me to come up
and talk, I basically had two
options.
And I went with this one, give you
a dead simple system, generate 100
organic content ideas in 15
minutes.
So instead of coming up here and
saying, you know, be authentic,
share your story,
I figured let's make this
actionable, something you'll
actually put into use, so let's
get right into it.
Just a quick question so I know
who here is already creating
organic content.
What's the breakdown?
It could be Twitter, LinkedIn,
TikTok, YouTube, maybe OnlyFans, a
few of y'all.
All right, good.
So like 50-50, hopefully by the
end of this, that's everyone,
you'll be organic content
machines.
All right, quick 30 seconds on why
you should listen to me on
organic.
July 2018, I started working at
BlackRock after graduating
college.
I immediately began plotting my
escape because the 40-year-old I
sat next to asked for permission
to go to his son's Little League
game.
His boss said no.
I saw that happen and I knew my
time as a corporate worker was
limited.
Immediately got on Twitter in July
2018, started learning.
Finally made an account in July
2020 to start posting.
Built up a small audience, posting
every single day.
That let me start Ship 30, which,
as Andre was saying, is a
cohort-based writing course.
Helps people start writing online.
And then I built that on the side,
working remotely at BlackRock for
that entire year, 2021, mostly
pretending to work.
Most finance work is pretty made
up, especially when you're remote.
So I was able to scale that until
March of this year.
I left BlackRock, finally able to,
or it didn't make sense for me to
work for someone else for much
longer.
Gave Ship 30 my full attention.
Which brings us to today, sitting
280-count Twitter, we do about
300K a month between Ship 30 and
TypeShare at 90% margin.
100% organic.
So I'm pretty naive.
So I'm naive on quite a few things
on business, which is why I'm here
to learn from y'all.
But I can help you on the organic
side.
So let's get right into it.
Like I said, how to make this a
useful keynote.
Actually do the exercise.
We're going to go through three
steps.
You're going to be able to
actually generate ideas that you
can go and create right after
this.
Okay.
Let's start with the single goal
of your organic content.
Daniel, you put this perfectly
right at the very initial keynote.
All it is is to get people to
trust you.
That's it.
When you have something to sell,
people are going to come to your
profile right away and say,
is this a real person?
Do they have something useful to
put out there?
How do we get people to trust us?
This is a great quote from
Hormuzzi.
Consistently provide valuable free
shit that is better than other
people's paid shit.
If you take that to heart, you'll
win the organic content game.
But that's where most people go
wrong.
Because right away they go, but
wait, if I give away all my free
stuff, no one is going to buy my
paid stuff.
And that pulls them back because
it's like, oh, I got all this good
stuff behind a paywall.
But then they put out, you know,
non-valuable free shit, shitty
free shit, if you will.
And no one ends up buying it.
So that's the first belief to
break if you're going to win the
organic content game.
It's realizing people do not pay
for information.
They pay for accountability,
implementation, packaging, speed,
and outcomes.
So if you're sitting on valuable
paid shit, start giving it away
for free.
Because what that's going to do is
immediately generate trust with
people who will eventually buy it.
So how do we get people to trust
us?
We need ideas.
And this is the system I use to
generate my content ideas.
It's the system we teach in Ship
30.
It usually takes us an hour, so
I'm going to run through it very
quickly.
But you should be able to kind of
keep up.
It's got three parts.
First, the two-year test.
We're going to find topics to
write about.
You're going to ask yourself a
bunch of questions of all the
things you've done over the last
two years.
And then you're going to get
specific where you're the only
person on earth who's qualified to
talk about those topics.
Then you're going to find your
Scroll Stopper.
That's a one-sentence line of
credibility that you're going to
reuse hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of times to generate a
ton of content ideas based on
that.
Then you're going to run your
Scroll Stopper through the 4A
framework, which are all these
proven paths and approaches to
generate organic content.
Once you have this system, you'll
never run out of ideas.
It'll be much harder to actually
not create content than to create
content because of how many things
you have up.
And I know people who are taking
pictures, I'll distribute all
these slides after.
So you can make sure.
This will all make more sense at
the end, too.
There's a lot on one slide.
But this slide, if you have, you
can create 100 ideas in 15 minutes
or less.
All right.
Y'all ready?
Let's do it.
Part one, the topic.
Let's figure out what you're going
to create content about.
So what topic are you going to
write about, create videos,
whatever it is, or what
specifically.
The P here is specificity is a
secret.
I'm going to show you all how to
get specific.
But the very first thing is the
two-year test.
So the goal of the two-year test
is to find all of the ideas that
are now extremely obvious to you
but are incredibly valuable to
others.
And the reason it's two years is
because all the things you have
done in the last two years are now
extremely obvious to you
but would have been incredibly
valuable to have two years ago.
So you're going to brainstorm
skills you've built, struggles
you've faced, hobbies you've
picked up, problems you've
overcome,
life transitions, stories, all of
those.
That is all the raw material that
you create organic content about.
And the way to think about it is
what are all the things you know
now that you'd do anything to have
known two years ago?
That is all the raw material.
So you start with that.
You do the two-year test.
And then once you figure out those
ideas, then you're just going to
start repeating them.
So throughout this, I'm going to
use some examples from the start
of the show.
Cold email wizard.
So if you were doing this, Dan,
you could go, okay, I moved to
Miami, then moved back to Tampa,
learned cold email,
grew to 100 count Twitter, started
a YouTube channel, right, started
a group coaching business,
scaled an input product to a
million dollars a year.
These are all things you could
write about.
Potentially my favorite, though,
most importantly, scaled and
optimized, a high-converting hinge
funnel.
I think if you made a YouTube
video on that or gave a keynote on
it, I think we'd all be taking a
lot of notes.
So just some content ideas for
you.
So this would be Daniel's, right?
He's got a bunch of broad topics
he could write about, and that's
number one.
So everyone sitting here has a ton
of unique experiences that they
could generate ideas about, and
that's where you start with.
So part two, adding specificity.
This is the most important part
and where most people go wrong.
So what you have to do from here
is generate three to four broad
topics like we talked about,
but now you're going to add
specificity until you are the only
person on earth qualified to talk
about that thing.
How do you do that?
Well, this is where most people go
wrong.
So I'm going to use Daniel's
example of scaling an info product
to a million bucks a year.
There's a big, as, you know, we're
inundated with this, but that's a
broad topic, right?
No specificity, tons of
competition, plenty of people have
done this.
So if you just came out and said,
hey, I did this, there's going to
be a lot of competition.
So what you have to do is get
specific.
How do you do that?
Seven specificity levers.
Price, problem, industry,
location, situation, experience,
and demographic.
You've dialed those up and down
until you were the only person on
earth who's done this.
So some examples.
Seven ways to niche down.
I'm going to take the same $1
million a year product idea or
product scaling and run it through
each of them.
And what you'll see here is each
of these, how the content changes
based on that one little
differentiator, right?
One word completely changes the
type of content you would create
based on.
So niche down by price.
A $299 product versus $4,000.
Much different.
The tactics, everything you would
share would be much different.
The type of person you would
attract would be much different.
My problem, so a cold email
product or an organic content
product, way different.
And this is also, if you're
creating a business yourself, you
can think about doing these
things.
You can apply this seven ways to
niche down where you specify your
offer so it differentiates
yourself.
Industry.
So B2B SaaS, small group fitness.
Location.
LA film agency or New York City
restaurant, right?
Situation.
For personal trainers or recently
laid off employees.
Experience.
Beginner versus a 10-year veteran
cold email product.
Again, much, much different.
And then lastly, demographics.
So for Gen Z entrepreneurs or for
up-and-coming money Twitter
hustlers, which is exactly what
Daniel did again.
So you can dial all of these up
and down until you take your broad
topics and you get extremely
specific with them.
So back to Daniel's example.
Scaling an info product to a
million dollars a year.
Not very specific.
Scaling a beginner cold email
video info product for
up-and-coming money Twitter
hustlers on gumroad
to a million dollars a year using
only organic content in just 12
months.
Right?
You're the only person on Earth
who has done it.
Which means every single thing you
have to say about that will be
100% unique.
No one will compare you to anyone.
You're going to actually generate
true fans where, like you said,
people buy from you.
They don't buy that thing.
That make sense so far?
You guys with me?
Cool.
All right.
So by now, you should have three
to five kind of topics, right?
Things that are ruining your head
a little bit.
All right.
Deep breath.
Because I know that was a lot.
That's part one.
Part one.
Now you have ideas to write about.
What do we do from here?
Now you need to find your scroll
stopper.
This one's simple.
You need a one-sentence line of
credibility for why people should
trust you that you're going to
reuse it time and time and time
and time again.
And everything you have to say
after that is going to be, okay, I
trust you.
You can go in 100 different
directions.
If you need a template for this,
extremely easy.
But once you have one, you can
reuse it.
So over the last X time period, I
achieved X outcome without common
obstacle to achieving X outcome.
Every person in this room can make
up a scroll stopper based on their
topic with that exact one.
And right away, once you have
that, everything you create after
it is going to resonate with that
reader who says, oh, I'm
interested in that.
Or I can trust you on that.
Now I'll listen to what you have
to say.
So again, for Daniel, I actually
went and wrote these tweets.
I made a cold email whiz account.
I'm surprised it wasn't taken.
So over the last 12 months, I
scaled my cold email info product
to a million dollars per year
without spending a cent on paid
ads.
100% organic.
You could see that if that was the
intro to any Twitter thread, what
he could put after that would be
valuable.
People are going to listen because
they're going to go, oh, shit.
You could write almost anything
after that.
Same with this.
I built a group coaching biz from
zero to 300K in three months
without taking my margins below
75%.
Enter just about anything.
I started three SaaS companies,
scaled them to 50K a month in six
months without a single full-time
employee.
You have these lines, and then you
can drop anything underneath, and
people are going to need it.
And then my personal favorite, my
Hinch profile brings me 25
qualified leads per day with a 50%
close rate,
and my clients are submitting rate
testimonials.
Right?
True?
I think that close rate's a little
low.
I almost bumped it up.
I almost bumped it to 90, but I
was like, okay, let's be real.
Let's do it.
All right, so with that, right,
you can say just about anything on
that topic, and people are going
to read it.
So that's your scroll stopper.
Scroll stopper makes sense.
So we've got topic, we've got
scroll stopper.
Part three, we're flying through
this.
The 4A framework.
So now you're going to take that
scroll stopper and squeeze as much
juice out of it as you possibly
can.
How do you do that?
The 4A framework.
The 4A framework says there's only
four types of content.
Actionable content, analytical
content.
So actionable is here's how.
Analytical is here's a breakdown.
Aspirational is yes, you can, like
sharing your story.
Anthropological is human nature,
the why.
And so all of these are, every
piece of content falls into one of
these four buckets.
An example to drive this home.
Anyone here read personal finance
books?
Right?
This is Money Twitter.
We all do.
Right?
Can you name a couple?
What are the couple that come to
mind?
Rich, dad, more dad.
Who said one?
Right?
Okay.
So what's cool about personal
finance is a big, big, broad
topic.
But within that, once you see the
4A buckets, you're never going to
look at content the same
again.
Because we have Ramit Sethi, who's
built an entire career around
actionable content.
His book is I Will Teach You to Be
Rich.
If you've read that, it's
literally got scripts to negotiate
with your cable company or your
airline.
Like, straight up actionable.
And you have Ray Dalio, right?
I studied a thousand economies for
thousands of years, and I put it
all together into this
breakdown.
So this is extremely innovative.
And you have aspirational.
Rich, dad, poor dad.
Right?
If you came from a poor money
background, then here's how to get
over it.
Here's my story.
You read that, you resonate with
it, or you don't.
And then lastly, psychology money.
Anthropological, totally human
nature, right?
The water.
Here's one big, broad topic,
money, with four examples.
And so as you take your scroll
stopper, you can dig and go up and
down all of these and
say, I want to share actionable,
analytical, aspirational, or
anthropological.
So, some examples.
Actionable content, this is how
to.
Anything like tips, tools, hacks,
advice, resources, frameworks,
ultimate guides.
Let the reader go from point A to
point B, and you're going to show
them how to get there.
Some examples.
And so, how I'm going to show you
with this is taking your scroll
stopper, your single
line of credibility, and combining
it with the 4A framework.
Because once you have it, you can
reuse it in infinite number of
ways, right?
So, here's Danny.
Over the last 12 months, scaled my
cold email to a million bucks per
year without a cent on
paid ads.
Here's six software tools that
made it easy.
Or, here are three tips if you're
stuck at 10K a month.
Or, here are three resources to
help you do the same.
Or, here's the four-step system
you can follow to scale your info
front.
Right?
Any single thing actionable, he
could follow up his scroll stopper
with, just like that.
You can do that time and time and
time again, especially when you
find one that works.
Which of this one would work very
well?
I mean, it's YouTube videos, it's
LinkedIn, it's everything.
You can use it just like that.
Right?
So, that's actionable.
Then there's analytical.
These are breakdowns.
Think of examples, things of doing
research.
Anything, you save the reader a
lot of time and say, hey, I looked
at a thousand different
landing pages.
Here's what's working.
Trends, numbers, reasons, swipe
files, examples.
Helps your reader see a new way of
thinking.
Or, watch her.
This is usually written content,
but it can be anything.
So, some more examples.
I started three SaaS companies,
scaled them at 50K a month in six
months.
Here's a slide-by-slide teardown
of the funnel.
Or, here's a breakdown of each
landing page and why they convert.
Or, here's the exact numbers we do
each month and where we're going
from here.
Or, here's what I think B2B SaaS
is heading in the future.
So, these are analytical, looking
at trends of where things are
going or breakdowns of why
things are working.
Third, anthropological.
We're flying here.
These are anything to do with
human nature.
So, it digs a level deeper.
It's a why.
It's a psychology.
So, fears, failures, struggles,
paradoxes, comparisons, red pills,
right?
Why others are wrong.
Why you've been misled.
Anything to do with the human
nature that says, okay, maybe
here's how to do something.
Let's dig a level deeper and look
at here's why.
So, even more examples.
I built a group coaching biz from
zero to 300K in six months.
Here are four brutal mistakes that
almost cost me everything.
Or, here are three beliefs I had a
break to get to.
Here's why everyone else struggles
to keep their margins high.
Or, here are three observations
that surprise me, right?
This is all human nature, the
psychology of it.
And, I think this is one of the
most interesting content buckets
you can have because everyone
has a unique understanding of why
things are working for them.
If you can help a reader or viewer
understand that, you're going to
really develop a deep
relationship.
Lastly, on the four A's,
aspirational.
So, this is anything sharing your
story.
Every single person here can share
their story.
That's the easiest one to do.
Whatever your two-year test was
for the journey you took over the
last two years, you can share
them.
So, these are stories, lessons
from stage reflections, underrated
traits, advice to your past
seller.
My favorite, here.
If you were sharing, how do you
scale and optimize your hinge
profile?
Here's what my clients have to
say.
So, you're sharing testimonials.
I'd like to read that one.
Here's how you can create a funnel
like this, too.
Here's my story.
Or, here's what I had to change to
make this happen.
So, this is all just sharing your
story and giving someone a resume.
All right.
That was the entire NLS idea
generator.
That was a lot.
We usually take about an hour for
that.
So, let's do a quick recap.
The goal of this keynote, I said,
give you a system to generate 100
ideas.
I hope the ideas are flowing, that
you can go and put this into
practice right away.
Hopefully, you were doing it while
we were going.
The single goal of your organic
content, get people to trust you.
That's it.
How do you get people to trust
you?
Consistently provide valuable free
share that is better than everyone
else's page.
If you do that, you will win the
organic content game.
We'll stop.
Started with the topic.
What are you going to write about?
How are you going to be specific
with it?
We did the two-year test.
Look back on your last two years.
Every person in this room has
unique things they can talk about
over the last two years that
they've learned.
You just have to get comfortable
sharing those things.
Seven ways to niche down.
One, I love this slide.
I think this slide applies far
more than just content, but
business as well.
Then you create your scroll
stopper.
Use this template.
Over the last X time period, I
achieved X outcome without common
obstacles.
You have that.
You have infinite number of
organic content ideas.
Then you look at the 4A paths.
Hopefully, you start to look at
content in a new way,
which is every single thing you
read or come across is one of
these buckets.
What's the type of content that
you resonate with?
your reader is resonating with?
Then I showed you this example to
drive it home with four different
4A buckets.
There it is all in one slide
again.
If you download that slide, take
it home, print it out, do this
exercise.
And if you take 15 minutes, it's
going to be very hard not to
create organic content from there.
So, boom.
Any questions?
Let's do it.
I have one thing.
I have one thing to sell you.
Unlike or mostly.
If you want these frameworks, go
to startwritingonline.com.
It's our free 13,000 word ultimate
guide.
And also, we have a SaaS product
called TypeShare that will have a
lot of these templatized.
Use code Ascension, free lifetime
pro for everyone who wants to sell
it.
Wow.
Thank you.