Full shot uh amir nice what's up
dave you got an iphone yeah nice
iphone nice to meet your iphone
very very creative very creative
bro the iPhones are like
apparently dying like this whole
uh
open ai johnnyives collab right oh
yeah yeah it's all that i'm
calling it now it's going to
be new glasses i'm telling you
it's going to be new fucking smart
glasses i'm calling it right now
10 bet it's going to be new new
meta version raybox that's
basically what it's going to be
wait wait wait what do you mean
iphone is dying who said that what
do you mean i was doing a
partnership with sam all in an
open ai so andre andre 10 bet
right now it's the glasses he's
wearing in the announcement video
it's the glasses jones wearing i
don't know this but this is my gut
instinct i'm convinced video would
actually be like the coolest
product announcement ever
because it was like way before it
was planted exactly hey so open ai
bought johnnyives company
for 6.5 billion dollars and it
hasn't even launched yet what the
fuck because he wore the glasses
that
are like the fucking tony stark
ones from avengers and they were
like oh shit the fire so that's
that's
holy shit i'm calling it i'm
calling it dude you know the great
for johnnyives by the way
like his his story is actually
insane he's like a pure creative
sorry i'll shut up in a minute
because no it's okay i love this
shit bro johnnyives is like a pure
creative right so when he was
early on in his career he was
getting recruited by microsoft and
apple and pretty much the deciding
factor was that microsoft denied
his request to have a shower in
his office and apple steve jobs
said
he could have it and the reason he
wanted a shower in his office is
because he'd get his ideas in the
shower so steve jobs was like i
get it and i i love that and so
i'm gonna honor your request and
we're gonna put a shower in your
office and so yeah i fucking love
that because that's so true the
best
ideas come literally in the shower
or while you're in the bathroom
oh man nice to see you guys what's
up dave what's up jp everyone what
is going on we have 39 people
here already i say some more are
going to come in throughout the
call uh thank you everyone for
coming along and thank you to naz
and aminat here for uh for joining
the call today uh naz is one of
the co-founders of poppy ai i'm
not just the head of partnership
over there and they are if any of
you have been to my ai calls you
know that i have not stopped
talking about poppy ai i'm just
saying the useful it is uh you
guys might have seen also my case
study interview with naz and
aminat on um uh their their own
channel and i think you guys put
me in like every ad you have uh
but
it has been um yeah it has been uh
it's been great it's been a great
good use the tool just getting
also to to kind of hang out with
naz and i'm gonna talk a bit more
about the products and see what
these guys are working on and uh
it is getting uh in insanely cool
what you guys are coming down the
pipeline sha just asked me
probably they can be due two hours
instead of one this is awesome uh
unfortunately i think the boys
can't but uh yeah let's get into
it though so i think today the
guys
are going to be running through
basically their kind of content
creation strategy uh using ai how
to
actually get kind of good content
out of ai tools and how to use
poppy to do that now this call is
also
going to be valuable for those of
you who don't have poppy because
naz showed me a little bit what
they're going to show and he will
be going through using tools like
claude as well as kind of going
into poppy and also giving you
guys the backstory on how they
found a poppy what the story is
there
and uh so i think it's going to be
super super interesting so naz i'm
going to spotlight you
now and feel free to take it away
thank you and can you also
spotlight amana as well
he he's my right hand man awesome
awesome thank you so much lucas
i'm really really happy to be here
and to be chatting to some amazing
people and uh in this i guess
workshop such call by the way just
really quickly uh i would love to
see you guys like one um uh in the
chat cameras on oh that's
like huge i love to see
everybody's cameras that will be a
fucking amazing so happy i love to
see
beautiful faces uh second thing
guys can you guys please put in
the chat where you guys are from
and
what do you guys do like what i
know a lot of you guys have
agencies and so forth i would love
to kind
of get to know the room more so in
terms of what the room does and
you know um yeah that would be
amazing so just where you guys are
from and what do you guys do
awesome shaw cold email
legion company amazing canada cold
email nice michigan chicago who's
that from michigan where
wait wait wait yo let's go
michigan i i love michigan i live
in michigan not right now but uh
my
parents i'm ukrainian but i've
been living in michigan for like
you know big part of my life a
bigger
bigger part of my life oh there's
another guy dude oh that's sick
michiganers let go some some of
the
nicest people i will say not that
everybody else is not nice but
like i will say the nicest people
uh and narbor yes oh sweet i am
from royal oak uh is it silly
killing i'm going okay i'm going
i'm
going ukrainian next month he's
married to ukrainian no wait
really yeah what do you guys got
him yeah
bro i'm let's see married now
about a month and a bit she's from
okay if i don't find kiev's region
dude i know if i don't think it's
oh my uncle lives there what the
that's insane
it's small world small world such
small world i've never i've never
seen some a group of guys get so
excited about where people are
from this is the most high energy
call we've had in ages
the most exciting thing no way
michigan holy
i mean it's amazing you know like
a small world
awesome new york city amazing
thank you guys uh super excited so
uh i'm just gonna preface really
quickly the goal for on this call
is to kind of give you some ideas
about using after content creation
we ourselves are content creator
uh content creators i'll go over
kind of how um and then after
after showing you guys how this
content creation isn't with claude
and just ai in general i want to
go
through a tool that we built and
that lucas uses um to make content
but not just content to write
landing
page copy to make sales scripts to
pretty much to write newsletters
emails called emails pretty much
anything uh and i'll go over that
later on um in the future if you
guys allow me to if you got like
yeah let's fucking see it if
you're like no fuck this guy
that's fine too either way is fine
um but at
this point i'm just gonna go ahead
and screen share my screen screen
share my screen and go from there
cool awesome you guys see my
screen oh no don't get to the good
parts hold on there we go all
right yeah
can you see it yes good you can
indeed all good all right let me
put in the chat up in here too so
i
can see you guys chatting and
answering questions but i'm gonna
have a slideshow slides didn't
work
the last episode i don't know why
but hopefully this time will work
yeah slideshow works yeah all
right
sweet so leverage ai as content
creators guys as a content creator
agency owner founder you name it
pretty much
but uh who i'm up my name is naz i
am co-founder of poppy ai right
here that says it right there
that's how
you know i'm a co-founder um but
uh pretty much uh together with
clever programmer together with
kazi
um and we co-founded poppy about a
year ago before that i was a
developer for about 15 years
like software developer i worked
in multiple startup companies
multiple enterprise companies
then i worked with kazi to grow
his youtube channel from literally
200k to a million subscribers let
me go ahead
and uh there we go to my
subscribers and we're basically we
taught hundreds of thousands of
people to code we literally took
waiters to to coders so we turned
um you know drivers truck drivers
to
developers you name it anybody and
we taught them how to code we
built we built literally like look
at
these like humongous videos 11
hours seven hours and we teach
them how to become developers then
we also
launched the boot camp and overall
throughout the time frame is there
it is here i am as well
with that beautiful face uh we did
about 5.2 million in revenue um
through cover programmer and we
also
did any new workshops in person
and that was super sick i would
love to even show you a workshop
that we
did um where we just play that
video where you were dancing uh
yeah yeah i'll i'll play that
later on
in a second here but yeah so we
did workshops just for fun as well
and we taught people how to code
overall fun time um and then
here's amonov and then who am i
i'm amonov and i'm the head of
partnerships
at poppy uh i've been working with
the guys for the last five years i
was part of the program as well
um great content and then yeah now
let's go to the next slide so yeah
i mean he i mean he downplays
himself but he pretty much helped
us grow to 1 million subscribers
as well and pretty much did
all the operations he is a genius
at e at the newsletters he's a
genius in copywriting um he's
the reason why one big reason why
we made 5.2 million dollars at
clever programmer so uh cold
emails uh
emails in general he is amazing at
that here's there you go i also
make content um yeah by mistake
one of my videos just blew up on a
brand new channel that made me
like oh shit i'm a content
creator now but there you go i
make videos too um yeah and with
clear pro not clear programmers
poppy
oh oh oh what's up what's up sasha
um um but yeah um i make content i
help with partnerships you know
uh we got almost like all the
biggest creators on poppy at this
point we got ali abdahl we got pat
flynn
um and you know that's kind of my
magic where i do cold emails i
reach out to these guys
and make that magic happen amazing
and he does all a lot of this
outreach stuff also with poppy ai
by
the way as well and that kind of
helps but not just poppy ai in
general so again clod chat gpt uh
probably most likely clod to have
made have this happen and then
poppy is basically the tool that
we use
uh that we built about a year ago
and the reason we built it and
this is i kind of want to give you
a
a little bit of background is
because i don't know about you but
i hate using chat gpt and i hate
using clod the reason why it feels
like 1980s it feels like using
samsung and i hate samsung and
i'm sorry for those of you guys
who love samsung i hate it i'm an
iphone guy and i love how simple
it is and how easy it is to use
okay um on the side of poppy we
built it because we want to make
it very easy to create things like
in chat gpt you throw different
things on the board or you throw
the
thing into the chat and it's like
just a chat back and forth you
don't know when where any of your
content is you don't know where
any of your documents are you have
some chats good luck trying to
search
within these chats it's impossible
good luck trying to brainstorm
trying to copyright real difficult
we're
like hey how can we do in a way
where i could just have this big
visual whiteboard and i could just
throw anything i want youtube
videos instagram tiktoks mp4 mp4
content with audio recordings and
then use
the eye now skip these slides so
they can see the ui oh yeah it's
kind of like this i'll just show
you
here okay kind of like this
basically i can throw anything i
want into it and then it's like if
miro
i don't know has anybody here use
miro by any chance i would love to
know in the chat
does anybody here use miro um it's
like a miro yes amber's like yes
it's like a miro oh actually
a lot of people use miro oh
amazing oh they if you guys love
miro you guys would love something
like
this i'm not going to sell you on
it if you don't buy it that's okay
i don't care um
but like yeah it's like miro and
chat gpt and they had a baby and
they injected with steroids
that's what we call it um but yeah
and then over the previous couple
of you know of the previous
months and 30 90 days so we did
about 1.3 million views on
instagram and our editor uses
poppy a lot
um to actually make the content to
brainstorm to make the story etc
so here's some examples of our
content actually amal can you show
some of the content i think you're
fine show us the day one or
day two i'll build an ass that'd
be awesome let's see yeah i'm
gonna show you really quickly
actually
let me see if i can pull one up
real quick
oh man all right let's see one
once you're ready you got it good
i got it you got it
share screen audio there we go all
right this is day one guys day one
yo this is day one of building
an ass ass to one million a month
dude i got a epic idea what's up
bro i think we should take our
whole thing to thailand bro bro
that would be sick right guess
what we did it
we literally packed up the whole
poppy team and moved them to this
ridiculous mansion in thailand
literally this is me coding on the
pool like what the but anyways
right now we're at two hundred
thousand dollars this month and we
still got two weeks left and today
we got this weird not found
error that's driving us insane at
first we thought it was just a few
users but now we got like 22 users
hitting us up about it so after
digging through the code for hours
coppy finally figured out
we found that it might be this
barometrics thing we just added
turns out barometrics was messing
with our dom components literally
removing
shit it wasn't supposed to we
removed that part and boom problem
solved so this is day one in
thailand
if you want to see if we can
actually hit a million follow for
day two yo let's go
so that's a little bit kind of
about how we do it thank you thank
you jacob thank you
yeah we do these videos um like
almost on a daily basis literally
our editor is like right here
this is our editor his name is
nico uh say hi hi nico uh
uh he he uses ai constantly was
the editor probably no it was not
editor poppy we're not that we're
not that cool yet maybe in the
future that'd be awesome
i think if you throw the editor
poppy but but the entire script
for that story so um whoa you're
sharing
slack nose i know i know i know
don't worry where did it go where
did my google ah there we go
yeah exactly there you go go back
one no no no yes so there you go
that board is basically like
our storyline creator so basically
what our editor does is like he
puts together all the footage
inside
and then says hey this is what
happened on day on this specific
day put together the entire script
and
then poppy spits out the entire
script of like there's a these are
the stuff that you need to talk
about and like the voiceovers and
everything yeah but we're not here
to talk about pipe it fully i want
to talk about actually ai and how
to use the after content creation
sorry sorry to interrupt i think
if you could actually count you
know where people have that exact
callaway youtube video on their
board
it'd be like it's on every single
one of mine yeah oh yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah exactly exactly it's
that
one there's one more and then
there's one more uh by what's his
name brian or something brian um
um oh uh yeah the the script
writing guy exactly exactly
exactly so they all have that one
oh yeah super cool so um anyways
really quickly i'm actually really
curious about out of you guys how
many of you guys currently use
like chat gpt or chat gpt or ai in
general for yep a ton amazing so
we
do have quite a lot and if you
don't just say no just say no
every day beautiful this yes yes
yes
yes evan awesome i'm here every
day nick yes uh every day
perplexed gemini deep seek amazing
okay
using it right now sweet yeah
michael is now watching the
webinar uh this call
sweet so yeah so basically ai of
course as you guys know it's huge
everybody is using ai for content
creation for helping you make a
copy for emails etc um i mean
literally youtube um channels
faces channels
literally dedicated to just using
ai and for example this one is
like where the guy is not
even a full-on guy it's just an ai
face it's just an ai hey gen video
and with the script generated by
ai
and the audio generated by ai and
everything so nowadays it's pretty
crazy what can be possible
um the biggest thing that we find
helpful for us at least and i'm
sure for you guys too is
for one it's amazing for
brainstorming ideas that's amazing
it's amazing or at least on our
side we'll
learn how to write amazing scripts
i don't know about you guys but
it's also really amazing i know as
a
winning content and this is
something that a lot of people i
feel like don't do uh they don't
maybe have
the capacity to do that it's like
one of the biggest use cases of
the overall that i think is missed
out on
it's amazing and making great
content if you prompt it right and
if you use it right that's
the key factor here so the thing
is you write a script usually for
for content it takes you five
hours or whatever you write it
with ai it's gonna take you 30
minutes and this could be for
emails this
could be for lindy be lindy peach
copy you name it perfect so chgpt
everybody knows about chgpt
however
what we have found and this is
something as content creators
found and you know a lot of our
content
creators do this is we actually
don't use chgpt so much uh what's
actually better for copying
overall
is clod this is the one big thing
that i feel like a lot of people
don't know so i'm really curious
actually how many of you guys use
chgpt how many of you guys use
clod in the chat
i'm really curious so i'd love to
see that um both both both both
okay so plot both okay
chgpt so nick if you're doing
chgpt try to use clod i'll show
you what i mean in a second here
clod overall has been rated by
many script writers and marketers
to be a lot more how do i say this
human there's not this bullshit
like greetings my friends you know
welcome to pop ai you know it's
actually like a much more human
like experience so the next thing
i want to talk about is prompting
and
this is what will actually get you
to get um a to make a good script
email landing page anything
and this is it prompting is a lot
of people think like oh here's
there's a key prompt that you have
to actually make and there's this
magical formula there's no magic
behind it you just have to speak
like a normal human being for the
love of god um instead talk to ai
like it's a five-year-old and
this is huge guys how do i like
it's a five-year-old what do i
mean with that when you talk to a
kid
what do you say you don't say hey
you're you've got 10 years of
experience in script writing you
need to
give me the full hook you need to
give me the full cta give me the
full script make sure it
approaches
this make sure that this make sure
does this good luck trying to get
a good uh script out or something
that's valuable enough right so
what i've done instead is i've
created something called a simple
framework simple prompting
framework because why i feel like
it's simple um so what does it
stand for
simple is for just use simple
language two instructions one at a
time one at a time
instructions three mark it define
who the script is for because
again our goal here is to teach
you how
to make content patterns always
teach it good patterns because for
example overall ai is amazing in
knowing a lot of different things
however however um ai doesn't know
a specific way of how to make
content it doesn't know
specifically how to sound like you
and so by giving it a way like
here's what
good looks like here's what a good
email looks like here's what a
good script looks like this is
some
some said the simp way yeah that's
funny so here's what a good video
looks like it will learn that to
be
and take and take that to be a lot
of your priority compared to just
you know uh using its general
knowledge on script writing so
this is huge amanda you guys see
something no okay great language
and
tone of voice define your tone of
voice this is huge and i'll go
over all these different all these
different things in a second here
and define any external resources
that the ai might use to make
the script or the copy better okay
so one simple language what do i
mean by that um here it is
first a lot of people might do
this i don't know has any any of
you guys have done this for your
defining you say hey you're a
professional script writer 10
years of experience and content
creation i need to do this yes
exactly like okay what does it
fucking mean to have 10 years of
experience defined for me the
difference between 10 years eight
years nine years seven years
experience
what is the difference here like
if i'm talking to you as a person
right like it does not matter
honestly what more so matters
because ai by default has all the
experience it knows the content it
knows
how to write all you have to do is
just talk to it so here's a for
example you know what i call a bad
prompt and here's a result you
might get with a bad prompt um for
example here your professional
script writer with 10 years
experience and content creation
write a script about five
productivity hacks for
content creators great so then you
might get something like this does
this sound familiar it's
2 p.m you've been working all day
but somehow you're you're you've
only finished half a blog post and
responded to three comments okay
not too bad sounds okay right
however here's what my good good
problem might sound like a good
problem might be like write a
script about five productivity
hacks for
content creators done like it's a
simple guys just and then the
result with that becomes well here
it
is write a script about five
productivity hacks for content
creators and this is the result we
get
are you spending more time
managing your content that
actually created if you're
drowning in endless
to-do lists struggling to stay
consistent or feeling like there
aren't enough hours in the day
this
video is for you it's about a it's
about to shoot i'm about to share
five game changing productivity
hacks that will transform how you
create content these aren't
generic tips you've heard a
million
times these are specific
strategies i've tested and the
successful creators swear by which
one is better
like just from the sound of it
this already sounds better it got
me hooked a lot more so why
because
i just use very simple language
and there's no need to over
complicate it okay so hopefully so
far
that makes sense any questions so
far guys are we all good yes so
far good great and one more thing
i'll add to that is like there's
one of the reasons why we also go
away from the hey do you like
think
like you have a 10 year experience
script writer is like not say what
does it mean but also here's the
thing you could be a shitty
copywriter or a shitty script
writer with 10 years of experience
or you
could be a complete god with just
two years of experience so it
doesn't actually really add a lot
of value to the prompt what
instead you could do is like say
hey use this copywriting framework
or use
this specific script writing
framework that actually adds more
value to the prompt than like oh
do it
with like 10 years of experience
yeah good and they just use the
knowledge it has anyways yeah
great
next one step two instructions one
at a time what i mean with that is
if you try to be like hey create
for me a full script with a five
with an attention grabbing hook
five productivity hacks examples
anecdotes call to action etc it
might give you okay results but
it's not going to give you amazing
results instead if you talk to it
the one thing at a time so for
example if i'm like lucas for
example
hey can you give me the structure
for the presentation of what we
need to cover in the workshop
right
she versus like hey lucas give me
the full presentation we need to
do right a structure might be a
lot
easier to start with but once we
get the structure we can go deeper
into the actual
structure and make the
presentation make sense so same
thing goes for cold email same
thing goes for
making content right give the
structure for the content first
and then from there we can go
about
making the actual script so for
example a good problem i sound
like stop recruiting a simple
outline
with an intro five main points and
a conclusion i get the structure
first and then i get the script
after make sense awesome step
three specify the market who are
you targeting so a lot of you guys
they
have you have a specific target
market you guys are talking to
right um this might be you know
other
agencies other content creators
might be someone who is a younger
more more beginner or someone who
is
more advanced depending on that
you can specify your prompt so if
you say something like make a
script
that will resonate with my
audience you might specify
something like this this is for a
seven
minute youtube video targeting new
content creators who are
struggling with time management
while working full-time
jobs okay so i'm defining who it's
for and then the ai will will a
lot better understand how what's
up
oh sorry because he just like
literally walked out they will
understand how to better uh you
know uh
what kind of work is to use
because for simple for categories
for beginners it will use words
that are a
lot you know easier or simpler to
understand for someone who's more
advanced it will use more advanced
uh
wordage or words i guess you could
say that's step three step four
hadn't show what good looks like
and i think this is honestly the
biggest way to get good scripts
and good emails landing page copy
overall
is actually tell it what a good
framework is actually give it okay
here's maybe lucas framework for
making a good landing page copy
here is for example a you know ali
abdahl's framework for making a
good script
right it will be able to actually
understand it a lot more than just
just a generic generic way of hey
let me just make some right some
kind of a script so start doing
this just like this here are
examples of
amazing hooks and scripts from
creators i love model the
structure and then you just define
them you define what
those look like okay um and then
it will also a good thing about
this is like ai itself is trained
on
examples right like ai itself is
like identify dogs and they feed
like hundreds of thousands of
images
and that's how ai gets trained is
like based on examples so if you
want good output instead of just
like
you know giving generic stuff say
hey here's five really good
scripts or here's like five really
good hooks from videos that i like
what are the good things about
this hook take that and model it
for
my video exactly exactly sha asked
the question says do you feed
pattern for supervised learning
map
inputs to outputs and provide
reasoning no i do not i do not
provide any reasoning whatsoever
um
all i do is i say here are
examples of great hooks and
scripts i love that's it i keep it
stupid
simple the kiss method um and from
there a guy will figure it out on
its own honestly it will do a good
enough job just from providing
good scripts lucas will lucas
probably knows this because he
uses popular
time and he will like where you
can bring in all these different
types of content you just provide
a
different content you say that
it's good you say what you like
and then from there it's able to
actually
you know understand it a lot
better just like for example if
you go to your mom and your mom is
like and
you're like hey mom can you can
you i love this casserole can you
make sure you make me this
consistently she'll make you more
casserole
there you go um awesome step five
language and tone of voice this is
i love to define this as well
if you want to sound a little bit
different or if you want to sound
more like you and don't want to
sound like ai or chat tpt define
your tone of voice okay instead of
saying hey use engaging style of
writing use energetic style of
writing to try and understand what
your voice sounds like have the ai
define what your voice sounds like
so what i mean by that is say this
please use my voice of tone and
words
and give it examples of the actual
words and scripts and videos that
you've done so what that might
look
like is you upload a script that
maybe you have done you upload an
email that you have done yourself
um you upload i'm i don't know
what else you upload a newsletter
maybe you've you've written right
maybe a text message you wrote you
wrote to a girl i don't know
anything right so you upload that
and
ai will learn from there as well
and i don't need to give my
reasoning i don't need to specify
anything
i just let the ai do the work for
me that's why examples and what
good looks like are so so so huge
and finally six um that's an
optional one external knowledge so
any external knowledge that will
be
helpful for example instead of
saying something like talk about
waking up early morning and
filling multiple videos at once i
might say something like use
content about productivity hacks i
provide it as a knowledge feel
free to talk about filming
multiple videos at once so give it
any
type of data that you feel it
could be helpful right and so a
lot of times i'll feed it maybe
data
from different websites i might
feed the data from different
youtube videos and it will use
that
knowledge to make new content for
me and that's also super crucial
as well and so that is what i call
the simple framework guys um now
but before we go and i show you
kind of how i do this with claude
are
there any questions so far are we
all understood i'm really curious
any questions so far no guys can
unmute or you can post in chat oh
post and chat what any questions
yes he said the questions oh okay
okay okay okay yeah okay but if i
was good okay if i was good we'll
just continue on okay so let me go
ahead and move on to using cloud
for this and i can we can also
give you guys this framework that
we have
built um as well and this should
be helpful to you as well um so
i'll go here all right so this is
cloud everybody knows cloud yes or
some people do know cloud um a lot
has something called cloud
projects
which is right here okay right
here on the left side you go to
here and when you make a new
project you can
define something called a project
knowledge and we're going to find
the knowledge so some someone
say do you do six different
prompts of all six in one ah so
great questions shaw said do you
do six
different prompts of all six and
one i actually do this one prompt
as the whole prompt so that simple
method
is going to be as one whole prompt
but sometimes i do also define the
voice of tone separately so let
me show you and you'll understand
what i'm talking about okay so in
terms of for example providing
external knowledge the voice of
tone providing it you know um a
framework for building something i
to
cloud give this right here so here
we have this thing called the
ultimate video um ultimate youtube
video
framework i have uh this something
called the ultimate youtube title
writing framework and
i will send you guys these as well
so you guys can use for yourselves
yeah i've already linked them
in the chat amazing the ultimate
youtube thumbnail creation
framework and the ultimate youtube
script
writing framework and we actually
made this using poppy as well to
to build this remember how i
talked
about the simple method provide
examples of what good looks like
this is what good looks like and
so we
provided examples of what good
actually looks like first then i
provided the voice of tone so all
i did
when i'm going to come to my voice
of tone right here i did something
very simple i just went to a
youtube
video i had which was this one
okay i got a transcript for this
youtube video using like a simple
youtube
transcript generator you can get
anywhere there's a ton of them out
there just type in youtube
transcript generator
then from there i copied this put
it into cloud hit plus like here
add text as content and say my
voice of tone
okay and that is it and i just hit
add content and then that's it
that's how i got this right here
okay
and then these ones this is my
external knowledge because i want
to create a piece of content on
you know content uh
hacks for content creators
productivity has got the creators
i provided other external
knowledge from
other videos so this is a video
from ali abdahl on five
productivity hacks for to create
more content
and actually actually no this one
is from ali abdahl the best
productivity hacks for of all time
from ali
abdahl and this is a different
video that i got which i think
it's this one yeah this one right
here
five particularly hacks to create
more content and i just got it
from him the goal here is to model
not to
copy but just to model to model
the structure to model what they
talk about etc because at the end
of
the day all ideas come from
somewhere and so we want to kind
of see okay what is the structure
that made
them go viral or made their video
good or made their email good and
again all this stuff can be
applied
not just to content creation but
to emails and newsletters right
what is the reason why this email
is so good
what is the structure of that you
can put all that into ai and say
hey this is a good email so if i
were you i would actually specify
this i'll be like hey add contents
add text content and i'll be like
amazing email to model right and i
just put that email inside here or
maybe that that might be your own
email or someone else's email um
that you might get for example and
that's it once i got all these
boldies like one what is it one
two three four five six seven
eight things i go into i might
just start
making the content so the first
thing i do and a shot asked me
this question like you know what
does the
process usually take to actually
um write it and the process is i
want to define my voice of tone
first so what do i do is i say hey
based on my tone of voice which is
the the text i provided how do i
speak and what is my voice of tone
and then once i have this i always
provide it to the ai the ai
will that itself understand the
content and will tell me how i
speak so it will tell me something
like
i'm very straightforward and
action-oriented i'm very
conversational and engaging value
focused
authority by approach and they
will tell it will learn what kind
of words i use at the same time
right so i will define that to the
ai first that's step one okay and
then once i got that let's do
let's use a simple framework to
actually make the piece of content
right simple framework simple
language i want to create a script
for youtube for five productivity
hacks for creators very simple
market who are we doing it for my
goal is to help for help creators
who have a full-time job
and don't have the time to create
content we define the market i
want to talk about the uh the one
take wonder fill the video in one
go just continue to talk to camera
don't stop i just gave it some
external context like external
knowledge right um general
knowledge about like what are some
things uh
to talk about okay next use the
frameworks or for writing a script
where is this coming from i give
it
the i give it the framework which
came from here right the ultimate
script writing framework
that is what good looks like okay
so we define that part let me go
to here
and then i say give the structure
for my video based on the
structure of other winning content
i
connected okay and so what i did
here is i said hey give the
structure first and then give the
script
second okay and the other winning
content i connected is the ali
abdahl video and that's the other
productivity hacker video so
that's what i did from there okay
then from there it went about now
sometimes
you'll get the structure and
sometimes this time ai cloud
actually decided to give me the
full script
and here's the script and this is
not the best script but i'll tell
you how you can improve it because
at least the script sounds like me
so for example let's watch this
video real quickly i'm gonna show
you
something look actually i know i
know i know i know i know i'm not
sure turn original sound there
you go you guys hear it now there
you go no not turn original sound
uh you have to actually
share a screen and then click
share sound got it got it got it
got it got it got it got it oh
good
now oh good now i'm just there we
go other sas client sorry here i
want to show you how i landed an
84 000 sas client as a young
software agency now as you can see
the there we go so i want to show
you
i want to show you blah blah blah
right so check this out i want to
show you how i created 52
youtube videos last year while
working a demanding full-time job
by the end of this video you'll
have
five productivity hacks that will
10x your content creation output
help you feel less overwhelmed and
finally let you build your creator
business without quitting my day
job these aren't just theory these
are exact methods i use every
single day to balance both let's
dive in right and so remember that
i
want to show you it kind of tried
to model me and what i do with the
structure of for example
ali abdahl and so it did talk
about example i said hey talk
about the one take wonder and
here's this
here's the one take wonder method
you hit record and you do not stop
until you've covered your entire
topic no matter what mistakes you
make you keep going why does this
work two reasons right so it give
your full script that's really
good and now this might be good
enough honestly to already at this
point make an amazing video but i
feel like hey naz i actually want
to improve the intro now how do i
improve the intro if i want to
intro even make it either make it
more punchy or just change your
overall
to sound like someone else what
would i do i'm actually really
curious on your guys aside you
guys
feel free to put it in the chat
based on what we just talked about
i would love to hear from your
perspective actually maybe shaw or
heretic can can let us know here
what do you guys think anything
any ideas
let's be good boys come on any
ideas could you repeat the the
last part of the question i had an
audio
glitch yeah so basically what i
said was like hey if i was to make
this hook a little bit better
right what would i do like how
would i improve this hook or how
would i improve this script
hold on
i'll probably give it like a video
transcript of callaway where he
explains how do you write a viral
hook and then just ask him like
ask claude to rewrite the book and
use the same framework by callaway
there we go yeah or you say what
jacob says and you just you tell
like you dumb can't try harder
that's what i did or sometimes i
will do something like this
that's this is this actually works
sometimes make it more viral no
make it more viral that's me
there's all the capitals
make it more about and i've i've
honestly had it where it does a
pretty pretty damn good job
honestly
do my favorite one is uh i i tell
it that i've kidnapped his
grandmother and if it doesn't do
what i say it's gonna be executed
uh but also if it succeeds it gets
paid eight billion dollars
and that actually has resulted in
better inputs i swear to god i
swear to god that's so funny i
mean this is pretty good look at
this this one had to be a hundred
thousand dollars in revenue while
working a soul crush nine-to-five
job i want to show you the five
productivity secrets that top
creators don't want you to know
including the forbidden method
that lets you create three days
of content in just three hours oh
so good so there we go the word of
just making mobile made it even
better yes hit it here heretic
heretic yeah you're good you're
good man but the problem here like
the
problem i still face with like
claw is still that you know like
like this hook is good because it
has
hundred thousand dollars revenue
in it and like i'm about to show
like five productivity secrets
that
let's you create 30 days worth of
content in just three hours like
it still needs to be sort of true
to put put that in your video
right so like how do you like that
that's one of my questions as well
that
how do you make sure that it it
doesn't hallucinate and make this
crazy information on its own just
to
make it viral and it's like still
yeah a little bit authentic to you
yeah that's a great question
that's a great question and it's a
the answer is fairly simple and it
comes down to providing it
your voice and who you are and the
content you wanted to talk about
so what i would do all the time
and this is something i do with
poppy you can do with claude as
well pretty much on youtube what i
would
do is out honestly here's me and
this is what i tell everybody to
do i go to voiceline was app
hopefully you guys know how to
record uh you know record your own
voice i go to here and i just
start
recording literally my voice and i
start recording my own thoughts
about what it means to do a
productivity
hacks then you know productivity
hacks for content creators i would
just say it with my own words i
would
blabber it doesn't matter
necessarily you know what the
structure is i don't care about
any of that
i speak the content then what i do
is i let the ai structure the
content in a way that is more
viral
based on these other videos does
it make sense so yeah if you speak
the actual content like you define
it
you're like here here's who i am
here's what i do here's the things
i want to talk about and you
actually speak those things
because there might be a lot of
different you know uh things that
you
have in your mind when it comes to
creating some kind of a copy it
could be an email so forth
and as long as you provide that
data it will use that um you know
it will use that to create the
actual content and that's at that
point i don't find that
hallucinates too much it will
hallucinate if
you don't provide any knowledge
about what you do or about your
type of content make sense
and i think that would be that
that would be your answer right
yeah and hopefully that's that's
pretty much it but i do this all
the time i will when i ask people
like hey i want to make some
content
for you guys for example let's
just say i get in a call with
somebody and i say uh hey let's
make
some content together i do one
simple thing i have them hit
record in pop ai and i'll show you
that
kind of later on and i ask them
three to four questions first
question is what do you do second
question is why did you second
question is is why do you do it
third question is what do you hate
about
about the current industry another
question is is what do you wish
people knew about the industry
right so i'm kind of it's
providing the pain points and i'm
providing kind of like the thing
that you
that you've done and that
knowledge is enough to not only
provide a story for claude or for
ai to be
inputted into your script but it
also provides a little bit more
context on how to actually write
the script make sense and that
usually comes out to like to
actually have really good content
so yeah but that kind of hopefully
that answers your question and
then of course having a good
framework that also helps a lot so
um yes and that exactly and that's
pretty much it guys that's kind
kind of how i we go about writing
content but of course this is not
the only way um the other way
that i we currently do is we we
decide to make this a lot simpler
for us and at this point what we
did
is we built poppy to make this
whole process simpler and easier
and faster and so with you guys's
permission i kind of want to show
you or if you guys are open to it
would i be able to show you kind
of what it does and how you guys
can make some dope-ass content uh
with poppy and if you'd say yes if
you say yes in the chat i'll make
it happen if you're like no don't
do it i don't have to either
they've been forced by me to uh to
look extensively at poppy under a
dress for the past while i'll
definitely show them for someone
that actually knows how to use it
better than i do
all right i'm mindful go ahead and
do that guys okay all right
beautiful preface this okay
this is for content creation for
landing page copy for newsletters
for pretty much anything
also please i beg you don't ask us
for a free trial we don't have
that okay i just want to preface
this as well okay this is not a
thing we're like hey where's the
free trial we don't have it
for a bootstrap company but we
have an amazing community and we
love to work with people and
a million tokens there thanks very
much i got you all right cool all
right amazing so um before i
actually start um because we have
a lot of like agency owners and
like cold email guys what i want
to ask
is do you want me to show you guys
how naz exactly wrote uh the
script or like but with poppy or
do
you guys want to try something
different what do you guys want to
do
uh one shot for same scripts two
and shot for something different
yeah either a cold email
what's what's you think what's
different what's actually what is
the different amount tell me
what's
different because you're like so i
mean oh no so like something
different meaning like something
like hey how can we write cold
emails something like that oh yeah
there's actually quite a lot of
cold emails yeah there's someone
said it's between content and cold
emails and script writing all
right um so you know what actually
i'll do like the uh the youtube
script but like in like five
minutes
because that's how fast you can do
that with poppy and then um i'll
show you guys how to do cold
emails amazing oh i don't know how
we can do twitter content there
you go perfect all right so i'm
going to share my screen uh do you
guys see my screen yep all right
awesome so first of all what
i'm going to do is i'm going to
take the the youtube framework
stuff that i created that was used
inside um clon and i'm going to
clone that template real quick so
i can use it and then also let me
show
you guys how i actually did it
with poppy um it's youtube
brainstorming where is it
yep youtube research and
brainstorming this one so here's
how i put that framework together
what i did framework for the
framework for that we sent to you
guys for writing uh writing uh
copy
and writing scripts writing
scripts exactly so here's how i
did it um in terms of youtube
videos
there's like four parts right so
we have the titles the the
thumbnails we have the intro and
then the entire
script so what i did is i went
inside youtube and then i just
like looked up videos on how to
write
good titles so and here's how this
it's this simple right so i go to
youtube um and then i just say
youtube titles there you go and
then all i have to do is just
right click uh copy link address
come inside
poppy and all i have to do is just
do command v boom and it
transcribes the entire thing and
everything is there like if you
want to see proof i can just
connect this to a chat and say um
what's
inside this video give me a
comprehensive breakdown of what
this video talks about in terms of
writing
titles let's see what it does
yeah there you go it transcribe
the video in seconds yeah so the
the the overall goal is think of
like if chat tpt is only for
writing only for writing and just
talking back and forth the whole
goal is
to be like how can i import
anything i possibly uh have that
can be used to model or to teach
right which
could be youtube videos could be
instagram videos could be tiktok
videos all that content gets
transcribed and
analyzed by poppy directly um and
then for you to go to create new
content and that will include
also facebook ads too so if you
love to create facebook ads
imagine just bringing in all your
facebook ads into here and be like
hey give me new ideas for facebook
ads um you have an instagram
page hey i want to model this
creator and here's the instagram
content and i'm modeling the
second
content for my own content for
example yeah yeah exactly facebook
ads function is so good thank
you i appreciate that we just
added that recently so the whole
goal i i want to record a voice
recording i want to can record
that i want to bring in a website
of my own my own website that
talks
about who i am i can do that too
so that's just a general note
that's general just a bit so yeah
so
what i did is i brought in those
youtube videos and i said hey um
let me just zoom in um let's see
what
i did i was like hey help me build
a framework that i can share with
my intern who's going to be
helping
me package my youtube videos
here's the resources i've given
you which i expect advice from
experts
in the youtube space and created
for me um and then um it went
through the videos and then put
together all the frameworks like
hey these are the cool emotions
that you need to tap into here's
the
title writing guideline here's how
the elements should be here are
examples blah blah and so forth
and then i said you know what be
more specific give more examples
so it's easier for for the person
who's
who's reading to understand so i
came up with like hey here are
examples for curiosity and fear
here's
curiosity and desire problem
solution format so it broke down
the entire video into very
specific
examples and then i was like all
right this is great now combine
this both and put something
comprehensive for me um and wait
some what happened oh i don't know
something weird happened for a
second
but that's good um but yeah and
then it put together the entire
framework for me and then all i
had to do
is now uh do the same thing with
thumbnails and then intros and
then script writing and then these
are all those
frameworks and now to recreate
what naz did here's what i'm going
to do i'm going to go to youtube
and bring in some of naz's old
videos from years ago
might go naz damansky
oh look at that hey do the one
where it's how i learn 84k how i
learn 84k cs client for example
that one paste this put it inside
the group what else do you want me
to bring naz uh do the one
where to do the one where day in
the life the day in the life one
day in the life oh yeah that one
that was such a long time ago oh
my god dude holy shit that was
like 22 years old that was a
major game detroit how old were
you 22 years old yeah i think so
or 21 and that's it i think that
you don't need any more than that
by the way i think two is fine um
awesome so we got that two
videos and then let's do
productivity videos yeah so
there's three three pillars one of
the frameworks
second is going to be like my
voice of tone and like my videos
my content
and then third will be like other
people's content you want to model
all right so let's say we need
to model this video well not sure
control copy like address copy
link address paste this video link
here and then what else did you
take naz there's uh there's ali
ali abdahl productivity hacks go
to
all the property hacks for example
ali abdahl productivity hacks all
right this one yep oh nice perfect
so i'm gonna copy link address
paste that boom all right now what
i'm gonna do is
what can you see actually you know
i'm just gonna do this what can
you see and tell this is like my
starter prompt that i like to use
um it's just like hey you know can
you just go through it see what
you
can see um so it's gonna take a
second to go through all of them
and then tell us what we have
yeah yeah because i think there's
yeah it's quite a lot in here i
think i believe
once it once it what's up should
be fine yeah yeah yeah there we go
and then go into full screen go
into full screen quickly there we
go yep there we go all right
perfect so now what i'm gonna do
all right great so now what i want
you to do is in the group that has
like my youtube videos what i want
you to do is use those videos to
understand my style of talking
like
the words that i use my tonality
my style and everything and then
use the videos uh by ali
abdahl and another video that i've
given you about productivity to
kind of come up with the structure
for the video that i'm trying to
make so basically the video that
i'm trying to make is a video
around
five productivity hacks for
content creators but i want to do
it from my perspective now um you
could
use examples from you know those
videos that i've given you as
examples but a crucial one that i
want
to cover in as a hack for content
creators is i want to talk about
my concept called one take wonder
which
basically is like you know you
just sit down click record on your
camera and then you don't turn off
the
recording and you just sit down
and then record until you finish
shooting the video and then
whatever
mistakes you make whatever
everything you make you cut them
down blah blah and then do it now
what i
want you to do is that's basically
the video that i want to make and
what i want you to do is use the
frameworks that i've given you
first come up with like three to
five different alternative titles
that
i can use for the video using the
title running framework and then
let's create three to five
different
options for intros that i can do
and then let's also come up with
an outline for the entire script
all right so let's see what you
can do hey i don't know what holy
shit i want to talk you know
usually what i like to do
personally i'd like to say hey
give me the titles first and then
i'll pick
a title and then i'll say yeah uh
from the titles now give me the
outline he just went all out and
just
said the full thing i'm not the
personal biggest fan of that but
that works sometimes too
take wonder method oh my god it
was one take wonder
but there you go why most content
creators failed and five
productivity hacks to avoid it
that's pretty
good i tested these five
productivity hacks for 30 days
here's what actually works that's
pretty good
uh and then let's see what it came
up with so problem solution
hook creating content consistently
is probably the hardest part of
being a content creator i used to
spend hours trying to make the
perfect video blah blah blah this
is how i used to create content
overthinking over planning and
barely publishing anything and
this is how i create content now
what if i told you the most
productive content creators don't
actually try to be perfect
discovered this when i take wonder
myth jesus uh big wonder you could
tell it'd be like the one
the one is like is that you could
actually tell it it's actually
it's actually a one tick take
wonder wonder
not wonder oh all right let's see
what it does now
all right there we go the one take
wonder method how i create three x
more content without burning out
so yeah there you go it came up
with all the different titles and
then these are titles that are
based on
frameworks that are proven right
so it's like you can test out like
five different titles
and then you can select whichever
intro sounds the best for you and
or if if you hate all these intros
you can say hey i absolutely hate
these intros um make it viral or
like stop being a cunt or like
i don't know something say
something violent and like get it
to do something better uh but you
know
this is like the faster way to do
it because like you didn't have to
transcribe the the videos
all of that is just done for you
out of the box so this was the
example for like how to do it
but with poppy now what i can do
is i can go on to show you guys
how to write cold emails
sounds good yep let's do it let's
do it all right amazing all right
so what i'm going to do is i'm
going to create a new board and
sorry just to know as well anyone
that uh can stick around this call
is recorded and will be posted
afterwards amazing awesome so i'm
going to call this cold email
wizard
but why don't you just show them
why with the cold emails you've
done manaf you have a bunch of
them
i haven't done cold emails i have
done uh ones for like writing
emails itself or like news show me
just
show us just emails you've written
and how you've written okay okay
so this one is what something
that we're using for pat flynn um
i don't know if you guys know pat
flynn but he's a very popular
marketer and here's kind of how we
do with pat flynn we bought in a
bunch of his email newsletters
that he wrote in the past and then
we just use this to like hey uh
let me see if we can yeah there
you go
please rewrite this blurb about my
book uh there was a part where we
did actually write a newsletter
there you go oh my god this is
like way too long oh yeah there
you go so he was like hey i'd like
to
create a newsletter about my
friend sean cannell sean is a
creator blah blah he did all of
this and then
boom it wrote the entire
newsletter in his voice that
sounds exactly like him and here's
a funny thing
if you guys are actually
subscribed to pat flynn's
newsletter um and like look up
sean cannell
and his newsletter you'll actually
find this email in your inbox but
what did you what did you do to
actually write like what did you
bring in to actually write this
write this newsletter like what's
the
stuff we just i'm curious we just
we just had to only bring in his
like previously written
newsletters
that's all we had to do right and
so you all you do is that command
you just all you do is just
pasting his letter that you've
done before and then and then yeah
and then there's one more thing
yes connected in there and then
underneath it what else is there
um and then we have this it's a
it's
his upcoming book about lean
learning um that we were covering
in one of the newsletters there we
go
so basically again bring in
different elements of writing
bring in a different knowledge
between
your pdf documents to your um uh
structure the frameworks and from
there you can just write either
emails and you've got a cold
emails just like your just like
yours and then after that that's
that's
pretty much all good uh that's
just my example for you and then
oh there we go and then uh
actually
i'll show you guys i want you guys
to read this email uh let's see i
think it's this email i want
you guys to read this email and
tell me uh what you guys think um
who wrote this email so go through
it i
i mean i mean with that question i
kind of i mean i mean it's implied
you asked it and it's implied
like hey just like so read the
email tell me what you guys think
yeah yeah yeah
wow i left everyone speechless
it's really good i was gonna say
if anyone here isn't actually
subscribed to the poppy newsletter
definitely do because uh the
emails are phenomenal yeah thank
you
thank you um but yeah basically
how did you actually put together
that email do you have a board for
that
i see yeah yeah i was gonna show
that but look at this guys this is
a six page email that was all
written by poppy and i did not
have to say a single word i mean i
didn't have to write a single word
but
basically what i did is this so i
had a video that i did as a case
study with lauren so i brought
brought in
that video that i did and then i
brought in um a website which is
poppy's landing page and then a
voice memo that i did about like
what poppy is and then i brought
in like a bunch of emails that i
wrote
in the past um with like an
analysis of like hey i would rate
this email a one out of ten a five
out
of ten ten out of ten because of x
y and z so i did an analysis and
then brought them all together
and all i had to do was go all the
way to the top and then show you
guys this as long as chat but wait
um i was like hey my goal is to
write an email sequence to sell
this course to poppy air users
blah blah blah um need your help
writing the rest of the email
sequence first of all i need your
help
writing a case study email for
lauren using the youtube video i
did with her give it a try see
what
she can do and then it gave me a
couple of subject lines and then
look at this how she made 250k
with
just nine emails um it was
literally the one that we ended up
using and then it wrote the email
didn't like it i was like hey
everything is good here's things
that i don't like
gave it feedback rewrote it again
and then i gave it more feedback
rewrote it again and then you know
i just went back and forth a
couple of times here are the
things that i like here are the
things that i
don't like and also by the way
what was horrible about this time
was back then we didn't have voice
prompting so i had to type all of
this instead of talking so it was
such a bad experience compared
to now which is now i just can
like hit record and then like talk
and give my feedback but yeah i
wrote
all of it and then it gave me the
entire email so uh let me just
keep going um that's a long one
holy
shit oh yeah i mean it's a six
page email so it is a really long
one but yeah this is how i use
poppy
and then this is one email we
wrote like five more emails after
this and like if i were to write
this
email all by myself it would have
taken me like i don't know three
to four hours because like i have
to
go through the video and
understand everything and then
write it versus poppy i was able
to like go
back and forth and write the
entire email in like five minutes
yeah yeah i think overall where
the where
it becomes like beautiful is like
your store gibberish in and then
amazing stuff comes out basically
um
that's that's kind of the goal as
long as you're like you're not
done with it like as long as
you're
just like hey just um write me
some random email as long as you
understand that okay there's some
knowledge space needs to be
provided our goal is okay how can
provide you with that knowledge
right
and so and then i keep part as
well that i'm going to show like
tell you guys like the cool
thing as well that we did which is
some a lot of people have asked us
for is you know a lot of people
have tiktoks for example or
instagram videos and maybe you can
show like a tiktok board here a
model
too where there's no there's no
audio being said right it's all
visual and so when you paste in
content
from tiktok from instagram from
linkedin from facebook ads for
example poppy will not only
understand the audio aspect
and this transcript but it will
also understand the visual aspect
it will actually watch the video
it will understand the text on
screen it will understand the
visual hooks it will understand
like we actually had this one girl
who where all she does is visual
hooks and we trained poppy on
visual hooks and then from there
she was able to come up with
amazing new visual hooks for her
own
tiktok and instagram and that was
super sick and she was like what
no way i could do this that is
that is amazing oh and then it can
also analyze um carousels yeah
exactly this is a carousel right
so if i
go in here and i just paste this
and then if i go and say find i
think it was this one is it is he
talking
he doesn't talk so that's good i'm
gonna bring bring these two in and
then i'm gonna give it a second
so it can analyze but if i create
a chat connect these two and say
and then again this also works
with
uh facebook ads as well yes yes
yes yes so those of you guys who
make ads that'd be super helpful
unless
you love to make ads just for
yourself then this is completely
useless to you um you know you
don't
need to you don't need to use it
at all um all right so yeah what i
want you to do is um give me a
breakdown of the two instagram
posts that i've given you one is a
carousel and then one is a video
um for the carousel give me a
breakdown of what's there in the
visuals and then for the video
give
me a breakdown of like what's been
taught what's been shown and be
very comprehensive so let's see
what it does
um but yeah i think after this
we'll just go into any q a you
guys have any questions
and then we'll go from there
so let's see if it actually does
talk about something called
peekaboo
yes shah go ahead what's your
question yes my question is not
specifically on the content
creation
side um but more like a like a
local llm um you know because i've
been trying to ideate some of
these things uh for a while and
and i want to see if um i can use
get poppy i can use poppy.ai to
to basically build a local large
language model for companies that
that need data protection that
need
that that level of privacy um to
to streamline their their tasks or
um basically help their employees
because i'm just thinking you know
because right now there aren't any
really big solutions out there
that
are um that are there for a
purpose like this so i just wanted
to pick you guys's brain on if
you've thought about something
like this
has this been in discussions or i
mean i could send some research
that i've done your way
yeah i mean for local models if
you're trying to build a local
model for like that's a whole
different use
case than like a poppy made for
necessarily right um we don't want
to bring local models yet because
for
us we just want to use the best
model to create content um and
that's what 99 of our content
creators
really genuinely actually just
care about um and also naz just to
uh add to that it's like when you
say also we use content creators a
lot because it's like almost like
what our user base is 50 of our
user base but we also have like a
lot of founders i mean lucas yeah
uh you know agency owners and like
we have like different audiences
that use poppy as well exactly but
the answer to answer your question
shot like you don't need poppy for
that like you could just use a
normal llm like like a chat gpt or
cloud to figure out how to build
that right if you want to do the
research because you know it is
really
good with research stuff so like
you can bring in different
research points um and then have
it kind
of tell you kind of what to do at
the end of the day we use cloud
under the hood and chat gpt and
then
we allow it to use gemini and jgt
4.1 and all different ai models um
but you don't need to use it like
at the end of the day like if
that's not the primary use case
what poppy is made for you can
just use it like a normal chat gpt
cloud unless you really really
love the visual workspace which is
what a lot of content creators do
love then that's you know that's
where it might be somewhat useful
to
you yeah see where i'm coming from
is some of the companies that i've
like personally worked at
that are medium-sized enterprises
thousand two thousand employees
those companies yeah for the use
of
something like chat gpt or claude
to you know analyze a data set
that you input so i was thinking
if poppy has the ability to create
something local in in like a
company's intranet or something
like
that or put it on their sharepoint
um you know add or append it to
their sharepoint perhaps i was i
was
just trying to think out loud if
that's something you guys have
thought about or or not yeah
haven't
thought about it yet um we do have
a few um businesses who do use us
um and you know
consistently um we haven't had
enterprise companies who are like
oh we need to be like where it's a
local alarm maybe at some point in
the future yet again we're only
one year old right so like
we started literally about like a
year ago and we're just trying to
grow um you know year a little by
little and so for us it's not so
much of not so much of a priority
just yet uh in the near future
maybe yes fair thank you okay
there's one question in the chat
here i just wanted to to bring up
super
quickly from uh srav because uh i
think that nazi i've actually
mentioned this to you before i
think
and you had a really good answer
for it uh he says respectfully is
the benefit of the visual
whiteboard
saw where you can have a visual
workspace just getting the video
transcriptions and submitting off
the
info to a cloud project would that
yield the same results so like
what's the difference between
what we did earlier where we
uploaded all that content of a
cloud project and then putting it
in poppy i think personally the
outputs are better i think you
guys are doing some magic but yeah
i mean
if you if you have fun copying
transcripts and and you have fun
spending a bunch of time
copying transcripts and taking
that and i don't know how you get
a transcript even from like
tick tock or instagram or how you
would visually analyze it if you
have fun with that and then
like you you can definitely bring
that into clod no problem like i'm
honestly to be completely honestly
it might be somewhat similar
because at the end of the day we
do use clod right but where we add
i think
or what we're trying to get to is
like we're trying to be it's a
most like a workspace and all one
workspace
we can do anything right so for
example another big thing is like
you can add directly upload mp4
content
so if you have direct mp4 content
you filmed yourself that is not on
youtube or anywhere else
you just directly throw that in
there so um to be completely
honest to you might not see a huge
difference uh but i think if you
love to save time then that's
where poppy will be a huge
difference for
you yes and also it's like hey if
you want to bring in say like 10
videos uh from like multiple
different
creators at the same time to
analyze and like kind of do it you
have to do if you were to do that
with
cloud you'll have to like do one
by one by one by one and like
spend like hours to like set that
entire thing up versus with poppy
you just like boom boom boom paste
the links and then when you group
it
and like you can give it context
with like notes and stuff yeah you
would give them a better context
in terms of like how to use that
specific data or information
versus like hey these are all the
context
that you have um and then like do
whatever you want with it also
yeah jp sorry kind of jp just said
just said there uh the ifm
personally being i'm able to
upload far more content to poppy
than to a
cloud project yeah yeah that that
is true actually too i think we
have a lot more limits so like
as you're chatting back and forth
to cloud it will start to tell you
hey you need to create a new
chat at this point we kind of we
try to push as much as possible
into cloud we kind of we kind of
uh
we push it to its maximum um and
so we have had people who find
that that to be a huge use case
too but honestly the biggest use
case i feel like it's just a time
saver like being able to upload
anything and see it visually i
personally because i we built
poppy for for for me and my
co-founder
like i initially built it we
didn't build it for anybody else i
it was like i just wanted to build
something that like i love to use
um and i i love miro so and i love
seeing something visually and like
being to and i was like i didn't
see you just add ai like why can
they just if i have all this
content
on there it's fucking useless it's
like i can look at it but it's
fucking useless you know like like
what's the point of adding on
there if i can't do anything with
it so i was like why can we just
take that and then just combine it
with ai which is it does all the
brainstorming for us and that's
where i found like okay that's
actually a huge time saver and
then luckily we did have a lot of
people
who found that to be very very
helpful um so yeah that that is
where i feel like would be a
benefit
more so but so maybe the visual
and then the the time saver is
where the benefit would come would
come from
yeah you got it absolutely and i
think you have your hand uh what's
up bro yeah guys when are you guys
increasing the limit on how much
content we can upload like
whenever i try to upload like is
there a hack
for it like is there a file
preference because whenever i try
to so the way i work is like you
know i would
so let so i i run a content agency
right so let's suppose i have a
client okay um he's a financial
expert he has like let's say 500
videos on youtube i would probably
scrape like 50 of his youtube
video
transcripts i would upload it and
like bobby would not give me
anything question i'm gonna break
you real
quick yeah why are you bringing in
50 transcripts what's the reason
behind it so the reason behind
this to like
grab anecdotes from what he has
spoken in like what he has spoken
about in the youtube videos itself
so
like take like like basically like
um so it acts like a brain right
so like the way i also set up my
poppy board is like there's a
brain which has like all the
information which is basically
what i need to
write the script about like the
topic and then you have the voice
then you have um how to write the
script
so like scripting frameworks
youtube videos hooks videos and
all that shit i you you probably
know
it as well so yeah yeah yeah yeah
so what how do i bypass that like
if i want to build that brain
sort of a thing on poppy yeah if i
were you so like that we are still
working within the limits of like
ai unfortunately right and and you
know claude has a 200k limit uh
gpd 4.1 could be super helpful
more because it has like a 1
million limit so we have that now
added what i would suggest if i
were
you because i have a few clients
who i work with and they're like
hey how did i do it where it's
like i have one big brain um what
i would do is i'll kind of put
together let's just say i let's
just
say i do 10 videos at a time okay
i'll bring in 10 videos and i'm
like hey give me the all the
anecdotes the most important
information from these 10 videos
and i'll put the other framework
from
that from those videos right first
right so i basically kind of like
would summarize or what
kind of summarize or get the key
parts out of those 10 videos first
and get those then then i'll bring
another 10 videos into a group and
i'm like hey now could maybe give
me now anecdotes from there
uh exactly and then give the
structures the most important
things the most important quotes
from that
video okay then i do another 10
videos another 10 so that is where
how you can go around it um
the issue with bringing 50 videos
is that you're going to hit a huge
limit where it's normal to
bring is 20 hours of content you
can connect it all to one ih at 20
hours of content that's usually
that's usually kind of what you
start to hit the limit of content
um yeah exactly but but the reason
why
it's done like that is because
like if you were to let's just say
if we were doing a way where like
the opposite 50 hours of content
or you know 100 hours of content
then we would have to somehow
like be more efficient and try to
figure out what's important and
that's something called uh
in in programmatic space it's
called using something called uh
what is it called like a vector
database
and exactly you start to kind of
pinpoint and search and it becomes
nasty you actually get very nasty
results most of the times um and
so right now we have a limit of
with just ai overall
some point in the future i'm sure
we'll have like two million three
million four million five million
million just came out so no no no
that's still 200k there's still
200k lemon unfortunately
yeah yeah yeah yeah jacob always
called for an offer like three
hours after it launched
how dare you guys you know what i
said to jacob earlier i said i
guarantee by the time
we're gonna get on the call yeah
we have it ready to go launch it
soon
it's clocked for on poppy i don't
know i didn't use it in the past
couple of hours not yet yeah
unfortunately it's gonna be out in
like another hour or so i don't
mind waiting for another hour
long fucking lead time
how dare you guys
but yeah that that's kind of that
i would say that would be your
answer honestly
um that's what i did i told it to
one of the customers recently and
they really have a bunch of
content um that's kind of what we
have to work with for now honestly
yeah try gpt try gpt try gpt 4.1
and try the limits of that it has
a million token limit try the gpt
that's what i was coming to
so what i did instead so do you
mind if i just quickly share my
screen of course
so so this is like the poppy board
okay that i was talking about okay
so it has those kind of videos
okay so these are like scripting
frameworks hooks resources and
everything then it's like project
purpose instructions all that
bullshit so like i tried uploading
this there but it didn't happen
but when i did it here like when i
uploaded the same document here it
actually processed it like
i tried processing it in gpt 4.0
uh in poppy but it didn't process
like so these were the documents
here like this was the data set of
your transcripts it did process it
here though but it didn't process
it in poppy when i uploaded it
like and i tried gpt 4.0 here like
i did not try uh no gpt 4.1 did
you
try 4.1 not 4.1 yeah try gpt 4.1
that one has a much bigger limit
i'll take a look at that
actually send me send me send me
your text and i'd love to take a
look at why that that was not
the case because it could be a
thing where maybe it's taking up a
lot of empty space that could be
a thing sometimes too but send me
a text at one plus one two four
eight eight nine zero eight nine
five yeah i'll just give you that
was so slow naz everybody got it
yeah yeah i just i sent you a
text send me a text i'll see how i
can help you okay all right
perfect i got it yeah also jacob
uh said
if you'd love people to title the
chat boxes i i do actually agree
with that one that'd be great
oh yeah okay i'll make i can make
that happen this week thank you
it's always great talking to the
the devs of this this offer you're
using a database like hey hey can
you just do that thanks
i did that in the even before i
talked to you guys i did that in
the customer support chat i was
like
hey i'm getting this error message
you know what it means and then
they were like oh yeah cool next
day the air message was updated
and it was just like you've got
too much to connect and fix it and
i was like great yeah yeah we're
still a young company very much
blue strapped and so forth so
but you know we're trying our best
and the crazy part somehow people
do love the product for some
you know um 40 what we have 4700
customers now 47 4800 paying
customers now which is crazy um
yeah and it's only only been like
we've been given an hour like
seven six seven months i think
out technically but it's a year
since starting development which
is really cool but yeah hopefully
hopefully that will answer some of
your questions any other questions
guys yeah let's go anything
anyone's want to ask the question
about ai in general or poppy if
not i am going to post uh the
little offer that uh both the guys
here at poppy have helped with and
something uh that i'm throwing
in myself too so in this chat uh
the zoom chat here i'm going to be
posting uh a link to get poppy
uh a very generous 35 dollar off
uh code for the guys here uh poppy
to get some money off you do my
subscription um the ai youtube
scripting data pack that's the one
that we the guys showed earlier in
claude it's all the files that
they they uploaded to uh claude to
write the script and then for me
personally a calendar link where
if you guys do buy poppy you can
book one hour call me where i'll
help you build out your board for
whatever it is that you want to uh
create so that's sick lucas
that's awesome there is the links
in the chat and uh i'll also be
posting that links in the
announcement
as well along with the recording
of this call um but i think this
has been easily one of the this is
you guys nearly beat our most
attended call you were so close
but it's easily one of the most
attended calls nearly hit the
record um i think it was super
super valuable uh you know i
really have
to thank you guys for uh the time
you gave here this went way over
the usual hour long and i let
me think it was well well worth
that people got a ton of value out
of this um both around the general
use of ai and also getting a
better understanding of what poppy
ai is and uh i am one of your guys
chief evangelists i will not stop
talking about this on uh the
weekly coaching calls because it's
the
thing i use every single day um
thank you but yeah lucas we're
about to introduce like uh poppy
awards for anybody who gets over a
certain specific amount like you
know how like click funnels has
the rewards we're gonna we're
gonna be introducing poppy awards
as well i'm on it do i get like a
sick
fucking record and like a frame or
some shit exactly exactly we
actually are we know the vendor of
the
the click funnels guy of the click
funnels that'd be great but yeah
okay sick i mean also i just want
to point out that that this was
like super valuable you guys
didn't even scratch the servers of
like
everything poppy can do to a
degree here like the more you use
it the more emails it can be used
for
like especially with the um uh
kind of a webhooks integration uh
for the higher tiers that he
introduced
recently that i've used to uh
build out full-on bots and uh
chatbots and all sorts of other
automations
uh incredibly incredibly useful um
so yeah again anyone if you make
sure to copy down those links
are in the chat there now um and
thank you guys so much we have to
really appreciate it this was a
great call and uh hope to have you
guys back again sometime very soon
thank you everybody thank you
so much for your time appreciate
it thanks so much guys i'll be
posting the recording later along
with those links again thanks
everyone thank you thank you thank
you sir thank you guys bye bye
thank you jacob bye
All right, I'm getting...