I had to do something weird all
right anyways welcome to module
one hope you like the drum
roll hope you guys could even hear
it with this mic i don't even know
if you really could but
anyways welcome to module number
one of the dream 100 of course
here inside of client ascension so
guess what we're gonna be talking
about we're gonna be talking about
how to sign whales and
make that internet money for free
because essentially the dream 100
strategy is that
you're going to go out there and
for zero marketing cost you know
zero ad dollars not buying domains
nothing like that you're going to
be able to sign massive clients
and yes it does take some work on
your front but again this is how
to sign whale clients and make
that internet money for free
right when i give us some of that
internet money so first what the
heck is this dream 100 thing and
who came up with it in the first
place so right here i want you
guys to meet amen so amen is
probably
some of you actually joined client
essentially because of amen but he
runs a content agency
and he is inside here as well so
if you guys want to hit him up for
sure definitely dm on slack ask
him some questions hit him up on
twitter he's got a great twitter
as well but amen came up with this
and right here is his original
dream 100 outreach video okay so
pause this real quick scan that
because
this is the video that it's about
20 to 30 minutes long i believe
and this is the video that i
actually
watched initially and learned
about the strategy so he came up
with it and coined the term and
pretty
much i just am taking this entire
thing this entire strategy just
expanding on it a little bit more
and diving into what has
personally worked for me and what
i've seen work for a lot of other
members
inside of the community lately but
again this is a great base point
to start with so definitely a
great video to to watch highly
recommend and recommend following
amen so what is dream 100 in the
first
place okay dream 100 is a cold
outreach method where you actually
research and perform free
upfront work for someone without
them asking you to or without you
asking them if you should do the
work in the first place okay so
free work as you're gonna
basically find out equals a lot of
money if
you do it right and yes you heard
that right you do stuff for free
upfront okay for free upfront
you're
doing free work upfront okay so
why does this work it's basically
because you instantly stand out
from
every single other cold dm cold
call cold email that any prospect
gets and all the paid ads they're
seeing right you stand out you
gave them something of value
upfront you took the time to
research them
see what they needed learn about
their company learn about their
offer learn about their style
learn
about you know what they're
currently doing marketing wise or
sales wise etc and you said hey
they have
some holes here i'm gonna i know
what these holes are i'm not just
gonna tell them about the holes
i'm not
gonna tell them that they're you
know ad copy sucks for example i'm
literally gonna go in and make
five pieces of ad copy for them
give it to them up front and show
them that i'm the guy that can
help
them reach their goals and get to
where they need to be so you stand
out from everybody by using this
strategy and you're just giving
goodwill back into the industry
back into the community and then
basically in
return you're gonna get a lot of
karma and a lot of deals coming
your way because of this when you
do
this right so with dream 100 too
for all you guys that are watching
this that are totally new you
don't
need case studies or tons of
testimonials back at the beginning
of this year in 2024 i worked with
some
companies right i've been doing
digital marketing kind of like
freelancing this like fractional
cmo stuff
here and there for quite a while
uh i didn't really have that many
like big name clients that i
worked
with i had some great results and
stuff like some screenshots but i
never really had like those you
know authority builder case
studies and those like you know
really strong companies i've
worked with
and since doing dream 100 and
acquiring uh you know gym lunch
and jason wojo both of those guys
you
know both those companies are
filming me some case studies now
which is freaking awesome and some
testimonials
and every single time i've told a
prospect that i've worked with
these companies it's made stuff
so much easier so much easier so
once you get these first few deals
from dream 100 in the bag
everything
else is downhill and i want you
guys to know when you're new you
don't need a lot of case studies
or
testimonials to use this strategy
why because you're already doing
the upfront work and providing
your worth in showing that you
know what you're doing ahead of
time for them that's the big thing
right you're if you if i just gave
you you know 10 pieces of ad copy
you're not going to ask me like
do you have any major case studies
you know you might ask me hey who
have you worked with before
and then you can you know say some
of that stuff or you can say hey
i'm totally new but i'm ready to
keep you know working for you and
uh want to keep crushing it for
you here's some more examples of
uh
some ad copy that i do right so
using dream 100 shifts the
prospect's view of you away from
hey
does this guy have case studies
and testimonials to oh shit he did
this thing for me this is really
good and it puts a lot of the work
on the deliverable and your skill
set itself and that's
the main thing or a lot of the
emphasis on your skill set and if
you're good so that's why i want
you guys that are new to
understand about this strategy and
why it's so good for you
so again it's perfect for you new
agency owners and plus it's free
right if you're on a small budget
you're only making two three four
five k a month right netting a
couple grand a month probably
don't
have a lot to spend on ads and um
you know you need something that's
a little bit more cost effective
and ideally free here well here
you go this is how you get your
first big deals through the door
and something to note too is you
know with other outreach methods
and other acquisition methods
you can get some big deals from it
but dream 100 is very freaking
targeted right it's free
and it's very targeted you can
pick the highest people in the
food chain the biggest companies
in
your space give them free stuff
and sign them and then from there
you leverage the
shit out of that case study you
leverage the shit out of the fact
that you're using them
or that sorry that you're working
with them and providing them a ton
of value getting them insane
results and then everything else
is downstream so every other
company below them on the totem
pole below them on the food chain
in that industry is gonna be like
oh man evan worked with them
that's crazy he's great uh he must
know what he's doing right so
that's why this strategy is great
and it also avoids these these
situations here so you know you
aggressively cold pitching your
service
that's the prospect uh and then
your prospect here you being a
sleaze trying to slide the dms for
a
quick buck i actually don't
remember writing that one but it's
kind of funny so i'm not gonna lie
that was great good job evan and
just for context i was able to
work with these guys using this
method
without a website without a
landing page without a vsl and
without content so that's
something that's
really funny too is i build
landing pages write vsls and run
ads for people and i was able to
sign
these companies without uh you
know actually having one myself so
goes to show again this works very
well if you do it right so i want
to be clear as we move on this
module too that these messages you
see
right here are not dream 100
outreaches these are just typical
cold outreach messages right so
this
person right here is saying hey
evan uh i've got an important
offer for you oh how important is
it
i'll write your copy for the next
10 email campaigns for free if my
emails outperform your current
ones
we can talk about doing more if
not we're all good mind if i send
over a portfolio of my recent work
so something to note this is not
dream 100 why uh he's asking me if
he wants me to do the free work
for him dream 100 is sending it
first right and we'll get into in
the next slide here you know
differences between a cold dm like
this which is a better cold dm i i
do have to be fair that is a
better cold dm with a better offer
versus just some dumb generic
stuff that you guys probably see
all
online but you know it's a
difference between that and a
dream 100 outreach and this guy
right here
it's literally saying hi i made
you a four-step cold outreach
script for gym growth so you can
book
15 to 20 plus gym growth workshop
tickets per month you're part of
my dream 100 prospects i want to
work
with that was just the stupidest
line because like it's he's not
using the strategy right okay is
you're part of my dream 100 like
what is that like you know it just
sounds very reachy and pitchy
right and like you're part of my
dream like big heart guys big
heart you know it doesn't
doesn't work did you see that
little heart scheme that's awesome
anyways um you know that's not
dream 100 okay that's a cold dm at
the end of the day the actual
dream 100 process of that would
have
been sending it up front doing the
free work or actually sending the
four-step outreach right so
and there's a big difference
between again cold dms and dream
100 dream 100 you have to do the
work up
front so yes there is a potential
that the person might not like the
work they might not need it they
might not even see it they might
ignore you we're going to go over
later in a couple modules down
the line here of how to combat
some of those things and battle
some of those things but and then
also
cold dms you know on the other
side is like just mass sending it
out like basically like this guy
here
on the left this ahmed guy said
hey do you want me to do this for
you he's basically like getting
people
to raise their hand so two sides
of things but right here cold dms
versus dream 100 so cold dms
they're not personalized they're
mass messages there's no upfront
work there's barely any research
done they're higher volume but you
get lower response rates and
usually if you're doing this
at volume you need uh sdrs or
setters really monitoring those
dms and working people you know
getting quicker uh quickly leads
and stuff like that messaging
leads quickly speed the leads
everything with cold dms and any
cold outreaches you know uh dream
100 is very hyper personalized
very individualized messages uh
upfront work is key here deep
research needs to be done deep
upfront work
needs to be done these are lower
volume but way higher response
rates and way warmer response
weights by the
other way too not just a lot of
like very uh you know cold kind of
like on edge stuff like as you
guys
know if you've you know answered
any any cold dm you've probably
been a little bit uh guarded your
guards
up a little bit you're like what
is this guy trying to sell me like
you know you're trying to dodge
some stuff and you're like very
guarded here with dream 100 you
just give them a ton of stuff
they drop that guard quick and
they're like wow this guy actually
like cares about my brand and what
i want to do in my company so uh
with this too there's no need
really for an sdr or setter
especially when you're just
starting out you can use a trello
board or some other kanban board
which we'll go into uh later on so
that is module one let's get ready
to go into module