All right.
So this is one of my favorite
modules too.
I've said this about a lot of
them, but this
is, this is genuinely one of my
favorite ones.
Cause, um, as you guys are
starting out with
this strategy, you're going to be
like, well, what happens if they
don't, you know, uh, read
my deliverable?
What happens if I do all this
upfront work?
What happens if they ghost me,
they don't like what I'm doing, et
cetera.
So all of this here, all those
questions and concerns
and objections you have in your
mind to starting this strategy and
scaling it, we're going to break
them in here.
And I'm going to show you exactly
what to do if something happens,
uh, and how to
break past it basically.
So first off, what happens if they
don't like slash C slash consume
my free
work?
So they don't see it follow up
forever, try new channels and get
creative with your outreach.
Read that book, right?
Get very creative with how you
outreach to these people.
They don't like it.
They say, I don't like the stuff
that you sent me.
It's not useful to me.
Don't like it.
Take the
feedback and improve adjusted for
them as well.
So say, Hey, no worries.
Uh, can we have a quick
five minute call to see like
exactly what you want me to change
with this thumbnail and kind of
like
how to stick with your brand
guidelines?
Cause I'd still love to, you know,
I already have it 95%
of the way done.
I still want to give you that
value and help you, uh, raise your
click-through rates
with this thumbnail.
So take the feedback, improve and
adjust it for them.
They don't need it.
They say,
I don't, I just don't need this.
That comes down to your research
process.
So you're reaching out to
the wrong people.
Again, you're not doing enough
research to judge beforehand,
before you make this
deliverable to see if they
actually need it or not.
You're not, you're not judging
that properly.
So refine your research process.
You keep getting left on read,
follow up and provide them even
more
work.
Again, if it is worth it to you,
you have a low take rate on your
deliverable means that many,
that basically just means people
aren't actually taking and
consuming and using your
deliverable.
you're not giving enough value.
You're giving the wrong thing to
the wrong ICP and you're just
being
too pitchy.
That's really it.
So another thing too, is if, you
know, you make something for
somebody
and they just ghost you, they just
don't want it.
You can also, again, just post it
as content, like
on Twitter, Facebook, Instagram,
YouTube, whatever saying, I made X
for person slash company
and kind of authority hack them
for some reach and showcase that
deliverable in your skill set.
So now got a couple more modules.
We're going to go to module 11,
increasing your response rate.