All right.
Welcome my friends to module
number 11.
We are wrapping up here very soon.
We're
getting into some more fun stuff,
increasing your response rates,
right?
So if you're sitting there
dealing with low response rates,
you're just making all this free
work, you're sending it out
and people just aren't replying to
you.
They're not booking your calls.
Like you're just getting
down.
What we're going to do today is
show you a couple more very
creative ways to increase your
response rates and take rates on
your deliverable.
So let's dive in.
So strategies to increase the
chance that someone will reply to
you and see your dream 100
deliverable.
There's a lot of cool ones
in here.
So let's go.
First is you can test with burner
accounts.
So you can basically send like
one kind of salesy message and one
prospect related message on burner
accounts to this prospect.
So something like just a generic
ass cool DM on the one and another
one, you can do something like
praising them for some content and
being genuine.
See if they reply or not on that
channel.
Because
sometimes you'll see that someone
is totally dead or they're just
using, you know, many chat or AI
or
something.
You're like, all right, I'm
probably not going to reach out
first on this channel.
I'll go
reach out and focus my time and
effort on another platform,
another channel, just by testing
with
burner accounts.
So send them stuff in person,
right?
Gifts, lunches, notes, add a QR
code on
other things as well.
It's a great way.
I send like donuts all the time to
people like coffee and
donuts to their main offices.
This works better with B2B, right?
You can actually pull their office
and headquarters locations.
So this works fantastic, by the
way, really well.
Call them just flat out for
call them.
Digital Starbucks card.
This is a hack.
Okay.
There is guaranteed deliverability
on a digital
Starbucks card email.
You will land in their primary.
All the cool email guys, Starbucks
has to be every
time.
Okay.
So if you have a dream 100
deliverable document, right?
You can have a bit.ly.
So it can be
like bit.ly slash Patrick by
David.
You can attach it to the
description of a Starbucks card
with a little
note and send them that card to
their email and it will land as
guaranteed deliverability.
If it's the
wrong email address, it will just
bounce back.
So you can just like keep trying
different emails.
If you
have multiple emails for a
prospect, this works super
freaking well.
So hit all channels, hit their
partners, not their wives, okay?
Their partners, their business
partners and executive staff.
Join their
coaching program, community, or
just pay for consulting calls from
them.
Use a connection or mentorship
platform to guarantee connection.
Again, like Manect is fantastic
for this.
Intro.co, I believe, is another
one that's really good for this,
but pay someone for their time and
then present the deliverable to
them.
It's
fantastic.
Ask them to be on a podcast.
If you guys have podcasts like Jax
Dwyer in here, he has a podcast
and he
cooks with it.
Like if he just did Dream 100 all
day long, he could just slam this.
Like just keep
crushing it.
So ask them to be on a podcast.
You'll be surprised at how many
people say yes to being on a
podcast versus yes, then hopping
on a call.
It's crazy nowadays.
So attend their events, go to
their
events with a thumb drive and a
stack of paper or something, hand
it to the actual person.
You know, publicly
post and tag them.
It's another thing, especially if
you're reaching out to like a
medium or smaller size
influencer, they have a much
higher probability of looking at
what you tag them in versus like
an
Alex or Mosey.
LinkedIn in-mail.
In-mail credits have pretty much a
guaranteed deliverability within
their inbox and email.
So you'll basically be able to
reach out to somebody with in-mail
credits.
If you have a, I think it's a
LinkedIn premium or it's the
LinkedIn sales navigator
subscription,
you have a certain amount of
LinkedIn in-mail credits you can
use per month to basically
guarantee
someone sees your outreach
message.
And then a calendar invite with
the deliverable description.
I've done this a handful of times.
It actually gets some pretty,
pretty funny responses to it, but
literally sending someone a
calendar invite with a deliverable
in the description saying, let's
go over
this and like, let's fix your ads.
Let's fix your funnel.
And then in the description, like,
yo, I did
this for you, blah, blah, blah.
It works really good.
Leverage a connection with someone
lower than
them in the company.
So build a connection, leverage
it, uh, raise up, literally fly to
the freaking
office.
If it's a big enough deal, of
course, it makes sense and
monetary and logical sense to do
so.
Definitely can do it.
Uh, post grade or sendoso.
These are direct mail services to
use
deck for multiple email addresses
and keep cross-checking those and
sending a basic repeat the process
and
send it to them.
Send them a YouTube video
explaining the deliverable tag
them in a post
again, or invite, uh, them to
collaborate on Instagram.
So the invite to collaborate has
been
really good, uh, lately for some
people that I've explained this
strategy to because it actually
shows
up in the, uh, in the primary and
in their notifications that this
person wants to collaborate
with you on a post.
So it'll basically just make a
post of you breaking down the
deliverable for them
and ask that person or influencer
to collaborate with them on that
post and they'll see it.
Message other people at the
company with the same, um, method,
right?
So you can repeat all this
stuff for directors, managers,
executive team, et cetera.
So in essence, if you relentlessly
follow
up multiple times through multiple
methods, through multiple
channels, you will get a reply one
way
I promise you that I promise you
that.
So just keep following up.
If you don't go back to your
targeting and research and find
someone bigger and more
attractive.
Now, module two, let's dive into
the path to scaling your agency
with dream 100.