All right, getting to the end
guys.
Module 12, your path to scaling
your agency with the Dream 100
outreach method.
Here we go.
I just want to draw this little
diagram for you guys.
So Dream 100 is really good for
you if you're just starting out,
don't have a lot of case studies,
right?
Not a lot of stuff to leverage and
don't have a big marketing budget.
You're between that zero to 10k
range per month.
So that's really what you want to
focus on to get you up towards
that 10k per month range where you
can start to layer on something
like cold email.
That's a little bit more mass
while still doing Dream 100.
But now focusing a little bit more
on those like case study builders.
Remember back a few modules ago,
we talked about, you know, the two
paths of Dream 100, the
moneymaking path and the case
study building path.
Okay.
So up here, when you're just
starting out, you want to really
have that moneymaking path.
You just want to get some reps in,
sign some deals, start stacking up
a couple of testimonials and start
stacking up some cash.
So then you can layer on a channel
like cold email once you're
between 10 and 25k per month and
also just keep doing Dream 100,
but start to shift it a little bit
more towards that like case study
builder point.
And then once you get to like 30k
per month, this is where you want
to just do, you know, paid ads,
layer that on, cold email, keep
scaling that and Dream 100 only to
whales.
Ones that are just going to be
huge deals for you, big case
studies and big builders in the
whole time, make some content,
keep ripping out content.
So when you're first starting out,
you, you know, don't have proof,
right?
So this is something I really want
to talk about when you're scaling
your agency is, you know, you can
go out in there and copy winning
offers, but the proof is what will
really help you sell things.
Okay.
That's really going to help you
sell your services.
So doing free work in implementing
the Dream 100 is a way to speed
run your proof in your proof
acquisition, basically to fuel
further scaling.
So what I mean by this is like, if
you stay niched, you're going to
be able to get bigger and bigger
testimonials from people in your
industry that are huge whales and
big fish, right?
So that all goes back to this
slide right here when I was
talking about stacking up proof.
So when you're starting out from
nothing, you're starting out from
scratch, you need to get this
proof that you know what you're
doing.
So you can basically speed run
your way to that and becoming an
authority figure in your space and
in your industry and in your niche
just by using Dream 100, staying
niched and going after the whales
in your industry.
Because for example, me with Gym
Launch, I signed Gym Launch.
Guess what?
They're pretty high up there in
the totem pool of info product
companies.
Everyone below them that I'm like,
yo, I work in Gym Launch.
You're like, oh shoot, you know
your stuff, right?
Even people that are on that level
with Gym Launch doing the same
kind of revenue and same
reputation in the industry and
everything, they're like, oh yeah,
he knows what he's doing.
He works with them.
So basically, you just want to
build like an endless conga line
of testimonials and proof that you
have helped major players in that
industry and keep going up the
food chain.
You will now blow everyone out of
the water who has a similar offer
because you have the proof that
you know what you're doing and
you've worked with big companies
before in the same industry.
So that's a big thing, again, that
I want to really just place here
with Dream 100 is it's a great
acquisition strategy to stack up
money and stuff like that.
But it's even better to be
hyper-targeted to these big
companies like you can get
hyper-targeted with your outreach
methods and only target ones that
are going to be big fish in your
space and just stack up, like help
you stack up authority within your
industry and your ICP so you can
really just keep leveling up
there.
So again, that's what I'm doing
with like my funnel build-up
offer, build-out offer right now.
I'm just stacking bigger and
bigger whales and until I've
worked with the biggest names in
the industry, it's like a frigging
ladder.
So final side note, if nobody
wants your free work, then shift
your ICP or your deliverable or
offer completely because that's a
very big indication.
If you do 100 outreaches and no
one wants your stuff, then you
know there's something wrong with
your ICP, your research,
deliverable, or offer.
So there's something there.
So you got to really like look at
it from a high level and see what
the issue is.
Word just asked me.
I got you.
So dream 100 is a tough strategy.
Most will give up.
So don't.
Okay.
Now we're going to move into
module 13 real quick, which is
your action items.