All right.
Final module here, guys.
Your action items.
So congrats on making it through
this
entire training.
Now let's show you what you
actually need to do to start
scaling step by
step.
So first, carve out two to three
hours of your day initially, if
not more, if you can,
especially if you're newer, got to
crank those numbers up for the
next 90 days.
Follow the strategy, everything in
here.
Make money.
All right.
Start sending stuff.
You just
got to freaking start.
That's really it.
Ask me any questions in Slack.
I got you.
Shoot me a DM.
It's just Evan, see it in Slack.
I'll help you out.
But action steps are pretty
simple, right?
Carve out time out of your day.
Start sending messages.
Start making deliverables.
Start doing
the research and reach out.
Ask questions.
There's a lot of people in the
community doing this.
I've done it a lot.
So you can ask me, lean on me, and
I got you.
So let's start making some money
with your 100.
I appreciate your time going
through this entire module.
I've had a great time with you
guys.
Again, let's start cooking and
making some money.
Peace.