All right it is time to celebrate
why because we're in module two of
the dream 100 process i
think i might keep these like
tunes going in the beginning to
kind of keep you guys that are
binge
watching this stuff a little bit
you know amped up and everything
so anyways let's dive into
module two which we're actually
going to be going over what the
dream 100 process is so
when you're looking to launch a
dream 100 campaign what are the
steps you need to take
to basically sequentially develop
your campaign and run it
successfully so first off got to
know
your industry right what industry
are you serving so for this
example that i'm going to run
through
all the way down let's just say
you're targeting uh you know
online coaches okay so i'm
targeting
online coaches i'm trying to get
them to run better ads okay what
i'm going to do next is i'm going
to
take that industry online coaches
and i'm going to go and find my
dream 100 prospects within that
industry okay so what are my 100
prospects within that industry
within the coaching industry that
i
actually want to go reach out to
then i'm going to make that list
of the 100 dream prospects right
so
i'm going to list out 100
different coaches in that industry
that i want to work with based on
different
criteria which we'll dive into in
a little bit once we really
determine what a qualified
prospect is
and individually i'm going to do
some research on each and every
one of them to see
what value i can provide them is
it uh maybe their creative suck
right i can give them some better
creatives i can make some better
statics for them up front their ad
copy sucks maybe i can help them
with that maybe their funnel is
really bad and i can go and kind
of give them a new funnel map or a
new
landing page build up front to try
and get my foot in the door with
them then after that i'm going to
create a dream 100 deliverable for
them so the actual thing that i'm
providing them of value
then we're going to send them that
deliverable on as many targeted
channels as you need
we're going to follow up with them
then we're going to book call with
them
and then we're going to close them
okay that's the process so we
start with the industry
right i want to target online
coaches then we research online
coaches within that industry
and we say all right these are the
hundred people that i want to work
with these are perfect
prospects i know i can help them
now we take those hundred and
individually research them we see
what we can actually help them
with that corresponds with our
core offer and our service and our
best
uh you know ability and skill sets
to provide value and then we
create the actual dream 100
deliverable for them we send it to
them on as many freaking channels
we possibly can okay we'll get
into that
later we follow up with them we
book a call and then we close so
how do we actually find the dream
prospects right you got to
leverage social media it's
everywhere right ain't going away
so use search
features on x instagram facebook
linkedin um that's a big thing
right so in eamon's video which in
the
first module i showed you guys he
does a great job of breaking down
on x how he actually goes and
finds
people so what uh i personally do
is i take a piece from that book
and also just use the search
features
as a whole so tiktoks as well has
been really good so for example if
i'm searching for um online
coaches
right i'm trying to find a hundred
online coaches that i want to
reach out to i'm going to go find
someone's account like uh andre's
that's the one that aemon used in
his example i'm going to go find
account like andre who you know is
a medium-sized influencer he's not
as big as hormosie maybe one
day he's going to catch up to him
but not as big as hormosie where
there's just a ton to sift through
he has a little bit more of a
targeted smaller and more
sophisticated audience of people
who are coaches
and you know agency owners so i
can go there and i can start to
look through his following right
so you
can first off search people within
that actual industry find someone
that has a small to medium
sized targeted audience and
consistently putting out content
look at their followers and who
they're
following and find different
people in that industry that way
or you can just use the search
features
on these platforms and say online
coaches agency owners ecom store
owner ecom brand owner right
stuff like that and you'll be able
to find a ton of a ton of people
to add into your dream 100 list
right so again this is another
thing too that i do is when i'm
just sitting there scrolling
through
instagram and scrolling through
facebook and twitter and stuff
i'll save profiles as i'm
consuming their
content right so i help i
personally help info products um
coaches agencies and sas companies
scale
so if i'm scrolling and i see
someone that i've never talked to
and never really done anything
like this
for or for before you know never
sent them any dream 100 uh
outreach deliverables i'll save
their profile
add it to my list and i'll go and
see if there's something that i
can do for them there
you could also join coaching
programs and groups within your
actual icp
so this is something that i need
to have a big warning on make sure
you aren't breaking any rules
with this and are not coming off
as being spammy okay so to succeed
with this genuinely you have to
provide an insane amount of value
up front with your deliverable and
have zero expectation of return
okay so don't just start going and
joining a bunch of 97 a month
groups and 10 000 a year groups
and just
start spamming everybody in there
with uh you know dream 100 stuff
like be very targeted with this be
a
a little bit careful right you
want to be you want to join a
group and then slowly elevate
yourself up to an authority figure
in that group by providing a lot
of free value and reaching out to
people individually on a very nice
and genuine basis like hey i saw
you were doing this i saw you just
posted about you know starting
your ad campaigns and i just
looked at some of your copy it was
a little
you know off i just made five for
you and wanted to give this to you
here so just be very careful with
this because you don't want to be
those you know dm setters that go
into these school groups and just
start spamming people okay but it
is a great a great way to uh to do
to do so so what actually is a
qualified dream 100 prospect so i
define a qualified prospect as
someone who is consistently
posting
content somewhere online has an
online presence in some capacity
has a landing page or website is
running
ads that's personally for me i
want to see people that are
running ads so this can be removed
if you don't you know have this
and if they can you can basically
just remove some of these or keep
them as you wish these are just
mine right uh and clearly is an
established business so for
example
some like roofing companies may
not be posting content or running
ads but you can search their
company
online to gauge reviews how long
they've been in business directory
listings etc so any combination
of these i deem as a qualified
prospect the more the better
though so the more that they have
like if
they're clearly an established
business they're running ads they
have a landing page or website
they have an online presence
they're consistently posting
content online they are an a plus
prospect to
me and i'm going to prioritize as
i'm working down my dream 100 list
of prospects i'm going to
prioritize
them over the other ones they're
like my a plus tier prospects to
reach out to so they get a high
priority stamp on there so that is
module two quick one for you let's
dive into module three after this
which will be the actual dream 100
deliverables