All right, so on this one, I don't
necessarily have an intro song for
you because I couldn't
figure out one, but I'm going to
figure out some other ones, keep
you pepped up, keep
you rocking through these modules
here in the future ones, but we're
on module three,
so listen up because this is one
of the most important modules of
this entire course is
going over your Dream 100
deliverables, so what you're
actually going to send the
prospect
during your Dream 100 campaigns,
okay?
I get this question all the time,
what should I do for free work,
what should I actually
send somebody with my Dream 100
outreach strategy?
This comes down to your research
entirely, okay?
So remember, you are doing custom
free upfront work for people to
prove that you can actually
provide them value and that you
are a subject matter expert in the
actual topic and offer
that you're trying to pitch them
on and you know what you're doing
to help their business
grow in whatever area you're an
expert in, okay?
That's essentially what you're
doing.
You're saying, hey, I'm showing
you that I can do the job well and
I can grow your business
in this specific area and here is
proof of that by sending them
stuff for free upfront that
they can get results with
immediately.
So what you do, you know, what you
actually deliver to them as free
work has to be a blend
of what they need and what you can
provide to them at a high level.
So there's two things that you can
do with people.
First off, you can help them start
something totally new, okay?
Or you can optimize something
they're currently doing for them.
So let's go into a couple examples
of each one.
First off, let's say you want to
reach out to Alex Ramosi.
You see he's not posting on
Reddit.
So guess what?
You can make him 30 days of plug
and play posts for Reddit to help
him start posting on Reddit,
start doing something new to grow
his audience on Reddit and get
more clients from Reddit.
Or you can go and help Daniel
Fazio start to make more short
form content.
So you can basically chop up 30
days of post form and captions and
say, hey, Daniel, here
are 30 days I've done for you
posts that you can take to start
reaching a big audience on
YouTube, Instagram, Twitter.
I see you're doing a ton of
tweets.
So I took some of your like, you
know, past YouTube videos and your
past tweets and just
took the tweets and made them kind
of more like captions here for you
to plug.
And then I also took your high
performing YouTube videos and chop
those up in the short forms
that you can take here.
So doing something upfront that
they aren't doing and helping them
start something new is
a great way to, uh, to basically
garner their business and get
attention.
And another thing too, a lot of
you guys that are doing cold email
are like, what do I do?
Well, here's something you could
do is you can write them scripts,
cold email scripts, and you
can give them a full guide on
setting up cold email
infrastructure that your agency
uses
for clients.
Yes.
You're giving them the sauce,
right?
You're giving them the secrets and
you're going to sell the
implementation down the line.
That's what you're doing.
You're giving them the secrets and
then you're selling the
implementation.
So basically you'd be like, Hey,
agency owner, you know, I saw you
running ads.
Um, not sure if you're doing cold
email, but if you're not, you're
missing out on a boatload
of clients like our clients right
now are averaging anywhere from
five to 10 closed deals per month,
just through cold email.
So what I went ahead is I looked
at your offer.
I look at your landing page, some
of your content.
I wrote you scripts that I know
will work really well for cold
email based upon your entire offer
and what you have online right
now.
And I also gave you right here a
full guide on how to actually set
up this cold email
infrastructure, how to land, you
know, in the primary inbox left
and right, how to set up
your domains and inboxes and
everything, uh, step by step.
It's the same stuff that we use at
our agency to help, you know, X,
Y, Z number of clients
get X, Y, Z results.
And I know it's going to get you a
ton of results too.
So that's a fantastic way that you
can basically go to somebody and
be like, yo, uh, instead of
just them, instead of you just
basically being like, yo, you
should start cold email.
You're actually giving them the
blueprint and the resources to
start it.
And then they're going to be like,
well, this is a ton.
Uh, wow.
Can you just like do it for me?
How much do you just charge?
Do it for me.
Right.
Or they sometimes like I've sent
people stuff and they take it and
they actually use it
and they come back and like, dude,
that works really good.
You know what you're doing?
How can we work together?
So be, you know, it's okay.
If someone takes your dream 100
deliverable and just like runs
with it and gets results,
that's awesome.
Right.
That's fantastic.
Be okay with that.
For sure.
But the other side of things that
you can do is you can optimize
something for them that
they're currently doing.
So for example, this is kind of
what I did for a little while is I
would fix up people's
landing pages, funnels, and
websites.
So I had like a CRO offer at the
time.
So I would redo their landing page
or a hero section for free in a
nice Figma board and
send it off to them and say, Hey,
I saw you were running traffic for
XYZ offer to this
landing page right here.
You're missing out on a ton of
traffic that could be converting
into book calls for your team.
So I went ahead and redid the
entire structure and copy of your
landing page to make it more
congruent with your ads and your
offer and make it more compelling.
By the way, this is a Figma board
that you can take and give to your
current developer and just build
into whatever funnel building
platform or website platform you
use right now.
Or if you want, we can just
schedule a quick 15 minute call.
I can introduce myself, break down
the actual page a little bit more,
and then I'll build
it into your platform 100% for
free.
So that's another thing that I
like to do.
And it's also, I'll get into this
later, but it's beating the call.
It's hooking that call with your
actual deliverables.
So that's something that you can
do if you see someone doing
something, you can take what
they're existing, what they're
currently doing and optimize it
some more.
So for example, another thing too,
I get a lot of guys that hit me up
like,
I'm in such a crazy productized
industry.
Like I'm fighting with Fiverr and
Upwork people, you know, like
thumbnails.
YouTube thumbnails are a great
example of this.
So how do you break through the
noise?
Well, you can go and redesign
three thumbnails for the actual
prospect, focusing on beating
their current CTR, it's supposed
to say CTR, not CTA, and tell them
that you'll make their
next two free thumbnails as well,
right?
So if you make thumbnails, you can
go, Hey, John, I saw that you're
making awesome YouTube
content.
I love it.
I made three thumbnails that based
upon my experience, I think are
style a little bit
better for your industry and can
help you get a better
click-through rate, which is a
huge
thing on YouTube to get you a ton
of organic reach and clients and
everything.
So I redesigned three with a
click-through rate in mind.
And by the way, if you have like
two videos that are coming out or
already planning to come
out and are in editing, I'd love
to hop on a quick 15 minute call
with you to start to
design those two for you for free
so we can get a jump on them.
So I want to help you out and help
drive up those click-through rates
for you.
And then finally, you know,
helping someone, something as
broad as like increasing their
ROAS, right?
You can basically say, Hey, uh, I
made five to 10 static ads after
looking through your
meta ad library that, uh, will
help you, you know, basically
drive up your ROAS and get
you a lot more, uh, click-through
rates and basically sell your
offer better, uh, through
ads and through paid advertising.
And you can just deliver that to
them and literally just tell them,
Hey, plug and play
these run them against what you're
currently doing.
And I guarantee that they're going
to beat what you're currently
doing.
Um, sometimes if I know they're
really going to do well, I'll even
go as bold to say to
them is like, I'll even pay for,
you know, um, I'll pay you $500
for wasted spend.
If they don't beat your current
ads within $500, right?
So it's basically like no risk
them.
So key points to remember with any
dream 100 deliverable, okay, is
everything needs
to be as plug and play for them as
possible.
Okay.
So, you know, you don't want to
basically give them something
that's like fragmented, uh,
kind of like going back to the
cold email example over here.
You don't just want to like give
them a script and then be like,
yeah, good luck with all the
other stuff.
Like cheers.
The script is worthless to them
because they don't have the
infrastructure.
They don't even know how to set up
the infrastructure.
Like there's so much there.
So you want to be, you want to
make it very plug and play for
them as possible, the thing
that you're giving them.
Then you want to make it custom to
what they specifically need.
This is the key.
So take the extra 10 minutes to
ensure that you really understand
what problems they have,
what problems they need to be
solved or they need to have solved
and how you can actually
solve them.
Okay.
So this is something like, I have
a lot of guys that have reached
out to me that run content
agencies and like, I don't know
why, you know, I'm trying to reach
out to people
that have 300,000 subscribers on
YouTube and I'm trying to write
scripts for them and edit
for them and they won't reply to
me.
Well, here's the thing.
Guess what?
Cause you're going after like guys
that already have it established,
right?
They already have, they really
don't have that many problems with
like editing and scripting
and all that.
Everything's already dialed in.
So you're basically trying to, you
know, sell something or give
something to somebody that
doesn't necessarily need it,
right?
Go to someone like me.
If you look at my YouTube, I have
like four videos.
I clearly do not have a good
editor.
I clearly do not have a good, uh,
you know, scripting process.
Like go to me because you see on
all these other platforms, I'm
posting constantly, I'm
posting constantly, I'm posting,
you know, revenue numbers.
So I'm, you know, all everywhere
online besides like YouTube and
stuff and YouTube, I'm just
slacking on, right?
So that's an example.
Go to somebody that actually
clearly from the outside needs
your service and doesn't
necessarily
have it fully dialed in.
Now on the flip side, if you are
targeting someone that has 300,000
followers and you clearly
see that their thumbnails suck and
you can provide great, you know,
specific knowledge
around that and specific value
around that very small thing of
their whole system and vortex
that they have going on, then do
that because that's going to stand
out.
It's more niche versus this broad
thing, right?
And what I tried to do too, is I
touched on this a little bit
earlier, but try to weave in
like a mandatory call to implement
the free work, uh, deliverable
that you did.
So for example, again, with the
landing pages, I would redesign a
landing page in Figma.
So I would send them the Figma
file, then tell them if you, uh,
you know, like this file,
we can hop on a quick 10 minute
call so I can get you to log into
your platform, uh, meet
you real quick.
So, you know, I'm not some crazy
dude off the internet and I'll
build them there completely
for free.
So you can just start running it
immediately.
And then writing cold email
scripts for someone you can, you
know, angle the deliverable
as a cold outreach script.
So you can use immediately to
generate warm leads, you know,
send them the scripts, send
them the actual infrastructure set
up and then try to get on a quick
10 to 15 minute call
where you can show them actually
the next steps to take the scripts
that you have and take
the infrastructure map and
step-by-step guide that you built
for them and show them what
to do next, right?
Make it again as plug and play and
easy as possible for them to do.
And also with all this here, you
got to be freaking relentless when
getting value.
Like just try to make someone's
life better.
Try to make their business better.
Try to make them better.
That's huge, right?
Be like Joe Rogan here.
This dude is relentless as
freaking heck.
He will get any interview, right?
He's, he's might not be providing
value to Conor McGregor's life at
this point here, but
this dude is relentless.
Okay.
So be like him.
Give value to people.
So how much free work should you
actually do, you know, you should
be going after a dream
100 prospects, right?
Let me emphasize one thing here.
Dream 100 prospects, the word
dream.
Okay.
Right here.
Big letters.
Dream.
These are the people that you
should be going after.
Like anyone can be a high paying
client.
I understand that, but you want to
be targeting proven people that
are dream prospects that from
the outside looking in are
qualified enough to pay you a good
chunk of cash.
If they like your work, it will be
a great case study builder in your
industry.
Again, this is a fast way to fast
strike growth.
So in knowing that you should put
some additional effort and time
into the free work that you do,
your reputation and money is on
the line.
So make it count.
Okay.
So again, this all kind of ties
in, right?
I didn't give you a clear answer.
I'll give you a clear answer in a
few slides here, but how much free
work you should do.
You should really change that
mindset to how much value should I
give somebody?
How long does it take to give the
necessary value to this person
that I need for them to
actually look at me and be like,
yo, this guy knows what he's
doing.
He helped us so much.
I need to talk to him more.
Right?
So just think, what would I have
to do to virtually guarantee that
XYZ person works
with me, notices me and sees the
value that I can provide them.
Now go ahead and do that work and
take as long as you need to get
that actual result and to
provide them with something of
immense, insane value.
So on one singular deliverable.
Okay.
Again, keep that in mind that you
want to really put a ton of time
and effort as much as needed
to send them something good and of
value.
Cause that's your whole campaign
relies on that.
Your whole lifeblood of your
campaign relies on you actually
sending them something good,
but how long should you actually
spend on one singular deliverable?
So one singular thing that I'm
going to send one prospect.
So first you have to decide what
your true goal with dream 100 is.
Are you trying to make money and
close deals?
So you're under like 10 K a month
trying to scale, or are you trying
to stack case studies
to accelerate growth?
So usually between that, like 10,
15, 30 K per month range.
So these are the two paths of
dream 100.
It's not really meant to be a
long-term acquisition channel,
right?
Your people that are at, you know,
500 K a month aren't necessarily
doing this, but it's
a great way to fast track your
growth.
So these are kind of a two paths
that you can take.
So if you take the case study
route, you're basically looking at
anywhere from three to
five hours plus per deliverable,
and you're doing about two to
three per week.
Oops.
And the money-making route, you're
doing about one to two hours per
deliverable, and you're
doing about one to two per day
you're sending out.
So why, why the big difference?
Case study builders are usually
bigger companies, right?
Like these are the gym launches.
So these are the huge companies
that you really want to make a fat
impact on.
You want to make a huge impression
on, right?
These are the people that you want
to sign that are whales in your
industry.
So I'm putting a lot of effort, a
lot of time, and a lot of work
into these deliverables
that I send them.
So I'm only sending about two to
three a week.
You know, these are the guys like,
right now I'm reaching out to Andy
Elliott.
You know, that's another one.
Like Jeremy Miner, I'm reaching
out to him.
So then you have the money-making
route, which is a little bit more
high volume.
It's not like cold DMs at all.
Don't, don't get me wrong.
It's not cold DMs, but it's a
little more high volume, right?
You want to pump out one to two
per day.
So if you're below like 10K a
month, this is kind of the route
you want to do.
Just keep like ripping out,
ripping out, ripping out, ripping
out and getting reps in.
So this would take one to two
hours per deliverable.
So you can do about one to two per
day.
If you can get up to three,
awesome.
But again, we got to go back to
these slides here.
That's why I had it beforehand.
How much free work should you do?
How long should you spend on it?
Again, these are some rough
timeframes right here and times.
But again, got to focus on making
these things good, man, and
putting a lot of work into them
and putting a lot of effort and
time into making them top-notch
and really give a great impression
to the client or prospect.
So organizing an outreach
document, what should you actually
put inside?
So I use gamma.app or Google Docs,
how to structure it.
You know, you basically have the
intro.
So explain the problem, the video.
I always put a video in mine.
Every time I put a Loom video or
YouTube video or something,
explaining what's in the document,
what the deliverable is,
why I'm reaching out to them, and
breaking down the actual thing
that they're seeing.
So the deliverable, deliverable
breakdown.
So what is it?
Why should they care about this?
The next steps, give clear next
steps.
This is, again, where you pitch
that call.
And I sometimes like to do a quick
bio, too.
So I'll do a quick little bio
myself.
So I am with contact info.
So definitely phone number,
definitely email.
I've literally had people call me
and text me.
It's fantastic.
So put your freaking phone in
there.
And photo, make it look a little
bit more human-like.
If you want to put your social
links, too, I do that as well.
And over here, I'm going to send
this actual presentation and have
it linked for you guys below in
this module.
So these are three different
clickable sections that you can
look at.
So right here is Andrew Tate's
videographer.
He made a fantastic Twitter thread
about this strategy, essentially,
and how he landed Andrew Tate as a
client.
So that's definitely one to check
out.
Over here is a Dream 100 outreach
deliverable document that I wrote
and did for Patrick Bet David,
redesigning their landing pages.
And then over here is the gym
launch document I did to actually
sign them that I'm going to go
over in much more depth coming up
here.
So note, if it's something like a
thumbnail or something you do
with, you know, you're sending
someone something that has like a
visual design aspect to it, right?
A thumbnail, a landing page
redesign, a static graphic, social
media images.
You can get away with just sending
them the images in your initial
message, right?
So this is what someone actually
sent me on Instagram.
They're like, yo, I redesigned a
few thumbnails for you.
I saw you were missing a couple
like here, three of them that you
can take right away and download
and put them in your YouTube.
So this is pretty cool because it
like showed as I opened up the
Instagram message like, oh, cool.
I don't have to click on something
else and go to another page, go
through another step.
It's just right there for me.
So that was awesome, right?
Really caught my attention, caught
my eye.
So how do we make successful free
work that actually converts?
So you have to make it custom to
them and what they need.
Again, don't make it salesy,
right?
That's a big thing.
A lot of people will try to make
these super salesy and they'll
have a big old document explaining
their whole process and their
unique mechanism and why they
should care about, you know, low
ticket funnels.
And, you know, why they should
care about YouTube content and all
this stuff.
And then they'll just be slamming
these CTAs with a call.
Like, don't do that.
Okay.
Again, we want to come from a
standpoint of genuine value up
front and we want to actually make
it good.
We're going to make it easy for
them to use, implement and
consume.
And this is a big frame of mind
here.
Treat the free work like you got
paid for it.
And now we're going to move into
module four on the next one.
We're going to go over the gym
lodge case study that I did.