All right, everybody.
Welcome to module four.
I'm just going to do a quick
overview of the actual document
that got me to launch the client.
So basically, long story short, I
had a couple of contacts that I
knew I could reach out to, to
potentially get in contact with
someone from their team.
So it was a little bit far
stretched down the line, but I was
like, look, these guys need help
with copy.
They need help with emails big
time.
They're not even running a call,
running a call funnel with a VSL.
Like there's so much value I can
provide them.
And they're a huge case study
builder client for me.
I'm going to sit down the next two
days, three days, and just crank
out a document with a ton of value
and a ton of plug and play assets
that they can take to scale their
business.
So what I actually put inside of
this document, and by the way,
it's 101 pages.
I'll link it down below.
So you guys can see the actual
video that I use the loom video
that I sent them.
You know, I had the about me on
here and everything.
So what I did was I literally went
and made email and SMS nurture
series for them.
So I told them they can plug and
play these into their HubSpot CRM
to nurture and close and book
calls with new leads that came
through their funnel.
I had a seven day value-based
email newsletter that they can
literally just take again and plug
into their current CRM and just
run with and get results with.
So again, plug and play.
I literally have up here, plug and
play in the title, Twitter,
LinkedIn, and meta threads, lead
gen, and, you know, value-based
posts that they can use for social
media to start, you know,
generating a lot of leads and a
lot of traction on those
platforms.
Because I saw that they were
really lacking on, you know,
content for Twitter, LinkedIn, and
meta threads.
VSL, again, they've never ran a
VSL.
So I literally was like, hey, you
guys need to run a VSL.
Like, here's a VSL script.
Please do this.
Please film this.
And like, let's go.
I'll even edit it.
Let's just go.
Book a call funnel landing page.
I had a whole Figma template that
they can pull and run with.
Facebook group engagement ideas
and proposed structure.
So they had a Facebook group.
They were working that had about
12,000 people at the time.
They don't use it anymore.
We switched to school with them.
But, you know, they just weren't
getting a lot of good engagement
in that group.
And I could see that.
So gave them some engagement
ideas, some post examples, and
also told them some other ways
that they can structure the group
to get more engagement and close
more deals from the group.
Over here, I had some, like,
additional growth ideas, too.
And then some sales assets for,
again, growth, which were, like,
lead magnets.
So it's pretty detailed, right?
Everything here was fully plug and
play, right?
Like, I had some graphics in here.
I had, you know, an overview of
each section, some instructions
for them to take and plug and
play, right?
So I said, hey, in the video, you
guys can literally just, like,
take these sections and give it
off to whatever team member that
is responsible for these.
Or, again, I can help you
implement it if you don't have
someone for that.
But I kind of, like, was not
really trying to pitch myself the
whole time.
I was like, hey, I analyzed your
business.
Here are some things you can do
and pass this off to whatever team
member.
So it, like, lowers their guard a
little bit more.
So it was a very long, long
document, right?
Had some images.
Like, I'm just showing you guys
this to show you, like, when you
have a potential in with a company
and you really are passionate
about helping them and you know
you can get them results, you've
got to go balls to the wall like
this.
It works and it pays off.
I did this with Jason Wojo.
I'm currently doing this with a
couple other clients.
I was on Wall Street.
I got a great rev share retainer
from them.
It's a base of about 5K a month
plus 10% rev share.
It's fantastic.
You know, August, I made, like,
25K from them just alone in one
wire.
Just because, like, I did the same
exact stuff here.
I just went and just gave a ton of
value and showed that I can help
their business grow in different
areas.
I mean, look, I even made, like,
GIFs to plug into emails to help
raise, you know, click rates and
stuff.
So there's a lot that you can
provide in these documents.
Again, this is an example of one
that just went really, you know,
just went, like, really hard with
it and just kept adding stuff and
adding stuff.
So it was 101 pages.
You don't need to go this
aggressive each time, but I just
wanted to use this as an example
case study to show you that, one,
this strategy works.
Two, you know, sending someone 101
pages of stuff will separate you
from everyone else that is
reaching out to them.
I promise you that.
And it will show your worth.
And three, like, again, if you
have a hook or you have an in with
a company that you really want to
work with, dude, sit down for two
to three days and just grind
something out like this because
it's going to pay off in the end.
So I'll link this in the bottom
here so you guys can check it out,
but let's move on to the next
model.