Alright, welcome back to the
slides.
Module 5, we're going to talk
about reaching out to your
prospects now.
So, you already did the research,
you know the process, you know who
you're reaching out to, you know
what you're providing them, and
how you're going to build it.
Now we're actually going to go
into the process of reaching out
to them, getting in contact with
them, and delivering them this
actual free work.
So first off, where do I contact
them?
Short answer, freaking everywhere
you can, alright?
Social media, email, coaching
programs, SMS, and phone calls.
Direct mail, I've even done it
before, I've done direct mail.
Pay for consulting calls, this is
a pure hack.
There are also platforms out
there, like Manect, for example,
Patrick Brett Davids, that you can
literally pay someone for their
time.
You pay them for a call.
You guarantee that they show up to
a call, that you can then give
them the free work on.
It's a freaking hack, okay?
So, be resourceful.
You've got to pay for these,
right?
But you can literally just
guarantee that someone sees your
stuff by paying them for a call.
It's insane.
One of the biggest hacks that you
guys can get out of this entire
massive presentation module is
that, right there.
So, then get creative.
Anyone can be contacted with
enough effort.
This is a fantastic book to read,
how to get a meeting with anyone.
I don't know how to pronounce his
last name, but Stu.
Fantastic offer, great book.
It shows you some very creative
ways to get in contact with people
and kind of the process of really
reaching out to high-level people.
So, it's a fantastic book to read.
So, reaching out to larger
companies.
A lot of you guys are working
with, you know, e-com companies
and just bigger companies that
have a lot of staff.
And the owner is not just someone
you can just DM on Instagram or,
you know, find their email online
easy and just send something to
them.
So, what do you actually have to
do to reach out to larger
companies?
First off, think of it like cold
email.
You want to hit as many decision
makers as possible.
If you provide great free work
that is valuable, even people
lower on the food chain will pass
that deliverable and message along
up the chain to people that are
decision makers, right?
They're going to feel so compelled
that like, shoot, this guy sent me
101 pages of work.
If I don't pass this along and it
gets to like my superiors, like,
I'm screwed.
They're going to yell at me,
right?
That's what you want.
That's, again, why it goes back to
the point of making your stuff so
good and so genuine of wanting to
help out that company that it'll
make people even lower on the food
chain within that company.
Pass it along, right?
So, don't just, you know, send a
funnel design, for example.
That's a good thing.
So, just, you know, don't send.
When you're sending outreach
messages to people, understand who
you're sending it to in the first
place.
I made this mistake once.
I sent a funnel redesign to their
funnel builder.
Don't know how I actually did
that, but I ended up doing it.
And guess where that went?
Right to the trash immediately.
So, just be a little bit conscious
of that.
Like, if you're sending someone,
you know, YouTube scripts or
trying to be a YouTube manager for
a company, don't send stuff to
their YouTube manager.
That's just, you know, a common
thing.
Send it to their director of
marketing or their CMO or the
owner, the CEO, the COO, something
like that.
Some other decision maker besides
someone just directly in line with
what you're trying to basically
replace.
So, what do I say when I send the
work?
You want to make it very tailored
to them and specific to the
problem you are solving for them
and what you observed in your
research process.
So, don't make this part generic.
You did all this upfront work, so
don't blow it here.
So, for example, you say,
Hey, name, I saw you've been
ramping up the content volume on
YouTube lately, which is awesome.
Love the recent video you did on
XYZ topic.
I noticed a few things on your
thumbnails, though, that can drive
up your click-through rate pretty
fast.
Here are three thumbnails for your
last three videos you can swap out
immediately that will drive
results and get a better
click-through rate.
I guarantee it.
I'll also make your next two
thumbnails completely for free
with that whole goal and objective
of raising your click-through rate
in mind.
I don't just make thumbnails to
make them look pretty and cute and
stuff and all this nice, cool
stuff.
I raise it with results in mind
and driving your click-through
rate up through the freaking roof.
So, are you free to hop on maybe a
quick five-minute call so I can
get briefed on what your next
videos actually are
so I can start working on them
literally tonight, again, for
free?
So, that's something that I would
send in that thumbnail example.
Another example is,
Hey, name, I saw you're running
ads right now for XYZ Offer.
I studied your funnel slash offer
and built out a full cold email
workflow and script for you right
here.
Link.
Inside of this document, there are
plug-and-play scripts that you can
use as well as a full
infrastructure setup guide to help
you get this off the ground ASAP
so you can start signing clients
like Wildfire.
Just for context, it's the same
system that generates our clients
on average five to ten
appointments per month.
So, I thought this would be a
killer channel to develop a
four-year offer to help you get a
consistent flow of leads.
I have some time today and
tomorrow as well where I'd love to
walk you through this whole system
and how to implement it.
Again, not trying to sell you
anything on the back end.
No strings attached.
I'm not going to, you know, make
you read your card number out to
me on the second we get on the
phone.
I just want to, yeah, I know this
can help you out and I really want
to give you this value.
So, when would it work for you?
And don't misspell stuff like I
did in this right here.
Check your spelling.
So, right there is kind of a quick
nutshell of module five, what to
say to the prospects.
And just to recap it, right?
Don't make it complex.
You want to make it, again, very
specific to them, the problem
you're solving for them and what
you observe in your research
process.
And just don't be generic.
You did all this work, right?
So, just follow some of these
scripts and kind of templates I
have for you here and go out there
and start sending some messages.