All right.
Module six is the follow-up
process.
The money is in the follow-up.
You guys have
probably heard this all the time,
but it truly is, especially with
this strategy.
If you're not
following up with prospects, you
don't have a dialed in follow-up
process.
You're just letting
money fall through the cracks and
you just basically hate making
more money.
So let's dive
in.
So again, the money is in the
follow-up process.
Set up a right now, pause this
video,
by the way, pause this right now,
go to Trello.com or Asana,
whatever platform you use for
tasks and
reminders and project management,
set up a Kanban board.
And basically this will be used to
track
follow-up set reminders, show your
pipeline.
So basically I have on mine
prospects that I want
to reach out to.
I have initial message sent.
So that's the first deliverable
sent.
Then I have
follow-up one, follow-up two,
follow-up three, follow-up four,
follow-up five, follow-up six,
follow-up seven, follow-up eight,
follow-up nine, follow-up 10.
All is separate modules or sorry,
separate columns that I drag a
card through and I'll set task
reminders.
So I'll say, all right,
if someone's in the stage, you
know, the follow-up two column,
I'll set a reminder for two days
later
to basically say, Hey, they're in
follow-up two.
You got to move them to follow-up
three,
meaning you got to send them a
freaking follow-up message today,
my friend.
So Kanban boards are
fantastic.
They look like this to just move
people along those stages in your
dream 100 campaign
process.
And just make sure you're
consistently following up with
people, especially when you're
reaching out to, you know, a
hundred people, right?
It's a lot of people.
You got to really keep track
of who you're reaching out to,
when you need to reach out to them
and who you've already reached
out to in the past, who you book
calls with, et cetera.
So what do you say in the
follow-ups?
I keep it simple, right?
So Hey name, just want to make
sure you got that.
If you need help with
implementing it, I have time today
to chat.
Here's my number as well.
I literally give my number a lot
in these follow-up messages
because it's easy.
You'd be surprised how many people
just hit the phone
and call you and be like, yo, it's
insane.
Hey name, just bumping this.
I know you guys are losing out
on result, like views, for
example, if you're, you know,
making thumbnails for people.
So let me know
if you need some help, uh, giving
these up.
Hey name is end result, still a
priority for me.
Hey name, I added that document.
I added more to that document
above.
I added some more additional
information to that document above
that will help you on out.
So this is something I use
strategically.
If I've maybe got someone that is,
uh, you know, they follow me, they
read a couple of my other
follow-up messages.
They looked at the loom video that
I sent them initially.
They looked at the
deliverable document.
I sent them initially.
I will basically frame it like,
yo, I added some more
stuff to this document that is
going to help you out.
So it creates that intrigue and
they're like,
Hmm.
What did he add?
Interesting.
I need to check it out now.
So that's a great one to use
down the sequence some more in
your follow-up process.
And then always be spotting, uh,
where
you can add value with anyone.
This is kind of a funny slide, but
like, uh, these they'll definitely
load on the one for you, but
basically it's me harassing Daniel
Christian and Andre, uh,
repeatedly
with different deliverables until
they basically decided to, to work
with me and also, you know,
gave me an opportunity to do stuff
like, like this year, uh, for the
strategy.
So, uh, just be very
mindful of where you can provide
value within an organization on a
recurring basis and a frequent
basis.
So you can just keep providing
them with stuff, right?
So like the one that's showing up
over
here is kind of my initial one
that I just randomly sent them a
bunch of landing page designs that
I made
that I did for a lead magnet once.
So, uh, even though you ultimately
want to make money, you have
to come from a position of genuine
value and care.
If not, you're going to come off
salesy and you're
going to come off needy to the
prospect and they're just going to
completely ignore you and then
just
lump you into those weird, cool DM
guys, right?
Also accept that sometimes bigger
prospects may have
something else more pressing.
You can get your foot in the door
with and then sell them on your
core
services afterwards.
So for example, with gym launch, I
initially signed them onto a
copywriting
agreement, right?
I didn't just go right for funnels
and ads and media buying, you
know, I started out
as copywriter with them for the
first, like two weeks.
And then they were like, shit, you
know,
you're doing a lot of other areas.
So like, let's, uh, let's move
away from that, you know, keep
writing
some copy for us, but let's like,
you know, get you on some other
stuff.
So I saw they desperately
needed copywriting immediately and
knew that.
And I knew I could help them with
that.
So I went
all in on that first and really
got my foot in the door that way.
So just understand these bigger
companies or just companies in
general, if you see something
that's more pressing, that's
within your
field of, of services, you can
kind of step out that boundary a
little bit and provide them with
that.
Cause obviously like in my case,
copywriting, for example, like
building funnels, uh, you know,
media buying, running ads for
people, it's all copywriting still
at the end of the day.
Right.
So I still had that skillset.
I didn't just reach for it.
I still had that skillset.
So I provided
them with a bunch of work around
that, a bunch of deliverables
around copywriting, got my foot in
the
door.
Cause they're like, dang, this
guy's a good copywriter.
And then once my foot's in the
door,
they're like, Oh wait, you can do
a lot of other stuff.
This is crazy.
So again,
once I was in the organization
still, and I had a contract, I was
still giving them a ton of value
on other things.
So I'm always a guy that's sitting
there thinking, how can I make
someone else's life
better?
How can I make someone else's
business better and get them
better results?
So now we're
going to go into one of my
favorite modules, module seven
mistakes to avoid with dream 100.