I brought a song out cavalier by
juice world it's really good uh
they just launched this new album
very well if whenever you guys are
watching this some of you might be
watching this like
two years down the line uh it's
still a great song cavalier by
juice world listen to it anyways
before we keep continuing i want
to show you guys uh some mistakes
to avoid when you're running
this dream 100 process in the
stream 100 campaign so module
seven mistakes to avoid let's dive
in so
mistakes to avoid big red exits
don't do these things okay they're
going to cost you time and money
and bring a lot of frustration
with them so adding too much
explainer stuff at the start of
your
document trying to convince them
why they should use your
deliverable just focus on what
they're
missing out on by not using the
thing that you're providing them
with or not using it to the right
degree or you know the right
quality and you know show what
they stand to benefit from using
your
deliverable as quickly as possible
okay so i've had some people send
me in the group some dream 100
deliverable documents and it's
like 40 pages of stuff but 30 of
the pages are just explaining
their process and why they should
use the strategy and like you know
very complex terms high level
stuff
like think if you're sending this
to patrick ben david he's not
going to read that like he just
wants to know what you gave him
that's it and what it's going to
do for him that's that's the
dude's busy so think like you're
reaching out to someone high level
like that every time you make
these documents you want to just
give them value so if there's text
on that page every single
you know freaking character every
word needs to earn its place it
has to have a purpose and some
value
on that entire page so don't just
add a bunch of fluff and explainer
stuff and everything that
could just be copied and pasted
over from document to document
deliverable deliverable because it
shows
another thing is not doing enough
research to see if the prospect
actually needs your deliverable or
not again this just burns your
time going back to the youtube
example we talked about earlier
if you're only reaching out to
youtubers that have everything
dialed in and trying to give them
you know editing services and
scripting services they're just
going to probably ignore you
because
they already have everything
dialed in so see if the prospect
actually needs what you're
providing
them sometimes they don't
sometimes they just flat out don't
especially with cold email right
some
industries just don't work with
cold email so don't reach out to
you know companies that are
selling low ticket products or
something like that try to pitch
them on cold email services
because
it won't work okay so this just
burns your time if you don't
follow this
not following up enough again big
one flat out uh i do a minimum of
10 follow-ups minimum before i
move
on uh and even then i'll still
just keep going until someone
tells me to screw off or they both
call
really like that uh and again this
goes back to you understanding
that you're providing someone with
a ton
of immense value if you know you
provided them with a shit ton of
value that they can pull
problem immediately and make money
with why would you not keep trying
to follow up with them and get
this in their hands you're doing
them a disservice at that point
not doing it so uh another mistake
is making the deliverable document
too long and too confusing so what
i like to do is condense that
and i add a video explainer inside
and then making the implementation
of your deliverable seem too
costly too confusing too time
consuming and just flat out
annoying so those are the quick
mistakes to
avoid now we're going to go into
some common faqs that i get from a
lot of people in the community
about this strategy so see you
over there