All right.
So this would be a quick one over
here for you guys.
Common FAQs that I get with
Dream 100 from a lot of members
and people just DMing me in
general.
I wanted to consolidate
these into a few slides here.
So let's answer some FAQs, shall
we?
What channels are best to use?
Every single one of them.
Like I talked about earlier, you
want to hit them from all angles
and just know kind of where your
ICP typically likes to hang out.
You know, that's another big
thing.
So if your ICP likes to hang out
on, you know, Instagram or
Facebook, you can kind of lean
and put some more emphasis towards
those platforms.
But overall, you want to hit them
from as many
angles as you possibly can to get
in contact with them until they
reach out to you.
And then from
there, you can shift them to
another channel.
If they prefer, you know, if they
answer you on Reddit
and you're like, yo, are you on
Reddit all the time?
Or like, would you rather talk on
text or call or
email or something?
You can shift the conversation
over to there.
But again, follow up on every
platform until you can basically
get in contact with them.
Also see where your prospect is
most
active on and where they're likely
to not have setters.
So for example, I work in the info
product
space a lot and a lot of the
accounts use AI or setters on
Instagram, but not in email or
other
channels.
So that's something to be aware of
when you are reaching out to
people.
How to get past
setters.
Let's just talk about that real
quick.
So you want to scope out the
outreach channel
beforehand.
And sometimes I'll even go and
book a call.
If the closer is the owner, you
can tell
really plain clearly if the closer
is the owner, especially with
agencies, you're able to find
that out pretty, pretty direct
just by looking at their Calendly.
Also scrape the direct email of
the
owner.
So use the Apollo Chrome extension
on LinkedIn to actually pull the,
the actual email from their
profile.
There's also a bunch of tools for
Twitter and Facebook that you can
do to pull emails from
and then still send the actual
deliverable to them and direct it
to the owner.
So sometimes like the
setters are pretty, you know, low
level or the actual owners will
read the DMs.
And I've gotten past
the setters sometimes just saying
like, Hey, I made this for, you
know, the owner, Gary, can you,
can you send this over to him and
just, you know, provide me with
his feedback or is there a way I
can
get directly in contact with them,
especially in more like B2B
scenarios, you'll be surprised at
how
easy it is to get in contact with
the owner through a setter.
Now, when you're in more B2C, like
info
products, it's a little bit more
difficult, right?
Like if you try and go DM, like
Dan Martel's page or
something, you're going to get
blocked with a setter and they're
going to try and flip the script
on
trying to try to sell you on their
stuff.
So just be cautious of that.
But these are some easy ways
to get past setters.
Is sending an email worth it?
Every single time, a hundred
percent.
Going to move
on.
Should I send a loom video?
A hundred percent.
Every time.
Or, you know, some sort of video
in
your outreach document?
Every single time.
Yes.
So these are two email, two
questions I get all the
time.
Should I send an email and a
video?
Yes.
Every single time.
Here's an optimal cadence for
outreach and follow-up.
So day one, I send the initial
message.
Day two, follow-up one.
Day three,
follow-up two.
Day four, I have basically I layer
on other channels.
So if I reached out to Instagram
day one, two, and three, then I'll
start to layer on Twitter,
Facebook, and LinkedIn.
Day five, I'll do
follow-up three of the initial,
you know, Instagram ones.
And then I'll keep just following
up from there.
And then I'll keep layering on
additional channels as we continue
down the process and as days pass.
So this is again, why you need to
have a campaign board to keep
everything organized and write
down
in the actual cards of the
campaign board and the prospects.
Like I reached out to
Dan Martell through Instagram on
this day.
And then set a reminder to send
them another one on Instagram,
Twitter, LinkedIn, et cetera.
So just make a campaign board, use
Trello.
It's free
and just build out this pipeline
and this process properly.
And if you need help,
hit me in Slack.
I definitely got you.
I'll help you out with that.
Of course.
So another question I got was
approaching, it was around
approaching medium qualified
leads,
right?
So it depends on how just, you
know, mid they are really.
So not everyone that comes to
your ad funnel or cool email
campaigns will be qualified,
right?
That's just part of the game of
marketing.
So it all goes back to your
research process with something
like Dream 100.
You control
who you reach out to and who sees
your stuff.
With ads, you can to a degree, but
still some people
might slip through the cracks that
aren't qualified.
So there are plenty of hot
prospects out there.
Reach out to the ones that you
think are spot on first and then
move down your list, right?
So
approaching kind of medium
qualified leads.
I still reach out to people that I
think are medium
qualified.
I just reach out to the hot ones
first.
Question as well, send a message
beforehand to connect a week or so
before sending the Dream 100
deliverable.
So I had someone reach out to me
that was like, yo, if I'm planning
on sending Dan
Martel, I don't know why I keep
using him as an example in this
one, but if I'm sending Dan Martel
a Dream 100 deliverable in a week,
should I send them a week before
to connect with them?
Yes.
If you don't have a salesy profile
and you actually sound like a
human, you know,
just be a human and try to make a
genuine connection with them a
week before, just build that
relationship, you know, like, like
some of their stories or something
and just come off
as like a freaking human, like a
fan of theirs and a fan of their
brand and what they're
doing.
Not overly crazy, but just like be
a human at that point.
And then you can send
them the deliverable saying like,
Hey, I've been following you, you
know, past week and
loving your content and
everything.
I've just been working on this for
you the past week
to want to send this over.
That's a great thing to do.
So module nine, let's go into
some KPIs and targets that you
need to hit to scale the strategy
up and scale your