Alright everybody, welcome to the
Client Ascension Dream 100
training modules here.
So, for those of you who don't
know me, my name is Evan Siech.
I've used this strategy since I
came into Client Ascension roughly
about six months ago
to scale my agency pretty much
from this fragmented, shambled,
weird fractional CMO thing I had
going on with a couple of small
clients doing around $5K to $10K a
month.
And now I've scaled this up to
$40K a month and we're growing and
I've signed some fantastic
companies, one of which is Gym
Launch and will actually go into
the whole deliverable and
whole process I used to sign them.
And from there, once you get one
big client like that, that turned
into a bunch of other
opportunities.
Jason Wojo and Wojo Media, I work
with them as well right now.
And from there, I just dropped
those names and pretty much have
been signing people left
and right due to that.
So, this is a fantastic strategy
to use.
It does require some legwork, does
require some strategy, does
require some time, but
trust me, it pays off in the end.
So, right now, I'm just going to
go over real quick in this
introductory module what we're
actually going to be covering in
this course.
So, first off, we just have the
introduction.
So, we're going to go over what
the strategy is.
Why does it work?
What's the difference between just
cold DMs and Dream 100 Outreach?
We're going to go into the actual
Dream 100 process in module two.
So, you know, overview of the
process, how to find the right
prospects, what platforms
to use to find the right
prospects, and just what is a
qualified prospect in general.
Then module three, we're going to
go into Dream 100 deliverables.
So, what type of free work should
you be doing?
Again, this strategy is, in a
nutshell, giving people free work
up front in return for their
potential business on the back
end.
So, we're going to go into, again,
what kind of free work should you
do?
How much should you actually do?
How much time should you spend on
your Dream 100 deliverable?
What should you send in a Dream
100 deliverable?
Then we're going to do a breakdown
in module four of how I signed Gym
Launch.
It's going to give you a great
example of what a very crazy, I
guess, example of a Dream 100
deliverable is, but it's a
fantastic one and we'll dive into
a lot of the strategies that
I use to sign them and break
through the noise of all the other
people and agencies, contractors,
freelancers that were reaching out
to them on a daily basis, why I
got the job and they
didn't.
Then, module five, we're going to
go to reaching out to prospects,
right?
Made the deliverable, we know who
we're targeting, so where do I
contact them?
How do I reach out to these large
companies with tons of people?
How do I get to the owner?
How do I get to the director of
marketing, the right person to
talk to, right?
What do you say when you actually
send the free work?
In the next module, we'll go into
following up.
So, following up is one of the
most important things that you
could do with this strategy and
really any outreach strategy.
So, we're going to go over what to
say in the follow-up.
What should your follow-up process
actually look like?
Then, we're going to go into
common mistakes to avoid.
There's a lot of these and I'm
going to list out every single
one.
These are mistakes that I've made
and I've also seen a lot of
members in Client Ascension
make and I'm going to be hoping to
help you avoid all of that
entirely and get through all
of that, shorten the learning
curve for you.
Then, we're going to go into some
Dream 100 FAQs.
So, since I did my coaching call,
which will be in this module as
well, about a month
and a half ago, I got a ton of
questions and basically, I've
consolidated these questions
into just a few that are the most
impactful and the ones that you
need to know right now.
So, like what channels are the
best to use?
How do you get past setters?
That's a big thing.
Should you send emails?
Should you send a Loom video?
What's the optimal follow-up
cadence?
Then, we're going to go into KPIs.
So, what targets should you
actually be hitting?
What are the inputs in your
expected outputs of those inputs?
And how do you factor in costs
whenever you're doing any
financial modeling or projections?
Then, I have a very fun section
here that I love.
The, what happens if, right?
Oh, what happens if they don't see
my free work?
What happens if they don't like my
free work?
What happens if they don't consume
my free work?
We're going to go over all of
those and I'll tell you exactly
what to do in every single
scenario.
So, as you're out in the field,
utilizing this strategy, making
free work, sending people
free stuff, you'll be able to say,
oh, they aren't seeing my free
work.
Let me go see what I can do to get
them to actually see that free
work, right?
Where I'm sending it to them and
they're not actually consuming or
using it.
They're just leaving me unread.
What do I do then?
So, next we're going to go into
strategies to increase your
overall response rates.
Then we're going to go into the
path to actually scaling your
agency with Dream 100.
And finally, I want to leave you
with some action items.
So, after you watch all of this
good stuff, all these modules,
you'll have a clear set of
actions that you need to take to
start scaling your agency and your
company utilizing this strategy.
So, without further ado, let's
dive in.