Okay, so technical deliverability
setup.
This is just like the first step
that you need to do,
which you might already have all
of this set up, but you might not.
If you're starting like a new
account, new domain, then you're
going to need to make sure that
all this is set.
But super duper
easy.
So seems very complex, but again,
most domains already have the
correct records in place,
maybe one missing.
So you need to make sure that you
have these.
You need to make sure that you
have SPF, you need to make sure
you have DMARC, and you need to
make sure that you have DKIM.
You can use this website here,
GlockApps, to just see if you have
everything.
Super duper easy.
You
can just create like a free
account.
Super easy.
Or you can do like a spam checker
right here.
But
literally, if like right here, you
could do DMARC Analyzer, Inbox
Insight, or you can literally just
look up on the internet how to
check if I have SPF and they're
like free, free everything.
More than
likely you won't have DMARC.
And so that's like the main one
that I call out.
So just see if you have
them.
If you enter your domain and it's
like, hey, you have it, then
you're all good.
If it says,
hey, you don't have it, then make
sure you have it.
If you're missing a record, this
link right here
has everything.
I didn't want to explain it for
you.
SPF, DKIM, and DMARC for Klaviyo.
Holy cookies.
It's just all set up right here.
So super duper easy.
Just test to make sure you have
it,
and then you're all good.
So super duper easy right there.
And then Klaviyo dedicated sending
domain is like the last step.
So you have your records and then
you need to make sure you have
a Klaviyo dedicated sending
domain, which this is part of like
the Klaviyo setup process that
they're
going to help walk you through.
This is like a new thing that is
like required as of 2024,
February.
So relatively new.
But this article walks you through
everything that you need.
Super duper easy.
This was like really big at the
beginning of 2024.
They were making this like switch.
A lot of emails
came with this, like you were
sharing from it.
You were sending from a shared
domain, but now you're
now that's not a thing because you
can't really be sending.
You're just going to go to the
spam inbox.
So just make sure you have that.
And then you're all set.
That's literally it for technical
setup.
Don't have to do anything else
besides that.
So super duper simple.
Get this, knock this out within
a couple hours if that should take
you like 20, 30 minutes.
Okay.
So technical deliverability setup.
This is just like the first step
that you need to do,
which you might already have all
of this set up, but you might not.
If you're starting like a new
account, new domain, then you're
going to need to make sure that
all this is set.
But super duper easy.
So seems very complex, but again,
most domains already have the
correct records in place, maybe
one missing.
So you need to make sure that you
have these.
You need to make sure that you
have SPF.
You need to make sure you have
DMARC and you need to make sure
that you have DKIM.
You can use this
website here, Glock apps, to just
see if you have everything.
Super duper easy.
You can just create
like a free account.
Super easy.
Or you can do like a spam checker
right here.
But literally, if like right
here, you could do DMARC analyzer,
inbox insight, or you can
literally just look up on the
internet how to
check if I have SPF and they're
like free, free everything.
More than likely, you won't have
DMARC.
And so that's like the main one
that I call out.
So just see if you have them.
If you enter your domain
and it's like, hey, you have it,
then you're all good.
If it says, hey, you don't have
it, then make sure you
have it.
If you're missing a record, this
link right here has everything.
I didn't want to explain it
for you.
SPF, DKIM, and DMARC for Klaviyo.
Holy cookies.
It's just all set up right here.
So super
duper easy.
Just test to make sure you have it
and then you're all good.
So super duper easy right
there.
And then Klaviyo dedicated sending
domain is like the last step.
So you have your records and then
you need to make sure you have a
Klaviyo dedicated sending domain,
which this is part of like the
Klaviyo
setup process that they're going
to help walk you through.
This is like a new thing.
that is like required as of 2024,
February.
So relatively new.
But this article walks you
through everything that you need.
Super duper easy.
This was like really big at the
beginning
of 2024.
They were making this like switch.
A lot of emails came with this.
Like you were
sharing from a, you were sending
from a shared domain, but now
you're, now that's not a thing
because you can't really be
sending.
You're just going to go to the
spam inbox.
So just make sure
you have that.
And then you're all set.
That's literally it for technical
setup.
Don't have
to do anything else besides that.
So super duper simple.
Get this, knock this out within
a couple hours.
If, if that should take you like
20, 30 minutes.