Okay, so you might be asking, what
do I do if my open rates are low,
my deliverability
is low, and I want to make sure
I'm landing in the inbox?
That is what I'm going to be
sharing with you because a lot of
people are in this situation.
Most of the brands that I come on
with, pause, they are kind of like
in this situation where
they have lower open rates and
they don't really know what to do.
This is what you do.
Okay, so why is engagement low?
Let's assume you have all the
technicalities in place.
You have like your DMARC,
everything with your domain that
you need.
If so, there are two possible
reasons why you're getting low
open rates, whatever it may be.
Either your emails suck, nobody
wants to open them because you
have terrible content, not
good copy, not engaging design.
People don't like your emails, so
they're not going to open them.
Two, you have a bad sender
reputation, and a lot of your
emails are landing in the spam
folder.
Those are the two only possible
reasons.
So to accomplish reason number
one, just make better emails.
If you make good emails, people
enjoy them and continue to open
them and help your open
rates.
You have great looking design and
copy that gives people dopamine.
Believe it or not, seeing a pretty
looking like piece of art, graphic
design, gives people
dopamine similar to like a funny
Instagram post.
It's just aesthetically pleasing
for people.
They get a dopamine release.
And then just like, I mean, we're
all machines.
You get a positive association
with this brand and these colors.
And so you get a positive
association.
And so anytime that somebody
receives that notification from,
hey, this is from this brand, they
have
that positive association.
Your brain associates that with
dopamine, and then they click on
the notification, then they
open.
So you get future opens.
So you make better emails, people
will start to open all of your
emails just because they
get that dopamine release that
they crave.
So make better emails, go to the
campaign, the copy and design
sections of this course, study
some of the great brands, go to
mild.com or really good
emails.com, study what they are
doing, copy it.
And you'll notice that over time,
if you have better email content,
your deliverability and
your engagement is going to
skyrocket.
So just make better emails to
build up your center reputation.
So if you're getting some 40%
opens, then you're likely getting
some higher promotions and spam
inbox placement.
If you just have lower opens,
Gmail is going to look at that and
be like, okay, probably
going to send this person, this
domain in the spam folder a little
bit more.
So we need to prove to these inbox
providers that people like our
emails and want to engage
with them.
So that is all we need to do to
boost our center reputation.
And that happens over time.
So we need to prove to them that
we're reputable.
How do we do that?
Let's boost our opens and clicks
for a period of time.
How do we do that?
Let's only send emails to people
who open and click our emails for
a period of time.
So it's really just that simple.
We just need to improve our open
rates.
Then Gmail would be like, oh,
they're getting better opens and
this is a reputable person.
People are actually opening this.
Let's put them in the inbox at a
higher rate.
So that's really all this is.
We are going to boost our opens
and clicks for a period of time by
only sending to people
who open and click our emails.
Super duper simple.
So what you want to do is you want
to create engaged segments of 14
day, 30 day, 60 day,
and 90 day variations.
So your most engaged subscribers
who have opened an email or
clicked an email in the past 14
days.
That's one segment have the same
segment, but for people who've
done that on a 30 day period.
So maybe somebody opened an email
four weeks ago.
They haven't opened one since.
They're in the 30 day engaged.
That's a very engaged person.
You have the 60 day engaged and
then 90 day engaged as well, which
are slightly less engaged people.
So this is how this looks inside
of Klaviyo.
The definition is just somebody
has opened an email at least once
in the past 60 days.
So this is the engaged 60 day
segment.
It's the same thing for 14,
whatever, whatever it is, it's
going to be the same.
So open email at least once in the
past 60 days or clicked an email
at least once in the past 60 days.
Now you might be wondering, well,
if somebody clicked an email, that
means that they opened it, which
is true.
But sometimes Klaviyo won't track
the opens.
It's just a little flaw.
Open rates are not going to be
perfect, but click rates are
pretty much like very accurate.
So you want to make sure that
maybe it didn't track somebody's
open, but like they clicked the
email.
This is just like a little fail
safe to help you out.
You want to make sure that this
person is subscribed.
You want to make sure that they've
bounced email less than two or one
over all time.
So very important to have these
and just make sure that like,
yeah, just make sure that this is
all set.
So that's really all you need.
Make the different variations and
then you're all set.
Super simple.
And then this is what like your
timeline should be for solving
your spam issue in six weeks.
So weeks one to three.
So we just want to create our 14,
30, 60, and 90 day engaged lists.
That's what we want to do.
So we're struggling with open
rates.
What we're doing, create these
engaged lists.
We want to turn off all of our
flows.
If you have a ton of flows, turn
them off.
Because we don't know what the
engagement is like on those flows.
We want to make sure that during
this time, we only want to send
high engaging emails.
And so we don't want all these
crazy flows.
We just want to turn on the
welcome flow, browse abandoned,
cart abandoned, and post purchase.
Because these are the highest
engaging email flows.
People engage with these emails at
a high rate.
Like the welcome flow.
People are going to that first
welcome email to get their
discount.
They engage with that at a high
rate.
So that gets high engagement.
So Google sees that and they're
like, okay, awesome.
Boost the reputation.
Browse abandoned flow.
That means somebody viewed a
product of yours and you send them
an email within 30 minutes.
They're very high, highly likely
to engage.
You get good engagement, boost
your reputation.
Same with cart and checkout
abandoned.
Same with post purchase.
People view and click these emails
at a high rate.
So we want to keep those on and
have those boost our reputation.
And then what we want to do is we
want to send engaging campaigns
that we're fishing for opens and
clicks three times per week.
Notice how that doesn't say one
time per week.
I know you're probably like, oh, I
want to improve my open rates.
I don't want to spam my list.
Shush.
I've done this not hundreds of
times, but a lot of times in
improving the list.
To improve your reputation, you
need to increase your sending
volume rather than decrease it.
Three per week is not a lot.
That's like Sunday, Tuesday, and
Friday.
That's like a cadence that you
could do.
That is not a lot.
People are receiving a ton of
emails.
People see, on average, 170 e-com
brands per day.
This isn't a lot.
But what it is is a healthy
cadence where you're going to get
a lot of reputation by sending
three times per week to these
people where you're going to get
over 50% open rates.
And three times per week, you are
proving to Google that you are a
reputable sender.
So that's what we're doing in
weeks one through three.
High engaging flows, sending to
our hyper-engaged list, sending
highly engaging emails.
Weeks three through four, at the
back half of the first month.
Once open rates to your 14-day
engage list, our 50% plus
consistently for a couple weeks,
just like three weeks, then you
can expand to like your 30-day
engage list.
Start expanding to your 30-day
Maybe turn on a couple of your
other flows.
But this has done a lot of the
damage.
This has done a lot of the
recovery.
And then weeks three through four,
kind of open it up a little bit.
Weeks five through six, open it up
a little bit.
So just monitor your opens and
slowly open up your list as your
engagement goes up.
So you don't want to dip below 40%
to 50% opens.
If you open it up to your 60-day
engage list and your open rates go
to like 35%, then that's a red
flag.
Go back to the 30-day engaged or
14-day engaged.
And so we just want to slowly open
things up.
And then once your 60-day engage
list is seeing 50% opens, you can
just keep expanding.
Just make sure you're staying
above 50.
So just slowly opening things up,
continuing to send three highly
engaged campaigns per week.
Usually by week six, you're all
set.
And then you only send to your
90-day engage list.
You don't start sending to your
whole email list again.
No.
Only send a 90-day engage.
Once a month, you can send a
campaign to your like main list to
try to re-engage past people.
But only send a 90-day engage
list.
I send, we manage lists with
millions of people on it where
we're sending campaigns.
We don't, there are like over a
million profiles in one of my
accounts that we don't send to.
You're probably like, a million
profiles, why aren't you sending
to them?
Because it's going to risk our
reputation.
And these people have proven that
they're not opening emails.
If you think about it, like some
of the times we'll send to like
365-day engage,
anybody who's opened an email in
the past year.
That's a long freaking time to not
open an email.
If I'm sending three emails per
week and you haven't opened an
email in like nine months,
you probably don't give a crap
about me.
You either, or you switched your
email address.
You don't view this inbox anymore.
I don't want to keep hurting my
reputation by sending to you.
So only send to your 90-day
engaged.
You can open it up a little bit.
Maybe your 90-day engage list is
getting 60% opens.
Expand it to like 120.
And then do that.
Just stay above 50%.
And then just send one campaign
per month to like an expanded
list.
of like maybe 365-day engaged.
That's completely fine to do once
a month and get, you'll get lower
engagement.
You'll get 20% to 30% opens.
That's fine to do once a month.
You'll re-engage some profiles and
enter them back into your engaged
list.
So that is the protocol to solving
your spam issue.
This is a client example to prove
that this is possible.
This brand was seeing 20% to 30%
opens on their campaigns.
They were constantly landing in
spam.
Open rates, this is what it was
like.
You can see the amount of people
here.
24%, 29%, 27%, 47%.
But that was like a, they were, it
was like a survey or something to
like a tight group.
29%, 29%, 29%, 11%, 25%.
Very, very bad.
This was frustrating because only
25% of their list was seeing their
messages.
They had over like 100,000 people
that they were sending to.
Super frustrating.
Upon an inspection, they had all
the technicalities set up.
This was happening purely due to
their reputation.
All we had to do was improve their
reputation and then open the full
campaigns back up.
So this was day one when we came
in.
Then it's like a day 60.
Open rates, 60%.
With 65, 60,000 people opening the
emails, sending to the same
people.
We're sending to the same people,
but now we're getting 60% opens.
This is because we improved our
reputation and we're no longer
landing in the spam folder
to where these people weren't
seeing the emails.
This was just literally 60 days
later following this protocol that
I gave you in monitoring open
rates.
And then let's look at the
revenue.
Look at the revenue right here.
Five grand, four grand, three
grand survey, four grand, two
grand.
Let's look at the revenue here.
19 grand, 23 grand, 15, 15, 6, 12,
10, 12.
Massive difference by showing, by
getting more people to look at
your emails
and making the emails better
because that's also what we did.
So it's really that simple.
If you ever have open rate
problems, you just got to play
with your segmentation,
play with different engagements,
and then do that over a period of
time,
and then you'll be all set.
Don't overcomplicate it.
Okay, so you might be asking, what
do I do if my open rates are low,
my deliverability is low, and I
want to make sure I'm landing in
the inbox?
That is what I'm going to be
sharing with you because a lot of
people are in this situation.
Most of the brands that I come on
with, pause, they are kind of like
in this situation
where they have lower open rates
and they don't really know what to
do.
This is what you do.
Okay, so why is engagement low?
Let's assume you have all the
technicalities in place.
You have like your DMARC,
everything with your domain that
you need.
If so, there are two possible
reasons why you're getting low
open rates, whatever it may be.
Either your emails suck.
Nobody wants to open them because
you have terrible content, not
good copy, not engaging design.
People don't like your email, so
they're not going to open them.
Two, you have a bad sender
reputation, and a lot of your
emails are landing in the spam
folder.
Those are the two only possible
reasons.
So, to accomplish reason number
one, just make better emails.
If you make good emails, people
will enjoy them and continue to
open them and help your open
rates.
You have great looking design and
copy that gives people dopamine.
Believe it or not, seeing a pretty
looking piece of art graphic
design gives people dopamine,
similar to like a funny Instagram
post.
It's just aesthetically pleasing
for people.
They get a dopamine release, and
then, just like, I mean, we're all
machines.
You get a positive association
with this brand and these colors,
and so you get a positive
association.
And so, anytime that somebody
receives that notification from,
hey, this is from this brand,
they have that positive
association.
Your brain associates that with
dopamine, and then they click on
the notification, then they open.
So, you get future opens.
So, you make better emails, people
will start to open all of your
emails.
Just because they get that
dopamine release that they crave.
And so, make better emails.
Go to the campaign, the copy and
design sections of this course.
Study some of the great brands.
Go to mild.com or
reallygoodemails.com.
Study what they are doing.
Copy it.
And you'll notice that over time,
if you have better email content,
your deliverability and your
engagement is going to skyrocket.
So, just make better emails.
Two, build up your sender
reputation.
So, if you're getting sub 40%
opens, then you're likely getting
some higher promotions and spam
inbox placement.
If you just have lower opens,
Gmail is going to look at that and
be like, okay, probably going to
send this person,
this domain in the spam folder a
little bit more.
So, we need to prove to these
inbox providers that people like
our emails and want to engage with
them.
So, that is all we need to do to
boost our sender reputation.
And that happens over time.
So, we need to prove to them that
we're reputable.
How do we do that?
Let's boost our opens and clicks
for a period of time.
How do we do that?
Let's only send emails to people
who open and click our emails for
a period of time.
So, it's really just that simple.
We just need to improve our open
rates.
Then Gmail will be like, oh,
they're getting better opens and
this is a reputable person.
People are actually opening this.
Let's put them in the inbox at a
higher rate.
So, that's really all this is.
So, we are going to boost our
opens and clicks for a period of
time by only sending to people who
open and click our emails.
Super duper simple.
So, what you want to do is you
want to create engaged segments of
14-day, 30-day, 60-day, and 90-day
variations.
So, your most engaged subscribers
who have opened an email or
clicked an email in the past 14
days, that's one segment,
have the same segment but for
people who have done that on a
30-day period.
So, maybe somebody opened an email
four weeks ago.
They haven't opened one since.
They're in the 30-day engaged.
That's a very engaged person.
You have the 60-day engaged and
then 90-day engaged as well, which
are slightly less engaged people.
So, this is how this looks inside
of Klaviyo.
The definition is just somebody
has opened an email at least once
in the past 60 days.
So, this is the engaged 60-day
segment.
It's the same thing for 14,
whatever it is.
It's going to be the same.
So, opened an email at least once
in the past 60 days or clicked an
email at least once in the past 60
days.
Now, you might be wondering, well,
if somebody clicked an email, that
means that they opened it, which
is true.
But sometimes Klaviyo won't track
the opens.
It's just a little flaw.
Open rates are not going to be
perfect, but click rates are
pretty much, like, very accurate.
So, you want to make sure that
maybe it didn't track somebody's
open, but, like, they clicked the
email.
This is just, like, a little
fail-safe to help you out.
You want to make sure that this
person is subscribed.
You want to make sure that they've
bounced email less than two or one
over all time.
So, very important to have these
and just make sure that, like,
yeah, just make sure that this is
all set.
So, that's really all you need.
Make the different variations and
then you're all set.
Super simple.
And then this is what, like, your
timeline should be for solving
your spam issue in six weeks.
So, weeks one to three.
So, we just want to create our 14,
30, 60, and 90-day engaged lists.
That's what we want to do.
So, we're struggling with open
rates.
What we're doing, create these
engaged lists.
We want to turn off all of our
flows.
If you have a ton of flows, turn
them off because we don't know
what the engagement is like on
those flows.
We want to make sure that during
this time, we only want to send
high-engaging emails.
And so, we don't want all these
crazy flows.
We just want to turn on the
welcome flow, browse abandon, cart
abandon, and post-purchase because
these are the highest engaging
email flows.
People engage with these emails at
a high rate.
Like, the welcome flow.
People are going to that first
welcome email to get their
discount.
They engage with that at a high
rate.
So, that gets high engagement.
So, Google sees that and they're
like, okay, awesome.
Boost their reputation.
Browse abandon flow.
That means somebody viewed a
product of yours and you send them
an email within 30 minutes.
They're very high, highly likely
to engage.
You get good engagement.
Boost your reputation.
Same with cart and checkout
abandon.
Same with post-purchase.
People view and click these emails
at a high rate.
So, we want to keep those on and
have those boost our reputation.
And then what we want to do is we
want to send engaging campaigns
that we're fishing for opens and
clicks three times per week.
Three times per week.
Notice how that doesn't say one
time per week.
I know you're probably like, oh, I
want to improve my open rates.
I don't want to spam my list.
Shush.
I've done this, not hundreds of
times, but a lot of times in
improving the list.
To improve your reputation, you
need to increase your sending
volume rather than decrease it.
Three per week is not a lot.
That's like Sunday, Tuesday, and
Friday.
That's like a cadence that you
could do.
That is not a lot.
People are receiving a ton of
emails.
People see, on average, 170 e-com
brands per day.
This isn't a lot, but what it is,
is a healthy cadence where you're
going to get a lot of reputation
by sending three times per week to
these people where you're going to
get over 50% open rates.
And three times per week, you are
proving to Google that you are a
reputable sender.
So, that's what we're doing in
weeks one through three.
High engaging flows, sending to
our hyper-engaged list, sending
highly engaging emails.
Weeks three through four, at the
back half of the first month.
Once open rates to your 14-day
engage list, or 50% plus
consistently for a couple weeks,
just like three weeks, then you
can expand to like your 30-day
engage list.
Start expanding to your 30-day
Maybe turn on a couple of your
other flows.
But this has done a lot of the
damage.
This has done a lot of the
recovery.
And then weeks three through four,
kind of open it up a little bit.
Weeks five through six, open it up
a little bit.
So, just monitor your opens and
slowly open up your list as your
engagement goes up.
So, you don't want to dip below
40- to 50% opens.
If you open it up to your 60-day
engage list and your open rates go
to like 35%, then that's a red
flag.
Go back to the 30-day engaged or
14-day engaged.
So, we just want to slowly open
things up.
And then once your 60-day engage
list is seeing 50% open, so you
can just keep expanding.
Just make sure you're staying
above 50%.
So, just slowly opening things up,
continuing to send three highly
engaged campaigns per week.
Usually, by week six, you're all
set.
And then you only send to your
90-day engage list.
You don't start sending to your
whole email list again.
No.
Only send a 90-day engage.
Once a month, you can send a
campaign to your main list to try
to re-engage past people.
But only send a 90-day engage
list.
I send, we manage lists with
millions of people on it where
we're sending campaigns.
We don't, there are like over a
million profiles in one of my
accounts that we don't send to.
You're probably like, a million
profiles, why aren't you sending
them to them?
Because it's going to risk our
reputation.
And these people have proven that
they're not opening emails.
If you think about it, like some
of the times we'll send to like
365-day engage.
Anybody who's opened an email in
the past year.
That's a long freaking time to not
open an email.
If I'm sending three emails per
week and you haven't opened an
email in like nine months,
you probably don't give a crap
about me.
You either, or you switched your
email address.
You don't view this inbox anymore.
I don't want to keep hurting my
reputation by sending to you.
So, only send to your 90-day
engaged.
You can open it up a little bit.
Maybe your 90-day engage list is
getting 60% opens.
Expand it to like 120.
And then do that.
Just stay above 50%.
And then just send one campaign
per month to like an expanded list
of like maybe 365-day engaged.
That's completely fine to do once
a month and get, you'll get lower
engagement.
You'll get 20-30% opens.
That's fine to do once a month.
You'll re-engage some profiles and
enter them back into your engaged
list.
So, that is the protocol to
solving your spam issue.
This is a client example to prove
that this is possible.
This brand was seeing 20-30% opens
on their campaigns.
They were constantly landing in
spam.
Open rates, this is what it was
like.
You can see the amount of people
here.
24%, 29%, 27%, 47%.
But that was like a survey or
something to like a tight group.
29%, 29%, 11%, 25%.
Very, very bad.
This was frustrating because only
25% of their list was seeing their
messages.
They had over like 100,000 people
that they were sending to.
Super frustrating.
Upon an inspection, they had all
the technicalities set up.
This was happening purely due to
their reputation.
All we had to do was improve their
reputation and then open the full
campaigns back up.
So, this was day one when we came
in.
Then, it's like a day 60.
Open rates, 60%.
With 65, 60,000 people opening the
emails, sending to the same
people.
We're sending to the same people,
but now we're getting 60% opens.
This is because we improved our
reputation and we're no longer
landing in the spam folder
to where these people weren't
seeing the emails.
This was just literally 60 days
later following this protocol that
I gave you in monitoring open
rates.
And then, let's look at the
revenue.
Look at the revenue right here.
5,000, 4,000, 3,000 survey.
4,000, 2,000.
Let's look at the revenue here.
19,000, 23,000, 15, 15, 6, 12, 10,
12.
Like, massive difference by
showing, by getting more people to
look at your emails.
And making the emails better
because that's also what we did.
So, it's really that simple.
If you ever have open rate
problems, you just got to play
with your segmentation.
Play with different engagements.
And then, do that over a period of
time and then you'll be all set.
Don't overcomplicate it.