Okay, so campaign A/B test, what
should we be testing in campaigns,
how do we do it,
all that good stuff.
So, the possibilities for A/B
testing are literally endless for
your campaigns.
You can test anything, and so you
should test anything.
Don't just wait for me to hold
your hand until you test this,
just test, just test.
It's important to make sure though
that you do have the proper volume
to know that your
results are conclusive.
If you send a campaign to 50
people and you have an A/B test
going to 25 and then 25,
it's just not quite enough to like
know if your results are
conclusive.
You can look up, I don't know if
you remember like algebra class
and stats class, but there's
something known as like
statistically significant where
you can like put in your numbers,
whatever
your A/B test is, put it into a
calculator and it tells you is the
winner really the winner
or is it just due to chance.
So you can use a statistical test
thingy for seeing if your results
are conclusive.
And so, that's something that you
want to make sure that you have in
mind is don't just
end A/B tests because you have one
is slightly more than the other.
Make sure you look a little bit
deeper.
If you need to send multiple
emails to get enough data to make
a conclusion, that's fine.
If you're testing sending at 9am
versus 12pm and everything's
relatively the same, feel
free to send again and again until
you get a clear winner.
If there's no clear winner, cool.
Then you know that 9am or 12pm,
you can use them both because the
results are relatively
the same.
Um, and since you can choose
anything though, I will
acknowledge that it's hard to
choose.
What do I test?
Um, so you want to start off with
the highest leverage tests, which
is what I'm going to
be sharing with you here.
Just super high leverage.
Focus on these.
And then once you have these down
and you have, you have like your
campaign layout and whatnot,
then you can test like the more
advanced stuff.
So moving right along, we have
some initial high leverage A/B
tests.
Number one is your campaign sends
time.
So, and this is also just happens
to be very high leverage and very,
very easy to set up
because you don't need to use
different email content.
You can just change the send time.
Different lists are going to
respond better at different times
of the day.
It's a really important to
understand.
Some people like your demographic
is like college kids.
They might be, um, not checking
their stuff like during the
morning.
You don't want to send before 10am
because people sleep in.
Um, but like night they're good,
whereas like some people like old
folks, they're better
responding at like in the morning.
So you want to make sure that
you're testing, um, good practice
to send at the same time for
most of your campaigns so that
customers get like accustomed to
receiving your emails at
a certain part of the day where
it's like part of their lunch
break to check your emails or
whatever.
Um, but you want to make sure that
you're mixing it up.
You don't just want to send every
single time at the same time, mix
it up a little bit,
but lean more towards the one that
performs the best.
Um, again, some lists will respond
better here and there and whatnot.
Typically, I found that in most
cases, 11am to 12pm is kind of the
best because people
are awake.
They can check their emails during
lunch, but you also give somebody
the full day to check
their email.
It's really difficult to get
somebody to open an email from
yesterday just cause it's
yesterday.
That's out of the person's mind.
So if we send early enough, like
at 11am, somebody goes to bed at
9pm, we have nine
hours for the person to open the
email app and see our email.
Um, that's why like you might get
more initial opens at 5pm if you
send an email then, but
you don't give people like the
chance to open the email for the
rest of the day.
So typically like 11am to 12pm,
1pm is kind of what I find.
Um, the main test times that I
would test for like your normal
sends are like 9am, 12pm,
2pm, 4pm.
I usually go by like two hour
increments.
Um, so you can test there, start
at 9am versus 4 and then slowly
like until you find like
the middle that performs the best.
So here's like the impact that a
send time could be something as
little as 11am versus
1:45pm.
This is like a reminder.
They're both same reminder.
We have a lot of data here.
Look at the increase in open
rates, 48% versus 42% and then
click rate as well was higher.
And then also placed order rate
was higher and the total revenue.
So that is a very big impact.
And so now we know, okay, 1:45pm
between 1 to 2pm is better than
like 11am before lunch.
Also important to keep in mind
what day it is.
Sundays are going to be different
than like Tuesdays because Sundays
people don't have work
or anything.
And so you want to have send times
for the weekend that are kind of
your go to and then
also weekdays.
So that's very important to note
as well.
Next, very high lever is like
graphic based emails versus text
based.
Now you can do like overall style
of just like mainly a graphic.
Based email versus one with like a
little bit more text.
That's something you can do.
You could also do base graphic or
plain text only, which is like
HTML for where it's just
the text.
It shows up native in the person's
inbox.
That's something that you can
test.
So it's really going to vary
across a lot of accounts and like
you're branding on other
platforms.
It's going to depend as well.
So just test, test, test, test the
different styles to see what your
list performs better
with lots of lifestyle graphics
versus like product style
graphics.
what works best, what gets more
clicks, especially for big drops
in sales.
You want to test this?
We find that you want to mix them
up, but use text based for like a
lot of key emails.
When you have a text based email
that's just from the founder and
it's like, hey, it's
Max from Well Copy.
Um, I wanted to personally reach
out and say that this sale is
live.
Those usually can perform really
well for, um, like big main
emails.
But if you send text based emails
every single time, then that
doesn't have novelty that text
based from me doesn't carry as
much weight.
So I like to do mostly graphic
based and then for important key
emails, really make them stand
out by using text based.
This example of like an AB test
that we ran on text based way
higher, open rates, 42% versus
48%, way higher click rates, just
giving people text, not
distracting them with graphics,
way
higher click rate.
And then look at the revenue as
well, way, way higher, um, 13,000
versus 8,000.
And so average order value was
down, but that's kind of just due
to chance.
Um, they were leading to the same
place.
So text based can really win out
in a lot of these and as like an
overall style test them
both to be like your go-to another
high leverage, uh, test is
promoting your categories in
your emails versus your products,
like shop hoodie versus shop
shirt.
Um, do you promote different
categories to shop hoodies, shirt,
pants, or do you actually
give them specific, just like try
this, um, this lightweight hoodie
and just link to that
individual product, uh, same for
like shorts and whatnot.
Some brand customers prefer to
shop by category and some by
individual products.
So test that it's important to mix
it up.
Of course, always, always, always,
but you can bias one a little bit
more, um, especially for
important emails.
If like a product or a sale drop
email and you want it to do really
well and it's, you've
proven through your brand that
people like category more than use
categories for your main emails.
This is like categories, for
example, winning, um, you can see
it had lower opens, but it's
just the email content that we
changed.
And so the opens, that's just due
to variability, but you can see
higher clicks for the categories
and then more revenue.
Now this is relatively low volume.
So it's hard to say if it's 100%
certainty, this could just be due
to chance.
Um, but clicks also being higher
tells us something.
Um, but this is something that I
probably test a couple more times
just to be sure.
Um, but you can see that it's
definitely like category seems to
be working better there.
And then the easy high leverage
one is subject lines and preview
texts.
Um, very obvious, but take the
learnings or supply to future
emails.
I see people AB testing like every
single campaign.
Just find the layout that works
and kind of stick with that.
So here are like some tests that
you can run for sales.
You can do including the discount
amount versus not like being like,
uh, warehouse sale, take
$20 off versus just warehouse
sale, claim your discount.
And does like the ominous, like
people don't know what the
discount is.
Does that perform better?
Or do people want to know in the
subject line?
That's something that you can test
including or excluding emojis.
Um, that's something you can do.
Um, using dot, dot, dot, or
excluding like a dot, dot, dot.
Um, adding time delays, um, for
certain, um, that's supposed to be
for flows.
So ignore that, uh, using all caps
versus not.
So does that harm like your inbox
placement rate for some?
It will, some it won't.
So you can use like all caps
versus not, but really just apply
what you, what you find and
apply it to like your future, uh,
emails, but make sure you mix it
up and don't just look
at open rates.
Look at the revenue, look at
revenue when you're testing your
subject lines and preview
texts.
That's all we care about.
Maybe one has a slightly lower
open rate, but it has more
revenue.
Those people who did open, they
were more ready to purchase based
on the subject line and preview
text.
And all we care about is revenue.
That's what we want if we want to
scale.
So these are the high leverage
tests that you can do in your
campaigns.
Again, these aren't the only
tests.
There are literally infinite
possible tests.
So test, test, test.
These are just the general ones
that are high leverage that you
can start with.
Um, possibilities are endless.
So don't just test what I'm
telling you.
Test more.
Okay.
So campaign AB test, what should
we be testing in campaigns?
How do we do it?
All that good stuff.
So the possibilities for AB
testing are literally endless for
your campaigns.
You can test anything.
And so you should test anything.
Don't just wait for me to hold
your hand and tell you test this.
Just test.
Um, it's important to make sure
though, that you do have the
proper volume to know that
your results are conclusive.
If you send a campaign to 50
people and you have an AB test
going to 25 and then 25, that's
just not quite enough to like know
if your results are conclusive.
You can look up, I don't know if
you remember like algebra class
and stats class, but there's
something known as like
statistically significant where
you can like put in your numbers,
whatever
your AB test is, put it into a
calculator and it tells you is, is
the winner really the
winner or is it just due to
chance?
And so you can use a statistical
test thingy, um, for, uh, seeing
if your results are conclusive.
And so that's something that you
want to make sure that you have in
mind is don't just end
AB tests because you have one is
slightly more than the other.
Make sure you look a little bit
deeper.
If you need to send multiple
emails to get enough data to make
a conclusion, that's fine.
If you're testing sending at 9am
versus 12pm and everything's
relatively the same, feel
free to send again and again until
you get a clear winner.
If there's no clear winner, cool.
Then you know that 9am or 12pm,
you can use them both because the
results are relatively
the same.
Um, and since you can choose
anything though, I will
acknowledge that it's hard to
choose.
What do I test?
Um, so you want to start off with
the highest leverage tests, which
is what I'm going to
be sharing with you here.
Just super high leverage, focus on
these.
And then once you have these down
and you have, you have like your
campaign layout and whatnot,
then you can test like the more
advanced stuff.
So moving right along, we have
some initial high leverage AB
tests.
Number one is your campaign sends
time.
So, and this is also just happens
to be very high leverage and very,
very easy to set up
because you don't need to use
different email content.
You can just change the send time.
Different lists are going to
respond better at different times
of the day.
It's a really important to
understand.
Some people like your demographic
is like college kids.
They might be, um, not checking
their stuff like during the
morning.
You don't want to send before 10am
because people sleep in.
Um, but like night they're good.
Whereas like some people like old
folks, they are better responding
at like in the morning.
So you want to make sure that
you're testing.
Um, good practice to send at the
same time for most of your
campaigns so that customers get
like accustomed to receiving your
emails at a certain part of the
day where it's like part
of their lunch break to check your
emails or whatever.
Um, but you want to make sure that
you're mixing it up.
You don't just want to send every
single time at the same time.
Mix it up a little bit, but lean
more towards the one that performs
the best.
Um, again, some lists will respond
better here and there and whatnot.
Typically I found that in most
cases, 11am to 12pm is kind of the
best because people are
awake.
They can check their emails during
lunch, but you also give somebody
the full day to check
their email.
It's really difficult to get
somebody to open an email from
yesterday just because it's
yesterday
that's out of the person's mind.
And so if we send early enough,
like at 11am, somebody goes to bed
at 9pm, we have nine
hours for the person to open the
email app and see our email.
Um, that's why like you might get
more initial opens at 5pm if you
send an email then, but
you don't give people like the
chance to open the email for the
rest of the day.
So typically like 11 to 12, 1pm is
kind of what I find.
Um, the main test times that I
would test for like your normal
sense are like 9am, 12pm,
two, four.
I usually go by like two hour
increments.
Um, so you can test there, start
at 9am versus four and then slowly
like until you find like
the middle that performs the best.
So here's like the impact that a
send time could be something as
little as 11am versus
1 45pm.
This is like a reminder.
They're both same reminder.
We have a lot of data here.
Look at the increase in open
rates, 48% versus 42%.
And then click rate as well was
higher.
And then also placed order rate
was higher and the total revenue.
So that is a very big impact.
And so now we know, okay, 1 45
between 1 to 2pm is better than
like 11am before lunch.
Also important to keep in mind
what day it is.
Sundays are going to be different
than like Tuesdays because Sundays
people don't have work
or anything.
And so you want to have send times
for the weekend that are kind of
your go-to and then
also weekdays.
So that's very important to note
as well.
Next, very high lever is like
graphic based emails versus text
based.
Now you can do like overall style
of just like mainly a graphic
based email versus one
with like a little bit more text.
That's something you could do.
You could also do base graphic or
plain text only, which is like
HTML for where it's just
the text.
It shows up native in the person's
inbox.
That's something that you can
test.
So it's really going to vary
across a lot of accounts and like
your branding on other
platforms, it's going to depend as
well.
So just test, test, test, test the
different styles to see what your
list performs better
with.
Lots of lifestyle graphics versus
like product style graphics.
What works best?
What gets more clicks?
Especially for big drops in sales,
you want to test this.
We find that you want to mix them
up, but use text based for like a
lot of key emails.
When you have a text based email
that's just from the founder and
it's like, hey, it's
max from well copy.
I wanted to personally reach out
and say that this sale is live.
Those usually can perform really
well for like big main emails.
But if you send text based emails
every single time, then that
doesn't have novelty.
That text based from me doesn't
carry as much weight.
So I like to do mostly graphic
based and then for important key
emails, really make them stand
out by using text based.
This example of like an AB test
that we ran on text based.
Way higher open rates.
42% versus 48%.
Way higher click rates.
Just giving people text, not
distracting them with graphics.
Way higher click rate.
And then look at the revenue as
well.
Way, way higher.
13,000 versus 8,000.
And so average order value was
down, but that's kind of just due
to chance.
They were leading to the same
place.
So text based can really win out
in a lot of these.
And as like an overall style, test
them both to be like your go-to.
Another high leverage test is
promoting your categories in your
emails versus your products.
Like shop hoodie versus shop
shirt.
Do you promote different
categories to shop hoodies, shirt,
pants, or do you actually give
them a specific, just like try
this, this lightweight hoodie and
just link to that individual
product.
Same for like shorts and whatnot.
Some brand customers prefer to
shop by category and some by
individual products.
So test that.
It's important to mix it up.
Of course, always, always, always,
but you can bias one a little bit
more, especially for
important emails.
If like a product or a sale drop
email and you want it to do really
well and you've proven
through your brand that people
like category more, then use
categories for your main emails.
This is like categories, for
example, winning.
You can see it had lower opens,
but it's just the email content
that we changed.
And so the opens, that's just due
to variability.
But you can see higher clicks for
the categories and then more
revenue.
Now, this is relatively low
volume.
So it's hard to say if it's 100%
certainty, this could just be due
to chance.
But clicks also being higher tells
us something.
But this is something that I'd
probably test a couple more times
just to be sure.
But you can see that it's
definitely like category seems to
be working better there.
And then the easy, high leverage
one is subject lines and preview
texts.
Very obvious, but take the
learnings or supply to future
emails.
I see people A-B testing like
every single campaign.
Just find the layout that works
and kind of stick with that.
So here are like some tests that
you can run.
For sales, you can do including
the discount amount versus not
like being like warehouse sale,
take $20 off versus just warehouse
sale, claim your discount.
And does like the ominous, like
people don't know what the
discount is.
Does that perform better?
Or do people want to know in the
subject line?
That's something that you can
test.
Including or excluding emojis.
That's something you can do.
Using dot, dot, dot or excluding
like a dot, dot, dot.
Adding time delays for certain.
That's supposed to be for flows,
so ignore that.
Using all caps versus not.
So does that harm like your inbox
placement rate?
For some it will, some it won't.
So you can use like all caps
versus not.
But really just apply what you
find and apply it to like your
future emails.
But make sure you mix it up and
don't just look at open rates,
look at the revenue.
Look at revenue when you're
testing your subject lines and
preview text.
That's all we care about.
Maybe one has a slightly lower
open rate, but it has more
revenue.
Those people who did open, they
were more ready to purchase based
on the subject line and preview
text.
And all we care about is revenue.
That's what we want if we want to
scale.
So these are the high leverage
tests that you can do in your
campaigns.
Again, these aren't the only
tests.
They are literally infinite
possible tests.
So test, test, test.
These are just the general ones
that are high leverage that you
can start with.
Possibilities are endless.
So don't just test what I'm
telling you, test more.