Okay, so this is an instant way to
boost your deliverability and how
your emails are set
up so that you don't look spammy
in the eyes of inbox service
providers.
So super duper easy.
We do this for every single
account that we work on and it
makes such a massive difference
and it's all in your footer.
So sending emails with images.
So in theory, you can send emails
with just image files.
You can do that, but it looks
spammy.
You probably have a higher inbox
placement rate if you're just
sending massive image files
and that's purely what's in your
email.
That's all that Gmail is seeing is
there's a ton of images in here.
However, a big misconception in
the space is that you can't send
email with many images.
You have to mix in HTML, you have
to mix and match stuff, which is
just completely false.
You can send primarily image-based
emails, you can have large image
files, you can have 20
different images in an email.
I wouldn't recommend that.
But you can do that as long as you
have HTML in your email,
particularly in the footer.
So what is HTML?
It's essentially just native text.
So like a text box inside of
Klaviyo or whatever provider
you're using, that is HTML.
It's not an image.
It's like coded into the email.
It is the text.
It's just a text box to write
text.
That is HTML.
So as long as we have some of that
in our email and we have a good
ratio of image to text,
then we are good to go.
The problem with HTML, so you're
probably thinking, okay, why don't
we have an email where it's
like we have image and then text
is HTML and then we do more images
and then text.
Now the problem with that is
because they are super annoying to
deal with and optimize in your
emails.
One thing is you can't put HTML
over images, so your design is
really limited.
So what that means is you can't
have text in your images.
If you want to have like HTML text
like over, if you have like a cool
image and you want
to put over top the image of like
someone wearing your product, you
want to say like new product,
that has to be fully in.
You can't put HTML over that image
as that text.
You'd have to design in an outside
platform and put that text over
top of it and export that
whole image.
That's the only thing.
So you can't put HTML over images.
So if you don't use, if that, if
the only way you use text is with
HTML, you're really limited
because then you have to separate
images and text everywhere.
So that's super annoying.
When you do Klaviyo discount
codes, that has to be in HTML, for
example.
So that's one thing.
Another is text size.
That's going to change for people
on different devices.
So if you have HTML and you set
your text size as like 16, that's
going to look different
for people on mobile versus
desktop versus iPad.
For people on mobile who have
zoomed in automatically on because
they have terrible eyesight, it's
going
to look different for everybody.
And so you have no way to predict
how your emails are going to look
for everyone.
So that's another thing.
A big thing is HTML sections are
also going to change colors in
dark mode versus light mode, which
is the most annoying
thing because you can have like an
awesome email with like the colors
perfectly.
They look amazing inside of light
mode.
All the colors go together.
Well, but at the second somebody
use turns on dark mode, if you
have HTML for like text,
everything's
going to invert colors and your
emails colors just get completely
thrown out of whack.
Super duper annoying.
So we want to avoid that at all
costs.
I hate HTML and I hate
interweaving it into my email
designs because it throws
everything
off and you don't know how your
email actually looks for the user.
The trick to put HTML in your
email is having a ton of text in
your footer.
So rather than mixing HTML into
your email design, which is going
to vary from person to person
cause an inconsistent experience.
We just add a shnikes ton of HTML
in our footer.
That's completely out of the way
of the design and it doesn't
interfere with it at all.
To take it a step further, which
doesn't throw off our footer.
We try to make the HTML invisible
as invisible as possible.
In some appearances, that'll be
like this little blurb, which
might people might be like,
"Oh, what the heck?"
But it doesn't make any impact on
conversions.
So we make it invisible where we
can.
So this is like light mode, for
example.
So all that we do, copy some copy
from like your about us section on
your website.
I'll just take like a random part
of the website that talks about
our mission or whatever.
Just copy it all.
Usually like 400 to 500 words is
enough.
And then add a text box in your
footer.
Paste that copy.
Make the text size as small as
possible.
So I believe this is size like
four or five.
Make it as small as possible.
You can see it with like the small
footer text right there.
So that really puts into
perspective how small this is.
Make it as small as possible.
Then make the text color the same
color as the background.
So this is before changing colors,
how much text there is, and then
after.
That's what it looks like.
You can see how small it is.
It barely takes up any space.
Doesn't really look like a big
anything at all.
But it makes such a big difference
in how your emails are looked at
with like Gmail.
Because when Gmail, when they're
just looking at your email file,
they're saying has some images and
it has a ton of HTML.
Good to go.
So that's a trick that you want to
make sure that you're having in
all of your emails.
Okay.
So this is an instant way to boost
your deliverability and how your
emails are set up so that you
don't look spammy in the eyes of
inbox service providers.
So super duper easy.
We do this for every single
account that we work on and it
makes such a massive difference.
And it's all in your footer.
So sending emails with images.
So in theory, you can send emails
with just image files.
You can do that, but it looks
spammy.
You probably have a higher inbox
placement rate if you're just
sending massive image files and
that's purely what's in your
email.
And that's all that Gmail is
seeing is there's a ton of images
in here.
Um, however, a big misconception
in the space is that you can't
send email with many images.
Like you have to mix in HTML.
Like you have to mix and match
stuff, which is just completely
false.
You can send like primarily image
based emails.
You can have large image files.
You can have 20 different images
in an email.
I wouldn't recommend that, but you
can do that as long as you have
HTML in your email, particularly
in the footer.
So what is HTML?
It's essentially just native text.
So like a text box inside of
Klaviyo or whatever provider
you're using.
That is HTML.
It's not an image.
It's like coded into the email.
It is the text.
So just a text box to write text.
That is HTML.
So as long as we have some of that
in our email and we have a good
ratio of image to text, then we
are good to go.
The problem with HTML.
So you're probably thinking, okay,
why don't we have an email where
it's like we have image image and
then text is HTML and then we do
more images and then text.
Now the problem with that is
because they are super annoying to
deal with and optimize in your
emails.
One thing is you can't put HTML
over images.
So your design is really limited.
So what that means is you can't
have text in your images.
If you want to have like HTML text
like over if you you have like a
cool image and you want to put
over top the image of like someone
wearing your product.
You want to say like new product
that has to be fully in.
You can't put HTML over that image
as that text.
You'd have to design in an outside
platform and put that text over
top of it and export that whole
image.
So that's the only thing.
So you can't put HTML over images.
So if you don't use if that if the
only way you use text is with
HTML, you're really limited
because then you have to separate
images and text everywhere.
So that's super annoying.
When you do Klaviyo discount
codes, that has to be in HTML, for
example.
So that's one thing.
Another is text size.
That's going to change for people
on different devices.
So if you have HTML and you set
your text size is like 16, that's
going to look different for people
on mobile versus desktop versus
iPad.
For people on mobile who have
zoomed in automatically on because
they have terrible eyesight, it's
going to look different for
everybody.
And so you have no way to predict
how your emails are going to look
for everyone.
So that's another thing.
A big thing is HTML sections are
also going to change colors in
dark mode versus light mode, light
mode, which is the most annoying
thing because you can have like an
awesome email with like the colors
perfectly.
They look amazing inside of light
mode, all the colors go together.
Well, but at the second somebody
use turns on dark mode, if you
have HTML for like text,
everything's going to invert
colors and your emails colors just
get completely thrown out of
whack.
Super duper annoying.
So we want to avoid that at all
costs.
I hate HTML and I hate
interweaving it into my email
designs because it throws
everything off and you don't know
how your email actually looks for
the user.
The trick to put HTML on your
email is having a ton of text in
your footer.
So rather than mixing HTML into
your email design, which is going
to vary from person to person,
cause an inconsistent experience.
We just add a nice ton of HTML in
our footer that's completely out
of the way of the design and it
doesn't interfere with it at all.
To take it a step further, which
doesn't throw off our footer, we
try to make the HTML invisible, as
invisible as possible.
In some appearances, it'll be like
this little blurb, which might,
people might be like, oh, what the
heck?
But it doesn't make any impact on
conversions.
So we make it invisible where we
can.
So this is like light mode, for
example.
So all that we do, copy some copy
from like your about us section on
your website.
I'll just take like a random part
of the website that talks about
our mission or whatever.
Just copy it all.
Usually like 400 to 500 words is
enough.
And then add a text box in your
footer.
Paste that copy.
Make the text size as small as
possible.
So I believe this is size like
four or five.
Make it as small as possible.
You can see it with like the small
footer text right there.
So that really puts into
perspective how small this is.
Make it as small as possible.
Then make the text color the same
color as the background.
So this is before changing colors,
how much text there is, and then
after.
That's what it looks like.
You can see how small it is.
It barely takes up any space.
It doesn't really look like a big,
big anything at all.
But it makes such a big difference
in how your emails are looked at
with like Gmail.
Cause when Gmail, when they're
just looking at your email file,
they're saying has some images and
it has a ton of HTML.
Good to go.
So that's a trick that you want to
make sure that you're having in
all of your emails.