So those are the basic use cases
now let's talk about the different
types of
segmentations and then we'll get
into like some actual core
segments that we
use so this type of segmentation
of email engagement segmentation
so it's
great for deliverability and
understanding how your list is
responding to your email so we're
just creating segments based on
somebody's
engagement with our emails not
with the store just with our
emails so typically
you want to send most your emails
to just the people who are engaged
so don't
send to the whole list just send
to like your 60-day engaged list
which I
outline here you can judge
engagement based on opens clicks
bounces and more
that's typically how you do it so
key segments are things like
people who have
opened an email in the past 60
days those are what you call your
engaged
profiles this is what you want to
be like your main segment and
again I will be
sharing definitions for all of
these like specific Klaviyo
definitions in just a
few minutes but that's like your
engaged list you have people who
have clicked an
email in the past 60 days that's
like your most engaged profiles
you people who
have subscribed to email marketing
in the past 30 days it's gonna be
like fresh
profiles so you can get a sense of
how many people have been joining
the list you
people who have bounced at least
one email over top all time which
a bounce is
essentially if you send an email
to somebody and like the email
isn't
associated with anything anymore
it's like a fake email then it'll
result in like a
bounce so that's a high-risk
profile we also have people who
have marked an
email as spam at least once
uninterested we want to suppress
them and then
people haven't opened an email at
least once in the past 120 days
churned
subscribers so if you think about
that 120 days is a very very long
time and so
yeah you don't want to be sending
those people that's four months if
you've been
sending emails consistently they
haven't opened any in four months
they probably
don't care so you can put them to
like churn subscribers and maybe
send them
emails like on black friday so
that's engagement based
segmentation now let's
talk about store engagement
segmentation very similar but
instead of talking
about email we're talking about
their actual interactions on your
store so
somebody could be engaged on your
store but not on your email list
and also the
other way around and so this is
store engaged segmentation so you
can get a
feel for where people are kind of
like being lost in the funnel so
if you see a
lot of people have been viewing a
product but they haven't been
adding to cart then
you know that you might have like
a product problem so these
segments and
metrics allow you to track when
people are viewing adding to cart
making
purchases so some key segments
you've people who have viewed a
product at least
once in the past 30 days but have
not made a purchase during this
time that's
like interested customers they've
gone on your side a bit but they
just haven't
really found the item that they
are ready to move on to make a
purchase with so
then you have a step further so
people have added a car to start a
checkout in
the past 30 days but they haven't
made a purchase that's high
likelihood to
purchase so these are people you
really want to make sure that
you're engaging you
people who place an order which
will be like recent buyers you
have people who
place an order five plus times
over all time that's like VIP
customers and then you
could do something even as far as
like people who viewed at least
three
products but like having made a
purchase it's like window shoppers
like they're
shopping around so that's like
store engagement that's kind of
like the stuff
that you could do for that you can
also do location segmentation so
segmenting
your list based on where they're
at in the world so it's gonna be
helpful for
personalized targeted campaigns
towards people in different areas
just as like if
you have like in-person events
like we're putting an email
together right now for
client for an in-person event if
it's like hey we're in San Diego
California and we're having a
pop-up store you can search people
who are in that
city and then send them emails
this could also be different for
like compliance if
you have compliance email
compliance stuff or different
stores for different
countries then you can have stuff
custom to them so common segments
it's just like
segment customers based on like
where your home state is or like
your brand
headquarters in case you have
pop-up shops or segment based on
country nothing
really you need to do there and
then we have a little bit advanced
we have
predictive analytics segmentation
so this is a Klaviyo feature which
aren't
perfect but they give you some
data to work with and this is like
kind of where I like to get
information about people's lists
it just looks at certain customer
behavior to predict certain like
metrics or characteristics so you
can find high
spenders who have like AOV
calculations so you can so if we
look here in Klaviyo
you can just go to create a
segment predictive analytics about
somebody if you go
average order value you can see
how many people are in different
cohorts of like
average order value so say your
products your store typically a
$50 average order
value you can create a segment of
people whose average order value
is $100 plus and
then segment that it's probably
maybe you have like a couple
thousand people you
could send them like large bundle
deals or if you have like a lot of
stock that
you want to get rid of you could
send them like a massive like hey
buy $500 worth of
stuff and you get like 50% off
something like that and they're
much more likely to
purchase so you've like predictive
AOV you find VIP customers with
customer
lifetime value calculations with
customer lifetime value value
right here you can
do that you could segment and send
timely messages to customers based
on like the
average time between purchases so
if you have a cohort where they
usually buy like
45 days in between purchases then
you could set up a flow where like
on day 40 you're
sending reminders to somebody
right at that time and also like a
big one that we use
a segment based on like gender and
then like send specific products
and emails
based on the gender that they that
Klaviyo believes they are and you
can see
these are the different options
that Klaviyo gives you so you can
take this as
far as you want