Okay, so we just got finished
talking about campaign A-B tests.
Flow A-B tests are going to be
very, very similar,
but flows are very important to be
testing
because these are always going to
be firing out to the customer,
and we want to make sure that they
are optimized
because, again, these are
high-converting important emails,
like abandoned cart emails.
Same as campaigns, possibilities
are endless.
You can literally test anything.
In the same tests that I gave you
for campaigns,
you can do to flows.
So apply those, graphic-based
versus text-based.
That's going to be super key for a
lot of your emails.
Like abandoned cart tests like a
graphic-based abandoned cart email
versus like a text-based and like
the placement of those emails, all
that.
So everything that I listed about
campaigns, A-B tests,
can be the same with flows.
One of the biggest levers I'd say
easiest to do are flow time
delays.
How long do you wait before
sending messages,
especially the first email?
So after somebody completes an
action,
how long are we waiting until we
send them like a site abandoned
email
or a cart abandoned?
How long are we waiting?
And so you can also time delay
between your messages,
between day one and day two.
Should we send the second email
same day, eight hours later,
or should we send it 24 hours
later?
Test, test, test.
So like this is an example of
waiting 30 minutes
versus waiting four hours for the
site abandoned.
We have over 1,100 people
receiving both of these,
and we have pretty conclusive
evidence here
that ordered product is higher,
placed order rate and revenue.
lower open rate and lower click
rate.
All we care about is revenue
though.
What we care about is revenue.
If we're waiting 30 minutes,
it's kind of like too early
where the person hasn't thought
about it too much.
Maybe they'll re-engage,
but they're not ready to buy.
And then this just happened to
perform better.
It's going to change brand to
brand.
Make sure you test it.
This was the one that we ended up
going with.
So flow time delays,
that first initial time,
and then also your time between
messages.
Make sure you're testing them
both.
Especially for flows,
we want to test your longer form
content
versus shorter form.
This is going to apply to
campaigns,
but especially in flows like your
abandonments
when people have objections,
you want to see,
do people kind of just need to be
reminded about the product
and we can have a really quick
email?
Or do we need to really extend the
email,
overcome their objections,
and all this good stuff?
Sometimes it makes sense to just
be quick
and try to get them to do an
impulse purchase.
Other times you want to spend time
working through objections.
So this was an abandoned cart
email too,
where we did like a really long,
longer email.
This was a text-based email.
And this was like a thousand
words.
And then this one was,
no, not a thousand.
This was probably like 300 to 400
words.
This one was like a hundred words,
if that.
And this one just performed
better.
A lot better.
Way higher clicks.
Open rate, I'm not going to
attribute to it,
but we have over 2,000 people
in a way higher place to order
rate
and way higher revenue
from just being short
and just being like,
hey, you left this behind.
Our product is really good.
Shop now.
Rather than doing this one,
where it's like,
hey, you left this behind.
Our product is really good
because of this reason, this
reason, this reason.
The short one just happened to
work in this scenario.
And so test your long form versus
short form.
It's going to change.
And then again, same as campaigns.
Graphic versus text-based.
Categories versus individual
products.
Subject lines and preview text.
But the real ones that I want you
to focus on
that are the highest leverage
right off the bat
are your time delays
and then also the long form versus
short form.
Okay, so we just got finished
talking
about campaign A-B tests.
Flow A-B tests are going to be
very, very similar.
But flows are very important to be
testing
because these are always going to
be firing out
to the customer.
And we want to make sure that they
are optimized
because, again, these are
high-converting important emails
like abandoned cart emails.
Same as campaigns, possibilities
are endless.
You can literally test anything.
And the same tests that I gave you
for campaigns,
you can do to flows.
So apply those.
Graphic-based versus text-based.
That's going to be super key for a
lot of your emails.
Like abandoned cart tests like a
graphic-based abandoned cart email
versus like a text-based
and like the placement of those
emails.
All that.
So everything that I listed about
campaigns, A-B tests,
can be the same with flows.
One of the biggest levers I'd say
easiest to do are flow time
delays.
How long do you wait before
sending messages?
Especially the first email.
So after somebody completes an
action,
how long are we waiting until we
send them like a site abandoned
email?
Or a cart abandoned.
How long are we waiting?
And so you can also time delay
between your messages,
between day one and day two.
Should we send the second email
same day, eight hours later?
Or should we send it 24 hours
later?
Test, test, test.
So like this is an example of
waiting 30 minutes
versus waiting four hours for the
site abandoned.
We have over 1,100 people
receiving both of these
and we have pretty conclusive
evidence here
that ordered product is higher.
Placed order rate and revenue.
Lower open rate and lower click
rate.
All we care about is revenue
though.
What we care about is revenue.
If we're waiting 30 minutes,
it's kind of like too early
where the person hasn't thought
about it too much.
Maybe they'll re-engage, but
they're not ready to buy.
And then this just happened to
perform better.
It's going to change brand to
brand.
Make sure you test it.
This was the one that we ended up
going with.
So flow time delays, that first
initial time
and then also your time between
messages.
Make sure you're testing them
both.
Especially for flows,
we want to test your longer form
content
versus shorter form.
This is going to apply to
campaigns,
but especially in flows like your
abandonments
when people have objections,
you want to see,
do people kind of just need to be
reminded
about the product
and we can have a really quick
email?
Or do we need to really extend the
email,
overcome their objections
and all this good stuff?
Sometimes it makes sense to just
be quick
and try to get them to do an
impulse purchase.
Other times you want to spend time
working through objections.
So this was an abandoned cart
email too
where we did like a really long,
longer email.
This was a text-based email
and this was like 1,000 words
and then this one was,
no, not 1,000.
This was probably like 300 to 400
words.
This one was like 100 words, if
that.
And this one just performed
better.
A lot better.
Way higher clicks.
Open rate, I'm not going to
attribute to it,
but we have over 2,000 people
in a way higher place to order
rate
and way higher revenue
from just being short
and just being like,
hey, you left this behind.
Our product is really good.
Shop now.
Rather than doing this one
where it's like,
hey, you left this behind.
our product is really good
because this reason, this reason,
this reason.
The short one just happened to
work in this scenario.
And so test your long form versus
short form.
It's going to change.
And then again, same as campaigns,
graphic versus text-based,
categories versus individual
products,
subject lines and preview text.
But the real ones that I want you
to focus on
that are the highest leverage
right off the bat
are your time delays
and then also the long form versus
short form.