- Deliverability, you can't make
any money
if nobody is actually seeing your
emails.
So this is one of my most asked
about topics,
deliverability, how to make sure
that you're landing
in the inbox and you're not
landing in the spam folder.
Now, obviously we don't wanna be
in the spam folder.
Now, this is one of my most asked
about topics,
is deliverability, kinda as I had
gone over,
but it's really not that
difficult,
but we're gonna break that in,
I'm gonna make it real easy for
you.
So results of great
deliverability,
this is kinda where you wanna be
at.
This is how you know you are
landing in the main inbox
if you're sending this to like
general engaged segments.
61% open rates, 2.79% click rates,
great place to order rates and
revenue per recipient.
So we recovered the deliverability
of this brand,
like this, and these were the
results.
So that's where you can be at if
you're in the right spot.
And I hate how complicated many
people
make deliverability seem.
So it seems like this really
daunting topic
and everybody throws out like all
of this stuff
with like these crazy terms
and S-B-A-B-A-B-A-B-A-B-A.
Like it's just none of it is
necessary.
Deliverability is really, really
easy.
And you can, anybody can do it.
Anybody can do it.
In most cases, a lot of people are
trying to make it seem
like you can't do it yourself and
then you have to work with them.
But I'm telling you right now that
it's super easy
and I'm going to go over why and
how to make sure
that you're doing deliverability
right
so that you can have long-term
placement.
So what is deliverability?
So inbox providers.
So if you think of like Gmail, for
example,
they want to improve the
experience of their customers.
Their customers are people who use
Gmail.
And so they want to improve the
experience
by only showing them emails that
the customers want to see.
So what your deliverability is,
is essentially your domain and
IP's like credit score.
So what, like in the eyes of these
inbox providers,
how good of a sender are you?
How much do people open your
emails?
How often are people engaging with
your emails?
If you're not getting a lot of
engagement on your emails,
then you're going to have bad
deliverability
because Google is going to see
that and be like,
okay, these emails are getting
sent,
but people aren't engaging with
them.
This is probably not a reputable
sender.
And we're going to give them a bad
credit score.
So if you have a good credit
score,
you're going to land in the
primary tab,
which is just like the main inbox,
which most of your emails are
landing in.
And then you also, if you have a
bad credit score,
you're going to land in spam,
which is down here.
And nobody really goes through
their spam,
which is unfortunate.
And that's going to destroy your
revenue numbers.
If someone in the middle,
you can land in the promotions tab
or any of these tabs,
different providers will have
different stuff,
but you can land in promotions.
But obviously we want to be in the
green.
So all we need to do to get
in the green is have a good credit
score,
which I'm going to be going over
with you.
So just think in the eyes of
Google,
I just really want to make it
clear
that it's really not that
difficult and complicated.
If you send an email and you get
20% open rates,
which a lot of the brands I audit,
they're sending emails and getting
20% open rates.
And I'm like, oh my goodness.
That means that two out of 10
people
are opening your emails.
That's what 20% is.
If you didn't know how numbers
worked,
20% of people, two out of 10,
you think they're going to put you
in the main inbox.
If you're constantly sending
emails and only two people out of
10 are opening them.
No.
So what happens?
You get 20% open rates.
Gmail looks at that and they're
like,
hmm, where should we put this
person?
Oh, their reputation goes down.
And so that further puts you
inside of like the spam folder
promotions tab.
And that continues to give low
open rates
because people also aren't seeing
your emails.
Meanwhile, if you have over half
the people
who receive your email opening
them in solid click rates,
Google's going to be like, oh,
okay.
People want to receive these
emails.
We can put this into the main
inbox.
And then that'll boost your
reputation.
You're landing in the main inbox
and this just feeds itself.
And so it can be a tough loop if
you're in the middle of it,
but that doesn't mean that it
can't be solved.
So what affects deliverability?
They're really only two things.
First one is super easy, technical
setup.
So pretty much just fancy records
hosted by your domain provider in
your DNS settings.
So like MX, SPF, DMARC, and DKIM.
Don't worry.
I don't know what any of those
mean either.
So this isn't meant to like
confuse you
because like I still don't really
understand like what all these
are.
But essentially, if you have these
correctly installed on your
domain,
then you're good to go.
All you need to do is have these
set up correctly,
which you probably already do.
If you don't, you can look it up
on Google
or when you sign up with an inbox
provider,
with an email sending provider
like Klaviyo,
which I hope you're using.
Don't use anything else.
Klaviyo will tell you,
oh, you don't have this.
So follow this guide to get it
installed.
Super easy.
Same as a dedicated Klaviyo
sending domain,
which rather than using like a
shared Klaviyo domain,
which again, Klaviyo will let you
know like,
hey, you're not on a shared,
you're not, you don't have your
own domain.
You need to set this up.
So again, that's super easy.
That's technical setup.
You set it up once,
it takes 10, 15 minutes,
and then you're good to go.
And then number two is send a
reputation.
That's the other thing that's
going to affect your
deliverability.
So your send a reputation is your
quote unquote credit score,
which is a combination of your
email engagement metrics,
like your open rates, click rates,
bounce rates, spam complaints,
all of those combined into like
one overall send a reputation.
Now there's not like a database
where you can look at your send a
reputation.
You can just look at like how
you're landing in the inbox and
whatnot.
So that's like the main thing,
your email engagement.
Plus one thing is just proper
domain warmup.
So which affects your send a
reputation.
So you can't just like buy a
domain on Squarespace or whatever
today.
And then tomorrow send emails to
50,000 people at once.
They see that Google sees and it's
like this fresh domain just did
all this sending and got poor
engagement.
You're going to get like
blacklisted.
So there's a proper domain.
Like when you're setting up a new
domain, you have to make sure that
it's warmed up.
And so which really is not that
difficult.
You just start off sending to a
couple hundred people and then
just increase that over time.
Really only takes like a couple
weeks.
If you have automated flow emails,
if you just let your flows run for
a couple months, you're going to
be properly warmed up.
Because flows will just
automatically send to people high
engaging emails.
So really not that hard.
But we're going to be talking
about all of this in these
modules.
Deliverability, super easy.
It's just where you're landing in
the inbox and what is your
reputation?
Have you proven that people want
to open your emails?
If you have, you'll land in the
main inbox.
So that's deliverability.
Let's talk about it.
Deliverability.
You can't make any money if nobody
is actually seeing your email.
So this is one of my most asked
about topics.
Deliverability, how to make sure
that you're landing in the inbox
and you're not landing in the spam
folder.
Now, obviously we don't want to be
in the spam folder.
Now, this is one of my most asked
about topics is deliverability.
Kind of as I had gone over.
But it's really not that
difficult.
But we're going to break that in.
I'm going to make it real easy for
you.
So results of great
deliverability.
This is kind of where you want to
be at.
This is how you know you are
landing in the main inbox.
If you're sending this to like
general engaged segments.
61% open rates, 2.79% click rates,
great place to order rates, and
revenue per recipient.
So we recovered the deliverability
of this brand like this.
And these were the results.
So that's where you can be at if
you're in the right spot.
And I hate how complicated many
people make deliverability seem.
So it seems like this really
daunting topic.
And everybody throws out like all
of this stuff with like these
crazy terms and SPO.
Like it's just none of it is
necessary.
Deliverability is really, really
easy.
And you can, anybody can do it.
Anybody can do it.
In most cases, a lot of people are
trying to make it seem like you
can't do it yourself.
And then you have to work with
them.
But I'm telling you right now that
it's super easy and I'm going to
go over why and how to make sure
that you're doing deliverability
right so that you can have
long-term placement.
So what is deliverability?
So inbox providers, so if you
think of like Gmail, for example,
they want to improve the
experience of their customers.
Their customers are people who use
Gmail.
And so they want to improve the
experience by only showing them
emails that the customers want to
see.
So what your deliverability is, is
essentially your domain and IP's
like credit score.
So what, like in the eyes of these
inbox providers, how good of a
sender are you?
How much do people open your
emails?
How often are people engaging with
your emails?
If you're not getting a lot of
engagement on your emails, then
you're going to have bad
deliverability because Google is
going to see that and be like,
okay, these emails are getting
sent, but people aren't engaging
with them.
This is probably not a reputable
sender.
And we're going to give them a bad
credit score.
So if you have a good credit
score, you're going to land in the
primary tab, which is just like
the main inbox, which most of your
emails are landing in.
And then you also, if you have a
bad credit score, you're going to
land in spam, which is down here.
And nobody really goes through
their spam, which is unfortunate.
And that's going to destroy your
revenue numbers.
For someone in the middle, you can
land in the promotions tab or any
of these tabs.
Different providers will have
different stuff, but you can land
in promotions.
But obviously we want to be in the
green.
So all we need to do to get in the
green is have a good credit score,
which I'm going to be going over
with you.
So just think in the eyes of
Google.
I just really want to make it
clear that it's really not that
difficult and complicated.
If you send an email and you get
20% open rates, which a lot of the
brands I audit, they're sending
emails and getting 20% open rates.
And I'm like, oh my goodness.
That means that two out of 10
people are opening your emails.
That's what 20% is.
If you didn't know how numbers
worked.
20% of people, two out of 10, you
think they're going to put you in
the main inbox if you're
constantly sending emails and only
two people out of 10 are opening
them.
No.
So what happens?
You get 20% open rates.
Gmail looks at that and they're
like, hmm, where should we put
this person?
Oh, their reputation goes down.
And so that further puts you
inside of like the spam folder
promotions tab and that continues
to give low open rates because
people also aren't seeing your
emails.
Meanwhile, if you have over half
the people who receive your email
opening them in solid click rates,
Google's going to be like, oh,
okay.
People want to receive these
emails.
We can put this into the main
inbox.
And then that'll boost your
reputation.
You're landing in the main inbox
and this just feeds itself.
And so it can be a tough loop if
you're in the middle of it, but
that doesn't mean that it can't be
solved.
So what affects deliverability?
They're really only two things.
First one is super easy.
Technical setup.
So pretty much just fancy records
hosted by your domain provider in
your DNS settings.
So like MX, SPF, DMARC, and DKIM.
Don't worry.
I don't know what any of those
mean either.
So this isn't meant to like
confuse you because like I still
don't really understand like what
all these are.
But essentially, if you have these
correctly installed on your
domain, then you're good to go.
All you need to do is have these
set up correctly, which you
probably already do.
If you don't, you can look it up
on Google or when you sign up with
an inbox provider, with an email
sending provider like Klaviyo,
which I hope you're using.
Don't use anything else.
Klaviyo will tell you, oh, you
don't have this.
So follow this guide to get it
installed.
Super easy.
Same as a dedicated Klaviyo
sending domain, which rather than
using like a shared Klaviyo
domain, which again, Klaviyo will
let you know like, hey, you're not
on a shared, you're not, you don't
have your own domain.
You need to set this up.
So again, that's super easy.
That's technical setup.
You set it up once, takes 10, 15
minutes, and then you're good to
go.
And then number two is send a
reputation.
That's the other thing that's
going to affect your
deliverability.
So your send a reputation is your
quote unquote credit score, which
is a combination of your email
engagement metrics, like your open
rates, click rates, bounce rates,
spam complaints, all of those
combined into like one overall
send a reputation.
Now, there's not like a database
where you can look at your send a
reputation.
You can just look at like how
you're landing in the inbox and
whatnot.
So that's like the main thing,
your email engagement.
Plus one thing is just proper
domain warmup.
So which affects your send a
reputation.
So you can't just like buy a
domain on Squarespace or whatever
today and then tomorrow send
emails to 50,000 people at once.
They see that Google sees that and
it's like this fresh domain just
did all this sending and got poor
engagement.
You're going to get like
blacklisted.
So there's a proper domain, like
when you're setting up a new
domain, you have to make sure that
it's warmed up.
And so which really is not that
difficult.
You just start off sending to a
couple hundred people and then
just increase that over time.
Really only takes like a couple
weeks.
If you have automated flow emails,
if you just let your flows run for
a couple months, you're going to
be properly warmed up because
flows will just automatically send
to people high engaging emails.
So really not that hard.
But we're going to be talking
about all of this in these
modules, deliverability, super
easy.
It's just where you're landing in
the inbox and what is your
reputation?
Have you proven that people want
to open your emails?
If you have, you'll land in the
main inbox.
So that's deliverability.
Let's talk about it.