Email marketing optimization let
us get into it this is the intro
to this new module which will
be pretty quick but we're talking
about how to so we built the bases
we have like our base
understanding but now let's talk
about how to like take our results
really to the next level so i do
want to reiterate 90 of the
results are driven by the basics
what you already know that's
carrying
90 of the load like whoever it's
just trust me the basics having
the basics in place carry
everything and so if you're under
like some like really high revenue
numbers then really just focus
on that once you get to above like
a mil a month 500k a month or so
then it really makes sense to
double down and triple down on the
advanced stuff and the
optimizations and all that stuff
but kind
of under there really just focus
on the basics and testing the crap
out of them um not necessarily
testing the crap out of them but
how do we optimize it's like you
hear like all my optimizations do
this do that really it's just a b
tests no matter what you think the
numbers don't lie this is what
optimization is just testing
testing testing testing a b tests
it's all it is testing one
thing versus another thing and
then going with whatever wins
that's as much as possible and
then apply your learnings that is
the biggest thing testing doesn't
matter if you don't apply your
learnings i see that some people
doing the same subject line or
time zone a b test for campaigns
every single day for months pick
the winner and stick with it and
if there isn't any clear winner
then you
know that you can switch between
the two but that is what we're
going to be going over is the
highest
leverage a b tests how to set them
up and all that good stuff so let
us get into it email marketing
optimization let us get into it
this is the intro to this new
module which will be pretty quick
but
we're talking about how to so we
built the bases we have like our
base understanding but now let's
talk
about how to like take our results
really to the next level so i do
want to reiterate 90 of the
results
are driven by the basics what you
already know that's carrying 90 of
the load like whoever it's
just trust me the basics having
the basics in place carry
everything and so if you're under
like
some like really high revenue
numbers then really just focus on
that once you get to above like a
mil a month 500k a month or so
then it really makes sense to
double down and triple down on the
advanced stuff and the
optimizations and all that stuff
but kind of under there really
just focus on
the basics and testing the crap
out of them um not necessarily
testing the crap out of them but
how do we optimize it's like you
hear like all my optimizations do
this do that really it's just a b
tests no matter what you think the
numbers don't lie this is what
optimization is just testing
testing
testing testing a b tests it's all
it is testing one thing versus
another thing and then going with
whatever wins test as much as
possible and then apply your
learnings that is the biggest
thing
testing doesn't matter if you
don't apply your learnings i see
that some people doing the same
subject line or time zone a b test
for campaigns every single day for
months pick the winner and
stick with it and if there isn't
any clear winner then you know
that you can switch between the
two
but that is what we're going to be
going over is the highest leverage
a b tests how to set
them up and all that good stuff so
let us get into it