What is segmentation so segments
are very very very similar to
lists but in one key way so lists
are stagnant so this is probably
what you're thinking about with
email marketing are your lists
as the name suggests just a flat
list of people whereas segments
are dynamic they can change at
any second based on the
requirements that you set on the
segment and as the name suggests
it is just
a segment of your full email list
a subset of people who meet
certain characteristics that you
provide so inside of Klaviyo it's
just right under here lists and
segments are under the same
apart you can see here are a bunch
of lists with different people
these are not segments just
because they don't say segment and
they're not dynamic they are
static so the possibilities are
literally endless for segments you
can do pretty much everything that
you could ever want so you
have everything from basics or
like segment based on like general
like email open behavior what
somebody's clicking how often
these people are doing that then
you have things that are
intermediate
where based on like recent store
activities such as like segmenting
based on if somebody abandoned a
start recently if somebody made a
purchase recently then you have
like pro which is segmenting based
on
like specific email or flow
engagement or like specific
product product category interest
all that good
stuff you can do all this the
possibilities are literally
they're literally endless but it's
just let's not get too
complicated is the main thing I
talk about with segmentation like
yes you could hyper segment your
list by their
favorite color and their belly
button whether it's an innie or an
outie and yes that would probably
increase your
conversion rate but at what cost
so I always like to ask like would
you rather send one to two
targeted
campaigns per week to different
groups of 10,000 people or three
to four broader email campaigns a
week to 50,000
people the latter will outperform
99 times out of 100 I always
prefer like our time is always
limited in the day and
what I've experienced is that
literally every single time just
by optimizing for sending more
emails to more people the revenue
is always way more
yes there's a time and place for
segmentation but optimize first
for getting like your core content
out to as many people as
possible and then from there once
you really have that down then you
can focus on the segmentation like
that's high leverage being
able to send good content to a lot
more people rather than hyper
specific content to a small group
of people who might not
even see your email because like
they're busy so I'll be sharing
with you the high leverage stuff
that you should be focusing on in
this guide