So those are the different types
of segmentation so now let's get
to like the juicy stuff which is
actually like the key segments the
segments that we build out for all
of our clients right off the
bat and stuff that we track over
time this is the 80 20 rule these
are the main ones that you want
to use all the other stuff is kind
of noise and you don't really need
to worry too much about it
uh just focus on these key
segments so this first one is the
x day engaged email members so
this is
for sending three three or more
emails per week we found that to
be optimal three to four times a
week across over 50 different econ
brands um seven and eight figures
send three to four email
campaigns a week keeps you top of
mind and it allows you to like
build that relationship with
the customer and as long as you
send good content then people will
enjoy your emails and they won't
find it annoying we notice lower
unsubscribe rates on this rather
than sending like once per week so
this is your base engaged email
segment for sending campaigns so x
stands for like whatever amount of
days you want to do i recommend
starting off with a 60 day engaged
list and only send emails to these
people like your general email
campaigns only send to people who
have opened or clicked
an email in the past 60 days so we
want to send this segment to
ensure that we're only sending
people who want to receive their
our emails to make sure we get
high engagement rates which will
keep our deliverability high
rather than sending to our whole
email list with fake profiles uh
churned
subscribers we don't want to send
to those people who aren't going
to open our emails so only send to
the engaged people um you can
adjust this from any day that you
want i recommend starting with 30
um i know i just said 60 that's
like the base but if you haven't
really done any segmentation
before start with 30 day and
slowly open your list to 60 90 and
120 as your open rates go up
so we want to be at least 40 opens
so say you start off with your 30
day engaged list and you have
uh like 35 percent opens um and
you start sending consistently you
start focusing on your content
your
open rate starts climbing it goes
from 35 to 40 to 45 to 50 once you
get to 50 then it's like okay
let's
expand the list a little bit um
then you switch it from a 30 day
engaged to a 60 day and maybe you
start
back down at like 30 and then keep
sending emails to them now you're
at 35 40 45 50 55 now let's open
it and so
that's what i always recommend
until you get to like 90 or 120
and then you're good to stop there
so this is the definition inside
of klaviyo someone can receive
email marketing because this
person is
subscribed um and then and we want
to have had someone has opened an
email at least once in the last 60
days um or it's right between that
or someone has clicked an email at
least once in the last 60 days
now you're probably like oh well
somebody has to click an email
someone has to open an email to
click so why do you both sometimes
klaviyo doesn't track the opens
sometimes it misses it so
it's just like a safety measure um
and then and what someone has done
bounced email zero times
over all time just to make sure
we're not sending to like these
fake profiles or people who have
blocked us or something so this is
like the main list where for my
clients this is where 90 of our
emails are going is just to this
sort of list and so moving on we
have the unengaged email members
so
this is for sending like one email
per month um usually this is like
for usually one campaign a month
we'll try to like unengaged people
typically you could have you could
have a specific email where
it's like hey you're you're
unengaged take 10 off to come back
um but typically we don't like to
complicate it we'll just send one
of our regular campaigns that
we're sending to the engaged list
which we which we just went over
we'll just send it to the engaged
and the unengaged people to try to
get these people back we don't
want to send every single email to
these people because they're just
going to hurt our center
reputation by driving down our
open rates but over time we can
send like once a
month typically is what i
recommend um so the unengaged
email members this insinuates that
they
were engaged at some point so we
just said someone has opened email
in the past but haven't done so
recently you can suppress these
people if you want so this is like
a base segment that you can use
someone can receive email
marketing because they're
subscribed they've opened email at
least once over
all time but they haven't opened
or clicked an email in the past 90
days so three months you could do
you
could change this from 90 days to
120 days it really doesn't matter
all that much the difference
between somebody not opening an
email in three months versus four
months isn't that big but
different
it's really all this is you can do
what you want just typically what
we do is around 90 days um
and then we'll still send emails
to these people like once a month
but this is what the segment looks
like you have you can have it here
for yourself again this talk is in
the description sorry if i didn't
say
that already um but you can have
this for free um but yeah there's
that um unengaged email members
right there this next one a little
bit more fun high potential
purchasers so this is for sending
one
to two times extra emails per
month on top of your engaged list
sends and then people these people
are
also getting abandonment uh flows
so uh high potential purchasers
this is a set of people who have
been
active on your site and have made
it somewhere in the funnel but
they just haven't made a purchase
yet so
high potential um you can send
them more emails try to get them
over the edge to increase your
sales
so maybe you have like a specific
uh sale that you're willing to run
for some people this is the
type of list that you want to send
that to like you don't want to
send it to everybody but you're
open to run a sale to a specific
number of people um people that
otherwise would be lost then you
can
send this stuff so this is the
definition that we use for high
potential purchasers you say
someone
can receive email marketing
because they're subscribed they've
placed an order zero times in the
past 30 days
so high potential purchasers
they're not purchasers right now
uh so zero times past 30 days and
they've
been active on site at least once
or you don't want to say and you
want to make sure it says or
they have viewed a product at
least once in the past 30 days or
they've added a cart or they've
started
checkout all in the past 30 days
if they've done any of those so
they've gone to checkout they've
added
to cart or they've been active on
site anything then they will
receive this now you might think
this is a
little bit redundant because
somebody if somebody adds an item
to cart that means they had to
have
been active on site sometimes
klaviyo doesn't track these things
maybe one of your triggers isn't
set
up right so it's not firing this
is just a precaution it's not
going to hurt you um use all these
just to
be safe and so this is what it
looks like inside of klaviyo it's
a lot more stuff um so you can see
this is they someone can receive
email marketing and um they've
been active on site or viewed
product
or added cart or checkout started
and they've placed an order zero
times um in the past 30 days so
that's
a segment that you want to create
for high potential purchasers and
send them like an extra one to two
emails per month if you would if
you choose to do so with like an
extra sale or just an extra push
to
try to get them over the edge then
we have vip customers which is a
another fun one so you this is
something you can send one extra
email per month uh i wouldn't do
more than this it's just a little
bit too much for a very small
subset of your list um because
they're also getting all the
engaged list
emails if they're engaged in your
emails but they're getting the
engaged list sent as well so
pretty
self-explanatory they're fans of
your brand and they keep coming
back um so you can choose to make
your vip list either on like the
number of purchases somebody has
made or the total amount spent at
your store completely preference
based me as a marketer i prefer
total number of
purchases because you can predict
it a little bit better and send
emails every purchase letting
people know how many purchases
they are from the vip list um so
for example if we do like uh on
your
fifth purchase you're a vip member
then that means like after
somebody makes their fourth
purchase we
can be like yo you're one purchase
away from getting like a free gift
or something and being on our vip
list with exclusive information um
so then it's a lot more it's a lot
easier to get sales that way and
you
can do that for like the third
purchase as well whereas if you do
like a total value spend of like a
thousand
dollars really it's a lot more
difficult to predict that because
somebody's at like 900 spent and
you're like yo you're it's harder
to say it's a little bit more
cheap not like it's like sales
they'd be like you have to give us
a hundred more dollars and we'll
give you a gift rather than like
you place another order and it's a
little bit harder to predict the
number like you can be you're so
close to being a member and they
are at like 950 spent of like a
thousand so you think like maybe
it's one purchase but then they
buy just like a 20 item like a
small one and then they don't make
it and then they might get upset
so um that's kind of what i
recommend it's a good very good
idea to
have like a simple vip email flow
to anybody who like joins the
segment uh thanking them and give
them
some exclusive content and like a
generous offer is always what i
recommend um and it's smart to
send
a vip email at least once a
quarter uh with like an exclusive
dealer offer you can send like one
extra email per month just like
with exclusive content at least
once a quarter you can try to
give these people a special offer
so definition like a base
definition is what i like to do
they can
receive email marketing and they
place an order at least five times
over all time super simple
you can do a little bit more fancy
stuff you could say they place an
order at least five times and
they've spent at least 500 at your
store it's just a little bit
harder to predict and um so i
always
prefer to do like five um but that
is vip customers now we have win
back potential customers so this
for sending like one extra email
per month on top of your engaged
list sends kind of kind of similar
to
unengaged but unengaged is for
email engagement win back is for
past customers so this list is
exclusive
people who have bought a certain
period of time ago they haven't
purchased recently the amount of
time
is going to vary based on like the
store and the average buying
period in between purchases like
if you sell hot tubs probably have
a couple years in between
purchases typically if there is
another
purchase and so you might want to
have a win back campaign to try to
get people back like way later
whereas like for a supplement
brand where you sell in like 30
day servings after like 30 days
you
want to have a win back campaign
so for this group you want to have
a few flow emails to fire when
they enter the segment to
encourage these people to come
back and make another purchase and
maybe a
good idea to later in the flow
give them a discount if they
haven't purchased yet something
like
a supplement where every 30 days
it's like a 30-day trial then you
might want to start your win back
campaign like on day 45 like it's
been hey you've used up all your
supplement like do you want to
come back how did you like it and
then send them a couple reminders
just to like try to get them back
and then maybe send them a
discount so the base definition is
definitely going to depend on your
store
and like what your numbers and
average buying periods are but for
this one it could be your win back
period could be a period of like
60 days so after three months so
if someone has a cheap has can
receive email marketing they place
an order at least once in the past
150 days they've placed order zero
times in the last 90 days so that
means their last order was between
90 and 150 days ago so we have
this 60 day period here where
they're win back eligible and
whereas like after it gets to 150
days it's
like okay they are not interested
they maybe went with a competitor
and they're more in the longer
term
win back flow but this one is like
a buying period where we met we
might want to send them a couple
extra emails and trigger them into
a flow so this went back potential
they can't receive it with
marketing and they've placed order
at least once in the last 150 days
you could change this and they've
placed order zero times in the
last 90 days so that's went back
potential now let's talk about the
suppressed list which is another
sad one but this is for not
sending any emails to so this is
an email
segment um that is used for people
who aren't engaging with any of
your emails and or their
high-risk profiles that don't
deserve to be sent emails because
they'll just ruin our email
reputation as i discussed earlier
so you should be looking at this
list once a month and suppressing
these profiles to save yourself on
deliverability and then also
costing your clavio bill which
charges
you based on like your email
profiles so base definition these
are the people that you want to
suppress someone has opened an
email zero times in the past 180
days personally i suppress all
these
people um just to save costs or
someone has bounced an email
anybody bounces an email i don't
want to email you
um or somebody has like marked an
email as spam at least once over
all time um so this is the base
list uh that i use and
automatically we'll have this on
the suppressed list and then once
a month we'll
look at this suppressed list and
then just suppress right in clavio
you can just click on the settings
of the list or of the segment and
mark them as suppressed so that's
what i do um a little bit more
advanced
here we have an interested in x
product or a category this for
sending one to two extra emails
per month if you want
on top of uh engage with sense
this is a list of people who have
had any interest in a specific
product or category in the store
and this will depend store to
store on like the different
categories you
want to set but it's a great way
to track what the interests are in
your store and then if you have
any
specific sales announcements or
releases related to the items that
you set in your segment then you
can
send that to this group anybody
who has is interested so you can
do this by product or category
whatever you
have in shopify you can do both if
you want um just depends on how
you have organized thing and
things
in shopify so customize it uh in
the segment definition to choose
either product or category
which i'll show you here in a
second so this is the definition
that we go for um this is for a
category
example just change it to product
rather than collection um so all
you do is someone can receive
email marketing and they have
viewed an item at least once where
the category is whatever your
category is
at least once or they've added an
item to cart or someone has
started checkout where collection
is
this item or they have placed an
order where collection is this
item so here's the base definition
for a category not product for
product you just want to change
the category and collection to
product but
you say someone can receive email
marketing because this person is
subscribed someone has viewed an
item
where the category is this at
least once or they've added to
cart where the category is that
over all time or
they've started to check out where
that's their collection or someone
has placed an order or that's
their collection so these are
going to be a little bit different
in shopify a little bit advanced
but i think you can figure it out
because uh these clavio and added
to cart metrics these are within
clavio and via clavios like um
clavios i can't think of the word
but how clavio connects to shopify
whereas these are native stop
shopify triggers start a checkout
place to order so they use
collections
whereas clavio uses categories so
you'll be able to figure it out as
long as you have everything
organized in shopify just create
the segment you'll be good so
there's this make all the segments
you
want for all the products and
categories you want and then we
have like the x cross sell for
whatever
you want which you could send one
to two extra emails per month on
top of your engaged list sends
or you can just set up flows to
take care of this for you so this
list of people who have purchased
an item or category in the store
that you set um so if you have a
common cross sell um you can
create
the segment um to people who
purchase one item so that you know
this person has purchased this
item
now let's try to cross sell them
to this item um so you can do this
again for both products or
specific
categories and you can customize
the filter to choose the product
or category you want so definition
for this category someone has can
receive email marketing and
someone has placed an order where
the item is the specific item so
say let's go back to the shoe
example say i have white shoes say
there's
one pair of white shoes in your
store and you want to you're
releasing you release like a white
pair
of socks and uh people often buy
them together um then if i buy the
white shoes then i can be added to
this segment to where you then can
be like okay this person bought
white shoes let's try to sell them
white socks then you can set like
a cross sell flow where okay
somebody entered this segment
let's try to
push them let's create an email
that sells them on socks and tell
them specifically you bought these
awesome white shoes match them
with white socks and so that's
something you can do literally as
simple
as this someone can receive email
marketing and they've placed an
order at least once over all time
where the collection equals
whatever it is in this case it was
protein you could also if you want
to
say it was protein and we are uh
trying to cross sell them
pre-workout and you don't want to
send an
email to anybody who's bought
pre-workout before that's
something you could do as well you
just add another
condition say someone has placed
order at least once over all time
where collections contains protein
and then add an and so add another
condition right here and say and
someone has placed an order zero
times over all time where
collections equals pre-workout and
then send an email to anybody who
open who joins this list set up a
flow that says hey you bought
protein you want to make the most
out of
your workout um buy our
pre-workout and that'll work
really well so let's go over a
bonus segmentation
hack which i like to do uh
received x email but didn't open
so this is going to be less of a
dynamic segment and more of like
one that you do on a case-by-case
situation but we're set we're
creating a segment for people who
received an email but didn't open
it um so there's a very useful
segment trick that you can use to
resend important emails to people
who like didn't open your original
email so say you have like an
important email for like black
friday or whatever and but someone
could
be busy at the time you sent the
email and they just didn't have a
chance to look at it um if it's
an important email you can just
resend anybody who didn't open it
like one to two days later
um and this segment in resending
this using this little trick will
help you get the most out of
your email so we often use this
for product releases big sales or
big announcements um just wait a
day or
two we got 60 opens on the initial
email that means 40 of people
didn't open okay let's take that
use the segment trick and resend
the email to them with like a
different subject line and a
different
preview text so it doesn't look
like we sent the same thing over
and over again if they did see the
first one but just didn't open so
step one all you have to do is
click onto your specific email so
i
just clicked on i'm in campaigns i
click on the campaign this is like
where the name of it would be
you can see 42 opened um all we
want to do is we want to grab this
little code right here so this is
the campaign message id uh this is
what how klaviyo tracks the
campaign so we just want to copy
this
that's all step one is click onto
it and uh for the email that you
want to resend and then copy the
long code in the url step two we
are actually creating the segment
of people who received that
email but didn't open it so all
you want to do is create a segment
with the following conditions
someone has received email at
least once over all time where
message that's the little uh the
metric
thing inside of klaviyo that you
want to do where message equals
and then paste your code um so
that
means someone received it and then
you want to say someone has opened
email zero times over all time
where message equals paste that
code so this is what it looks like
in klaviyo it received x email
but didn't open someone has done
received at least once over all
time where message equals that
code and
then it's going to show up the
name of the campaign and they've
opened email zero times
where message equals that code um
that's all there is so now you
have the list of anybody who
didn't
open um then step three just
duplicate the campaign and send to
that segment you can duplicate it
you
can you could keep the same
subject line in preview text or
you could slightly change it i
always
recommend slightly changing it