So let's talk about why segment.
So the purpose of it.
Segmentation allows you to
pinpoint certain members of your
list so you can gather data.
That's one of the main things that
I use segmentation for, gather
data.
And then also create targeted
emails to send based on where
they're at in the customer
journey.
So some benefits.
The main benefits is you can make
more sales from it if you do it
the right way.
You can improve your
deliverability as long as you're
focusing on content in targeting
the right people.
You can save time with automation.
So putting people into segments
and having automations to send
emails to these people based on
characteristics.
And then a personalized customer
experience.
That's the other thing that you
don't really see too much like on
revenue.
But having customized experience
really helps like the customer
makes them feel like valued.
So basic use case, use cases kind
of extending upon which we had
before.
So these are kind of like the four
main use cases that you can use.
So using engaged list for improved
deliverability.
So you can segment your general
list for campaigns to only include
people who have recently opened
or clicked emails so that you
ensure you're only sending people
who want to open your emails.
This is the biggest use of
segmentation.
And you should never be sending an
email campaign to your whole email
list.
Except maybe like Black Friday or
a massive announcement.
Because the truth is a lot of
people won't care about your
brand.
And a lot of people use fake email
addresses.
And so they're never going to open
an email of yours.
So by you continuing to send
emails to these people who will
never open your emails, they
don't care about your brand, they
changed email addresses, they used
a fake email address.
If you send to them, you're just
ruining your deliverability.
Because if an inbox provider sees
you're sending emails to a lot of
people and not a lot of people
are opening them, that's going to
tell Google, be like, hey, not a
lot of people want to receive
these emails.
Not a lot of people opened it.
Let's send them to spam.
And so if you can just only send
to people who have opened your
emails before, it's a
huge difference on your
deliverability in the long run and
make sure that you will continue
to land in the inbox.
And then the next one, two
interested customers for more
sales.
So you can target people who have
been like active on your site or
have like added items
to their cart, but haven't made a
purchase and send them extra
content to try to get them
across the line.
That's something extra that you
can do.
A lot of this stuff can be taken
care of with your flows and your
automations, setting
up just like your abandoned cart
flow, for example, to send emails,
people who abandoned
a cart, but you can also send
campaigns on top of this, like
maybe a couple of times a
month, you send a special discount
to people who have abandoned an
item recently, but they
haven't purchased.
So that's something else that you
can do.
You can also do a targeted
campaigns based on product
interests.
So people who show interest in
certain products or categories,
you can send them information.
Like maybe you have a new colorway
that came out for like your shoes,
your, your clothing
story of all sorts of different
stuff, but you only want to send
this like my
growth campaign to people who have
bought shoes before or have looked
at your shoes before.
You can do that and send like more
targeted campaigns to them without
bothering the rest
of your list.
That's another use case.
And another one, remove unengaged
profiles for improved
deliverability.
So kind of tied to number one, but
kind of the opposite, removing the
unengaged profile.
So it's important to always track
and suppress people who haven't
been engaging with your emails
since customers will just
naturally churn.
You can't expect someone to be
with you until they're 80 years
old.
They're going to naturally,
there's going to be a point where
they stop opening your emails.
So since they aren't opening your
emails, you want to remove them
from your list so that
you aren't harming your
deliverability, A, to not send to
them.
And then also to save your Klaviyo
bill so that you can know to
suppress these people so
that you're not getting charged by
your active profile.