What is going on guys?
Welcome back to part two of the
cold email training in this video
I want to go over the cold email
KPIs that you can expect from a
successful cold email campaign
Meaning if you're hitting all of
these metrics on the screen in
front of me, you are golden
You can scale that campaign as far
as you want and you are highly
profitable on your campaigns.
So
Starting at the top of the funnel
open rate.
I do not put a big emphasis on
open rate because
Tracking open rates puts you at
risk of being flagged by Microsoft
or Google as
Spam and you'll go to spam and not
deliver your emails anymore
because
This is from a technical
perspective.
I'm a copywriter, but this is what
I hear from my partners
If you track open rates, it puts a
line of code in your emails that
Microsoft or outlook
Can detect and flag you on which
will put you in spam
Is this 100% true?
I don't know but everything else
on this chart if all these other
metrics are on point
That means that your open rate is
also on point.
Therefore.
It is an insignificant metric to
track
Right, it's like if you're booking
two to four calls per a thousand
prospects
Who cares what your open rate is?
You're you're seeing an roi you
can scale your campaigns.
Everything's good
So an open rate should be 50 to 60
percent or higher on a good cold
email campaign
But once again, I do not track
opens
Many of my peers do not track
opens.
I would not recommend it
So open rates not important, but
let's move on
Total reply rate your total reply
rate of all prospects reached out
to should be between two to four
percent of total prospects
contacted
Meaning if you're reaching out to
a thousand people
You are getting 20 to 40 total
replies.
Even if they say no, thanks
unsubscribe f you screw off
Doesn't matter because if your
total reply rate is between two to
four percent or higher
That means that your emails are
not going to spam.
They're being delivered
Um, and we just have to work on
the product market fit with the
copy in the audience, right?
Because even if i'm getting a
bunch of no thanks
That means people are opening the
emails and seeing them
We just have to test new copy to
get them to say yes instead of no,
right?
So total reply rate is a really
good indicator of deliverability
and your domain health
um, even more so than open rate
People love to obsess over open
rate.
I personally don't care at all
about my open rate as long as
these metrics are on point so
total positive
Positive reply rate not the total
reply rate the positive reply rate
Should be between 0.25 and 0.5
percent of all prospects contacted
Meaning if you're reaching out to
a thousand people a month
You're getting three to five
positive replies on the on the
average
If you sell a no-brainer offer
like I have a podcast and I want
you to come on it
This is going to shoot up to three
to five to ten percent of
prospects contacted are saying yes
And if you sell cyber security or
web design or branding this is
going to go down towards
0.1 to 0.2 percent where you're
only getting one to two positive
replies per 1000 people contacted
So this range is realistically
anywhere from point one to you
know
five percent
but for most services and
businesses
That you know are in the
marketplace.
It's between point two five and
zero point five percent
And then out of these replies
You're converting them to
meetings, right?
Because once a prospect responds
yes
That gives you permission to
enroll them in your crm call the
number in their signature pull up
their linkedin profile and connect
with them
Follow up with them 5 10 15 20
times like when somebody says yes
You should be on them like a hawk
every single day
Until they book a call with you
To the point where if you get five
interested replies in a month
You should be booking two to three
of them
On a call and then from those two
to four calls, you know, let's
hope two to three of them show up
And you're closing one deal per
1000 prospects contacted as the
golden kpi
of cold email
If you're closing one deal per
every 1000 people you're reaching
out to
You are roying at such a high clip
that you can scale your cold email
campaigns to the moon
And you will see that roi as the
campaign scale campaign scale very
linearly
Um, you know, there's no
exponential growth curve or uh,
you know, your campaigns fall off
a cliff
If you reach out to a thousand
people and close a deal
You can pretty much safely assume
that you can reach out to 10 000
people and close 10 deals with the
same copy
And the same audience that is the
beautiful part of cold email is it
scales very cleanly
Um and very predictably right
Because if you're closing a deal
per a thousand prospects
That means your deliverability is
on point your copies on point
Your audience is on point your
list of leads is on point
um, and your
Inbox management and appointment
setting is on point and you can
scale this is the all the
Biggest green light in the world
to scale your campaigns if you're
closing one deal
Per 1000 prospects contacted now
If you're meeting booked rate is
not up to speed.
This is an inbox management issue
This is a sales issue because
you're getting leads in the door
people are saying yes, yes, yes
But you're not converting them
into calls
And we'll go over this later in
the training how to convert
interested replies into booked
meetings with follow-ups and loom
videos
And linkedin connections and
calling phone numbers and
signatures
Um
If your positive reply rate is not
up to speed, this is a copy issue
You're just not pitching people
things that they want to buy
Um, and we'll talk about how to
fix this with lead magnets loom
videos free samples guarantees all
this fun stuff
ai personalization
If your total reply rate is not up
to speed
This is a deliverability issue
You're going to spam no one's
seeing your emails
Um, and you're just having a major
issue with deliverability
And this is fixable
By auditing your copy
You don't want any links any html
Any photographs in your copy or
your signature at all
Just plain text black text on
white background in gmail or
outlook.
That's it
Um
And you want to make sure that
you're sending volume per inbox is
not too high
I'll talk about the inbox rules in
the next video or my team and I
will talk about it with you
You don't want to send more than
20 emails per day per inbox
In cold email, right?
Some people will come to me saying
hey, I sent 200 emails from one
inbox
Why am I going to spam?
Because you're sending way too
much volume from
One single gmail inbox that google
is like absolutely not
Go to spam jail.
You're not coming out.
Don't pass go don't collect 200
bucks, right?
So
To recap if your total reply rate
is not up to speed deliverability
issue audit this with
Um
Making sure that your copy is only
plain text and your signature no
headshot photos in the signature
at all
Um and don't overdo it with the
volume like if you go past the
speed limit google is going to put
you in jail and give you a ticket,
right?
So you scale campaigns by
purchasing more domains setting up
more inboxes and warming them up
properly
Which we'll talk about in later
videos
Positive reply rate is a copy
issue and a leads issue
because if you sell an hr software
and you're reaching out to
um, you know cmos and project
managers, you're not going to
convert if you have shitty copy
It's not going to convert.
So this is a product market fit
issue
Meeting book trade is a sales
issue and of course golden kpi of
cold email is also a sales issue
With show rate and you know offers
made in closed deals.
So
Throughout these next couple
videos i'm going to go over every
single aspect of a cold email
campaign that
Addresses all of these metrics,
right?
Like if your reply rate is low fix
this if your positive reply rate
is low, here's how to fix your
copy
Here's how to fix your inbox
management.
So we'll make sure that every
single aspect of this funnel is on
point
Because if you close one deal
rough math here, um
A thousand prospects contacted
costs around 120 dollars a month
so if you're closing a deal for
120 per deal
that is
An unheard of acquisition cost
compared to ads compared to
content right the money that you
would invest into other marketing
channels
So if you can hit this metric
unless you're selling a service
that's literally 60 dollars
you are roying out
like
Like crazy from a cold email
campaign now
The cool part about cold email is
let's say this is one closed deal
per 4 000 people contacted
Which on paper you would be like
Dude, this is a horrible
conversion rate.
Why would I ever scale this?
Well
If you multiply 120 by 4 480
dollars a 480 dollar acquisition
cost is still pretty damn good
Better than paid ads unless you're
crazy.
You have a crazy good ads funnel
So the beauty of cold email is you
have a lot of leeway here even if
campaigns don't convert at the
highest level
You can still see an incredible
return on your investment with
cold email
So i'm excited to dive into the
rest of this training with you
guys
and kind of go over
What goes into a cold email
campaign with domains inboxes
warming them up sending tools copy
list of leads inbox management
offer creation
Lead magnet creation cold emails
tricky in 2025.
It still works
I want to show you why it still
works and in these next couple
videos
You will see how to hit all of
these kpis throughout the funnel
and hit the golden kpi
Of one closed deal per a thousand
leads if you're at one closed deal
per 2 000 leads
You're probably still seeing an
roi 3 000 even 5 000 leads.
You're still seeing an roi
Like for 10 000 prospects a month
you're paying a thousand dollars
if you're closing a deal for a
thousand dollars
That is still pretty damn good,
but let's shoot for the stars here
Go for a closed deal per a
thousand prospects and I will see
you on the next video