All right, so what happens when
somebody responds saying yes,
please send me a video
What do you do from there this
entire guide is going to break it
down from you from top to bottom?
With examples of a video pitch
that you can use I have one two
three different examples in here
Along with you know a whole
backstory on my business.
How do you frame the the video
over email?
How do you send the email that
sends the video in it how to book
a call on the back end?
Basically?
What I'm doing here is I'm trying
to think of every what if
situation where you get a result
and you're like
What do I do now?
I want to have a video in this
module for every single possible
scenario where you could possibly
say what now, right?
So if someone says yes to a video
for yourself
Reference this doc if someone says
yes to a video from your client
send your client this document
have them read it and then make a
really
Well done video on their end,
right?
So here's how it works, right?
Somebody says yes to a video
Right, they say yes, I would love
to see a video.
Please share it
What do you do from there?
Well, I'm not gonna go through
these videos in detail, but
basically here.
Let's check this out
Alright, this is the first example
of a new video I would send to a
prospect that they agreed to get a
video for me
In this case, I'm pitching a web
design service to a coaching
program find ascension
I have a co-founder at this
coaching program.
That's my business partner video
on the screen
But I just want to show you a
great example of what a new video
would look like once a prospect
said yes
Send me the video, right?
There's a couple key things to
know here
I'm gonna do the example video and
I'm gonna go over why I said what
I said
So right there.
I'm starting the video off.
Hey, thanks for responding to my
email in this video
I'm gonna go over three things you
can do to accomplish X improve
your website improve your emails
improve your marketing
Whatever the case may be don't
waste time saying here's who I am.
Here's what I can do
Here's how I can help you
literally come in and say here are
three things that you can do right
now to accomplish X
And then go into detail going over
those three things which is the
bulk of this video and then wrap
up the video at the end
I'm wrapping up the video by
saying how does a call tomorrow or
thursday at 2 p.m.
Eastern work for you?
So there's no gray area or
confusion from the prospect and it
and they know exactly what the
next step is
To book a call with you to learn
more, right?
So that's how you make a really
well done video
And I have three examples of them
for you to go through using the
doc in the description down below
What happens once the video is
filmed?
How do you actually send it over
email to get somebody to open and
watch it?
Here's how
So this just doesn't want to load
hold on
All right, well, I'll just skip
ahead ready
This is all in the doc down below
if you want to go read it
Okay, so here we go, right?
Let's check out this script pulled
up in front of me
Here's the custom video I made for
you.
Just click the thumbnail below to
view it
Actually say click the thumbnail
because people won't know what to
do if you don't say that and then
I say
You'll notice at the one minute 30
second mark
I discuss how to use vibrant
colored backgrounds
To boost your conversions and at
four minutes
You'll see how ugc videos can
convert more customers from your
campaigns
Thumbnail of the video
Would you be open to a quick call
tomorrow or thursday at 2 p.m.
Eastern?
If those times don't work, you can
pick a slot on my calendar
Here and that is how you send the
video
Over email to get people to open
and click on it and watch it
And book a call with you
What happens if they ghost the
video that you send?
How do you follow up?
Here's 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 templates
that you can use
So this doc down below is a full
breakdown of how to make the video
How to send the video over email
how to follow up on the video how
to book a call
Everything you need to know about
what happens once the prospect
says yes, I would like a video
Is in this doc down below?
I'm not going to keep harping on
it because you can just go consume
this doc on your own time
But basically what i'm trying to
do is eliminate any scenario where
you don't know
How to proceed with a prospect or
a customer and i'm eliminating all
that self-doubt and just giving
you the playbook step by step
So i'll see you on the next video