What's going on?
I want to make this video to
explain how I personalize cold
emails at scale, no matter
what industry you're in, what
offer you have, who you're
targeting, or any of that.
So let's break it down.
There's four different scenarios,
pretty much, of what you can do
for personalization.
Scenario one, to act as a fan or
consumer of their brand.
Scenario two, stroke their ego,
which I'll explain more in a bit.
Scenario three, tap into a pain
point or desire that they have.
Scenario four, build some rapport
and trust with them with your
opener.
So let's dive into each one, a fan
or consumer of their brand.
This is primarily for e-commerce
brands or SaaS, right?
So in this scenario, you want to
be able to come across as if
you're a consumer of their
brand.
You're shopping on their website.
You came across their Instagram.
You saw a TikTok video of theirs.
Basically any e-commerce brand or
anyone you see online that you can
come across as a consumer.
So here's how I would do it for
different industries within
e-commerce and then a local
business
in your city.
So toddler brand, right?
Let's say you scrape a list.
I always recommend that if you're
targeting e-com, you get really,
really specific on your
targeting like toddler brands,
skincare brands, jewelry,
clothing, CBD, like choose a
really
specific niche because you can
come across as a consumer of their
brand.
And it's going to bring the
prospects guard down when you go
to write a cold email.
So here's what I mean by acting as
a fan or consumer, right?
So what are they going to see in
the preview of the email?
I was doing some shopping for my
sister's baby shower.
They're a toddler brand and they
make baby products.
They're going to open your email
and read what you have to say,
right?
And chances are, they're going to
be like, oh, congrats on your
sister's baby, yada, yada.
Granted, this is not true that
your sister is having a baby.
The whole purpose is to get their
attention and show them that
you're a consumer of their
brand rather than someone pitching
them.
And this works really well for
e-commerce.
So another example, skincare, how
do you come off as a consumer of
their brands?
Here's how.
So my cousin sent me one of the
company's Instagram posts the
other day.
It looks like you're on her
Christmas wish list.
Now, I'm writing this right around
Christmas time, 2022.
So obviously, Christmas is super
relevant.
If it's not around Christmas, you
can do something like her
birthday.
But either way, you want to show
the brand owner that you're doing
some shopping for your
cousin's birthday or her wedding
or her Christmas gift.
Whatever it might be, this line is
going to get their attention and
make it seem like you're
a fan of the brand.
And it's going to get them to open
it and respond.
And the cool thing about these
kind of lines is, okay, so say
you're a TikTok marketer.
You can say something like, based
on your Instagram, I think your
products would be a huge hit on
TikTok.
Boom.
Now you can say TikTok CTA, right?
It's a really smooth transition
from opener to middle line to
transition into TikTok.
Or based on your Instagram, I
imagine you're getting a lot of
opt-ins to your email list.
Klaviyo CTA, right?
Like no matter what offer you
have, you can transition your
opener into your pitch really
seamlessly.
As opposed to like, saw you went
to Harvard, you know, really
impressive.
And then being like curious, are
you looking for more email
revenue?
Like it just doesn't flow the way
that the openers I'm showing you
flow.
So yeah, really pick a specific
niche and get really, really
targeted with that opener.
And then local business in your
city.
Say you're targeting restaurants.
You could do something like, I'm
looking for a new restaurant for
my wife and I's anniversary dinner
and came across companies' website
from Google.
Looks like you have some delicious
dishes, right?
Any restaurant owner reading this
is going to be like, oh, they're
giving me a compliment.
Let me hear what they have to say.
And it kind of shows that you did
your research and it's more of a
personalized approach than,
you know, a blasted cold email out
to a thousand people.
Once again, it is an email blasted
out to thousands of people.
But the whole point of this opener
is to make it seem like it's super
personalized and well-researched.
So that's scenario one.
I'm going to pause real quick and
go through scenario two.
And then I'll be back on video to
talk it over.
So be right back.
All right.
So scenario two, this is where if
you're targeting like recently
funded startups, law firms, local
businesses, et cetera.
So a lot of these target audiences
for this scenario could also apply
up here to like a fan of their
brand.
But the main one is for recently
funded startups.
So, you know, if you're scraping
the list of recently funded
startups, you could open your
email with congrats on company's
recent funding round.
It's super inspiring to see your
recent growth.
And then, you know, you're just
stroking their ego, making them
feel good, be happy emotionally so
that they're more open to reading
what you're going to pitch them as
opposed to, you know, if they're
having a bad day and they just
read your email, they're going to
not give you, they're going to
tell you to screw off.
But if you give them this nice
compliment in the opener, it's
going to get them to see, oh,
they're congratulating me and my
funding.
And then you can maybe translate
it to something like, you know, as
you look to deploy your marketing
budget, I'm sure you're looking
for profitable ways to acquire new
customers.
We can help you XYZ, right?
Like it's a really smooth pitch
from the opener into your actual
pitch and what you're trying to
sell them.
Another example, top businesses in
the area.
Say you're going after like law
firms who get pitched nonstop in
the inbox.
We're getting pitched nonstop in
the inbox, right?
You could give them a nice
compliment so that they're less
abrasive to reading your email.
Like was doing a search for the
top law firms in Tampa, Florida
and came across company's website.
You have some amazing reviews.
I'll keep you in mind if I, I
don't actually know if you want to
go down this route, but I don't
know if I ever need, I don't want
to say ever need a divorce
attorney, but you get what I'm
saying.
If you just keep it at this, but
basically they know that you're
searching for a law firm in Tampa.
They're saying, oh, you're, this
person's recognizing me as a top
law firm in Tampa.
Let me hear what they have to say.
They did the research.
They like my website, yada, yada,
right?
You're just making a good first
impression on them as opposed to
just going into a pitch.
And then a senior level position.
So you're going after like a CEO
or a CMO at like a fortune 500.
You could say something like
really impressed by what you've
accomplished as the CEO of
company.
You know, not many major
corporations have your kind of
track record.
Basically, if you're, you know,
recently funded startups, senior
level, top businesses, any way
that you can approach a prospect
and stroke the ego for a bit and
warm them up to your pitch is
going to help you.
I'm sure these are just three
specific examples.
You could probably come up with a
way to, you know, play to
someone's ego in just about any
scenario.
But these are some examples that
I've seen with my clients and
people here in Client Ascension.
So, okay, scenario three, tap into
a pain point or desire.
This is good for just about any
industry.
It's best when you have a specific
offer.
A no-brainer offer, actually.
So I like to use this kind of
opener when it's a no-brainer
offer, like a sales agency or a
lead gen agency or a guarantee.
If you have a guarantee in your
offer, this is going to be a great
one.
Here's what I mean.
So as, you know, as the founder of
a fast-growing agency, I'm sure, I
mean, this is like a pain point
and a desire.
Let me try to find a better one.
I'm sure you know how hard it is
to find motivated, experienced
sales reps.
You know, we can place a
commission-only sales rep on your
team.
Meaning they only get paid a cut
of the deals they close for you.
Can't type, but you get what I'm
saying here.
Where, you know, we're saying we
can place a commission-only rep.
Is this something you'd be
interested in discussing any
further, right?
So the pain point, they can't find
experienced reps.
We know that if you have a really
deep knowledge in an industry like
agency life, SaaS companies,
startups, and you know a pain
point that is true for you and is
also true for anyone else that
you're reaching out to, just
mention that.
Like, I'm sure you know how hard
it is to find motivated reps.
I'm sure you're frustrated with
how dried up the talent pool is
for sales reps right now.
And then go into your pitch of, we
can place a rep on your team,
right?
The reason I say you want to have
a really specific offer for this
is because if you offer something
like, what's a random, like, I
don't know, I don't want to insult
any offers here.
But, like, say you do, I don't
know, end-to-end marketing for a
company, like branding, logo
design, everything.
You can't say, like, as the
founder of a fast-growing agency,
I'm sure you know how hard it is
to get a good logo or to have a
good brand strategy.
Because someone reading that,
they're not going to say that and
be like, oh, yeah, that's true.
Like, I hate, you know, I wake up
in the morning and I'm wondering
how I can have a better brand
strategy.
Like, no.
People wake up and they want to
know how to make more money, get
more calls, find better team
members.
There's, like, really tangible
things that you can quantify in an
email.
So, what does this look like as a
desire?
As the founder of a fast-growing
SaaS product, I'm sure you're
always looking for more qualified
demos.
We can book eight to 12 demos on
your calendar each month on a
pay-per-call basis.
Meaning you only pay once they
show up to the demo.
Right?
So, you know that SaaS companies
are probably looking for demos.
Agencies are looking for qualified
calls.
Right?
No-brainer offer.
They know it.
They know that they need it at all
times and it's something that it's
going to get the reply.
So, you know, CTA.
So, that's tapping into a pain
point or desire.
Only use that if you have a pretty
tangible, quantifiable,
straightforward offer or a
no-brainer offer.
And you know your industry really
well.
Because the last thing you want to
do is say, like, I'm sure you're
always looking for X.
And they're like, I've actually
never looked for X in my life.
Because then you're just going to
look unqualified.
So, that's that scenario.
And scenario four, building
rapport.
This is best if you're reaching
out to the same industry that you
operate in.
Here's what I mean by this.
If you're reaching out to agencies
and you're an agency owner, you
could say something like, you
know,
as a fellow agency owner, super
impressed by your growth with
company.
I've actually run a B2B legion
agency for, you know, the past X
years.
I've scaled my agency to 100K MRR
in that time.
And I have a blueprint to help you
do the same.
Interested in hearing some growth
ideas I had in mind.
So, in this case, if you're
reaching out to an industry that's
the exact same industry that
you're in.
And you have a proven track
record.
You've had success.
You can help them with the same
things that you've accomplished.
You can make a whole angle that's
basically like a resume.
Like, hey, look, I've run this
agency for this many years.
I've accomplished this.
And I can help you do the same.
Right?
Like, you can't reach out to an
e-commerce brand as a Klaviyo
owner and be like, I've actually
run a Klaviyo agency for two
years.
I've scaled through.
Maybe you even could say, like,
I've scaled four other skincare
brands to 100K and I can scale
yours too.
Right?
Like, just basically if you're in,
if you've accomplished something
that the person you're reaching
out to also wants to accomplish
and they're in your industry, you
can reach out to them with a line
like this.
And it's going to get a lot of
great results.
Right?
Same job role.
This is one.
This is going to be a lot easier
to explain.
Right?
So, you know, noticed you're the
CMO of company.
I actually have a really great
opener for this.
I'm going to dig it up real quick
and I'll be right back on.
All right.
So, for this example, say you're
reaching out to the VPs of
e-commerce at a bunch of clothing
brands.
Right?
And this is the opener that I like
to use if there's the same job
title.
So, as the former VP of e-commerce
for a fast growing brand, I know
how important it is to
consistently acquire and retain
new customers.
I scaled XYZ company as their VP
of e-com in under X years and I
have Blueprint to help you do the
same.
So, might you be interested in
hearing a few growth ideas I had
in mind for company?
Right?
Right.
So, these two kind of tie
together.
Like, they don't have to be the
same job role.
It doesn't necessarily have to be
the same industry.
All you want to say is, you know,
you're an agency owner, I'm an
agency owner.
As a fellow, I might have even
done these backwards to be honest.
Like, this could probably go up
here to the industry and this
could probably go to the job role.
But either way, all you're doing
is stating how you're in the exact
same shoes that they're in,
whether it's job title or
industry.
You know, as a former VP of
e-commerce for a brand similar to
yours, this is what I accomplished
and I can help you accomplish
something similar, right?
So, where these angles work the
best is in an offer where it's
like holistic growth partner,
outsourced CMO, you know,
end-to-end marketing.
Like, anything that's hard to
quantify in an email where you
can't say, like, you know, ads,
paid ads, UGC, emails, where it's
like a bunch of stuff piled into
one offer, like, kind of like a
consulting offer.
This is where you should go with
an opener, like, as a fellow
agency owner, as a former VP of
e-commerce, you know, I've ran a
B2B lead gen agency.
I was a VP of e-com for this
brand, right?
Like, using your past experience
as a cold email angle and getting
replies that way.
So, long story short, there's four
different scenarios, acting as a
fan of their brands, typically for
e-commerce brands, stroking their
ego if they're recently funded, if
they're a business in the area, if
they're a high-level position at a
big company, tapping into a pain
point or desire.
If you have a really tangible
offer and you know the industry
you're reaching out to very well,
you can use something like, as a
founder, you know, I'm sure you
know how hard it is to find,
motivated sales reps, or you're
looking for more qualified demos.
And then scenario four, building
rapport, if you're in a similar
industry or a similar job role as
the prospect you're reaching out
to, and your offer is vague,
growth partner, outsourced, CMO,
etc.
So, hopefully these are all
helpful.
I'll post a link to this doc as
well under the video so you can
check them out on your own time.
And yeah, take all of these angles
and all of these openers, rather,
and put them into your own words,
spin them up into the industry
you're going after, and I
guarantee you'll get a lot more
opens and a lot more good replies.
So, hopefully this helped.
Thanks.