All right time for the most
important part of any cold email
campaign the copywriting
What are you actually saying in
your email to get a random
stranger to raise their hand and
say yes?
I want to learn more
There is a very specific art and
science to this and I want to show
you how to do it step by step
so you can write a really good
cold email from scratch without
much
guidance or hand-holding
Obviously we have an AI tool
that's going to show you how to
write good cold emails where you
can just input the
Service that you're selling and
it'll spit out a really good cold
email script based on my training
and my guidance because I
Fed an AI bought all of my work
and all of my training and
everything
so you have an AI at your disposal
that can write really good cold
emails, but
You still want to understand
The fundamentals of a good cold
email scripts because you if you
don't then you'll have no clue if
the AI is actually producing good
content or not
So let's learn the basics of cold
email
So when you use the AI tool you
will actually know how to create a
good cold email scripts with it
and how to judge if the script
that it created is good
So let's dive in so the only two
things that matter in a cold email
scripts are the offer
What are you selling right and the
call to action?
What do you want the person to do
next?
Think of this like a commercial
you're watching George Lopez at 4
in the morning and some commercial
comes on for a vacuum and they're
saying
It could be yours today for four
payments of $19.99
Call this number now to claim your
free
Accessory with the vacuum the
$19.99 for installments is the
offer
It's what's being sold in the
video and the call to action call
this number to claim your prize or
your free bonuses is the call to
action
I want to I want to frame it in
terms of an infomercial so you
comprehend what I'm trying to say
here
In a cold email sense the offer is
we can book you 10 calls a month
We can help you collect 50k a
month in revenue
We can add 100k followers to your
instagram account, right?
What are you actually pitching to
somebody to get them interested in
raising their hand and saying yes
because
Saying that you can do cold email
for somebody is not a good offer
Saying that you can do email
marketing for somebody is not a
good offer saying you can manage
somebody's instagram for them
not a good offer
good offers are
The benefits and the outcomes that
come as a result of the service.
So let's say you're doing a
A cold email script pitching your
own cold email services.
You would say hey, we can help you
book 10 sales calls a month
From a cold email campaign, right?
That's a good offer, right?
Hey, we can help you collect 50k a
month in revenue with an email
marketing
System
That is a good offer because
you're saying what you can do for
them 50k and revenue collected
with an email marketing system,
right?
We can add a hundred thousand
followers to your instagram
account with our social
Growth system once again good
offer 100k new followers on
instagram anybody with a social
media account
And a pulse really will want to
add 100k followers to their
instagram because any business
owner should desire
100k new followers if you're
confused right now
Why are you writing all these
different hooks and open it?
Like why are you writing all these
different sentences?
I'm showing you what a good offer
looks like
so when you're dealing with a new
client who offers
Email marketing or social media
growth, you know how to dissect
their business and come up with
good offers on your own
Because this is what people are
going to pay you for is for the
strategy and the consulting around
coming up with a good message
To put in a cold email for that
business, right?
Let's say you're dealing with um
I don't know a custom t-shirt
company that wants to reach out to
more schools.
We can
um creates custom polos from ralph
loren
with um
tampa
central
schools
Logo on it right good offer that
is a good offer
Why is it a good offer?
We can create custom polos from
ralph loren with tampa central
schools logo on it saying exactly
what you can do for the business
What does a bad offer look like
like this?
We can run cold email campaigns
for your business
Okay, great.
What does that get me?
You can run a cold email campaign
for my business.
Is this like charity work?
No, you can get 10 calls a month
for their business.
You can get 50k
In sales for the business you
never want to just say
Oh, I can run cold email campaigns
for your business.
Who cares right?
Nobody cares
bad offer, right?
We can make custom clothing
For your school, right?
Why is this a bad offer compared
to this being a good offer?
Because custom polos from ralph
loren
Is a desirable thing
That most people are going to want
to learn more about ralph loren's
my favorite brand
You can put our logo on a ralph
loren shirt custom to our school.
That's so cool
It's enticing.
It's
think of it like if you're on
youtube and you see a youtube
thumbnail and a title and it grabs
your attention
Think about what in that title
grabs your attention
The world's best hamburger
Is a lot more enticing than I
tried a good hamburger today,
right?
Same principle applies when you're
writing cold email scripts
We can create custom polos from
ralph loren with your logo on it
versus
we can make custom clothing for
your school
When you're writing a cold email
scripts you want it to be so
enticing
That anybody would be a fool to
not want to learn more
100k followers to my instagram
account 50k a month in revenue
with my email marketing system
Here we go.
Good offer 100k followers to your
instagram bad offer
We can grow your instagram account
Vague not enticing it's not sexy
you want to be able to write a
cold email offer and have it be
sexy 100k followers custom polos
50k a month 10 sales calls
Much better than we can run cold
email campaigns.
We can make custom clothing.
We can grow your account.
No one cares about those things
So keep that in mind when you're
writing your cold emails and using
the ai
And then the only other piece of a
cold email campaign is the call to
action
What do you because if somebody
reads your cold email?
They need to know what the next
step is or else they're going to
get confused and log off and not
answer your email
Think about just think of like
human nature
If somebody gets an email from a
stranger in their inbox and it's
not clear
What the next step is they're not
going to answer you
Think about the average human at
the airport if if the tsa agent at
the airport doesn't say
Go into lane six.
How many people are going to be
like?
Where do I go?
Oh, and just sit there with their
mouth open the same thing is true
over email you have to guide
somebody
Hand hold them into opening their
email clicking respond and saying
hey, yes
I would love to learn more
So what are you pick what is your
tsa agent instruction to this
person to get them to answer?
Would you like to see a quick
video explaining further?
Hey, we can book you 10 sales
calls a month from a cold email
campaign.
Would you like to see a quick
video explaining further?
That is a good call to action
Mind if I send over a catalog of
our ralph
Loren products
So you can pick out a few samples?
Why is this a good call to action?
Because i'm creating the curiosity
factor
By asking if they want to see a
catalog of the products that we
offer so you can pick out samples
Right what else is a good call to
action?
Would you be open to seeing a
sample instagram post I made for
you?
Why is this a good call to action?
Because i'm offering free upfront
work in exchange for nothing,
right?
So when you guys are using the ai
bot and writing the cold email
scripts on your own
Think about what would entice
somebody to click on your email
and respond back to it
Yeah, I would like this.
I would take a video explaining
further
Yeah, I would take a catalog of
products.
There's no harm in that, right?
I would be open to seeing a sample
post that you made for me
What are some bad call to actions?
Open to learning more
It's vague, right?
There's no clear next step if I if
someone reads this and says, uh
Yeah, I could be open to learning
more, but I don't really know
what's going on here.
Click next, right?
You have literally three seconds
to get someone's attention to get
them to respond back to you
Or else you're just not going to
get them to say yes, right?
And i'll show you guys examples of
good cold emails in action.
So this is like
because I hate when
I hate like if you're watching
this if I was watching this from
your perspective, I hate theories
and
You know thought like I don't want
to just show you what my thought
processes are
I want to show you real examples
from our clients that work so you
can see this in action
Um with a business that's actively
generating cash
From what i'm teaching you in this
right?
So sit tight i'm going to go
through the theory of it and then
i'm going to show you
Real world applications of what
i'm telling you so sit tight pay
attention and then we'll relate it
to a real example
so
Are you open to learning more bad,
right?
Would you
Be open
To a quick
Call to learn more
Bad call to action because once
again
Um, first of all they're like
This is going to take time out of
my day to talk to this person
I don't really want to talk to
them yet
As compared to oh, yeah, i'll take
a catalog and then once they see
the catalog, they're like wow
This is great.
Let's hop on a phone call
So you're kind of reversing the
psychology of it where you're
giving people things a video a
catalog a free sample
Instead of asking for things like
would you be open to a quick call
to learn more?
What's another bad call to action?
Um
Are you interested?
Would you want to talk more about
this like?
Bottom line here is the entire
email needs to be sexy, right?
We can help you book 10 sales
calls a month from a cold email
campaign
Would you like to see a quick
video explaining further is a lot
sexier than we can run cold email
campaigns for your business?
Are you interested?
Right?
Let's go through full examples
here
Like let's just piece this
together, right?
Let's turn it into a real cold
email angle
We can book 10 sales calls a month
from a cold email campaign
Would you like to see a quick
video explaining further that is
the meat and potatoes of a cold
email angle that would actually
work?
If you're watching this and you're
like
All I have to do is write two
sentences and I can get strangers
to say yes to my email and want to
learn more
Yes, you can that is a real
No bs answer.
Yes, you can
Are there things you can do to
make this better?
Yes, but we're we're going very
basic right now
And then we can expand on this in
a second
Angle number two
We can help you collect 50k in a
month in revenue with an email
marketing system
Using klaviyo klaviyo is an email
marketing software that a lot of
e-commerce brands use right?
Call to action
Mind if I send or let's do
Mind if I send over an email
template I came up with
for you
Using the products on your
Website
Yes, I would love to see the
products that you've made for me
on the on your website, right?
Angle three
We can create custom polos from
ralph lauren with your central
school district's logo on the polo
Mind if I send over a catalog of
our products so you can take a
look and pick out a few samples
Good angle, right?
These are what good cold emails
look like and once I go into real
real examples, they really are
this short and to the point
Now
Let's call this meat and potatoes,
right?
Because this is like
These are like the fundamental
basics of a cold email campaign
that makes it successful
Let's go into the toppings
That can add flavor to your cold
email, right?
What are some toppings?
Instead of just saying hey, we can
book you 10 sales calls a month
from a cold email campaign.
We can also say
List kit was able to sign two new
high ticket clients
From the calls we booked for them
And we can replicate
This success
For you, right?
What is the topping here?
It's a case study
Of work that I did for somebody
else
If you're brand new to business
and you don't have any case
studies yet
You can't use case studies as a
topping until you have
Case studies to use
So what you can do instead
For yourself or for your clients
Is use a guarantee?
What is a guarantee?
For me, it looks like this
We can help you collect 50k a
month in revenue with an email
marketing system using klaviyo
If you don't
See at least a 50k boost
In sales
Within 60 days
You don't have to pay us
Why is this a guarantee?
Because you're guaranteeing the
end outcome
Of 50k a month in sales within 60
days
Or else you don't pay us
That's why it's a guarantee
because there's no risk to the
prospect
To say yes to this, right?
Of course, you or your client has
to actually be comfortable
With selling a guarantee
Like you can't just make up a
guarantee for your client and then
go
Hey, mr.
Client
I guaranteed this person this
amount of revenue
They're gonna get pissed at you
and probably fire you
So make sure that you have
You know some sort of process of
asking your clients if they're
comfortable with pitching a
guarantee
Otherwise, this isn't going to
work, right?
Let's say you're doing an angle
for your own business and you want
to have a guarantee in there
We can add 10 sales calls
Per month to your calendar
With an outbound cold email
campaign
If you don't
You only let's do um, we work
fully on performance.
So you only pay us
for
Per booked call that actually
Shows up to the meeting
Mind
If I send over a video explaining
Further
So literally the meat and potatoes
is the offer
What are you actually offering to
the person on on the other end of
the email?
And what action do you want them
to take?
Say yes to a video
Say yes to a template that you
made for them.
Say yes to a catalog, right?
Obviously, if you're a cold email
business, all of your
messaging is going to be around
cold email, but you're going to
work with clients that sell email
marketing custom polos
Any b2b service, we have a client
that sells amish gazebos to pool
builders, right?
So
The beauty of cold email is you
can work with any business
The downside is that you have to
get really good at writing cold
emails for a lot of different
business and service offerings
But i'm here to show you how to do
it.
So
Hopefully this makes sense meat
and potatoes offer call to action
toppings
Case study if your client has a
case study use it if you have a
case study after a few months of
being in business use it
If you don't have a case study
that you can use
Guarantee throw in a guarantee ask
your client if they're comfortable
with the guarantee
And then go from there
And now because I know a lot of
you are going to be asking this
Subject lines
What subject lines do I use to get
people to open my email and i'm
going to give you literally four
options
With the first being quick
question the most classic
cold email line of all time is
quick question it works for
It's worked for the last
Five six years and it's going to
continue to work for the next five
years
It just works really well at
getting people to open the email
and respond to it
It's as simple as that.
I don't know what it is about it
People just love to open a quick
question email
But I like to test a couple
different things in my outreach to
see what performs better
Because if you're just running one
strategy, then you're
Not being a smart marketer because
you have the ability to test
different things and you should be
testing different things
What else can I use as a subject
line?
I like to do
company name
So this is going to be a text
replacement for the actual
business that you're reaching out
to x
Your business name or your
client's name
So like list kit
Intro, right?
So what does this look like from
the the person on the other end's
perspective?
Let's say the person on the other
end runs a company called
um
sunny
Plumbing right sunny plumbing is
the name of their business.
It would look like this sunny
plumbing x
Your business name i'm list kit is
my business.
Let's say you're running.
Um, one two three leads
Intro
Why does this work because I had
an email in my inbox that said
um
Like list kit x one two three
leads intro and it got me to open
the email because it looked like a
warm introduction
To a new client a new referral
So I was like, oh, this is an
introduction and then I opened the
email and I realized it was a cold
email pitch and i'm like damn
They got my ass
Therefore i'm going to be using
this because of myself
If I fell for this as a cold email
expert other people are going to
fall for this same thing and click
on the email so
company name
x your business
Intro is a really good cold email
pitch
Or a really good cold email
subject line
What else is a good one?
Question for first name similar to
quick question
first name x christian
Intro once again just like the
company one you can do the same
thing for your
First name and their first name
Tom x christian intro anybody that
reads this subject line is going
to be like who's
Being introduced to me.
Is this a new client?
Is this a potential lead?
Let me click on it, right?
What else can we do?
Ralph loren polos for first name
I'm saying the benefit of my
service in the subject line ralph
loren polos for first name
100k followers on ig or 100k
followers for company name so like
When you're writing your cold
email
Scripts the subject lines should
be an afterthought you plug in
quick question
The gold standard of cold email
subject lines you plug in
Company name x your business name
intro and then you test out like
one or two of these other ones and
that covers subject lines
completely
So let's tie it all together,
right?
A master email
I'll just call it a master email
Subject line quick question
Hey tom
We can book you 10 sales calls a
month with an outbound cold email
campaign
And we work on performance
So you only pay us per booked
Sales call that shows up to the
meeting
Mind if I share a quick video
Explaining how this would work for
Sunny roofing right whatever the
business's name is that's just a
stupid example.
I came up with
It would actually look like this
because you want to use the text
replacement so that you can
Automatically pull in the name of
the business that you're reaching
out to
And that's it guys hey tom we can
book you 10 sales calls a month
with an outbound cold email
campaign
And we work on performance so you
only pay us I would actually cut
this
Into two lines it looks easier to
digest this is another good thing
to know
Look at how easily digestible this
is
Compared to this where it's like
two sentences in one you want to
segment this as much as you can
So it looks easier more bite-sized
to read because once again the
average person doesn't want to
read a big block of text
They want to read short bite-sized
pieces of information
And that's the entire email can
you throw in a question to open it
of course
Are you looking to sign more
roofing clients?
We can have an icebreaker we can
say hey tom noticed you're
the owner at
sunny roofing
So like you can use different
icebreakers if you want but the
only things that matter
Are the offer and the call to
action and sprinkle in a little
ketchup and mustard
With the guarantee or with the
case study, right?
meat and potatoes
A little bit of ketchup and
mustard and then a little bit of
an opener
There see what I mean does this
opener have to be like this?
No, you can say
Saw you're a leading roofer in
tampa
Saw you oversee marketing at sunny
roofing so like you can just
experiment with a ton of these
openers
But once you have the offer and
the call to action your cold email
is set
And you just got to mix in a
couple other variables to make it
as perfect as possible
In the next video.
I want to go over a live campaign
that i'm running for my business
Along with a few examples of my
clients
So you can get a better concept of
how this works because I want to
ease you
I want to ease you into this as
much as I possibly can so
hopefully this is helpful so far.
Let's see.
Let's get to the next video