What's going on?
Welcome to the cold email section
of AI clients.
My name is Christian
and I want to teach you everything
you need to know about cold email
so you can use cold email
to sign your own clients and then
get clients results using cold
email.
That's the beauty of
this service is you can use cold
email to grow your own business
and then use that same skill
to help get your clients results.
It's a very self-sufficient model.
And for that reason,
if you're watching this, you're in
luck because you chose the best
skill to learn by far.
Yes, I'm very biased about this
because I run a cold email
business and I've done so
for the past four years.
Um, but the beauty of cold email
in all truthfulness is that it's
the most in demand service out of
any marketing service in the game.
You know, if it's a recession,
a bull market, a bear market, a
depression, it literally doesn't
matter because every single
B2B business owner in the world
needs leads and therefore they
need cold email services because
I'm going to explain cold email to
you.
Um, as if you're hearing it for
the first time,
which if you're watching this, you
might be, but basically cold email
helps businesses get
in touch with other business
owners, um, who need what they
sell.
So let's dive in.
First
of all, quick background on me.
My name is Christian.
I'm a co-founder at a business
called client
Ascension, which is the parent
company of AI clients.
Um, and I'm also a co-founder at
list kit, which is a B2B database
software.
And my only responsibility over
the past five
years has been helping, you know,
clients and students and
consulting clients and my own
businesses do cold email
effectively at scale.
Um, so I've literally done cold
email for four
years in a row.
It's basically, you know, like
riding a bike at this point, I can
look at,
I can look at a cold email
strategy and dissect it and break
it down and fix it and make it
better.
So not to toot my own horn, but
there are very few people in this
world that are more
qualified to teach you cold email
than myself.
Um, am I a nerd about this stuff?
Do I geek out on it a
little bit transparently, but
you're going to learn everything
that I know, you know, across four
years of trial and error and
working with clients and growing
my own business condensed into a
30 minute
or probably an hour long module of
videos.
So what is cold email, right?
The whole point of this intro
video is to introduce you to the
model of cold email in and of
itself and why it's so important
and why every business needs it.
So the example I like to give a
lot of the time is Wolf of Wall
Street.
You're probably seeing the movie.
If you haven't go watch it, Jordan
Belfort, the main
character picks up the phone and
dials people all day to get them
interested in his stock services
and
sell, you know, he's selling
people, penny stocks through phone
calls and he picks up the phone.
Hey Margie, this is Jordan Belfort
here.
Are you looking to invest in the
stock market?
I have a
winning penny stock that is going
to boom in the next couple months.
Um, that is a cold call, right?
He's picking up the phone and
calling people to get them
interested in what he's selling.
Cold email is
very similar to cold calling,
except of course it's over email,
not over the phone, right?
You're
actually emailing people, getting
them interested in what you and
your clients are selling.
Who does cold email work for?
It works for any B2B business in
the world.
Any business that helps
other businesses can benefit from
cold email.
You can't email Nancy down the
road and sell her a
penny stock strategy like Jordan
Belfort used to do, but you can
email Tom at his business email to
get
him interested in your clients,
um, remote controls, right?
So we literally have clients that
sell
physical products like French
fries, gazebos, t-shirts,
trophies.
Um, and then we also have
clients that sell email marketing,
copywriting, video production,
consulting.
So you can help
literally any B2B business owner
in the world with this service,
which is good news for you
because there will never be a
shortage of clients that you can
work with.
And there will never be a
shortage of opportunity in the
world for what you sell.
So with that being said, let's
dive into the
fundamentals of cold email and
what does it actually look like?
Are you sending emails one by one
for
your clients all day on the
keyboard and Gmail to get them,
you know, to get them new leads?
No,
you're using automations and AI
and softwares and tools that are
built specifically for cold email
so that you can send a thousand
emails a day for your client, 2000
emails a day for your client and
deliver them five new leads, 10
new leads, two new leads a day.
Um, and the name of the game for
you is to get people interested in
what your clients are selling.
So here's an example.
Let's
say you sign a client and they're
a marketing company or a marketing
company, a marker company,
and they want to get their markers
into more businesses.
Hey Christian.
Um, I have a marketing.
I said marketing again, I have a
marker company and I want more
school districts to use my
markers.
Can you help me?
You would go, Hey, Mr.
Prospect, I can help you reach out
to 10,000 schools every
single month to get them
interested in your markers.
He would go amazing.
How much is this
going to cost me?
You would go nothing up front.
You only pay me for every sales
call that I book
on your calendar.
So if I don't deliver you the
result that you want, which is new
sales conversations
and new leads, you don't pay me.
Does that sound fair?
He's going to go, yes, that sounds
great.
Let's
get started right away.
And that is the great part about
cold email is you can sell it on
performance
only and get people interested in
your service.
Even if you're watching this at
18, 19, 20 years old
with no past experience, no
results, no case studies to show
for it, you can still generate new
business
because people will put their
trust in you.
If they're not having to pay you
anything upfront to get
that campaign started.
Hopefully that makes sense.
Um, the marker is a very practical
example
because let's say you reach out to
a thousand schools a day.
Hey, Mr.
School, um, I'm a marker
company and I can provide new
markers for each of your students.
Would you like to see our catalog?
That's a very easy idea to
understand in your head, right?
Another example that's less easy
to
understand a little bit more of a
complex topic is let's say someone
sells email marketing services to
e-commerce brands.
You can run a campaign for your
email marketing client that
reaches out to 10,000
e-commerce brands a month to get
them interested in their email
marketing.
And you'll notice the other
courses or the other paths in this
course are services that could
benefit from your cold email
services,
which is the beauty of cold email.
Once again, is you can help every
other person in this AI clients
community.
That's not doing cold email.
Christian, if somebody is selling
email marketing,
why would they need my email
services?
They already know how to do email,
right?
Wrong because
cold email and email marketing are
very different things.
Email marketing is a service for
e-commerce
brands and coaches and software
companies, um, to help them, you
know, sell more stuff to their
existing
customers.
Kith, a great brand that I love
wearing wouldn't need an email
marketing company to send emails
to their
existing customers like me to sell
new products that come out.
So if Kith releases a new line of
t-shirts
and they want to sell more
t-shirts to their customers, they
would hire an email marketing team
to email those customers, which is
very, very different from a cold
email campaign where you're
reaching out
to brand new people to try to get
them interested in your client's
services, right?
Email marketing
is designed to reach out to an
existing list of customers.
Cold email is designed to reach
out to,
a list of new people that have
never heard of your client's
business before
and, you know, trying to get them
interested in what your client
sells.
So like I said,
you're going to use cold email to
sign your first couple of clients
and then you're going to use cold
email to get your client's
results.
And it's like a snowball effect
that just keeps trickling up.
Three years ago, 2022 was when I
first started my cold email agency
and we signed all of our clients
from cold email and then we got
them results using cold email.
So if you master the craft of cold
email,
which you won't even really have
to do because the AI workflows
that we have will help you do it.
You're a self-sufficient business
owner for the rest of your life.
You will never
find or have trouble finding new
clients and you will never have
trouble getting results for your
existing clients.
And that compound effect just goes
up and up and up into infinity.
That's the beauty of
cold email.
In these next couple videos, I'm
going to show you how to write a
good cold email because
you can't get results if you don't
know how to write good messaging.
I'm going to show you how to get a
list of leads because if you need
to build a list of 10,000 leads
for your clients, you're going to
need a
software that has email leads.
And then I'm going to show you how
to automate the entire setup
with a sending tool, with inboxes,
with domains, and basically build
the correct infrastructure
to actually send a thousand emails
a day.
Because guess what?
You're going to need to set up
some
pretty in-depth technology stuff
if you want to contact a thousand
new people a day consistently
from cold email.
So don't, you know, don't panic,
don't stress out.
I'm going to show you everything
from a very beginner standpoint as
if I was, you know, I'm going to
film this as if I'm watching
it for the first time in my life
four years ago and I'm going to
speak through that lens.
So it's like
very basic.
And you know, if I was just
starting out, I would comprehend
it because I want you to
understand this skill on a basic
level and you know, learn it and
get good enough at it so you can
go out and
build your business to a hundred K
a month is where we reached with
our email agency.
So sit tight, lock in.
These next couple of videos are
going to teach you everything you
need to know about cold email.
And let's start out with
copywriting and how to write a
good cold email, because that's my
favorite
topic to teach.
And it's the most important topic
to understand if you want to
become good at this skill.
Let's go.