All right, this video is gonna be
very intro and elementary but I
feel like it's necessary because a
lot of the terms that I'm
Going to use over the course of
this program and a lot of the
terms that you're gonna hear
When you watch these videos are
gonna be brand new to you
And these are terms that I've been
using for four plus years.
They feel like second nature to me
so there will be times where I say
something like
LTV or CAC or margins
That seems like you know an easy
thing to understand
But you probably have no clue what
i'm saying because this is a brand
new
Concept to you
So I want to go through a bunch of
key terms that you need to know
And understand so that when you're
watching the content and you're
conducting business as a business
owner
You know what they mean and why
they're important.
So
First of all an offer.
What is an offer?
Daniel went over this and all the
videos you watched before
An offer is just the way that
you're packaging up your services
and selling them and selling them
to your clients, right?
We can book you 10 calls a month
on a performance basis offer
We can generate you 10k in new
business with a cold email
campaign offer
We can help you sign five clients
a month with an outreach campaign.
That's an offer, right?
What you're selling cold email is
not an offer.
Daniel explained this very well
I'm sure you comprehend this by
now.
Let's move on
Pay per call
This is a pricing model that's
commonly used to sell cold email
services
It's the the model that i'm going
to be referencing in the next
video
Basically, it's a structure where
you only get paid for every call
that you book for your clients and
it's very
Incentive aligned because they're
only you know your clients only
paying you for every call that you
book for them
And this is a model called the pay
per call
Model pretty straightforward,
right?
Close rate.
What is a close rate?
This is the percentage of sales
calls that a business converts
into paying clients
If you get on five sales calls and
you close one of them your close
rate is 20%
You got one person out of five to
pay you money and become a client
you closed one deal out of five
calls your close rate
is
total closes or signed clients
divided by the number of calls you
took the higher the close rate the
better you are at sales
The more you can scale right?
MRR monthly recurring revenue and
arr is annual recurring revenue.
This is just how much money you're
making every single month
Let's say 10 clients are paying
you two grand a month.
Your mrr is twenty thousand
dollars a month pretty simple
Lifetime value how much a client
is worth to a business?
LTV for short lifetime value LTV
This is how much money a client is
worth to you
so let's say
This is going to take you a long
time to realize on your own and
figure out what your lifetime
value is
But what you're going to want to
ask on sales calls is what is your
lifetime value of a client?
which is
um
Basically, how many months a
client pays somebody for times how
much they're paying them so let's
say on average
I
Keep my clients for six months and
they pay me a thousand dollars a
month
On average my client lifetime
value is six thousand dollars if I
sign a client
I know based on law of averages
that they're going to pay me six
thousand dollars before they
eventually leave
And go off on their own or stop
paying me right and this is a
metric that you realize once you
have
A business for a long enough
stretch of time
hey, I know that pretty much for
certain
I'm going to keep a client for 12
months and they're going to pay me
a thousand dollars a month
My lifetime value is twelve
thousand dollars pretty simple
Um, and this is what you're going
to want to be asking people on the
phone
To figure out how much you should
charge which is something i'll
explain in the next video
But hey
My lifetime value of a client is
10 grand I keep people for 10
months.
Usually I charge a thousand
dollars lifetime value 10 grand on
the other hand
CAC customer acquisition cost cac
Is how much it costs for you to
acquire a customer?
Right, let's say you spend
1200 on a cold email campaign and
you sign a client your cac your
customer acquisition cost is 1200
because you paid
Your invest you invested rather
1200 bucks into a cold email
campaign to sign a client
Let's say somebody refers you a
client and you close them and you
sign them as a
Client your cac is zero dollars
because you didn't invest in any
marketing to sign that client and
the big
golden ratio of business is
However much you're spending to
acquire a customer needs to be
less hopefully a lot less than the
lifetime value of a client
If you invest a thousand dollars
into a cold email campaign
And your clients are worth 10
grand to you your cac
To lifetime value ratio is 10 1 to
10 i'm spending one thousand
dollars to acquire ten thousand
dollars worth of business
If your cac is higher than your
lifetime value
You're obviously going to go out
of business because you're paying
more to acquire a customer than
what they're worth to you
This is going to be very important
for your sales process
Because you're going to be
charging a pay-per-meeting model
So ideally if somebody can close
20% of the sales calls that you
book for them and you're charging
200 dollars a call
They're closing every thousand
dollars they spend 200 times five
calls
A thousand dollars is their cac
their cac is a thousand dollars
So hopefully their lifetime value
is more than a thousand dollars
That is how you will be successful
with your agency because you're
charging two hundred dollars a
call
Your client is closing one in five
of those calls.
So they're paying ten a thousand
dollars to acquire a customer
That's their cac
And their lifetime value is
hopefully five ten grand and
they're happy to work with you and
pay you 200 bucks a call
I'll dive into that in the next
video.
Let's stay focused on the rest of
this list
Margins profit margins how much
profit a business is making each
month relative to total income
Let's say you made a hundred
thousand dollars.
You paid out 60 grand and
Salary and fees and all this stuff
your margin is forty percent you
took home forty thousand dollars
out of the hundred thousand
dollars that you're
Generating in revenue, right
revenue minus expense equals
margin profit margin
Okay, technical cold email stuff
Deliverability this is a term that
is used to measure
How many of your emails are going
to the main inbox?
One of the biggest things that
you're going to want to focus on
as a cold email agency owner
Is good client deliverability
because if your deliverability is
bad
Their emails are going to go to
spam
Your clients going to get no
responses and they're going to be
very upset with you because
they're not getting results
Good deliverability means that
Their email is landing in the main
inbox right here the main gmail
inbox and not in spam
Here's my spam folder.
No good.
Here's my regular inbox.
Very good.
We want to be in this folder
Not in spam.
So if you have good
deliverability, that means your
emails are landing in the main
inbox
If you have bad deliverability,
your emails are going to spam and
we will show you how to fix that
so
Scripts pretty simple.
What is actually being said in
your cold email?
I'll show you how to write really
good scripts, but
You're like what the hell is a
script?
It's just what you're saying in
the email to get people interested
Okay lead list
This is a list of email contacts
that you're using in your cold
email campaigns
Let's say you're reaching out to
ceos of tech companies.
You will be building a lead list
Of ceo emails at tech companies.
That is your list of leads.
It's in a csv excel file or a
google sheets file
That is your lead list
That is a list of email leads that
you're reaching out to to get them
interested in what you're selling
Different than a lead so when I
say lead
I either mean the actual email
address that you're reaching out
to that is an email lead
A lead could also mean someone
that's interested in your
services.
So there's a distinction there
Hey, I got a lead yesterday.
That's someone interested in what
you're selling.
Hey, I have a list of leads
That's an email list.
They're not interested in what
you're selling.
You still have to reach out to
them
So there's a little bit of a
caveat there just realize which
one i'm referring to
Did I get a positive response lead
or do I have a list of email leads
that i'm going to reach out to?
Kind of confusing but you'll
understand it
As we progress here
Okay
What is an upsell an upsell means
selling your client more services
and charging them more money?
Let's say you're reaching out to
10 000 people a month for them
And they're really happy with you
you want to upsell them on 10 000
more contacts a month
Hey, man, you're getting great
results.
Let's just double your volume and
uh, you know
Book twice as many meetings you
just upsold your client, which is
a good thing because you're making
more money
Similarly a cross sell is selling
your client new services and
charging them more money.
So instead of just selling them
more of the same
Hey, you already ordered a steak.
Do you want a steak for your
friend here?
You're selling them.
Hey, here's the steak.
Do you want fries with this or mac
and cheese with this?
So like cold email, maybe you get
really good at cold email and then
you introduce
LinkedIn outreach or content or
youtube you're cross selling them
new services
to generate more revenue
Cross sell upsell two different
things
Inbox management, what is inbox
management you're literally
managing your email inbox
And uh responding back to people
that are interested in what you're
selling.
Here's a look at the email inbox
that I have for my campaigns
I'm managing my inbox by coming in
here and answering rob's email
I actually have to book him in for
a call still.
I need to jump on this after I
finish this video
Um, but that's an up.
That's an inbox management.
You're just managing your email
inbox for yourself or your
clients, right?
A-b testing this is just testing
two different scripts against each
other to see which one does better
um
Literally like
If you look at a thumbnail on
youtube from mr beast, he's
probably a b testing different
thumbnails
To see which one is getting a
better click rate
The same thing is true with an
email campaign
You want to be a b testing
different messaging to see which
one performs better
Here's a really good example.
Um, all these angles are different
as you can see here.
I'm a b
c and d testing different
messaging to see what does the
best
Um, that's an a b test
What is an email angle different
ways of explaining what you sell
so in this here's how I would
refer to this
I'm a b testing different angles
to see which angle performs the
best
An angle is just what i'm saying
to get somebody interested instead
of saying leads i'm saying calls
Like one angle could be hey i'm
going to get you 10 leads a month
Another angle could be hey i'm
getting you five sales calls a
month another angle could be hey
i'm getting you one new client a
month
Another angle could be hey i'm
generating you 5k and new sales
every month
All of those angles are selling
the same thing of cold email.
I'm just offering it differently
A common thing that I will say is
hey, try new offer angles
Instead of selling buy one get one
free try
Bring a friend for five dollars
like different ways of selling
what you're already offering in
this case
Obviously cold email right offer
angles
Just different ways of saying what
you're reaching out to somebody to
sell them
Um, okay
Retention this is how long you
keep a client for
If you keep a client for six
months you retain them for six
months my customer retention on
average is about six months that's
retention
Churn is what happens when you
lose a client and you're no longer
retaining them
Yeah, I churned a client last
week.
It sucked not churn is not a good
feeling but
Churn is the the thing to describe
what happens when somebody
Churns from your business.
They no longer work with you.
They fired you.
They don't want to work with you
anymore
You churned that client not good,
right?
Domains, okay
Domains are the web urls you will
be setting up for your client and
yourself to run cold email
campaigns
For example, let's say I am steve
jobs and apple.com is my domain
You would never send cold emails
from the apple.com domain because
If you wind up going to spam with
the apple.com domain every single
apple employee can no longer send
emails without going to spam
And that's a huge problem.
So for yourself and your clients
You're going to set up fresh
domains specifically for cold
outreach
Use apple.com get apple.com try
apple.com
You're gonna have all these
different domains that all send
emails for you and your clients to
avoid going to spam
um
So yeah, whenever I say domains,
that's just like the website urls
that i'm purchasing from a tool
like
pork bun
um
Literally, it's called a domain
registrar, right?
So like
Use apple.com.
I doubt this domain is even
available
um
It's registered already use apple
products
Dot com this one's probably also
taken
um
Okay, it's actually available
eleven dollars a year, right?
That's a domain that I would set
up for my client
On top of the domain you're going
to set up inboxes
Right because you're running a
cold email campaign.
You need to have an inbox
Multiple hundreds of inboxes for
some of your clients.
So when I say hey set up new
domains
That's just going and setting up
Buying new website urls for your
client inside of a registrar so
that you can send emails from them
And then when I say inboxes, this
just means
Steve at use apple.com
Kevin at use apple.com
It's the actual email inbox that
you're setting up on top of the
domain the easiest way to think of
this is
You have a work email, right?
Like
Tom at tampalawyers.com
Your inbox is tom at
tampalawyers.com the domain is
tampalawyers.com
Right so domains and inboxes the
website and then the actual email
address that you set up on the
website
two more things
Email warm up
So warm up is what happens when
you first set up a new domain in a
new inbox
You're not just going to send
emails from that domain on the
first day.
That's the easiest way in the
world to go to spam
Instead you're going to want to
warm them up for two weeks so that
by the time you launch campaigns
Google and outlook, you know
Think that you're a human instead
of a robot that just sent cold
emails on the first day of setting
up that inbox
same thing
You wouldn't go out to your car in
the freezing cold and sitting it
freezing cold and drive off
You would let the car warm up
until it's good enough to sit in
The same thing is here true here
you want to warm up your inboxes
for two weeks
Um, and i'll show you how to do
that later
Warm up emails, right?
They all landed in the inbox
That's why you warm up your
domains and your inboxes because
you will not go to spam, right?
So
You will have bad deliverability
If you don't warm up your inboxes,
right?
That's just
Different ways that I refer to
This is the kind of terminology
that I use so I want to give you
this context now
Sending tool, what is the sending
tool?
This is the software that you're
going to be sending your emails
from it looks like this
You're not sending emails one by
one by hand
You're setting up a sending tool
That does the outreach for you
Because you're not going to sit
here and send 2300 emails by hand
that would drive you insane
You have a sending tool that does
it all automatically.
So these are all the terms that
i'm going to be using
There will be more terms that
you'll probably hear
But I wanted to give you a crash
course on the different terms that
i'm going to be using
During these videos and during the
course of your business career so
you understand them
Um, and let's dive into the meat
and potatoes of cold email.
Thank you for watching this
Hopefully this wasn't too boring,
but I think it was important.
So cheers