All right.
So last video, I went over theory
around cold email, like giving you
my philosophies
of how cold email works.
In this video, I want to show you
cold email applied to a real
campaign
for three different businesses
that have all generated
significantly effective results.
So
pulled up in front of me is a real
estate marketing campaign.
Basically, we have a client that
sells
marketing services to real estate
agents.
And this is brand new for you, I'm
aware.
So what we have
here is total number of emails
sent 45,000.
We've generated 433 total replies,
which is around
3% reply rate, which is really
strong.
Anything above one to 2% reply
rate is really good.
Out of those 433, we have 189
positive replies, which is
phenomenal.
It's an, it's an outstanding
result.
So we've reached out to 15,000
people.
Each person has received three
emails, which is
why the total email metric on the
last page was around 45,000.
And we have 189 unique positive
replies, which is incredible.
So if we come down here, we can
see all the different variants
that
I'm currently testing.
A, B, C, and D.
Like you see pulled up in front of
you, A, B, C, and D.
And it looks like email 1B has 37
unique positive replies, which is
a clear winner because the other
ones have seven, 22, 17.
So I want to show you guys what a
winning cold email angle looks
like
in the real world to real people
getting real results.
And here it is pulled up in front
of me.
Hey, Mark, we've helped hundreds
of real estate investors find
motivated sellers over the past
five years.
That is the offer, right?
Helping real estate investors find
motivated sellers.
Our leads come from people
actively looking to sell their
properties, giving you higher
conversion
rates than cold prospects.
This is like a topping.
It's not the meat and potatoes.
We compete on both
price and volume.
So you get more leads for less
money, another topping, and then
CTA, the call to
action, interested in seeing what
leads we have available in your
area.
So we have hundreds of real
estate.
We've helped hundreds of real
estate investors find motivated
sellers.
Are you open
to seeing what leads we have
available in your area?
That is the entire email subject
line, Mark X,
same thing I showed you guys in
the previous video.
The subject line that's working is
first name X
clients direct, my client's name,
seller leads.
That's the entire email.
It's working like a charm
compared to this angle, which only
has seven positive replies
compared to 37 because we always
test
different angles in our campaigns
to find a winner.
So this one is a clear winner.
Variant B, clear
winner.
Variant A is underperforming.
Are you struggling to find
motivated sellers?
We provide
high volume seller leads to real
estate investors at competitive
prices.
Our leads are people actively
looking to sell their properties.
We've been connecting investors
with sellers for five years and
worked
with hundreds of active investors.
Do you want to see our current
lead inventory?
Why is this one
underperforming?
Because the offer, we provide high
volume seller leads at competitive
prices.
Want to see our current inventory?
The call to action is not as good
as do you want to see what leads
we
have in your area?
We're making it specific and
relevant to each person and that's
why this is performing so
well.
And if we go back, email 2B.
So for context, all of the things
that I've been showing you so far
is about
the first email in the sequence.
What is the first email that we're
reaching out to somebody saying to
get them interested in what we're
selling?
But there are follow-ups.
So I know this is brand new.
I'm trying to make it as simple as
possible to you so you understand
it.
Email 1 is the initial email, but
only
1-2% of people ever reply to the
first email.
So do we just let them go forever
and never reach out to them again?
No, we follow up with them with
the second and a third email that
all have positive responses 21 66
So all the follow-up emails also
get great results
As well.
So let's take a look at what a
follow-up email looks like that is
producing results
Most lead companies charge premium
prices for low quality prospects,
but we compete on price and volume
Our seller leads are motivated
homeowners actively looking to
sell
Giving you better conversions and
cold outreach minded by sending
over our current pricing and lead
inventory
So once again pricing and lead
inventory is a clear winner in the
call to action
and the offer
Our seller leads are motivated
homeowners actively looking to
sell giving you better conversions
than cold outreach.
This is a winning angle
66 positive replies to this
follow-up email
So every single campaign that you
ever write
Should be a three-step email
sequence email one and two
follow-ups to get people
interested because as you can see
Each step one two and three is
producing positive results
The third email in the sequence
that's getting results is this one
We're helping several investors
secure motivated seller leads this
month at competitive prices
I've put together our current lead
inventory and pricing for your
market
Would it be helpful if I shared
that with you here?
Right put together our current
lead inventory and pricing for
your market
I'm leading with a free piece of
value a free piece of information
And this angle is getting a ton of
great responses as well.
So
Here's what it actually looks like
when you're building out a
campaign inside of the sending
tool.
This is advanced
We'll get to this later on but
here's what it looks like you put
all of your
A b c and d variants because like
I said, we always like to test
different angles for each
different
Client that we work with and you
should do the same.
So I have four variations of email
one
A b c and d all the messaging is
different as you can see
And all of the subject lines are
very different as you can also see
And the biggest thing that you
want to be testing is the subject
line because it's different in
everyone
The offer and the call to action
like I showed you guys in the last
video
Those are the biggest levers that
you want to pull and the biggest
things that you want to test
When you're writing those emails,
right?
If they don't answer right, let's
say you reach out to somebody with
the first email
Camera died on me, but we're back
Um, so like I said, if you reach
out to them with the first email
There's a pretty high percentage
chance that prospects aren't going
to answer this email like a 98
chance
So
You set a follow-up four days
later
That just reiterates what you
already said in the first email
Our seller leads come from people
looking to sell their properties
not cold prospects
You have to convince we've been in
business for five years.
Do you want to see seller leads?
We have available if they don't
answer that one three days later
after that we send another email
That says we're helping several
investors find motivated sellers
at competitive prices
I put together our lead inventory
and pricing for your market.
Would it be helpful if I share
that with you?
So think of a cold email campaign
as a three-step outreach sequence
where you have an initial email
that you have four variations of
Where 25 of the prospects will
receive this one 25 here 25 here
25 here
And if they don't answer this
first email, they get sent a
follow-up message
Four days later and then three
days later with another follow-up
to get people interested
That is what cold email looks like
in a nutshell and this is what it
looks like in the sending tool
And if you're wondering what are
these brackets christian?
What are these brackets with the
word variations all these brackets
do is switch up the wording of the
email
so that you don't go to spam
because if you send the exact same
email to 10 000 people google and
outlook and microsoft are going to
smack
Smack you on the wrist and say
this is bad
You're going to spam and then your
campaigns are going to completely
melt down because all of your
emails are landing in the spam
folder
Rather than the main inbox
So what we do is we use this
little thing called spin tax
Which is what I have pulled up in
front of me
Where it's just variations of the
same phrase.
So if you read this
Are you struggling to find
motivated sellers?
Are you having trouble finding
Are you looking for motivated
sellers?
They all say the same thing we
provide supply deliver high volume
leads
the only goal is that whenever the
The software sends out an email
it's going to pull one of these
combos at random to send your
email out
So no two emails look the same and
you stay in the in the main inbox
and you don't go to spam
We will show you how to make spin
tax for your emails using ai it
takes three seconds
But this is just a really good way
to stay out of the spam folder
Because if you go here the emails
look regular when they actually
get sent out, right?
Are you looking to find motivated
sellers in your market?
Right, but when we set it up on
the back end, we use this little
bit of
Technology, I guess you can call
it or just like text replacement
To have variations of the same
email going out so you don't go to
spam.
Hopefully that makes sense
If you have questions on it,
please reach out
I know it's a little bit complex
and new for you
But basically you're choosing
different variants of the same
sentence
So that no two emails look the
same and you go to the main inbox
when you reach out to people now
Number or email
Let's where am I here?
Okay, so
This campaign that I have pulled
up in front of me is the first
campaign is a client that we have
that sells real estate marketing
this is the
Dashboard for list kit my own
business
We do outreach for our own
business just like you will be
doing for your own business on top
of your client outreach
And we have a bunch of campaigns
going and the most successful
campaign of all time
Is this campaign that we're
running targeting web design
agencies because like I said
Even marketing agencies need cold
email marketing right like the
best marketing companies in the
world
Don't know how to market
themselves and get new clients.
That's where you come into play
and do it for them.
So
Just like I did with the real
estate marketing company
I do the same stuff with my own
business and pay close attention
because you want campaigns running
for yourself
Alongside your clients because you
want to be able to sign new
clients
At the same time as you get
results for your other clients.
Hopefully that makes sense
Right
And this the messaging is almost
the exact same
Saw you're in charge at visual
fizz
We can get you 12 new leads a
month interested in a new website
all from cold email
Mind if I share a quick video
going over a campaign strategy
that got my web design client 11
high quality leads in one month
Right
What's the hook here?
12 new leads a month and a new
website all from cold email.
What's the call to action?
A quick video going over a
campaign that got my client 11
leads in one month
What am I saying in the follow-up
almost the same exact thing?
We can deliver you 10 to 12 new
prospects a month all from cold
email hook
Ketchup and mustard the topping
our client in dallas got 11 new
leads in the dallas fort worth
area this month from a cold email
campaign
All from a new website build out
Do you want to see a video call to
action breaking down our strategy,
right?
So once you get the feel
For the how cold email works, it's
the same plug and play system
every time hook
toppings like meat toppings
Bun
For a lack of a better term hook
case study call to action
Email three
Similar
I recorded a video going over a
cold email strategy that can bring
you 10 to 12 new leads a month
hook
Call to action mind if I share the
video here.
That's the entire email
Done, right?
Same thing over here with a custom
merchandise client of ours that
has reached out to
215,000
People and got 446
Leads from a single campaign
Keep in mind this this company
sells multiple five-figure
packages
So one client to them is worth
five figures and they have 446
leads from our campaign
And very similar to the last two
examples
We can create branded apparel for
your company from brands like
peter millar patagonia and travis
matthew hook
You'll reduce your cost by 20% in
fact, we guarantee
You'll reduce your product costs
or else you don't pay us
Ketchup and mustard the toppings
the call to action mind if I share
a video going over our apparel
catalog
hook
guarantee
body
Just like this email
Hook case study
Call to action.
I meant to say call to action not
body hook guarantee call to action
Hook case study call to action.
It's the same system over and over
and over again
And once you get really good at
it, you can just do this at scale
for each of your clients
Hopefully i'm getting you in the
right mindset of how to write good
cold emails
In the next video, I want to show
you how to respond to people once
they so you're probably like
christian
This is cool and all but what
happens when somebody actually
says yes, i'm interested
How do I make a video?
How do I respond back to them?
How do I book them in for a sales
call?
I'm going to show you that on the
next video stay tuned