Okay, in this video, I'm going to
show you how to structure your
lead generation offer
in such a fashion that it becomes
a no-brainer for people to say yes
and become your first couple
clients.
This is the exact same offer
structure that I used four years
ago
to start my lead generation
business from scratch.
I had no past experience.
I had no case studies.
I had no one to vouch for me.
I had no confidence yet.
And if you're watching this,
you're in that exact same position
probably
that I was in four years ago.
So I'm going to show you how to
sell your services on a
pay-per-call basis
so people are only paying you once
you deliver them a sales call
because it makes it really easy
for someone to say yes, I'll give
it a shot.
I don't have to pay you any money
up front.
And it's going to help you build
confidence
because you'll get your first
couple clients in the door
and you'll start getting
experience in your first couple
case studies.
If you're watching this and you're
a complete beginner,
you're going to be nervous on your
first couple sales calls.
You're going to be shaking.
You're going to be stuttering a
little bit.
That's completely fine.
That's part of the process.
I still get nervous for some sales
calls, but you're a complete
beginner,
so it's completely fine that you
get nervous.
Here's how to sell your services
in a way that overcomes the
nerves,
overcomes the lack of experience,
and gets somebody to say,
you know what, I'll give it a
shot.
Let's try it out.
So before we dive in, I want to
talk about using your own
instincts, right,
because there are no rules in this
game like I said before, and I'll
say again.
You can sell your services in
whatever fashion you want.
I'm simply recommending what
worked for me and what helped me
sign my first couple of clients.
Throughout this entire program, I
want you to use your own critical
thinking skills,
your own gut instincts, and your
own business acumen because you're
a smart person.
You invested in yourself.
You're here watching this video
right now.
You're ahead of 99% of the
population.
Trust yourself and your gut
instincts and do what you think is
best, right?
Just because I'm telling you to do
something doesn't mean you have to
copy it word for word.
The most successful business
people that I know have the
ability to think on the fly
and think on their feet and have
their own compass that guides them
without just copying people word
for word.
So keep that in mind as I go
through this.
Here is what worked for me and
what will most likely work for you
as you just start out in this
business.
So let's dive in.
Okay, so pay per call is the offer
structure that you're going to
want to follow
where you only collect an invoice
from somebody per sales call that
you book for them.
300 bucks a call, 200 bucks a
call, right?
Doesn't matter how much you charge
for it.
That is the structure that you
want to follow.
Why?
Because it creates a win-win
scenario for you and your client,
right?
You're getting paid for the number
of sales calls that you generate
for them.
If you generate them 10 calls at
$200 a call, you're collecting a
$2,000 invoice, right?
Okay, hold on one second.
I need to refresh my background
because it's not scrolling.
One sec.
Okay, I'm back.
So you get paid for the calls that
you generate for them.
Your client gets qualified sales
calls added to their calendar with
no risk
because they're only paying you
for a completed sales call.
So you basically have a no stress
situation because if you don't
deliver results,
you're not going to get paid so
their client will be a lot more
patient with you
compared to if they paid you
upfront.
You are also not relying on your
client to be good at sales.
Think about it for a second.
If somebody is paying you a
percentage of closed deals,
you're only getting paid if they
close a client.
And if they're bad at sales,
you're not going to get paid
because they're not going to close
any clients.
So you basically charge at the
point where you pass the
responsibility over to them.
Your responsibility is all the way
up until a sales call is booked on
their calendar.
You charge your $200, $300 per
call.
And then you say, you know what?
I don't even care what happens to
this sales call.
It's completely up to my client.
They can go close them.
And if they're bad at sales, you
still get paid.
That's not being selfish.
That's just being a good business
owner and charging what you're
worth, right?
Like imagine you book somebody 20
sales calls and you're working
fully on commission.
How mad would you be if they
didn't close a single deal out of
20 calls?
You did all this good work.
You got them 20 calls booked.
You haven't been paid yet.
You're ready to cash in on a big
payday because they told you,
oh man, you'll get so much
commission once we close the deal.
And then they don't close a single
client.
You're going to be pissed.
So for that reason, you should
charge per booked sales call.
Let's say you have a client who
sells TikTok marketing services to
restaurants
and you get them 10 calls booked
with 10 restaurant owners.
You get paid once that sales call
is added to their calendar.
And the amount that you charge is
completely up to you.
When I started out in business
four years ago, we were charging
$250 per booked sales call.
And then as we got more confident
and got better at what we did and
got more results,
we bumped it up to $300 per call
and then up to $350 per booked
call.
The key thing to know, like I
said, is there are no rules.
Charge however much you want and
use your own business acumen and
gut instinct
to charge a price on the phone,
right?
If you're feeling confident and
ballsy and you say 500 bucks a
call,
somebody probably will say yes to
you and sign that contract, right?
So don't be afraid to overcharge
and say 500 because if they come
back to you and say,
oh, I can do 300 a call, you still
get a client, right?
So don't be afraid to be a little,
you know, confident and shoot your
shot basically, right?
Hey, 500 bucks a call.
Oh, I can do 300.
Okay, deal, right?
So charge however much you'd like.
But if you want some mathematical
guidance, here's a good formula.
Number one, ask the client how
much a client is worth to them and
then ask the client what
their close rate is on sales
calls.
What do I mean by this?
Let's say I'm reaching, I'm on a
call with Tom and he runs a TikTok
marketing business.
I would go, Tom, just curious, how
much is a client worth to you?
If you sign a client, what, you
know, dollar amount is that client
worth to you?
Based on how much you charge and
how long that they stay on with
you, they will probably
tell you, oh, five grand.
A client to me is worth $5,000.
I charge $1,000 a month.
I typically keep a client for five
months.
So $5,000 is how much a new client
is worth to me.
Okay, great.
What's your close rate on sales
calls?
How many calls are you closing and
signing on as clients?
What is a close rate?
That's just how many conversions
you get from the amount of sales
calls that you take.
If they close one in four calls,
their conversion, their close rate
is 25%.
Hey, every four calls I get on, I
close one deal and generate one
new client.
Okay, Tom.
So it takes you four sales calls
to sign a client and the client is
worth $5,000 to you, right?
Would you be okay with $250 per
booked sales call?
Because on average, you're going
to spend about $1,000, $250 per
call times four calls
to generate a $5,000 client.
They're going to go, yeah, that's
a no-brainer, man.
I would love to pay $250 a call to
get a $5,000 client every four
calls, right?
You see how this is making sense?
It's just a mathematical equation.
Let's say somebody goes, hey, man,
a client is actually worth $30,000
to me because I charge
a lot of money and clients never
really leave.
And we close at about a 20% rate.
So every one in five calls that we
take turns into a client.
Okay, would you pay $500, $750 per
call?
Oh, you know what?
I would pay $750 per call because
it's going to take me five calls
to close a deal.
What is that?
$750 times five.
That's $3,700 to close a $20,000
client.
Yes, that works with me.
So you can literally not even come
to the call with a price in mind
and then ask your
client a couple of questions.
Hey, how much is the client worth
to you?
Oh, we keep our clients for a year
and we charge two grand a month.
24 grand is what a client is worth
to me.
12 months times two grand, right?
24 grand easily is what I would,
you know, how much is what a
client is worth to me.
And I close at a 10% rate.
It takes me 10 calls to close one
deal.
I'm not that good at sales.
I like to do client work a lot
more.
Okay, great.
Would you pay 300 bucks per call?
Because it's going to take you 10
calls at 300 bucks per call to
close a client.
They're going to go, you know
what?
If I'm paying three grand to you
to close a $24,000 client, I'm
going to say yes to that
all day long.
You see how this mathematical
equation makes sense?
As long as the amount, the dollar
amount per call that you're
charging them is, you know,
a no brainer relative to how much
the client is worth to them.
They're going to say yes to you
and they're going to want to sign
on and work with your
business, right?
It's pretty much that simple.
And I need to delete.
This is a different document.
One second.
I'm going to delete the rest of
these tabs.
Okay, great.
So I want to space this out so I
can get through the rest of this
text without my face being
in the way because this box is
blocking out the text.
But that's basically what I was
saying.
Reverse engineer the math.
So if a client is worth $10,000 to
a business and they close 20% of
their sales calls, they
need five calls booked to sign a
$10,000 client.
They would be very willing to
spend $400 per call because
they're paying two grand to get
a $10,000 client.
This is simple math and it will
help with your sales process.
Now, other offer structures,
right?
Because let's say, oh man, you
know what, Christian?
I don't want to charge just on
performance.
I want to be compensated for my
time ahead of time as well.
No problem.
Here's what else you can do.
Monthly tech fee plus pay per
call.
Honestly, I would recommend a tech
fee of some sort because there is
a tech expense related
to or involved with running your
campaigns.
It's going to cost a fixed amount
of dollars every month to run cold
email campaigns.
You need inboxes, you need
domains, you need a sending tool,
and you need leads, right?
So there's a couple of different
components of a cold email
campaign that costs actual money.
If you explain this to somebody on
the phone, they will most likely
be willing to cover the
cost of the technology, right?
Oh, sure, Christian.
I'll pay you the money that it
costs to run the software if you
just do it all for me.
Okay, great.
So now, what can we do here,
right?
Oh, the monthly tech fee is going
to be $500 per month to cover the
tech costs.
And then plus $250 per booked
sales call, right?
Hey, man, you know what?
It's going to cost us about $500
to run this system every month.
So that's what we're going to
charge you no matter what every
month.
And then it's going to be $250 per
booked sales call.
You know, factoring in how much a
client is worth to you, this is
still plenty of leeway
because you're only paying $1,500
to close a client, $500 plus 250
calls times four calls
at your 25% close rate, right?
Still a no-brainer because let's
say the close rate is 25%.
They need four calls booked to
close a client.
They would be paying $1,000, 250
times four calls, right?
Plus the $500 tech fee equals
$1,500 to sign a client.
As long as this person or as long
as a client is worth, you know,
$3,000 plus to this person,
they will happily agree to this,
right?
Even with the flat tech fee
involved, if you price the cost
per booked sales call accordingly,
people will be happy to pay you
the tech fee and the cost per call
pricing
because they're acquiring a client
for $1,500.
And if that client is worth $3,000
or more to them, they're going to
happily say yes.
Now, you're probably saying,
Christian, why, you know, if
someone's lifetime value of a
client,
if a client is worth $1,500 to
somebody, why can't I just charge
this same pricing?
Well, because no one's going to
want to pay you $1,500 if their
client is only worth $1,500 to
them
because they are literally not
making any money on that client
and they're paying you all of the
profit margin.
So think on your feet.
Once again, there's no set formula
here.
It's just a ballpark range.
But, you know, price it in a range
that makes it a no-brainer to the
client based on your gut
instincts, right?
If a client is worth $5,000 to
somebody, you can ramp up this
tech fee to $1,000 and the cost
per call to $300.
So they're now paying $2,200 to
acquire a client, but it's worth
$5,000, right?
So there's no set number in terms
of what you should be charging
related to how much a client is
worth to your client.
But you just want to have a gut
feeling.
If it's like 5X, if a client's
worth $5,000 to somebody and
you're only getting paid $1,000 in
total for 250 calls times four
calls,
you're going to sign that person
very easily.
They're going to want to work with
you, but they might, you know, you
might be selling yourself short.
So find the perfect range where
it's a no-brainer for your client
because the mathematics makes
sense for them.
The math makes sense for them.
And it's a good situation for you
because you're being paid
according to your time and your
value.
You don't want to have a scenario
where you're charging $100 per
call and that person is signing
clients that are worth 20 grand
because you're getting, you know,
$500 for five calls and they're
getting a $20,000 client.
So you can price the cost per call
in accordance to what it is worth
or to what a client is worth to
that business
so you both get upside because
you're getting paid per the calls
booked
and your client is getting revenue
in the door from the calls that
you booked.
So hopefully this makes sense.
Once again, there's no rules here.
So if you want to do, you don't,
like, let's say the tech fee
really is $300.
It costs you $300 to run a
campaign.
You can show up to a call and say,
hey, man, it costs me $1,000 a
month to run this system.
You pay the $300.
You pocket the $700 in profit.
They're not going to know that
it's only $300.
This is called business.
People, you know, make a margin on
services because the business
owner doesn't really know how much
is required to run a campaign.
If you say $1,000 and they believe
you, you collect the invoice for
$1,000, you pay the $300 in tech
costs, and you pocket $700 in
profit, and then you get the
pay-per-call fee as well.
So if you're a confident
salesperson and you can explain to
somebody why it's a no-brainer for
them, you can make a lot of profit
margin without doing any extra
work.
Do you see what I'm saying?
Let's say somebody has a massive
business and they sign $150,000
clients.
You can say, hey, man, it's going
to cost me like $2,000 a month to
run these campaigns, and then it's
going to be $400 per call.
Is that okay with you?
Oh, yeah, that's cool.
Where do I sign?
$300 a month to run the campaign,
you pocket $1,700 because the
$2,000 minus the $300 to run the
campaign is $1,700, and you make a
lot of profit.
That is business.
This happens all the time in any
industry.
If you go to the grocery store and
you buy a Red Bull for $2, Walmart
paid $1 to have the Red Bull in
their stock.
Red Bull makes money.
Walmart makes money.
You have a product in your hands
that makes you happier because it
gives you energy.
Same thing here, arbitrage.
You pay $300 in tech costs to run
the campaign.
The client pays you $1,000 or $500
or $2,000, it doesn't matter.
You pocket the difference before
you even get into the pay-per-call
situation.
Now, I hope you're still watching
because I want to dive into set up
fees, right?
You want to cover your own ass up
front before campaigns even
launch.
You'll see in later videos.
Okay, I should have explained the
set up fees a little bit earlier
in the video here, but hopefully
you're still watching.
There is a fixed cost required to
set up a cold email system, right?
You need to buy domains like .com
addresses on behalf of the
business owner.
I'll explain why in later videos.
You need to buy email inboxes that
are on each domain like Christian
at apple.com, Suzy at apple.com,
right?
That's an email inbox.
They cost money through Google or
Outlook.
You also need to buy leads, a list
of email contacts to reach out to,
and you need to buy a sending
software to automate this entire
process because you're not going
to be sending emails by hand.
You're not going to be sending one
by one, um, that would take
literally all day and it would be
a waste of your time.
There's a software that does it
automatically.
Um, so you have to buy these
things before you even get started
with a client's campaign and you
have to invest.
You are investing into your own
labor or a virtual assistance
labor, right?
Not only do you have hard costs,
you have either your own time that
you're investing or a virtual
assistance time who you have to
pay for their labor, right?
So you want to charge some form of
an upfront setup fee, you know,
$1,000, $1,500, 2K, right?
We used to charge, I think, 1,500
bucks as a setup cost and then pay
per call.
So you go, hey, Mr.
Client, I'm going to need 1,500
bucks up front to build this
entire system out.
This is going to be invested into
hard costs, um, for the domains,
the inboxes, the leads, the
sending tool, my own messaging,
and copywriting abilities and my
labor and my team's labor, right?
You own the system, you know,
we're building it out for you.
We're basically building you an
asset that your business has
forever.
You're just going to have to pay
me some kind of upfront capital
to, you know, deploy into this
actual system being built, right?
Do you need to charge a setup fee?
No, but ideally you cover your own
ass and pay for the technology out
of their pocket, not your pocket.
And then you go ahead and charge a
pay per call model or a tech fee
plus pay per call model or a tech
fee plus pay per call plus rev
share model.
Once again, there are no rules
here.
Um, these are just a bunch of
different ways to frame, um, or
charge, you know, for the offer
that you're selling.
Hey, we can get you 10 calls a
month on a pay per call basis.
You only pay us 300 bucks a call.
Hopefully this is in depth enough.
I think I explained this very well
and very, um, thoroughly.
So, you know, how to, how to, you
know, structure your offer so that
it's an easy no brainer for your
client and an easy no brainer for
you to get them to, to sign on
with you and get to work.
So hopefully this helped see y'all
on the next video in the next
video.
I'm going to basically be going
over, um, how to actually write a
good email, a good cold email,
because number one cold email is
how you're probably going to sign
your first couple of clients.
And two, the entire service that
you're selling is cold email.
So it's in your best interest to
become very, very good at writing
cold email so you can get results
for your clients.
I want to teach you everything
that I know based on four years of
experience writing cold emails in
this next video.
So please pay attention to the
next video because it's probably
the most important one that you're
ever going to watch in this, um,
course in this program.
So thanks for watching.
Let's dive into the copywriting
section of cold email.
See you there.