Okay, I'm going to show you in
this video how to use AI to create
a three-step email sequence with a
few simple inputs
this AI is trained on hundreds of
my
Cold email scripts over the past
couple years and my screen is
frozen.
So I'm gonna fix that real quick
before we dive in so
Okay, great.
So basically this AI dashboard has
a bunch of really cool tools that
you can use to create cold emails
sales call reviews
Get offer creation input chat with
my CEO Andre on operations chat
with Daniel on offers
Basically a bunch of different
cool tools that you can use to
build your business with AI
But the focus of this video is
going to be on the cold email
creation
Chat or bot or whatever you want
to call it
So basically all you have to do is
tell it what you're selling what
your audience is
What's your background and what's
your campaign preferences and also
I'm gonna say is this I?
I noticed my box is actually in
the way.
Let me see if I can
Okay, there we go.
So I'll leave the bar down below.
That's fine
But basically what I'm gonna do is
let's start with the content
creation
Agency path.
I run a LinkedIn content
agency
Helping CEOs builds authority on
LinkedIn with long-form
posts
and
video
Contents I handle all of the
content creation and
Distribution for them I post
Everything on
There be half okay?
Okay
My best case study is helping
Andre from list kit close 10
clients in one month on LinkedIn
And I prefer to offer a video
going over a LinkedIn
Strategy I had in mind for them
and
Then this AI will
Create a three-step email sequence
for whatever you want to sell
Obviously, you're gonna have to
use your own
Critical thinking and input to
make this better, but this is
going to give you a really well
done email sequence
Or a lot of varieties of different
email sequences
That you can use so please make
this a three-step email sequence
With a be testing for each angle
Great one C 1d email 2 great.
So with any AI the outputs are
only as good as the inputs
So make sure that it's a
three-step email sequence because
I always prefer to do three-step
email sequences with my campaigns
You're free to do whatever you
want.
There are no rules to this game
But I like to do three steps.
So email 1a LinkedIn authority for
CEOs.
Are you getting enough qualified
leads from LinkedIn right now?
We help CEOs build authority with
long-form post and content
handling all content creation and
posting on your behalf
Andre from LinkedIn closed 10
clients in one month
Mind if I share a video going over
a LinkedIn strategy I had in mind
for you
Great CEO LinkedIn content done
Most CEOs struggle to consistently
create LinkedIn content while
running their business want to see
a video outlining the LinkedIn
strategy 10 clients from LinkedIn
Right, so like this sequence is
very very good all from a simple
input that I gave it.
So now
All I'm gonna do is move it to a
Google Doc and
paste it in here
obviously clear up the formatting
because it looks like
Shit right now
Okay, cool
Now I'm gonna make some changes to
the subject lines LinkedIn content
for
First name this will make it say
LinkedIn content for Christian Tom
Steven.
It'll pull in the actual name
Hey, Tom, are you getting enough
qualified leads from LinkedIn
right now?
I prefer to say we can help you
instead of we can help CEOs we can
help you build authority on
LinkedIn with long-form posts and
video content
We handle
All content creation and posting
on your behalf
Fake I made up this case study my
business partners Andre Andre from
list kit close 10 clients in one
month after we started
Started managing his LinkedIn
presence mind if I share a video
going over a strategy ahead of
mine for you
That's a good angle, right?
Really good angle all from AI in
the click of a button
Df y LinkedIn content
Most CEOs struggle to consistently
create LinkedIn content we handle
all creation and distribution
For busy executives long-form
posts.
Okay, great.
Good, right?
So like you guys can see
that
The AI is going to output you a
script sequence that is so close
to being perfect that it's
actually insane not to toot my own
horn
It's trained on my writing.
So it comes out pretty damn good.
Um, but like
You don't really need to make too
many changes to what it gives you
if you have a good prompt LinkedIn
company name X list kit
intro I
Would actually change up this
angle completely we can help you
sign five clients from LinkedIn
fully guaranteed with
Authority LinkedIn content posted
for you I
I don't like these subject lines
to be fair.
So I would switch up the subject
lines in this case
I
Don't know why they're doing a dot
instead of a hyphen here, but I'm
just making sure that looks good
Okay.
I mean like if you're doing the
the lead generation path like this
AI will literally knock
The time of your work like when
you sign a client if you're
running a legion agency and you
have to write them a new email
sequence
This AI will cut that curve from
an hour to five minutes, right?
If you're in the other paths and
you're just looking to write your
own scripts
This AI will be helpful.
Um, but you're probably not gonna
have to rely on it super often
because you're only doing outreach
to sign your own clients
The legion path the whole business
model is running campaigns for
clients for the other paths
You're only doing outreach for
your own campaigns
So this bot is gonna be most
effective for people running a
legion agency cold email, but if
you're running other
Another agency path you can still
benefit from using this AI to test
different angles, right?
This looks great write me a
similar three-step email sequence
For a professional I want to try
to confuse the AI to see if it can
really overcome
Hurdles for a professional
tickler.
I show up
To corporate events and tickle
people as a funny way to make the
events more fun
Nike
got
rave feedback from
Their employees after I tickled
them
Pitch a tickle video in the call
to action.
I want to see if I can throw a
wrench in the AI is thinking and
make it mess up because
Are you?
Okay, so the AI actually is
writing some fire for a
professional tickler
Which proves that this AI is your
one-stop shop for creating?
really good email content
Even for the weirdest offers in
the world corporate event
entertainment are your corporate
events memorable enough to get
employees talking for weeks
We provide professional tickling
entertainment for corporate events
a unique way to break the ice and
get create unforgettable team
bonding moments
Nike got rave reviews mind if I
share a video of our tickling
entertainment unforgettable team
events
Please make the angles
Shorter more concise so like you
can sit here and prompt the AI
over and over again, and it'll
rewrite it for you
There we go the best emails are
short as I showed you in previous
videos, so let's make these as
short as possible
Corporate events don't have to be
stiff and formal we provide
tickling entertainment that gets
everyone laughing Nike got rave
reviews open to seeing a video
So as you can see this is like the
beginner mode of AI
Script writing if you're a lead
gen path cold email lead
generation
This is extremely valuable for you
because you're gonna live in this
bot because you're gonna have to
write new scripts for each of your
clients if you're following the
email marketing path or
The content path or something
similar this is gonna be you know
A little bit less relevant for you
because you're not going to use it
as much, but it will still help
you write really good outreach
messages
For when you're doing your own
outreach.
So hopefully this helped in the
next video
I'm gonna be going into a much
more advanced
AI workflow that can help you
write cold email scripts that are
personalized to every single
person in your list of leads
This AI is gonna be a lot more
in-depth and it's gonna take a big
learning curve
But once you master it you can
write
personalized emails to every
prospect because clearly these are
not personalized to everyone in
your list
They're just templated blanket
statements that will still work.
Well, but they're not
They're not personalized to every
person.
So in the next video
I'm gonna show you how to write
personalized ones for every single
prospect in the list.
See you in the next video