- What's up guys, Lucas here.
Today I'm gonna be showing you
the RSS auto feed to content
pipeline.
So this is a very interesting one.
I'm gonna be showing you a few
elements of this as well.
Not only am I gonna be showing you
how this workflow works,
I'm gonna show you how to create
your own curated RSS feeds
of YouTube channels, Twitter
accounts,
just trends and mentions in the
media,
anything you wanna follow
and you wanna talk about in your
content
so that you can create
personalized feeds
and then feed this in order to
create
perfect LinkedIn posts for you.
So let's take a look at this first
and see what we've got.
So the first thing I've set up as
usual,
all you need here is Slack.
You'd open router set up.
I have perplexity out of, not
necessary really,
but I like having perplexity for
extra research.
And then we have bloatato for
scheduling,
which we went over in one of the
previous scheduling
was a multi-content platform
factory,
multi-platform content factory
video.
But it's pretty simple.
bloatato kind of just gives you an
API key from bloatato
and you paste it in there.
Slack as usual is just gonna be
the connect to Slack button.
And then open writer is your API
key for open writer.
So what this does essentially is
every, I think it's four hours.
Yeah, every four hours, what this
does is it runs
and it pulls content from these
different RSS feeds.
Now I've got TechCrunch in here.
I've got Hacker News.
I've got Crunchbase.
I've got AI trends and I've got a
wired and their AI business
section.
So this was gets the latest news
from these outlets, right?
This one up here, rss.app, this is
my custom one.
So if you actually go to the
website, rss.app and log in,
you can create feeds from pretty
much any social media platform.
So if I click add feed here, see,
you can choose our web page,
an Instagram feed, Twitter page,
TikTok, Reddit, literally
anything.
There's loads of options down
here, right?
Then you can also just use topics.
So you can just take a topic and
it'll find the best place to get
like that.
So like, you know, e-commerce, if
you're about e-com a lot,
or you're running an e-com agency,
there's a ton of different ones in
there.
And once you've added all of them,
I've added some stuff from Fazio,
some other kind of marketing
accounts and people I follow on
Twitter,
you can then create a bundle.
A bundle, what it does is it
combines all of these feeds into
one feed.
So I'll go to bundle.
I click add bundle.
You can just select everyone and
I've already done this.
And now I've got a feed here that
has all the content
from all those accounts all in
here.
So once you have that, then all
you do is you copy this,
your bundle URL up here and in and
then you're just going to paste it
in here.
And the next thing we have here is
a keyword filter.
This filters for your particular
topic.
So you're going to want to change
this depending on what topic you
want to talk about.
For me, it has to contain the word
AI.
If it doesn't contain AI, it
doesn't continue through.
That's cause I talk mainly about
AI.
So as you can see here from this
one, we got two items.
We got five from here.
We got a known from here.
We got four from here, 10 items
here, six items here.
Then this aggregates it all
together and we merge it all into
one item.
Then we just wait to make sure
that that's done.
And then we take aggregate again,
all the information and we send it
to our AI agent.
Now you will have to edit this as
well.
I'm going to show you how we set
up this AI agent prompt.
Cause this is actually very
interesting.
So the user prompt is fine.
It just tells it that it's make it
1500, 2000 character LinkedIn
post.
And then it has all of our
different information from the RSS
feeds here.
Right.
But if we go to the system
message, this is where things get
kind of important.
You have to change this.
Look for this reference document
one.
And if you scroll down, you'll see
there's reference document two.
You're going to want to change all
of this.
Cause this is about you.
This is about all my information.
This is where it is given the AI
context in who I am, what I want
to talk about, like the
kind of different, uh, uh, you
know, topics that I cover, things
like that.
So what I would suggest doing is
copy all this, go to chat GBT,
paste it in and say,
I want to rewrite this for me
specifically.
I am whoever, you know, I run it
as this I'm from this place.
Uh, here's what I, I, you know, I
do.
I have my background, uh, my
offer.
And if you're using chat GBT a lot
already, it will should have some,
uh, memory about who
you are like to kind of start
from.
And we'll rewrite this for you and
just paste that in there.
You of course can just fill it out
manually yourself.
Just the, um, uh, name, location,
roles, background, uh, your offer,
all that sort of stuff.
The second reference document
tells it how to write high
converting LinkedIn posts.
So don't change that.
But after we do that, we get a
LinkedIn post out.
That is really good.
And then we're going to send this
to ourselves in Slack.
So, uh, the way this works is that
it sends it to you and wait for
you to approve it or
disapprove of it.
So you can see what the post looks
like.
Um, this is actually a really good
one.
Someone Hacker News has pointed
out that the current AI boom looks
eerily similar to
the automobile boom in Detroit
circa 1910.
After Ford's Model T success,
nearly 2000 car companies were
founded.
99% failed.
Only Ford, GM, and Chrysler
survived.
Sound familiar?
Today, Anthropic just raised $13
billion at $183 billion valuation.
Their revenue exploded from $1
billion to $5 billion in just
eight months.
Meanwhile, open AI is dealing with
safety concerns, rolling out new
protections.
The industry is consolidating
around giants with massive capital
requirements
creating nearly insurmountable
barriers to entry.
But here's where it gets
interesting for agency owners.
In the early auto days, the real
winners weren't just the
manufacturers.
They were the businesses that
figured out how to leverage the
technology to transform
their operations.
The same is happening now.
As an agency owner, you don't need
to build the next cloud or GBT.
You need systems that turn these
tools into revenue engines.
The agencies thriving right now
aren't just using AI.
They're fundamentally rebuilding
their operations around automation
and AI-native workflows.
I'm seeing it firsthand.
Agencies that treat AI as just
another tool are struggling.
While those building proprietary
systems and workflows around these
platforms are scaling
rapidly and profitably.
The opportunity isn't competing
with Anthropic or open AI.
It's building your business to
harness their capabilities in ways
your competitors haven't
figured out yet.
What's your agency's AI strategy?
Are you using the tools or your
architecting systems to transform
how you deliver value?
Great post.
Really good, right?
Now, when this runs, I will get a
message in Slack.
So you're going to have to change
your, obviously, connection with
your Slack.
And then you got to send it to a
channel or to yourself.
And it will send it here.
You see, then we have a response
type is approval, approve, and
disapprove.
You'll see two buttons in Slack.
You can change, let's say, approve
or decline.
You can change the labels there.
And then I decline this because I
just want to post on LinkedIn
right now.
But if you approve it, it will
take the post and it will post it
to, it'll schedule it
in Botato to post to your
LinkedIn.
Obviously in Botato, you'll have
to have your LinkedIn connected
up.
And if not, if you say no, it just
finishes the workflow.
So that's basically it.
When you send this to active, this
will just roll in automatically
every four hours.
And every four hours or so, you
will get a message in Slack with,
"Hey, here's your new post.
Do you want to post it?"
And you say yes or no.
Really simple way to run your
content pipeline.
And obviously you can customize
this as well for your clients.
If you're running a content
agency, just, you know, obviously
get the feeds of and create
feeds of the topics that they talk
about or the people that they kind
of want to emulate.
Give it your own kind of maybe
tweaks on their voice and style in
the AI agent prompt and you
are good to go.
So I think it's going to be a
super useful one, very easy, very
simple to run.
Automate your LinkedIn for you
pretty much.
And yeah, I think it's very cool
that you can customize your own
RSS feeds.
Make sure to check that out,
rss.app.
Just sign up.
And again, new feed, add the stuff
from wherever you want to add it
from, and then create a bundle
and add all those feeds to a
bundle that you will then take the
URL of up here and send,
put it pasted into your RSS node
here and you're good to go.
Also make sure to remember to edit
the keyword filter for whatever
topic you want to talk about.
Hope this is helpful and I will
see you guys in the next one.
Peace.