What's up guys, Lucas here.
Today I'm going to be showing you
guys a detailed YouTube script
creator, a automation.
And essentially what this does is
you submit client information, it
researches the client,
it does a ton of different AI
agents to craft a perfect YouTube
video, then it will create
a Google Doc, it'll put it into
your client's folder, and it will
send you an email with
the flow or you can email it
directly to the client, whichever
you'd prefer, and alert
you in Slack that the script is
created.
So I'm going to start by walking
you through step-by-step what this
flow looks like and
what it does, and then show you
the elements that you will
probably have to authenticate
when you add it to your own
account.
You shouldn't have to actually
edit really anything here, so
maybe one element I'll show
you, but you will have to connect
up your accounts and authenticate
them as I showed you in previous
videos in the N8N section.
So let's start off by zooming in
on the first part, what you call
the client intake system
and what this does and what it
looks like.
So the first part is a form, on
form submission.
So N8N's got a very basic form
builder that works really well.
So we've created a form and I've
got pinned information here.
This just means that I've already
run this and I've pinned the
results here.
So I submitted this form.
As you can see here, the questions
we ask are the name of the client,
the email, the niche
that they're in, their channel
URL, are they a returning client?
Have you been making scripts for
them already?
What is their social media
profiles?
Additional context about the
client, and then these are done
automatically.
So as you can see, I put myself
in, Lucas sent it, my email, I'm
in the business agency
and AI automation space.
There's my channel URL.
Am I a returning client?
Yes.
I put my LinkedIn and social media
profiles to give you more
information about me.
Now, the other thing you have to
do is set up a Google Drive with a
clients folder.
You should have this anyway, but
just go to Google Drive, create a
folder called clients.
That's all you need.
You can see in here, I've got the
folder name clients and I've got
myself already in here
along with their test client.
So that's why when it came to
returning client, I set it to
true.
I just said, yes, they're a
returning client.
So that information then goes to
the parser.
And then there's three different
sections that runs through.
This one decides that if they are
a returning client, sorry, no, if
they have a YouTube channel
input, because not all of your
clients will have a YouTube
channel, but if they have a
YouTube
channel, it scrapes some of their
most recent videos using Apefy.
Then it sends that data to the
merge node.
The other if statement says that
if they are a returning client,
then it searches your client's
folder for the client's name,
finds their last created script
and sends that to the merge
node too.
And then this agent looks for more
information on the client, does
deep research using perplexity
to get a ton of information about
the client and context.
You can see here, we got a big
comprehensive market intelligence
report on me just using
perplexity.
There is the prompt you can see in
here what it looks for.
It looks for the creator business
profile analysis, their YouTube
channel deep dive, content
strategy,
competitive landscape, all this
stuff.
Just goes to a full deep dive on
the client.
Actually, if I go back here again,
you'll see it says you're
conducting a market intelligence
research on me, monitoring
research me, my channel, and other
people, and then just more
information we got from the form.
So after that, all that
information is taken and put
together.
So we have my YouTube videos, we
have my client research, and we
have previous videos that
this AI has created that are in
the client folder.
This goes to a data intelligence
agent.
And this basically does another
structured analysis of the client
researching information
and looking for things like
content opportunities, competitor
insights, audience behavior,
things
like that.
That thing goes to a YouTube
category agent.
And all this does determine what
YouTube category the video should
be created in.
So we can see here, it says the
category should be business and
entrepreneurship with a confidence
level 95 and explains why it
thinks that.
Then we go to the audience persona
agent, and this creates a detailed
audience persona.
So based on the information we got
from all the other parts, the data
intelligence agent, the client
research agent, it will create a
basic audience persona.
Demographics are people aged 30 to
45, male, location, primarily
developed English-speaking
markets, education, income, all
these sort of things.
Basically, you're coming up with
who your likely audience viewers
are.
Then we create a content strategy
from all of this information.
This creates content pillars,
content types and formats,
publishing schedule, video
concept, SEO strategy, all that
sort of stuff there.
Again, based on our previous
information from the other agents.
The whole time here, we're passing
through the data collected by
other agents.
Finally, we get to the script
writer agent.
This script writer will do a few
things.
It will obviously write the
script, but using the information
from previous agents, it gets the
content strategy, the target
audience, the market intelligence
report.
It also looks for our previous
AI-generated YouTube script.
This is so that we don't keep
making the same script each time,
because if we're doing the same
research, get the same information
for the client over and over, it
could very likely produce the same
videos each time.
So then it sends it the most
recent YouTube script generated
and says, don't make this script
again, essentially.
Then it gives it examples of other
clients' other scripts.
Again, if they don't have other
scripts from YouTube for their
YouTube videos, that's totally
fine.
It'll just use all the other
information.
Then it writes the script, as you
can see over here.
Now, we could be done there, but
we're not.
So the next thing we do is we make
an SEO package based on this.
And we come up with a pretty
detailed breakdown of how we
should be covered with video
titles and descriptions and tags
and all that sort of stuff.
Then we send it to a quality
review agent.
This reviews the script and then
makes suggestions.
So the revision recommended strong
foundation and broken ready for
several high-impact edits to
materially improve retention,
walkthrough in CTR with a 78%
level of confidence.
So it comes up with suggestions on
how to improve the script based on
information we've gathered from
professional YouTubers and
professional script writers.
Then it sends those edits to the
script improver agent, which takes
the original script and improves
it based on the suggestions given
by the previous quality reviewer
agent.
Then we send that over here to our
final results aggregator, just
sorts things properly in the right
kind of string names and things.
Then we convert the script to
markdown, so it just converts the
information we need to a correct
markdown format.
And then we send that to a service
that turns markdown into formatted
Google Docs.
The final thing we do is we check
it again if they are a returning
client.
It will search for the client
folder and move the script to the
existing client folder.
If they're not a returning client,
it will create a folder with their
name and move the file there.
Finally, we make a very nice
looking email that just tells them
the script is done with links to
the script.
And we send that email.
Now, here's where you can edit it.
You can decide if you want this to
go to you or you can just get the
client's email from the data
validator and parser.
Just get client email and drag
that in there if you want to send
it to the client.
But otherwise, you can send it to
yourself or to a test account like
I have.
And then finally, we have a Slack
notification set up.
From here, you'll authenticate
your Slack and you will just
choose your name from the list.
Or you can send it to a channel if
you want to have a channel as the
right place this goes.
And it will just say, hey, the
script's done.
Here's the link to the script.
So that's primarily it.
Again, the only thing you have to
change for most of these is going
to be authenticating your account.
So you have to get your OpenRouter
account authenticated in there.
You have to get your Apify account
authenticated in there.
Your Google Drive authenticated,
your Google Docs authenticated,
and your Gmail and Slack
authenticated.
Aside from that, that is pretty
much everything.
To do that, again, you'll just
copy and paste this whole workflow
into your own N8N.
Then you'll see some of these will
be red because you'll need to
authenticate them.
And you will just go in and either
create or connect your existing
Google Drive account.
You may have to change the
folders, give it the folder that
you need it in.
So, for example, in search for
client folder, you'll want to
change this here.
Just click from this and just type
in clients, which is what you
should name your folder, and
select it.
So it knows to search your clients
folder.
That is pretty much everything.
This produces really good scripts.
So I'll show you an example now of
this is the email that you're
going to get from the AI when it's
done.
So this is what you or your client
could see.
It's got a link to the script
folders.
It's got a direct script link.
And it gives it some next steps
and suggestions.
I think you can obviously change
the name to your name down here.
To do that, you would just edit
this composed client delivery
email.
Email body, you would just change
the best regards, and then your
name in here.
And then when they click this
link, it'll bring them to the
drive that contains their scripts.
And if you click this link, it
brings them directly to the
script, which will look like this.
So you can see we've got the
client name, their email, the
timestamp when this is created,
the script, the title, the hook.
It's the intro and value
proposition.
A full thing, fully laid out, full
script, ready to go.
It includes emphasis and visual
suggestions for them to go
through.
And then if you go down here,
there's the SEO package, which has
some video title suggestions, the
description, the hashtags,
thumbnail text suggestions.
End screen elements, community
posts, pre-launch engagement, SEO
keywords, and optimization notes.
So this creates really, really
good YouTube scripts.
This should be all you need to run
your YouTube script writing
process.
Again, you simply just input the
information into the form, and
then this does pretty much
everything else.
Any problems, feel free to hit me
up.
We'll take a look.
But once you authenticate your
accounts, it should be pretty much
ready to go.
So I hope this is helpful, and
look forward to seeing what you
guys do with this.
Peace.