What's up guys, so today I'm going
to be showing you the
multi-platform content factory.
I'm going to be breaking down just
some of the nodes we're going to
see,
some of the things we're going to
have to set up briefly,
and telling you kind of just
overall how it works.
So what does this do?
This takes any call transcript
that you have,
either automatically from any Zoom
call you make,
or by pasting a transcript into
the automation,
and it turns it into a YouTube
script, a LinkedIn post, a Twitter
post, and an email newsletter.
So I'm going to start by going
over the first nodes here.
We've got two here.
We've got webhook, and we've got
when chat message received.
When chat message is pretty
self-explanatory.
You'll notice down here, it
probably looks like this, at the
bottom of N8N,
you will see chat over here.
And if you click this, you can
talk to this like you would to
chat GPT,
but what we're going to do here is
we're just going to paste in a
call transcript.
Now, for all our call recordings,
you might be using read.ai, you
might be using otter.
We use fathom.
Now, fathom's great, but fathom,
unfortunately,
doesn't allow us to directly send
call transcripts out.
What it does do, though, is it
works with Zapier.
So we have a Zapier setup that is
just simply two steps.
So if you want this to happen
automatically, you'll have to set
up this zap.
And the zap essentially says when
a new transcript is created in
fathom,
it sends it to a webhook by
Zapier.
What that does is it gives you a
URL, or it allows you to input a
URL.
So you will go back to NNN, and up
here you'll see the webhook, and
this is your URL.
Use a production URL one, but
that's your URL there.
So you copy that, and you paste it
into Zapier on the URL.
You choose post for the method.
And then here, like you go to any
other Zapier, you want to send
information,
you add the information that you
want to be sent.
The main thing we want is the
transcript, but you can add all
this other stuff too.
So now this means that every time
a new call is created, so when
fathom is on a call of mine,
it will send the call transcript
afterwards to this automation.
But if you don't want to go
through all that hassle, and you
don't want to pay for Zapier as
well as N8N,
then you can simply take your call
transcript and just paste it in
here, and it will trigger the
automation.
It just means it's not fully
automated.
Whereas for me, every time I do a
call, I get a Slack message
showing me the most recent content
made from what I talked about on
that call.
So let's go over this.
We'll start off by looking at the
YouTube script agent.
Very simply, when you paste the
transcript in here, or you do a
call on the webhook, it receives
the transcript.
This writes a YouTube script based
on some of the information we have
from other YouTube experts on how
to write scripts.
Then this creates a title for it.
To walk you through just the AIs
we're using for this one, we're
using Claude to actually write the
script.
Again, you have to set up Open
Router for this, which you should
have set up with all the other
workflows.
And as you can see, it's using
Claude 3.7 Sonnet.
And over here for this one,
because this is only just making a
title, it's not a very, you know,
intensive sort of process, we're
just using DeepSeq R1 free.
So it's a free AI.
So we're just using that to create
the title.
After that is created, the
script's created, we use this
node, which I'll explain to other
ones, but it's a service called
MD2Doc to create our Google Doc.
It's nicely formatted, it looks
good.
So once it's created, then it
moves the file into a folder I've
created for it, you have some
Google Drive as well, called
YouTube Scripts.
So in your Google Drive, just make
a folder called YouTube Scripts.
Then this one is LinkedIn Posts.
Then this one is called Twitter
Posts.
And then this one is just called
Newsletters.
So once you have those created,
you can then, these will move the
files appropriately into the right
folder.
I made a folder that's called
Content.
And then if we go back here, say I
want to use a different folder, I
would simply choose the parent
folder here, type in the name of
it, but I've got YouTube Scripts
created, so it's going to go in
there.
But from here, you can choose what
folder you want the YouTube
Scripts to go into.
Then when that's done, it will
send me a message in Slack to edit
this.
Again, obviously connect Slack,
send message to user, and then me,
or you can send it to a channel if
you want to have all of your
content in one channel.
And then over here, we prepared
the YouTube content for Q1.
It just basically takes it and
gets the content type, the text,
the document URL, stuff like that.
And it sends it to a Google Sheet
we've created.
So we're going to create a Google
Sheet, call it Content Calendar,
and add these titles to it.
So if I show you the sheet, it
looks like this, Platform, Date,
and Link.
So that way, when this is done,
this will now just log the
information of the posts here.
So it's our YouTube Script, the
date was created, and the link to
it here.
Obviously, because you have to
record the YouTube Script, we're
not going to schedule that.
That's obviously something we're
just going to come back to later.
We'll just get a notification
saying it's finished.
But for the others, we're actually
going to schedule them.
So when you send the transcript,
after the YouTube Script is
created, it will create a LinkedIn
post.
Then make a title for that, make a
Google Doc, move it to the correct
folder, and it will then send you
a message and wait for your
response.
And basically, it will give you a
preview of the post, and you
decide if you want to post it or
not.
If you don't want to post it, it
just stops.
But if you say you do want to post
it, then it sends it to the queue,
and we use Blotato for scheduling.
Blotato is a tool.
They have a free version, but for
the API, it's actually very
affordable, and it allows us to
schedule all of our content across
different platforms.
You can create all sorts of posts
on it.
It's got an API.
You can see if you can connect to
Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook,
TikTok, Instagram, threads,
everything, right?
So we're going to set this up by
going to the plus button here, or
actually, this will already be on
your workflow, but you'll have to
install this node.
So if you type in Blotato, when
you first click it, it'll ask you
if you want to install this
community node, and just click
install, and then it'll work.
So this then creates the LinkedIn
post posted for you, and then this
prepares the content to be logged,
and it adds it to the Google
Sheet.
They all work the exact same way.
So now the Twitter post is the
same thing.
Twitter post agent makes the
posts.
Then creates a title, creates a
Google Doc, moves it to the
correct folder, sends you a
message, you approve it, and then
it gets posted to Blotato, and
then logged to the sheet.
And finally, we have the
newsletter.
Now, for the newsletter, we're
using ConvertKit, because they
have the most available API.
So this writes the newsletter,
gives it a title, makes the post
in a Google Drive, moves it to the
correct folder, then sends you a
message, asks you to approve it,
and if you approve it, it'll add
it to your queue.
It won't send the newsletter
directly, it'll add it to your
drafts in ConvertKit.
And you'll have to modify this
slightly yourself.
So if you click over here, you
will be asked to authenticate, and
basically just put your API in
here.
Under API secret, go to
ConvertKit, sign up for
ConvertKit, go to settings, go to
API, create an API key, and just
paste the API key in here.
And now, when you're done, it will
send that newsletter text to your
queue, your drafts in ConvertKit,
and then it will log it in the
Google Calendar.
And that's basically the whole
thing.
The only thing you're going to
need to set up again, as I
mentioned before, make sure
OpenRouter is authenticated.
Make sure that your Google Docs
are authenticated.
Make sure that Slack is
authenticated.
And to do that again, you click in
here, and you just log in with
Google, and it should work.
I go over this in another video as
well.
I had to do it on self-hosted as
And then same for Slack, you'll
click here, you'll just log in
with Slack, and you'll be good to
go.
Potato, you're going to get your
API key.
You're going to get that from the
Potato dashboard.
Or, yeah, just have a login.
You'll use the credentials and use
your Potato login, and then it
will be posted to your LinkedIn
account after you've also
authenticated it in Potato.
You'll have to go to Potato's
thing here, log in with LinkedIn,
log in with whatever platform you
want, and then you'll get your API
key over here.
Just copy it, and you just paste
it in, and you are good to go.
So, again, the prerequisite is
what you need.
You need folders for all of these.
So, you need a YouTube scripts
folder, LinkedIn posts folder,
Twitter posts folder, newsletter
folder on Google Drive.
And then you need to log in to all
the various accounts.
And you need to create a Google
Sheet just called Content
Calendar, and select that in here.
And once you do that, then, and
you paste the transcript in here,
you will have a ton of content
ready to go.
Now, this, again, works, if you
want to have this work
automatically, you will need to
use Zapier to create a webhook
from Fathom to send the most
recent call transcripts to your
N8N workflow.
Again, to do that, it's a two-step
Zapier, new transcript from
Fathom, webhooks by Zapier, you
paste in your webhook from the
first step here, and then you test
it.
It'll receive the transcript, and
then you can just set it live, and
you're good to go, and that'll
work automatically.
So, yeah, that's basically it.
Any issues, feel free to hit me
up, and I will go over it with
you.
But hopefully that kind of
explains the whole thing, and I
think you guys are going to get a
lot of use out of this one.
It makes it super easy to create
content pretty much on autopilot,
and, yeah, works across multiple
platforms.
So, hit me up with any problems,
and see you in the next one.
Peace.