All righty, ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls, here we are today
talking about how
to create a banger VSL for your
B2B service offer.
Why do you need a VSL?
That's a great question because
it's the best way for you to be
able to scale your offer
to 30K a month, 40K a month, 50K a
month.
Why is that, Nick?
Great question.
I'll tell you.
First and foremost, it makes your
sales calls a hell of a lot
easier.
People are going to come on your
call pre-sold.
Second of all, it makes people
actually want to get on a sales
call with you because when
they click on the link in your
cold email or when they look you
up and they find your website
and your domain and then they
watch the video on there, if it's
a really good VSL, guess
what?
They'll book a call with you.
They'll be excited to actually
talk with you because they're
like, oh my goodness, this person
understands my problems.
And on top of that, also, they
understand what I want.
And on top of that, they provide a
really good service that I would
like.
Please take my money.
That's how people think.
Exactly like that.
Don't quote me.
Now, on top of that, also, guys,
this is a great way for you to
separate yourself from
your competition.
There's a lot of people out there
that are probably providing the
same service as you.
Okay.
Unless you have some blue ocean
offer, which some of you guys do,
but majority of you guys
are selling things that other
people are selling.
And your VSL is how you can
separate yourself from the
competition.
Most people don't even want to get
on camera.
They're terrified of getting on
camera.
Oh God, people are going to judge
me.
Super lame.
Don't be like that.
If you are good on camera, it'll
immediately separate you from
everyone else because you
are a charismatic individual.
You should obviously program
yourself to thinking like that.
You are a charismatic individual.
And people are more attracted to
that than the geek that's...
They're a little, sorry, I just
need to send an email out.
I can't get on camera.
I would prefer if we kept the
communication through text.
Like, trust me, you will be much
more appealing to your audience
when they can see you and
understand
how you act, right?
And how you actually hold
yourself.
Okay.
So let's get started, guys.
Let's talk about how to craft a
Bangor VSL for your B2B service
offer.
In this module, we're not going to
be diving into the specifics.
This is more of like a
housekeeping introduction module,
but very important you watch it so
you
know what's to come.
Okay.
So here's what we're going to be
covering inside this short yet
powerful program.
Okay.
So what you must do before you
write your VSL script and produce
your VSL.
Okay.
Pretty much everyone ignores this
one thing and it's why pretty much
everyone else out there sucks.
Okay.
If you do this one thing, your
life will be so much easier.
You are going to come to me in the
messages of Slack instead of
client ascension.
And you're going to say, Nick, I
cannot believe I tried to market
my offer or market my business
any other way than the way that
you're going to tell me to do it.
And the one thing, which you're
going to find out in the next
module, that one thing changed
my perspective on how to message
and how to market and how to do
all that stuff.
Right.
So it's what you're going to find
out in the next module.
You're also going to learn how to
write a VSL script that speaks to
your prospect's desires
and also their pain points.
And it incentivizes your prospect
to book a call with you.
So we're going to talk about that
as well.
And then on top of that, we're
also going to show you the three
different types of VSLs
you can produce and how to know
which one is best for you and your
personality type.
And here's the thing, guys, I'm
just, I really want you to think
about this.
It should not take you more than
one to two days for you to produce
your VSL.
Okay.
One to two days.
I'm going to prove that to you by
doing exactly that today with you.
I'm going to produce a VSL in a
day.
Okay.
And you're going to see, holy
shit, like the four minute mile.
This is totally possible.
I promise you it is.
It's not hard.
People that tell you this needs to
take like three weeks and you
really need to dive into it.
Like, nope.
It's super simple stuff.
If you've done your work
beforehand and have an offer put
together, I mean, you've talked
with Daniel.
You've actually been on Daniel's
call.
You have your offer.
You have your guarantee.
This is all really simple going
forward.
It's a lot of organization.
If you don't have that yet, I
would highly recommend you get
that first before we move on to
anything else.
If you do not have an offer, if
you do not have a guarantee,
it's going to be really hard for
you to get any value from this.
If you do have an offer and you do
have a guarantee, you're ready to
rock and roll.
So let's keep going.
So who am I?
Why am I teaching this?
Okay.
My name is Nicholas Verge.
I've been a direct response
copywriter for five years now.
Okay.
Let's get all fingers in the
picture.
Five years now.
And I've been in Klein Ascension
for a year now.
And I write Daniel's newsletter.
Okay.
During those five years as a
direct response copywriter,
I've produced right around $30
million for my clients.
It could be 35.
Honestly, you lose track after a
while.
But I've produced a metric fuck
ton of revenue for my clients.
And I've written and produced VSLs
for celebrity clients like Alex
Jones, Jordan Belfort,
and many other underground names
that you don't know.
But they're quietly cleaning up
seven to eight figures a year.
Okay.
So I've done a lot of VSLs.
I've done a lot of copywriting.
I've done a lot of messaging.
I know what I'm doing here.
And I'm really excited to share
all the little secrets and little
things that I know
that's going to get you guys to at
least that competency level where
you can do it yourself.
Okay.
And here's the thing, guys.
I literally sell VSLs for a
living.
This is what I do.
I don't take on a lot of them
because I'm pretty pricey.
But, you know, I do like three to
four VSLs a year for a fairly high
ticket package.
And I've, again, produced just a
disgusting amount of revenue from
them.
They're a high-end luxury service
for me.
And I also coach people on a
one-on-one basis how to do it
themselves.
So this is my living.
This is what I do.
And I'm going to show you guys how
to do it as well.
So here's some housekeeping
information before we dive into
all those juicy things that are
going to get you your VSL across
the goal line.
Okay.
First and foremost, our weekly
calls as of right now are on
Wednesdays at 2 p.m.
PST right after Daniel's offer and
strategy coaching call.
Okay.
That may change.
And if it does, you will be
updated in the Slack.
Okay.
Super straightforward there.
If you need help or you need
support with your VSL or your
script or anything like that,
message me individually on Slack.
We can totally review it on the
group calls.
If outside of the group calls you
would like support, just shoot me
a message.
Do not ask questions in the
channel.
I will not respond to you.
If you ask questions in the
channel, I'm just going to
redirect you back to this module.
You're going to say, hey, Nick,
I'm really struggling with
crafting the right intro.
And I really think that this will
be best.
What's your thoughts?
And I'm going to be like, oh,
awesome.
And hey, go check out module one
minute, whatever this is at right
here.
Six minutes and 20 seconds in.
This is the best place for you to
start.
Send me individual messages.
It's a lot easier for me, guys,
when I don't have 16 different
messages on a group chat and I can
instead see individual messages
inside of the Slack.
Slack channel, again, is only
intended for updates on calls,
notes, et cetera.
Now, guys, we have a zero goose
egg.
Say it with me, everyone.
Goose egg.
Zero plagiarism tolerance.
On calls, we will be reviewing
your VSLs, your scripts.
We'll be talking about your
intros.
We'll be talking about stuff, all
that good stuff.
If it turns out that you decided
to jack your fellow Klein
Ascension member and you decided
to blatantly plagiarize their
script or their VSL or their offer
or whatever it is, and you feel
like that's the case, reach out to
me.
If you found out that someone did
that to you, reach out to me.
I'm going to send the information
to Daniel, and he will handle it.
I have discussed with him what the
consequences are.
He said don't tell them what the
consequences are, but he said that
he will handle it, and I put in
parentheses there, not good,
because it's not good.
I'm not going to say what's going
to happen, but not good, okay?
So, guys, don't plagiarize
someone.
Don't jack someone's stuff.
That's so lame.
There's infinite ways you can
explain your offer.
You do not need to steal your
fellow Klein Ascension members'
stuff, and if you guys feel like
that's happened to you, speak up.
Let me know.
We'll make sure we handle it and
make sure, you know, we actually
get to the bottom of it.
So, that is everything, if I
remember correctly.
Yep, that's everything.
So, that's everything for this
module, guys.
We are now going to move on to the
next module, which is going to
talk about that one thing that you
have to do if you actually want to
put together a good VSL.
So, let's get started.
My goodness, I can't find the
stop.
There we go.