Alrighty guys, welcome back to the
next module where we're going to
be talking about how to craft and
create a banger VSL for your B2B
service offer.
So, let's not waste any time,
let's get started.
And today, we're going to be
talking about what you must do
before you write your VSL script
and produce your VSL.
Again guys, pretty much everyone
ignores this and that's why they
suck.
If you do this, it's going to be a
hell of a lot easier for you to be
able to produce this VSL.
It's going to be a hell of a lot
easier for you than produce
marketing materials going forward
for yourself.
And just in general, you're going
to feel a lot more organized on
what you're doing inside your
business, especially when it comes
to selling and marketing your
service.
So, what are we talking about?
Well, I'll tell you guys.
It's a very common mistake.
Don't do this.
A lot of people try and go
straight to writing their VSL
script before taking any time to
actually organize everything they
need to craft a banger VSL.
Slow down, buckaroo.
Whoa, hey, whoa, we're not in a
rush.
All right.
Here's the question, guys.
Are you trying to get this done?
Are you trying to get it done
right?
Okay.
Because just getting it done does
not necessarily translate into
sales.
Just because you have a VSL on
your homepage or on your landing
page does not mean you're going to
get sales.
It's not an automatic, boom, there
you go.
You're going to get sales.
That's not how that works.
If you have a shitty VSL, I
guarantee you will not get sales.
You want a good VSL.
And so, a good VSL is the right
VSL.
And the way you do that is by
listening to what I'm telling you
to do today.
Okay.
A lot of you are still not going
to listen to me.
And then you're going to come back
on the call and be like, oh, I
don't know why I'm not booking
calls.
And I'm like, how much time did
you spend on your VSL?
How much time did you spend on
your actual creative brief?
Do you have a creative brief?
Oh, I just spoiled it.
Well, let's just dive in, guys.
This is why we take the time to
create, drum roll please, a
creative brief, right?
This is the one thing that you
need to have.
If you don't have this, you're
making it 10 times harder for
yourself to craft a good VSL.
Okay.
The creative brief is the
organization of specific product
information, which allows us to be
able to organize all the selling
points we have and create a
hierarchy of messaging.
Okay.
So that's what I was talking about
just a second ago is that you're
going to come and you're going to
say, oh, man, like, oh, it's not
working.
Like, no, it's not working.
And then I'm going to say, can I
see your creative brief?
I don't have one.
And I'm going to be like, that's
why you're not getting any sales.
If you don't have a creative
brief, it's extremely hard for you
to be able to actually put
together an offer and messaging
for that offer that's effective.
Creative briefs are what make it
very, very easy for you to be able
to craft effective messaging.
Because, again, they're the
organization of the messaging.
And so you're like, well, what is
a creative brief?
What is that?
Oh, great questions.
I'm going to tell you.
Okay.
So writing an effective video
script, guys, isn't really all
that different from an attorney
speaking to the jury.
Right.
You're just stating an argument.
Think about that for a second.
When an attorney is trying to
prove that his client is innocent,
he is stating an argument to the
jury, explaining to them why his
client is innocent or why, you
know, the defendant is guilty,
whatever it is.
Right.
He's stating an argument.
You selling your product or
service to someone is stating an
argument and your argument has to
be so good that they believe you
and that they decide to buy.
Okay.
So if you want a good argument,
you need to have all the facts.
Lawyers can't present to a jury
when they don't have all the
facts.
If they don't have all the facts,
they're going to look like a
dummy.
And you are the same way.
If you don't have all the facts,
it's not going to look good.
It's not going to be a good VSL.
Okay.
So if you want a systematic
process for creation that you can
use, you need to transform the
chaos that's going on in your head
into order.
Okay.
So you having these ideas of like,
well, the client thinks this, and
they also think this.
And on top of that, they also
believe in this.
And this is their main problem.
It's all up here.
Right.
That's chaos.
It's not like organized in any
way, shape or form.
And I'll ask people specific
questions about their offer and
they just elaborate on it.
And I'm like, do you have this
written down anywhere?
No.
Okay.
That's a problem.
So the creative brief is the first
step before we write a VSL, before
we write a script, before we
produce the VSL, before we put it
on our landing page, we need to
have a creative brief.
Okay.
And guys, if you've ever struggled
to write, meaning that you're
going to probably in some way,
shape or form, some of you are
going to tell me, oh, I'm really
struggling to come up with the
right VSL script.
Like I don't know what to write
here.
Guys, lazy writing is really just
lazy research.
Okay.
If you want to be able to write
effortlessly for this, you need to
do a good amount of research.
Okay.
That's how you come up with a good
offer for a market.
You're not just going to spin it
up and it just happens.
It comes on the back end of a good
amount of research.
Okay.
So the unfair advantage that
everyone is looking for is on the
other side of intense research.
Okay.
So guys, if you want to be able to
make it really easy for you to
write a banger VSL script, very
simply, just do a good amount of
research, understand your market
inside and out, and it'll be
really easy for you to be able to
craft a banger VSL script.
Okay.
So let's keep moving on.
So here's some advice for you
putting together a VSL script and
specifically the creative brief
for your VSL script.
You should put a lot of time into
the creative brief.
Okay.
I've been telling you guys that it
is probably about a day or two
that you can spend on a VSL.
60% of the time should be on the
creative brief.
It's not hard.
It's, it's, it's, it's not hard to
put together a VSL.
It's getting all the information
and getting all the facts
straight.
That is hard.
And you have to actually put
effort and time into accumulating
those facts and that information.
It may come from client research
calls.
If you have previous clients, you
can call and talk to, it may come
from doing market research and it
may come from reverse engineering
other people's offers.
Right.
And seeing what's wrong with their
stuff and what are they doing?
How can I do it differently?
And so on and so forth.
Right.
So guys, this is going to be where
you spend the majority of your
time doing the research.
It should not be spent on writing
and it should not be spent on
production.
Those are all very simple,
especially with the fact that
we're writing a five to 10 minute
script.
Like guys, 40% of your time should
be spent on the actual creation of
the thing on writing and on actual
production.
60% of your time should be spent
on research.
Okay.
So the more time you do put in,
the better results you're going to
see.
Okay.
But you don't want to put in so
much time into it that you never
take action.
Okay.
I've seen people spend like a
month plus on a creative brief and
it's just, that's so dumb.
Don't do that.
Get it done.
You should block this out for the
next day or two.
This should be the only things
that you focus on is getting a
creative brief and a VSL script
written.
You can even produce after that,
but I would, I would highly
recommend doing that.
Okay.
Set a deadline.
This thing can take forever to
complete if you let it.
And so we don't want to let it
take forever.
What is that?
Parkinson's law.
Usually it's like the amount of
time that we allow something to
take up is usually how long it'll
take.
Set a deadline one day, two days,
something like that.
Okay.
So how do you build a creative
brief?
That's a great question.
There are going to be templates
down below or wherever the
resources section is for this.
I just hand everything off to
Andre and he handles everything
else, but there's going to be some
templates where I'll show you
actually how to do the creative
brief.
Okay.
And I'm also going to have a demo
video where I show you how to
write it.
I'm going to go through and I'm
going to do one with you.
Like I said, I'm going to do one
with you so you can see this is
plausible for you to do it in one
day.
Okay.
So that's what I'm going to do
with you in the demo video.
And then also you guys are going
to get templates for it.
So that is everything that you
need to know.
Okay.
Guys, creative brief is the first
step.
Do not skip this step.
Get this organized.
Get all your facts straight.
It's going to be a lot easier for
you to then move into the next
stage, which is actually writing
the VSL script when you have all
of your facts and all of your
information straight.
So let's go ahead and let's dive
into the actual demo and producing
the creative brief.
And then from there, we'll dive
into actually writing the VSL
script.
So that's everything, guys.
All the best.
Bye now.