All righty ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls here we are doing a
creative brief together so
here's what i'm going to instruct
you to do take your phone get it
out put it on do not disturb
don't be distracted so we're going
to take this turn this off okay
and as you can see i am here
in a locked office well actually
you can't see that at all um but
no one's distracting me and
that's how i'm going to be able to
get this done in one go um versus
you know it taking three days a
week two weeks so on and so forth
so let's get started let's do a
brief overview of the creative
brief you're going to have a
template um for this but let me
just go through it real quick so
we got
some questions which is just
questions about your service about
your avatar everything like that
and
i'm giving credit where it's due
this is actually from taylor welch
um one of his programs obviously
these are fairly you know generic
questions but i didn't want it to
be like you know i just jacked
it from him without giving credit
so i put taylor's little book here
as an exchange for saying thank
you for giving me these questions
so great book for you to go and
buy the wealthy consultant you
can't
see me right there but yeah the
wealthy consultant great book i
like it i'm just going to put that
in
there no affiliate link nothing
like that just a good book okay so
that's saying thank you to taylor
for
providing these questions in a
worksheet that i did with him so i
like these questions we'll go
through these and answer these
questions but you're going to
answer these questions which will
give you
a good understanding of the rest
of the questions okay so now we
have the actual brief itself so
what
you're going to do is you're going
to you know expand on the promise
that you have for your service
what is the problem that you solve
let's list out all the possible
problems they're going to
encounter what's the desired
situation of your prospect what is
the gap how do you bridge it okay
so
what's the difference between the
problem and the desired situation
okay how do we take them from
problem to desired situation you
know what is the difference
between them being there and then
how
do we bridge it okay that's
usually your solution okay usp and
usp details what is your unique
selling
proposition how are you different
from everyone else out there and
what are the details what are the
details which gets you there what
are some reasons i should believe
you it doesn't necessarily need to
be
just case studies and testimonials
those are very useful but we could
just use for instance statistics
data stuff like that okay the
product tell me more about the
product how would you explain the
product
how would you pitch the product to
me sales argument why should
someone buy from you what is the
sales
argument this is going to be like
your first piece of copy this will
usually translate directly over to
your vsl and then customer
verticals who can you use this
with you know for some of you guys
it may
just be you have one customer
vertical for others it may be they
have four or five and then
potential
questions what are some potential
questions we could ask our
prospects which would elicit them
to think
about our service okay so let's
get started and let's just dive
right in so describe your client's
current
situation so guys i am writing for
my offer i called it inbox
intimacy i have the domain and
everything
like that for it and essentially
what i am doing is just to you
know i i very rarely sell this
offer
i want to give you guys an uh open
uh example where we can actually
do this together um and you can
see
how to do it i am so like
reluctant to offer this to people
um i have a very high level of
friction with
anyone i work with because i
primarily do like one-on-ones with
people and i prefer that versus
done for you but if the person's a
perfect fit for my done for you
services that i'm like hell yeah i
would love to be able to you know
explain that to that person so or
actually sell this to that person
so here's the thing guys you can
go and you can write all this
stuff yourself right and do it
manually
here's what i think would be best
okay we're gonna go up here and go
to a little tool you may have
heard of called chat.openai this
is going to make everything way
faster okay so what you want to
do is you want to get this tool
right here okay this is called
voice in you can go to the google
chrome
web store and you can download
voice in and pin it up here so you
have it just like i do
and you can see the first question
is describing your client's
current situation okay so what i'm
going to do is i'm going to
describe the clearance the
client's current situation
my ideal client is an info product
business owner who sells courses
and coaching services
and is doing a minimum of 100 to
200 grand a month they are running
paid ads to acquire customers
and as a result they are
collecting leads which they then
follow up with through setters and
the
setters set appointments for the
closers who close the deals
their service or product ranges
from five thousand to twenty five
thousand dollars
and they primarily use a vsl book
a call funnel along with ascension
funnels
to get people on sales calls
since they are accumulating leads
from their advertising efforts
they have a large list of emails
these are people who expressed
interest in the product or service
but did not book a call or booked
a call but were not ready to buy
yet
so the reason why i'm not talking
to you during that is because
it'll pick it up on that
so here's a pretty good summary of
this person's business okay and
i'm explaining their current
situation right who is my ideal
client avatar it's not going to be
someone that has
email marketing down pat it's
going to be that they're not doing
everything they could
with their email list and or
they're having to do everything
themselves they know that there's
a lot of power in their email list
they know there's a lot of money
to be made there and
it's a great nurturing mechanism
however they just don't have the
time to do it okay
so i'm just going to go back and
explain that real quick to them to
chat hippie team
i'm just going to edit some things
here right 200k month they're
running paid ads to acquire
customers
as a result they're collecting
leads and which they then follow
up with through setters and the
setter set appointments phone
setters and the setter set
appointments for the closers who
close the
deals their service or product
ranges products services or
products range from five thousand
to twenty
five thousand dollars right and
they primarily use a vsl uh book a
call funnel along with ascension
funnels low ticket ebook courses
to get people on sales calls since
they're chameleon leads from their
advertising efforts they have a
large list of emails these are
people who express interest in the
product
or service but did not book a call
or booked a call okay the offer
owner knows that they can extract
more revenue and more book calls
from their email list however they
are either having to write the
emails
themselves which is more on their
plate than they would like to deal
with comma or they ignore the
emails
entirely and as a result miss out
on the potential opportunity to
extract as much revenue as
possible
they've hired copywriters in the
past but the copywriter was never
able to hit the voice of the
business owner
and always produced spammy
emails which sounded like a
copywriter wrote them
the emails were entirely based on
pitching the product and the
business owner more than likely
saw
a drop in results after an initial
spike from trying to recover dead
leads that were on the list
the reason that drop off happened
is because they milked the list
dry and as a result nobody
very few people
remain on the list who want to buy
comma and a majority of people
stopped reading the emails because
there was
no value in them
the business owner the business
owner would like to pour more
value into their email list as
they know
that it is a amazing tool for
nurture
however they don't have the time
for it and they don't have the
trust in hiring someone else
because they feel like it is only
going to ruin their brand
reputation
okay so notice how specific this
is okay this is very very specific
that's because i'm selling this to
a very specific person like i said
earlier i don't want to sell this
to everyone this is not for
everyone i don't want to sell this
to the guy who's perfectly cool
with pitching every single email
that's not my client it's not my
customer it's not the person i'm
going to enjoy working with all
that
much i want to work with people
who enjoy providing value to their
audience and so
what i'm going to do is i'm going
to send this to chat gpt and then
it's going to say okay and it's
going to go do whatever and so now
i can go and take these questions
and feed it to it yes yes yes
so now i can go describe my
client's current situation and
then make sure to speak from the
first person perspective okay
so here we can see it's now
speaking from the first person
perspective it's like
the person actually saying hey
here's what my problems are so we
can put this in a quote
i use a mix of marketing
strategies including the vsl book
calls and essential photos from
lower
ticket items like ebooks and
courses this approach effectively
gathered is a large email list of
potential customers who've shown
interest but haven't committed to
a call or purchase my challenge
lies in maximizing the potential
this email list i'm aware of its
value and generating more revenue
and booking calls but managing
effectively has been a struggle
writing emails myself adds to my
already full plate and ignoring
the list leads to missed
opportunities my past
experience of the copywriters
haven't been fruitful their
content often felt inauthentic and
overly
sales focused not truly capturing
my brand's voice this approach
initially spiked interest in
recovering dead leads but
eventually led to a drop in
engagement as the content didn't
offer real value
to my audience i understand the
importance of nurturing my email
list with valuable content but
time constraints and concerns
about maintaining my brand's
integrity make me hesitant to
delegate this
crucial task i'm looking for a
solution that aligns with my brand
voice engages my audience
meaningfully and effectively
leverages my email list to enhance
my engagement and revenue without
compromising the authenticity and
reputation of my brand boom how
solid is that right and so now i
can go back
and so what i'm going to do
i know that's annoying right
hey come on don't be difficult now
right there we go so that's as if
that person was going to say that
so i could do that exact same
thing with any offer just describe
what that person is going through
well nick i
don't understand what that person
is going through hey okay solid
do another chat for you let's say
you're a lead gen offer
i am trying to do lead gen for sas
companies that provide demos for
their customers and sell
a software that is around two
thousand dollars for the year and
primarily help sales teams
optimize their sales process and
provide a better follow-up
experience for their clients
so i don't really know a whole lot
about this audience i would like
to conduct research on them
could you help me better
understand this prospect and what
their current situation is
so i don't even know what the heck
this is it looks like it's
browsing i don't even have
like a browsing plugin this looks
like it's a brand new feature from
gpt which is kind of cool
but regardless guys what i'm
trying to show you right here is
that if you don't understand
your audience all that well number
one you need to go do more
research you can do that with chat
gpt
but this is how you do your
research you either use chat gpt
and look it's like literally
searching
the web right now which is crazy
so understand the prospects and
current situation of sas companies
that provide sales it's important
to consider several key aspects
right strategic trial periods
many sas providers offer free
trial periods as part of their
sales process which vary in length
depending on the complexity of the
product and the target consumer
base right cool effective
communication demos maintain
regular communication with
prospects during the trial period
is
crucial demo should be valuable
understand the target audience so
on and so forth
if you had to explain from the
first person perspective what is
the primary problem that this
customer is dealing with comma and
use emotional and visceral
language to explain
their situation comma what would
you say
pressure of turning free users
into committed paying customers
it's a high stakes game teetering
on a razor's edge between success
and failure every day i grapple
with the challenge of aligning our
sales and marketing teams
constantly battling against a sea
of competition that seems to grow
more
formidable by the hour the
complexity of our product adds a
leather layer of difficulty making
it harder
to convey its value distinctly
right it's a relentless pursuit
blah blah blah blah blah now i
want you
i want you to assume this identity
as this sas business owner
and i am going to interview you to
better understand you
understood what are some solutions
that you've tried thus far to book
more free
trials for your service
what worked and what didn't work
see so now we can just keep
interrogating it be creative guys
talk with it like literally treat
this like someone if you don't
have access to the business owner
now you can see look for instance
a seven-day trial for simpler
offerings and up to 30 days for
more complex enterprise level
solutions
flexibility allows potential
customers to fully experience the
benefits of our software we'll
also focus on
enhancing our demo experiences
instead of overwhelming prospects
with information blah blah blah
blah blah
i could go to youtube i could go
to reddit i could go to google i
could find all types of things
that
people talking about it do your
research so you can be able to
explain it the way i'm explaining
it here
in mind so let's keep going now i
just want to show you a real quick
example of how you can do that
just with if like you don't even
know the prospect you can do a ton
of research with chat gpt
i'm gonna crack my neck real quick
sorry guys i know it's weird but
we always think that's odd i'm
like you know i could just adjust
myself real quick
all right so what is the cost of
them staying where they are so now
what is the cost of them
staying where they are financially
emotionally time etc stay in their
current situation without
effectively leveraging the email
list as several costs for the
financial owner or the info
product
business owner and financial costs
the most direct impact is
financial the underutilized email
list
represents a significant loss
revenue opportunity considering
the business's current revenue
scale
even a small percentage increase
in conversion rates from this list
could translate into substantial
income additionally the money
spent on generating those leads is
not fully capitalized upon
affecting the
overall return on investment from
their marketing efforts right
opportunity cost emotional cost
time cost brand reputation
customer relationship cost loss of
competitive edge so on and so
forth right
boom let's not make this the same
as everything else let's make this
bold and not bold okay so now i
have
that okay now what is the number
one most important thing they want
to accomplish in their life or
business if your client is more
b2b okay so if it's their business
what's the most thing i mean
pretty much all you
you guys are going to be b2b so in
their business okay about 17
minutes right now so let's keep
going
so i'm saying hey it wants to you
know effectively leverage their
email list increase revenues goal
encompasses converting leads into
paying customers entering
relationships so on and so forth
right that's
not that doesn't really sound like
it right sometimes it's going to
give you answers like that's not
really
it so what i'm going to say to it
is i want you to think bigger
picture i don't think anyone is
waking up in the morning and
saying hey i want to effectively
leverage my email list
what do they really want from
their business
okay and keep going
give it a sec
beyond the medical tactical goals
the info product business owners
ultimate aspiration is likely to
scale
their business what a shocker and
establish themselves as a leading
authority in their niche the big
picture goal
encompasses several aspects
scaling the business right they
aim to grow their business
substantially not
just in terms of revenue but also
in reaching impact this includes
expanding their customer base
increasing the value build a
stronger respected brand so on and
so forth create lasting impact
right achieving financial freedom
and stability legacy and influence
but you realize i'm saying the
number one
one most important thing so out of
all of these things what is the
number one most important thing
so i'm going to say
just that we don't need everything
else okay so you know this is
great but i actually like this
it's
saying everything else you know
hey here's what it's going to do
so boom come back over here
so on and so forth and we can go
and we can turn this into a list
you can do that as well with this
one
boom yeah we'll come back and
we'll fix that we'll pause it so
you guys don't have to sit here
and
watch me format it okay so what
are the three to five necessary
steps you'll walk them through
that
we'll get them to their finish
line so this isn't something i'm
going to ask chat gpt right this
is
my own thing so i'm going to go
and i'm going to explain it to
them let me explain to you the way
that i get my clients results
following the inbox intimacy
method first and foremost what i
do is i go
through the material that they
teach so i can better understand
them and i also go through
podcasts
they've been on interviews they've
been on so i can understand the
avatar then what we do is we get
on
a guru
the next step is getting on a
personalized interview with the
guru where i ask them questions
based on
the curriculum they teach and
other material that i have
obtained from their podcasts
when we first start working
together we will do one call every
two weeks
and eventually as we move on it
will turn into one call per month
just to be able to serve as fuel
for
the content after i'm able to
obtain the person's information
from their interviews that i
conduct with them
comma i'm going to transcribe
those interviews and then turn
those interviews into email copy
which will serve as newsletters
we will send out three value based
emails which are derived from
the guru's mouth directly and
their words directly so it sounds
like them
and then once a week we will pitch
our services
our services or product to the
newsletter
we will do this for
on a weekly basis and at the end
of every single month we will
check in on the metrics of the
email list health
and on top of that also overall
revenue comma number of book calls
comma etc etc
right so here we go and so this
basically breaks down the
step-by-step basis and so i can do
that right here
so it's doing hey personalized
interviews right transcription
transformation email campaign
structure
okay regular monitoring adjustment
at the end of each month you
review key metrics such as list
health
okay appears highly effective
you're damn right
you're damn right chat gpt all
right so let's do this
all right let's take this back
here
bow bow no bold boom
yeah okay we'll come back and
we'll fix that later
in one sentence right
describe what i do for my clients
in a way that makes sense
boom boom isn't that great look at
how look at how little
i have to work right now oh nick
this is gonna take so long no it's
not just leverage chat gpt guys
like
now here's another thing what you
also could do is you could just
record yourself going through all
this
stuff transcribe it feed that
transcription to chat gpt and be
like answer these questions
if you're not getting the inputs
that you like from chat gpt um you
know it could be very specific
offer that's super niche and like
chat gpt doesn't have insight on
it just record an audio message on
that
okay so let's go back and let's do
this again
what sacred cows do i kill um do i
stand against
right and so now it's going to go
into this it's going to explain it
again
generic outsource content you
stand against the common practice
of using generic outsource content
lacks the authentic voice over
reliance on sales pitches unlike
standard practices that heavily
focus on sales pitches
you balance one size fits all
that's damn straight short-term
tactics over long-term
relationships you're
damn straight that's right uh yeah
by the way guys look at how icy
crispy that that merch is right
now
you should definitely go to the
client ascension events so you can
get more merch okay so
let's go let's go here
up there we go
right there we go okay what oh
what do you believe to be my
single most competitive advantages
right and let's just ask it
oh i realized i just moved the obs
screen there we go okay
how great is that
now the only reason why i'm
getting such good outputs is why
do you think that is guys
because the inputs are really good
look at what the input started
with
a very in-depth explanation of my
avatar and showing them what the
issue is and then as well
when we got to explaining the
service
i just gave it to them like that
right and now it understands my
service the thing is the reason i
can
explain it so well is because i've
done it and i've been doing it for
a while and i've done it for a lot
of clients so i really understand
it so guys this will be a little
bit easier if you're a little
bit further ahead in your journey
it'll be a lot more difficult if
you're just starting out right
because you got to figure things
out but don't let that stray you
from you know figuring things out
you'll figure it out because
you're smart and you're inclined
ascension you can ask me on calls
and we'll do this together all
right
pow pow pow pow pow look how good
that is peace of mind pride and
authentic communication reduce
stress and overwhelm increase
confidence in their marketing
strategy satisfaction from
enhanced
customer relationships you'll
defeat the globalists no just
kidding empowerment from improved
business
results right sanctification
through jesus christ all these
things are amazing right so let's
go ahead
how sick would that be yeah i
sanctification as a service
the og sass
oh god that was pretty good jesus
was the og sass avatar oh that's
so good okay i'll go back and
format it
later like i said okay now what is
it about my program slash service
that distinguishes me from my
competitors okay wow i'm just i i
don't even have to change your to
why
right in-depth personal interviews
customized content creation
authenticity and messaging which
is often diluted
balanced approach to value in
sales ongoing adaptation
optimization okay building
long-term relationships
this is fantastic
okay so look at that isn't that
great i just went ahead and that's
perfect uh wait i don't get
why this is the dumbest thing oh
no no there we go okay there you
go sometimes google docs will do
it
where like you just can't yeah
like this this is so dumb i think
it's gonna do it right now yeah
like what
this is in no way shape or form
connected to go like a separate
line and then i go and i say this
is centered
and then if i want to now if i
want to do it though is it going
to do it again please don't
okay google docs whatever guys so
look at that got all those
questions done and now it's a lot
easier
for me to go and now that i have
this literally loaded into chat
gpt i can just now ask
what is a core promise that i can
offer to clients which will
generate and spark interest in
them working with me
okay see you guys can't see the
chat box down below like if i you
know you can see that right
there but don't worry about that i
want you to be able to see kind of
like right here there we go
that's probably better
i guess you guys don't really need
to see the the url tab
a core promise that would generate
and sparking it could be
transferring you into a powerful
tool
for genuine connection increased
revenue with our inbox intimacy
method ensuring every message
authentically represents your
voice and expertise deepens
customer relationships and drives
tangible
business results the promise
encapsulates the essence of your
personalized approach emphasizing
authenticity connection and
effectiveness which are key
factors that set your service okay
so i like this
that's pretty damn good i don't
have to like come up with some
crazy guys people think that they
need
to like i need to like come up
with some like guys when the
mechanism is good like my
mechanism is
unique that's not what a lot of
people do everyone else is just
pitch pitch pitch pitch pitch when
the
mechanism is good guess what the
promise is going to be good
everything is going to be good
because
the mechanism is what makes
everything different so your
mechanism is your unique
differentiator and
that's my inbox intimacy method
now if you're like hey i'm
struggling to figure out my
mechanism we can talk about it on
your calls with me daniel as well
will be a great resource for you
leo as
well will be a great resource for
you all of us understand this
stuff pretty well so it's not hard
for us to be able to come up with
something for you now i'll go and
i'll say i want you to describe
the problem the business owner is
dealing with in depth
in a way that will establish
preeminence meaning they will read
this description and it will
explain
their problem better than they
could explain it themselves
and i'll give you guys a link to
this as well so you guys can just
take these questions and copy
paste
it but as a successful business
owner in the infoparker you're
grappling with a complex challenge
it's often overlooked and much
understood by many in your
position you build a substantial
business
generating significant revenue
through courses and coaching
services skillfully leveraging
paid
advertising to create a robust
pipeline of leads i'm going to
pause this real quick guys because
i need to take off
this hoodie it's so hot here we go
look at that you're like oh nick
you can take off your hoodie
and you're not going to have klein
ascension merch on
what it do rip the set gotta rep
the set klein ascension set.com
forward slash nick promo code
buy again paying full for the year
okay so i also realized the
headphones weren't connected to my
laptop
they were connected to my phone
but they're cozy because they're
um that's a word for it noise
canceling
so let's keep going so as a
successful business owner and info
product
revenue through courses and
coaching services and however the
true potential of your email is a
collection of leads and interest
is much more than a potential
database it's a goal
mine of potential conversions and
long-term customer relationships
that's not being like
i know you've got it going on one
hand managing this host to
yourself as an overall burden to
your
already full plate on the other
hand your previous attempts the
delegate have led to a discipline
resulting of the lacked
authenticity felt overly salesy
and failed to resonate with your
audience
ultimately causing a decline and
engagement and possibly even
harming your brain's attention
fantastic this problem is deeper
than just an effective email
marketing it's a strategic gap
that's costing you not just in
immediate revenue but in long-term
growth and customer loyalty the
emails sent out under your brand's
name should be a direct reflection
of your expertise and values
but finding someone who can
accurately capture and convey your
unique voice and insights has been
a
formidable challenge the content
needs a circuit about the local
knowledge right the
underperformances and just lost
revenue it's missed opportunity
for building lasting
relationships with your audience
these relationships are the
bedrock
right in essence your challenge is
not just about sending emails but
effectively communicating your
unique value yep all right cool
good solid notice how i'm not
again i'm not having to do like
everything myself why because the
inputs are good when the inputs
are good when the inputs are good
this is a lot easier when the
inputs are bad it's a lot harder
when you give little to no context
or you
don't have a unique service and
you don't have a good product this
is a lot harder when you do it's
very easy to
produce something that's very good
now i want you to produce a list
of 25 problems this avatar is
experiencing
i want these to be in depth and
again establish preeminence
okay under utilization of email
this is going to take a second so
i'm just going to hit pause
so you guys don't just got to
watch this get generated okay here
we go so there we go we got
25 problems all these are pretty
good i was reading them as they
came out pretty damn good so i'm
just
gonna actually just copy and paste
this right here gosh darn i keep
forgetting about that
all right there we go um i don't
like when it does the bold though
now i have to go and it's like
anytime it does this just replace
all just get rid of that so now we
got the desired situation
now what i want you to do is
explain the prospect's ideal
situation comma exactly what they
want and again i want
you to establish preeminence here
by explaining it better than they
could explain it themselves
period go in depth on every detail
comma and really establish an
understanding of their ideal
situation
through descriptive language and
emotions as well
let's see what's going to pop up
your ideal clients envision
situation is a harmonious blend
of strategic success personal
fulfillment and a profound sense
of achievement in their business
here's an okay let's give this a
little pause real quick quite okay
so you can yeah no that's going
fast here's an in-depth
exploration of this vision right
optimization optimal utilization
of the email
list they dream of transforming
their extensive okay let's pause
this because it's kind of slow
okay so continuing on here we got
12 different points here i like
all these the only one that i was
like i don't really think they
care about this is like they
utilize the latest in marketing
technology
and automation with ease making
their email marketing both cutting
edge and effortlessly efficient i
don't think
like i think they just don't want
to have to handle it at all um and
then like also data decision data
driven decision making like
they're already doing that so
there's just no need to have those
so what i'll do
is i'll take this oh wait i need
this whole thing
all right and i'll go to desired
situation oh let's not make the
same mistake 15 times in a row
nick there
we go no there we go so let's get
rid of data decision driven and
then technological mastery because
sometimes it's not going to give
you everything you ran right so
there we go all right that's
their desired situation
and now what i can do as well
let's put this right here
oh nope nope same close right and
so also what i can do here what is
the gap was how did they bridge it
what i want to do is diary entry
of working with me you can say
diaries kind of kind of gay right
so
journal entry okay so i can say
that now i want you to write a
first person perspective journal
entry
of them experiencing the benefits
of working with me after six
months and the transformation it
has
created for their business
okay so six months ago i embarked
on a journey with nick and today i
can completely say it has been
transformative for both me and my
business it feels like i'm living
a dream where my vision and
aspirations are turning to reality
every morning i wake up to a inbox
buzzing with positive responses
to our emails the way nick has
captured my voice and expertise in
these emails nothing short of
magical they're not just words on
a screen they resonate deeply with
my audience creating a bond that
feels both personal and profound
the time-saving aspect has been a
game-changer delegating my email
marketing and nick has freed up so
much of my schedule i'm no longer
bogged down by the nitty
greedy of crafting and sending out
emails the extra time has allowed
me to focus on scaling my
business and exploring new
creative avenues our email list
wants a neglected asset is now a
thriving
community blah blah finally the
impact is undeniable revenue from
email marketing has significantly
increased i've seen a remarkable
return on investment the
strategies nick implemented have
not only
boosted sales but also enhanced
the overall value of our brand but
it's not just about the financial
gains the emotional satisfaction i
get from knowing that we are
genuinely helping and connecting
with
our audience is priceless our
emails are now eagerly anticipated
and the feedback we receive is
overwhelmingly positive the
monthly check-ins with nick are
always enlightening reviewing our
metrics and strategizing for the
future has become an exercise i
look forward to
it's incredible to see how our
efforts are translating into
tangible results perhaps
the most profound transformation
has been how i view my business
with nick's help we've cultivated
an
authentic voice that echoes
through every email the
authenticity has not only
attracted more clients
but also has invigorated my entire
team we're not just running
business we're leading a community
in retrospect than the decision
right boom
love that that's great so like
guys the reason why you watch
again you guys are probably
laughing at
those um the reason why we're
doing this is so we can have an
extreme understanding of our
prospect
to the point where when we sit
down to write the vsl script it's
so easy to write it right because
it's like it all this stuff right
when you have an overwhelming
amount of information it's easy
for you to write that
so let's go and take this what is
the gap how do they bridge it
let's keep going
lies in the disconnect between
their current email marketing and
the potential of what their email
could achieve despite having a
substantial email list and
significant resources they
struggle to
create authentic blah blah how
they bridge it embracing strategic
content creation regular
communication and refinement
perfect data-driven optimization
correct nicholas verge
building trust and relationships
leveraging expertise solid all
good in summary they bridge the
gap by
being awesome okay
so
oh my god i think i'm gonna make
this perpetually for the rest of
my life
i don't need to do the bold okay
i'm sorry guys i'm sorry you're
having to sit through this this
suffering okay so usp and usp
details okay so i can go here
i would like for you to provide me
with
transforming your email list into
a goldmine of authentic engagement
and revenue growth with the
personalized touch of the inbox
into amazing method i like
transform not transforming
um so my one thing is it's saying
your service i could obviously
just go back and edit this so
i'm gonna do that so let's go and
let's take this come on come on
come on come on come on come on
come on
finish holy shit it's taking
forever we're almost done guys
come on all right
okay
okay boom i'm not gonna do it
again i'm not gonna do it again 12
unbold it let's go okay
okay reasons to believe
well let's start here reason
number one
daniel case study so i recorded a
case study with daniel and that
case study is basically just me
interviewing him we've made nine
hundred and thirty thousand
dollars from the email list and
starting
about 11 months ago 11 months 930
000 that is about a what is that
divided by 11 close to 90 000 it's
not exactly that um but 90 grand a
month from that so let's just say
it's that's 10 it's pretty close
that's like 80 whatever seven or
something like that okay so let's
just say 90 000 a month and
daniel's
investment with me like that was
just a ridiculous roi for him he
made a ton on it so just makes
sense
right so number one is gonna be
daniel's case study but
i want you to provide statistics
facts insights
and other metrics
to provide reasons someone should
believe
my methodology
and that this solution will fix
their problem
provide me with
20 reasons
okay so notice how i ask these
questions guys as well like i can
just ask it anything
and then it'll do it now this is
cool i haven't again i haven't
seen this before
this is my first time seeing this
where it just now browses for me
whenever i ask a question so
that's
awesome so let me go ahead and
pause this while this loads all
right so here's where we need to
like
pick and choose right because
there's gonna be some bad ones
there's gonna be some good ones
so growing email usage 4 billion
daily email users number expect to
rise to 4.6 billion
eh right like i mean you could say
did you know there's 4 billion
people that use email right
there's
not 4 billion people on your
facebook ads whatever but i don't
really like that 64 of small
businesses
use email marketing to reach
customers that's not useful 37 of
brands are increasing their email
budget that's not useful um 72 of
the most effective email marketing
strategies involve
message personalization highly and
that's not useful um 62 of
businesses adapt adjust adjust the
frequency of emails based now 41.5
regard email marketing is critical
that's not useful as well
77 of marketers have observed an
increase in email engagement over
the last year okay that's not
bad um personalized email subject
lines that's not true well that's
not true it's just not useful
um ai email content creation this
is actually not bad right 95 of
marketers are using generative ai
for
email creation and here's the
thing is like you know if
everyone's using ai like people
can tell when
things are written by ai and it's
just garbage so could maybe use
that um i like this one this one's
good email marketing you know 81
and who is this that said this
hubspot solid 64 of b2b monology
effectiveness of their email
marketing strategy right sending
fewer than five news a week leads
to higher
open rates and click rate
suggesting that quality and
personalization trump quality
uh quantity personalization high
open rates for welcome emails
projective email marketing revenue
growth
i like this one email marketing
revenue is estimated to reach
almost 11 billion by the end of
showcasing it's a growing
importance that's not bad um
continued growth
yeah people think it's dying it's
not so let's go through and let's
go back to this let's just start
adding these in this one right
here from hubspot not bad
all right so why do i need these
well when you're in your vsl and
you're going to state a fact
don't you think it's useful to say
when by the way a study from
hubspot showed
fake because if you don't know
what that is we'll talk about it
when we get to the writing section
so uh continued growth being
increasingly adopted did i say
that already yeah um email
automation
certainly involving automation
okay cool so there's a couple that
are half decent right but it's not
a
crazy amount i just want to have a
couple of them just in my back
pocket okay so now we got features
and benefits okay so i want you to
give me the features and benefits
for this service
make sure to list out benefits for
each feature
okay so we got features and
benefits we then have a
description of the product itself
and then we have a sales argument
okay then we got customer
verticals and then we got
potential
questions okay and you guys were
thinking wow wait a minute we're
doing so much of this through chat
gpt
nick aren't you a copywriter yes i
am and here's the thing guys
anyone who's smart knows they
should
do chat gpt it's so much faster
imagine we had to write all this
out by hand this video would
already
be at an hour 40 probably be an
additional hour or even more and
we wouldn't even be where we're at
right
now it would be like up here at
this part right here we wouldn't
even be where we're at right now
and i'm getting way more volume
and you're going to see how we can
then plug this in to write a
really banger vsl script as well
so let's see what it says feature
in-depth personal benefit
ensures content and feature
customized email yep very real
strategy review yep data driven
insights
okay uh balance between value and
sales pitch yep specialization
high ticket yep ongoing client
engagement uh yep i guess yeah
that's true reduction in the
client workload correct
feature utilization of ai and
latest technologies eh not really
i don't really do it all that much
i
mean i do but like how's that like
why do they care at all right so
like i'll use it sometimes when
i'm hitting writer's block but i'm
not going to use it all the time
with client newsletters sometimes
i
literally just again sorry guys
sometimes i'm literally just like
on my phone in the sauna and
i just write all my emails for the
week it's super easy because i'm a
stud it's super easy for me okay
i'm great i think we already did
this didn't we maybe just repeated
it
i guess not so let's describe the
product now
did we already do this
huh i guess not okay so the
product i thought i repeated it
now what i want you to do is
explain the product to me as if
i'm a prospect for this service
i don't want you to do this in the
format of a listicle make these
paragraphs
there's some things that i just
wanted to be a paragraph because
then i can take that and put
that directly into my copy
perfect this is solid
okay boom
product i'm not going to do it
again
i'm going to fix it there we go
now
what are the possible objections
that someone would have to
utilizing this service
okay okay so i don't have a
section for this you could totally
include this in the
in the doc it's already getting
pretty long we're already at like
19 pages we're not even done yet
um but i'm going to do this
because a sales argument guys like
think about what an argument is
remember how i said this in the
previous module
like you're a lawyer and you have
all the facts right and you have
to prove to the jury that the
client is innocent right that's
your argument to the court now the
thing is is the jury already
has an opinion based on all the
facts they've accumulated so they
have objections as to why
that person's not innocent or why
that person's not guilty
or innocent or guilty or whatever
so here we go right so now what
i'm going to say
taking all these objections into
account i want you to craft
a useful and compelling comma and
persuasive sales argument to sell
someone on this service
i want you to imagine that you are
jordan belfort
one of the best sales people of
all time
and utilize his straight line
strategy
selling
to create this sales argument
the reason i said it that way is
sometimes it'll be like jordan
belford's a criminal
there you go
you
Yeah, this is solid as fuck.
And no one's going to care about
data privacy, right?
So how solid is that?
So now I have a sales argument.
It's pretty good.
And if you don't know, what's a
straight line selling is
essentially like, I'll just do
this real quick for you.
This is the best way to do this.
So it's essentially this, okay.
Here's a straight line.
Imagine that it's actually
straight.
And what we have up here is Pluto.
Right down here is Uranus.
Okay.
Oh, you can't see me here.
I'm over here now.
Okay.
So what we have is Pluto and
Uranus, right?
The prospect could sometimes go up
here, right?
And we want to always stay right
here.
This is the open and this is the
close.
Okay.
And so what happens is prospects
will go over here and my dog did
this and blah, blah, blah.
And then like, oh, like, you know,
my, my aunt Sally's from Alabama.
And then, oh, and what we have to
do is keep them on a straight
line.
And the way we do that is by
addressing all of their concerns,
understanding all their desires,
and then all the problems they
have currently and showing them
how our product not only solves
all their problems, meets all
their desires, but also handles
all their concerns.
And on top of that, everything
they've tried previously, I'm
going to put tried.
This is better in every single
way.
And so we're doing that through a
straight line.
And so that's what a straight line
methodology is, by the way, guys,
great stuff that you should
research on YouTube, by the way.
So let's get back to it.
I don't want to spend too long on
that.
So let's go and let's pull me over
here.
Let's take this, bring this down
to 12.
Okay.
Not the bold.
I don't really need customer
verticals.
You may need that section.
You may have several different
verticals that you work with.
And so as a result, you know, you
may be kind of like, Hey, uh, I
don't want to write this
for, you know, I have it for, it
works for SAS companies.
It works also for lead gen
agencies or marketing agencies or
whatever.
Um, I personally don't have that.
It's info product people.
So it's like, I don't need that
now.
This next question is really
useful.
Okay.
So remember how I said the IED
intro identifier?
I'm going to add a lot of
questions, empathy questions, and
then opportunity
questions.
So I can go through and explain
these three right here.
And so what I want to do is I want
to come back here and I'm going to
say,
I would like for you to provide me
with 10 questions for three
separate categories of questions.
The first is empathy.
Identifier questions, which are
intended to call out to the
audience to get them to raise
their hand and say, yes, I am this
person.
The next type of question is an
empathy based question.
This is intended to explain the
customer's problem.
Prospects.
and makes them want to learn more
about what I have to offer.
This is an opportunity based
question in a way that shows that
I understand their current
situation.
And the last type of question is
an opportunity based question.
This is a question that has a
direct benefit to the prospect.
And makes them want to learn more
about what I have to offer.
I would like for you to provide
again, 10 questions for each one
of these sections.
Okay.
So I like some of these, um, but
at the same time, I'd like for it
to be a little bit more robust.
So we'll go into that in a bit.
I would like for the identifier
questions to all say, are you an
info product business owner?
Are you an info product business
owner and then have the identifier
questions that you created for me
afterwards attached to them?
Okay.
So that's just a nuanced thing
right there.
So that's all pretty good.
So I'm going to pick the best one
and those will be in my VSL and
I'll decide that when I get there.
Oh, shit.
What the heck's going on here?
Oh, a lot of new features today
from GPT.
I've never seen this before
either.
I'm going to go with this one.
Let's pause this real quick while
we keep this going.
Okay.
So now I just wanted to give me
all of them.
Oh, shit.
There we go.
Let's get into that.
Wow.
Okay.
So we can see now we have, are you
all this, right?
So on and so forth.
Okay.
So I can now ask those questions
in my VSL.
And so here we go.
Let it keep going.
Boom.
There we go.
So we are going to now take all of
this and put it into our document.
Okay.
Opportunity based questions.
Thank you.
Okay.
So we'll take all that and put it
in our document.
And then guess what guys we're
done now.
So we have the creative brief
done.
We've got it done in approximately
one hour, about 59 minutes.
You know, I paused a couple of
times.
I never paused for more than like
a minute at a time.
And you guys saw me coming back
and right.
It's not like I'd be paused.
And then all of a sudden there's
like a huge block done.
Like it was like little things.
Like I just wanted to let chat to
BT load.
So you could see, you can get this
thing done in like an hour.
Do not let this thing take three
days.
And you can see clearly that it's
a lot easier for me to spend time
on this when I'm already
really understanding of my
audience and really understanding
of my offer.
If you don't know that yet, you
probably need to do more research
before you start here.
Now, remember what I said, guys,
that like 60% of your time, 50% of
your time
should be spent on this right
here.
Yeah.
Because now think about how easy
it is for us to go and write a
five to 10 minute video
with all of this in mind.
This is so easy.
So now what I can do.
Is I'm going to go back and take
this.
Control C.
Control.
Oh, shit.
I'm not going to make that mistake
again.
Boom.
And then I can go and do that.
Now, guys, I'm going to go and
format this a little bit just so
it's pretty for me.
Right.
I'd like for it to be able to be
easy to scan and read and
everything like that.
So I'm going to go and do that.
But outside of that, whatever,
it's going to take me 10 minutes.
I'll pause it real quick.
I'll just do that real quick.
Okay.
So we are so back.
So as you can see, I added these a
little like titles.
So if you want to do that in
Google docs, all you got to do is
highlight a piece of text
and then just take it right here.
Go to title.
Make it a title.
And then you'll have this.
I can go service brief, promise,
problem, problem list, so on and
so forth.
Right.
And it'll go through everything.
So I could do like bold in and
make it look pretty.
I don't really care right now,
though.
So that took me like a minute.
Not really that long.
So we now have our creative brief
done.
Cool.
I've done this before.
So I'm kind of like, yeah, I'm
good.
Like I can move on to it.
Um, you may want to spend more
time on this.
That's okay, guys.
I don't want to make this video
three, four hours long.
If you feel like you want to spend
more time on it and add more to
it, that's solid.
Just make sure that you remember
what I said.
Do not let this take three days.
Do not let this take four days.
Get this done in like a day or
two.
If you want to do four or five
hours on it, that's fine.
That's fine.
That's great.
You're going to get a lot of good
stuff out of it, but do not let it
take three, four days.
Okay.
So that's everything for today,
guys.
We're going to now move on to
writing.
Okay.
So now we're going to move on to
the next section, which is going
to be writing.
And I'm going to show you again,
really easy to get the writing
script done.
So let's go and let's dive right
into that.