Alrighty, here we are.
We're back again, talking about
how to create a Bangor VSL for
your B2B service offer.
So what we're going to do is talk
about exactly that.
But in today's module, we are
talking about how to write a VSL
script that speaks to your
prospects, desires and pain points
and incentivizes them to book a
call with you.
OK, so in order for us to do that,
in order for us to be able to get
them to book a call with you, we
need to speak to their desires.
What do they want?
And also address their pain
points.
OK, when we do this, we're doing a
little something called direct
response.
OK, so here's a quick overview of
direct response.
This is a very in-depth field, but
I'm going to give you an 80-20
course on it right now.
OK, so direct response marketing
is a style of marketing that
elicits a direct response to turn
attention into a specific outcome.
OK, it turns attention into a
specific outcome.
How do we get attention?
We speak to their desires and pain
points.
OK, how do we get a specific
outcome?
We ask for a direct response.
Super simple.
I know copywriters that have been
in this game for three years and,
like, never were able to piece
together why it's called direct
response.
And people that have known about
direct response but never thought
that the name itself implicitly
implies what it is.
So people think DR and direct
response means, like, spammy sales
letters, like those 60-page long
ones, like for old people where
they have dementia and it's like
selling them on some snake oil,
you know, bullshit supplement.
That's not the case, guys.
Companies have definitely used
direct response to do that, but
direct response is just a tool.
And a tool can be used in a lot of
different ways.
I can have a hammer that I can use
to hang a portrait on the wall for
my grandma, and I can have a
hammer that also can be used to
break someone's kneecap.
You can use it in many different
ways, a tool.
So everything you guys do in
regards to marketing a product or
a service should be direct
response.
Except for, like, branding and
content, pretty much everything
should be direct response.
Because it's the only way to truly
see if marketing was effective or
not.
Remember those ads that you would
see on TV for, like, a product?
It was, hey, Billy Mays here with
a fantastic new product.
If you guys are not from America,
you're not going to know what that
is.
But Americans, my fellow
Americans, you know what I'm
talking about, where there's
someone on TV.
It's Billy Mays.
He's yelling at you, telling him
about this, you know, amazing
product.
And there's a phone number on the
bottom.
And it's saying, call this right
now, and you're going to get this
free plus shipping exclusive
package.
And we're going to send you also
all these bonuses and everything
like that, you know, to call the
number to buy.
Okay?
We were probably too young, or
maybe you're older and you were
calling those numbers.
But, you know, you remember seeing
those commercials, right?
Here's what a lot of people don't
know.
On the different commercials, on
different channels, they would
change the phone numbers.
So, like, the golf channel would
get its own phone number.
The home network would get its own
phone number.
Nickelodeon would get its own
Why is that?
Because they wanted to track which
channel was getting the highest
level of response.
So, you need to do the same thing
as well.
Whenever you're testing something,
you need to be able to test
whether or not one form of a VSL
or another form of VSL or one
platform or another platform is
getting you better response.
Otherwise, here's something that
you should keep in mind is you're
going to be wasting your time if
you're not doing that.
So, perfect example of this, guys.
I have a free group and I was
looking at my revenue from my
offers that I sell and I looked at
it and 10% of my revenue came from
my free group.
But, like, 40% to 50% of my time
was being spent on my free group.
And so, I see that and I'm like,
okay, that's not good.
That implies that it's not like a
small sample size either.
It's been like a few months now.
And so, I'm like, okay, something
needs to change here because
either A, I need to make more
offers to my free group or
something's not right here.
So, that made me look at that and
go, hmm, it's not good.
I'm not getting the right amount
of response I want from there.
I am getting a really good
response, though, from talking
with people and getting on
networking calls and, like,
coaching people and offering stuff
to people's communities and stuff
like that.
So, it makes me think then, okay,
hey, I should do more of that and
less of the other thing.
See what I mean?
I should advertise more on
Nickelodeon and less on Golf
Channel.
See what I mean?
That's how to think about this
stuff, guys.
And so, when it comes to your VSL,
when you're just starting out, you
don't really need to think about
that all that much.
But you do need to be able to see,
hey, have I gotten any book calls
from this VSL?
If you've sent out a shit ton of
emails to it, and I mean, like, a
thousand plus, like, a ton of
people have, and I'm talking about
responses, not you sent out a
thousand emails, responses of
people wanting to see the VSL and
have actually gone to your
website.
You've gotten a thousand views and
nobody has booked a call,
something's up to your VSL, okay?
And so, you need to be able to
notice that.
So, we track these things.
Now, when you're first starting
out, just get one VSL up there,
and that's it.
If you're a bit more advanced,
maybe you have a little bit more
cushion on your revenue, you have
employees, you have time, it may
be worth your time to go and test
two different VSLs and split test
which one people are landing on so
you can see which form of
messaging appeals more with them.
If you're just starting out, don't
worry about that.
But, again, the reason why you
need to get good at direct
response and copywriting in
general is because you're
constantly going to be testing
like this.
You need to be able to think like
this so you can see, like I did
with my group, hey, this is not
right.
This is what I should be doing
instead.
That's why you need to understand
direct response.
Otherwise, you're wasting your
time.
Direct response principles to
follow.
I'm going to give you guys a
little master class right now.
Okay.
So, ladies and gentlemen, say it
with me.
Nobody cares about your shiny
shit.
Say it with me.
Come on.
You didn't say it.
Nobody cares about your shiny
shit.
Say it out loud.
Just say it right now by yourself.
Say it.
Nobody cares about your shiny
shit.
If you could write one principle
with the golden arches above you,
in your office, in your house,
above every door, on your bathroom
mirror, if you have an Expo
marker, go write this on your
mirror.
Nobody cares about your shiny
shit.
This one principle will increase
your marketing IQ by 60 points
minimum.
Guaranteed or you don't pay.
I'm just kidding.
But seriously, guys, nobody cares
about your shiny shit.
I see this all the time.
Copywriters, marketers, I offer
this and this and all these
amazing features and all this
stuff.
Nobody cares.
Nobody.
Nobody cares about your shiny
shit.
They care about the shit they got
going on.
They care about what is going on
in their world and their problems
and their desires.
They do not care about you at all.
Unless you're Dwayne the Rock
Johnson or Alex Hermosi or
Leonardo DiCaprio or like, I don't
know, David Goggins.
People don't care about you unless
you're a celebrity, which I have
not met a celebrity in client
ascension yet.
If David Goggins is watching this
right now, right on, brother.
But most of you guys are not in
client ascension as celebrities.
You're not doing that.
So if that's the case, I mean, can
you imagine a David Goggins
agency?
That'd be sick, right?
He's like, I'm going to show you
how to carry the boats guaranteed
or you don't pay.
Like, that's probably what's going
to happen.
But no, like we're not doing that.
Stop being silly for a sec.
Like, guys, you're not a
celebrity.
Think about that.
If you're not a celebrity, why the
fuck are you talking about
yourself and your stuff and your
features and your product and all
that stuff?
Now, this may come off as, you
know, something that you guys
haven't heard before.
And so you may be thinking, well,
how are people going to know how
to buy my product?
Great crop.
Great, great question.
Great question.
Amazing question.
I almost said that wrong.
Great question.
The only way you get them to care
about your product is by showing
that you understand their
situation better than they can
explain it themselves.
It's called preeminence.
If you can achieve that, you are
going to have it where they're
interested in finding out more
about your product.
You need to focus more on their
situation, on their shit, not your
shit, on their shit.
And that will make it a lot easier
for you to be able to talk about
your product and actually get a
response from it because they know
you understand their current
situation and their desires.
Make sense?
Make sense.
One more time, everybody.
Say it out loud.
Nobody cares about your shiny
shit.
Solid.
Okay.
Next.
You want to enter the conversation
going on in the prospect's head.
And the only way to find that is
with good research.
Okay.
So that's what I was talking about
with preeminence.
You being able to explain what's
going on in their business better
than they can explain it, that is
preeminence.
And that's what we want.
We want to have preeminence as
consultants and as agency owners.
We want to be able to have the
ability to explain our prospect's
problem better than they can ever
explain it themselves.
And the only way you find that is
with good research.
Good research is either going to
be from diving deep on the
internet.
I think ChatCPT is way better for
that.
And I'm going to be showing you
guys how to do that in the demo
videos.
One of the demo videos.
I'm not sure which one.
But then on top of that, also
talking to your prospects.
Literally getting on the phone and
talking with them.
If you don't have access to a lot
of your prospects just yet because
you're starting now, right, you
can just go and you can just do it
on ChatCPT and do research that
way.
However, if you have a previous
client roster, literally just, and
even an existing client roster,
just ask them, can we get on a
call real quick?
I just have a couple questions to
ask you.
And if any of your clients are
being difficult to, oh, no, I
don't want to get on the call or
whatever, like offer them
something.
But for the most part, all of them
are going to be cool.
Just say, I had a 50-minute call.
This won't take up a lot of your
time.
I just have a quick question for
you.
It'll be super useful for my
business.
Is that okay if we do that?
I cannot imagine any of your
clients are going to be like, no,
fuck you, like, right?
So don't worry about that.
Next one.
The best direct response is a
perfect blend of EQ and IQ.
So there's a specific guru whose
name shall not be named.
And he thought it was a genius
idea to go ahead and write a VSL
and a little doc, whatever, loom
doc, that had just disgusting
amount of math equations on it and
was all very high-level financial
math and everything like that.
And he thought that was a good
offer.
And a lot of people bought.
Why?
Because they're like, wow, look
how smart that guy is.
You know what ended up happening
that nobody talks about?
Like 80% of people refunded.
There was a very aggressive
guarantee on it.
He could not fulfill on it.
And like 80% of people refunded on
it.
And it was like, wow, people
bought because it was really
smart.
But here's the thing, guys, is
like, was it because of the offer
or was it because he was a notable
guru who'd been around for a
while, who'd already had a lot of
case studies?
And then he came up short on that,
which wasn't why they bought them
by because he came up short.
They bought because of his
previous track record.
And unfortunately, though, it
didn't matter.
So here's the thing, guys.
He went so heavy on the IQ scale
that there was a lot of people
like me that maybe would have
bought if he could actually
explain it in a way where I felt
that it explained my problems and
understood.
He understood my situation.
He didn't, though.
He just talked above me and said
how blah, blah, blah, math
equations and this big thing and
finance, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And so as a result, I felt really
dumb watching it.
And I was like, I have no idea
what the hell this guy's talking
about.
I just stopped watching it.
So you got to realize that good
DR, direct response, is EQ and IQ.
It's not just intelligence.
It's not just trying to make
yourself sound smart.
It's also showing that you
understand what the prospect is
going through.
You have empathy and you
understand from their shoes, their
perspective.
That's good direct response.
Someone should be able to watch
your VSL and be like, I was just
thinking that the other day.
That's good direct response.
Okay.
Next point.
Good marketing, good direct
response is about getting results.
You need to show people that you
can get results.
Again, guys, I'm just going to
shout this at the top of my lungs.
Nobody cares.
About your shiny shit.
Nobody, nobody cares.
Even with your results, case
studies, all that stuff.
Guys, here's the thing.
Someone's going to crucify me for
saying this.
I don't care.
This is the truth.
If you can explain someone's
problem better than they can
explain it themselves and you can
show them how you can get them
results, you don't need any case
studies.
You don't need them.
Will they help?
Absolutely.
Right?
But I've seen so many people
struggle.
They have 30 plus case studies and
they still struggle to get clients
because the case studies are not
what get clients.
They'll buy from you because they
have confidence that you can get
them a result.
The whole purpose of the whole
purpose of your VSL should be to
inspire the viewer to think I can
get that result with this person.
Okay?
So good marketing revolves around
results.
Okay?
Showing the person that you can
get them results.
They don't know.
No one's just throwing away money.
We're not in this fake money age
like post-COVID where everyone was
just throwing away this government
credits that who cares or just do
it, whatever.
People buy because they want a
specific ROI from you.
You need to show them I am going
to get you a specific ROI.
It may not always be that it's a
financial thing.
It may not be you give me a
dollar.
I'm going to give you $5 back with
like a lead gen offer.
Okay?
It could be that I create systems
in your business that then speed
up your workflow, which then allow
it to be, oh, shit, my camera's
moving.
One sec.
Then allow it for you to be able
to save way more time every single
week and make it much easier for
you to be able to focus on the
things that actually matter.
It could be saving time.
It could be that you're helping
them with their relationship.
Okay?
And you're going to help them not
have the issues in their
relationship.
I don't think those people are in
client ascension.
They're not.
Okay?
So probably not in that route.
Most of you guys are going to be
money for money.
And if not, it's going to be money
for like efficiency, money for
systems, money for productivity,
something like that.
Money for hiring, like being able
to find the right person, whatever
it is.
Okay?
So you need to show them that you
can get them that specific result.
That's what good marketing does.
Okay?
So understand this.
Good marketing is not just ego
stroking yourself and making sure
that you look good or you feel
smart or you look smart.
See the example I talked about
earlier.
He looked really smart.
And then what happened afterwards?
Everyone realized, I feel like I
just got hoodwinked and they did.
And he refunded a shit ton of
people and then disappeared off
the face of the earth.
So learn from his mistakes.
Okay.
Next point.
At all times, the prospect is
looking for a reason to leave.
You need to give them a reason to
stay.
So how do you do that?
Well, it's a little principle
called open loops.
So what if I did this?
What if I said, hey, dude, and
we're starting a conversation and
I told them, told you, I got a
gift for you that I wanted to give
you.
I want to tell you a story real
quick, but I want to give you this
gift as well.
Can I tell you the story first?
You're like, yes, tell me the
story.
And then I'm telling you the
What are the odds that you're
going to leave the conversation
when it's like, oh, wait, there's
this gift that he's going to give
me.
That's a very, very specific
example of it.
But an open loop is showing that
the person should stay and it
gives them a reason to stay.
And so really good VSLs have open
loops in them.
There's a specific benefit they're
looking for.
And so you should open a lot of
loops in your VSLs.
You should give them reasons to
stay.
Another way that you do this,
okay, is you don't take up too
much of their time.
Giving them a reason to stay, it
could be that it's just like a
five-minute video, right?
I've seen it where people do these
B2B videos and it's like 25
minutes long.
Guys, I want you to think about
your prospect for a second.
They're busy.
They probably have kids.
They probably have a wife.
They have a business.
They have employees, right?
They're running a, if you're
targeting the right types of
companies, they're running a big
company.
Do you think they have 25 minutes
in their day to listen to you
ramble on a loom?
No, they don't.
Respect their time.
Your video should not be more than
10 minutes long.
In fact, it should probably be
around five minutes long.
That's the goal.
Make it around five minutes.
And people will be like, oh man,
like how do I do that?
We're going to show you how to do
that.
But also, just keep that in mind
the entire time while you're
writing.
I can't make this go super long.
I want to make this inherently
simple and inherently
straightforward.
I'm going to show you how to do
that today.
Okay?
So, give them a reason to stay.
It could be through respecting
their time, making it short enough
that they have a reason to stay
throughout the whole time.
Open loops.
Visually appealing.
You can make the video visually
appealing with the right editing,
all type of stuff.
Okay?
So, last but not least, ladies and
gentlemen, direct response is an
extensive body of information.
This is not something that you
learn overnight.
I'm giving you guys some pretty
high-level principles here that
are pretty good for you to just
start with if you don't have any
experience at all.
And that's not enough though, your
entire career will be filled with
direct response related activities
because if you plan on selling
things, like a lot of you guys are
starting with offer A right now,
and eventually it'll move on to
offer B and it'll evolve into
offer C and offer D.
You can ask Daniel, Daniel's
produced damn near 20 to 30, I
think even maybe 40 different VSLs
for client Ascension.
Eventually your offer will evolve
and you will need to change the
VSL and you may change the
different style of offer and you
may have to change the
deliverables or whatever, and
you'll change the VSL.
You will always be doing direct
response in some way, shape or
form.
So, you are whatever your skillset
is, lead gen, e-commerce, graphic
design, video production, and a
direct response
copywriter/marketer.
You always have to be that way.
So, think like that and invest in
your education with the time that
it takes to learn this stuff.
Okay, so a great example of this
is going to be a reading list that
I provided for you guys.
This is some of the best work that
you can consume on direct response
by the legends.
Okay, I would highly recommend you
guys go to Kinko's spend 30 bucks
50 bucks and just print out
everything and get them in binders
and make this your curriculum.
Take it seriously guys.
This is this is like really
important stuff.
You know why?
Because it makes you money.
It makes you money.
The better you get at direct
response and copywriting and being
able to produce effective
messages, the better you're going
to be at making money with your
offer.
It's a one-to-one correlation.
Can't make it up.
So, those are some direct response
principles for you to follow.
Enjoy the reading list.
If you guys have any questions at
all, you can always message me.
The reading list is definitely,
definitely, definitely going to be
worth your time.
You need to be spending time on
educating yourself in this realm
so you can get better at it.
Okay, let's move on.
So, now, guys, it's time for us to
write.
Woo-hoo, super fun.
So, here's your biggest obstacle.
Hint, it's you.
Okay, I can already see it right
now.
People are going to be messaging
me.
I'm just struggling to write the
VSL script.
Oh, I hate that.
I'm going to send them to minute
1938 on this video.
Tell them to go watch this.
Guys, the reason you're struggling
with the ability to write is
because you're not researching
the right way, okay?
Guys, lazy writing is lazy
research.
If you did the right amount of
research with your creative brief,
it should be very easy
for you to write.
It should be extremely easy for
you to write.
You should have writing bursting
out of your ears and coming out of
your eyes.
You should be crying with words
that are going to sell your
product, okay?
If you haven't completed your
creative brief, this is going to
be really hard.
Go do that.
Otherwise, you're making it 10
times harder than it needs to be,
okay?
The whole point of the creative
brief is that you collect a shit
ton of research and information
that makes it easy for you to then
go and write.
When you don't have that and it's
all scatterbrained chaos in your
head, it's really hard for you
to then write.
When you have it organized, by the
time you finish that creative
brief, you should be able
to dive right into writing and be
like, oh, I already know what I
need to do.
And you go do that, right?
Another thing, some days, guys,
you're going to be in a total flow
state, right?
You're going to be writing your
best shit ever.
It's going to be so good.
Just sauce, just pouring out of
your fingertips, just sauce
everywhere.
Other days, you're going to be
about as creative as a sack of
potatoes, right?
Regardless, you still write on
both days, JFW, just blank, right?
Okay.
So if you're trying to get this
VSL done, just write, don't say, I
need everything to
be perfect.
I need the cosmos to align.
I need to write when Mercury is
not in retrograde and only when
it's a full moon and when my
numerology calendar, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
No, no, just write, okay?
You have me to critique your
stuff.
And on top of that, also, guys, is
you should be trying to get this
done in a short timeline.
Like I said, one to two days max,
and so you may go, I don't feel
really like just
write, just get done, okay?
You have me to support you.
And then on top of that, the whole
point is to just get the one done.
It will not be perfect.
If this is your first VSL, it
won't be perfect.
Just accept that.
It's okay.
Isn't that great?
Awesome.
So let's keep talking about
writing.
Here's some general writing
guidelines for you guys.
First and foremost, the
introduction for your VSL is by
far the most important part of the
script you're going to write.
Without a doubt, it's the most
important part.
If you don't nail the intro, guess
what?
You'll lose them early on, okay?
The introduction is the most
important part of the VSL, story
time.
So when I was working on a VSL for
an Amazon FBA offer, this guy was
converting at about 3%
and had about a $300 cost per book
call, writing a lot of ads.
So not something you guys are
going to be doing really.
A lot of you guys are going to be
doing cold emails, but $300 for a
cost per book call with paid ads.
And so what I did is I sure I
changed some other stuff in the
VSL, but primarily I focused
on the introduction and I
completely changed the
introduction.
Just like gave it a whole
facelift.
We were able to take that
conversion rate from 3% to 6% and
his cost per book call was cut
in half as well.
So it went from $300 cost per book
call to $150 cost per book call.
He was operating at $300,000 a
month.
And because of those expenses and
for it to be able to be lowered,
he now is operating at $700,000 a
month.
And this was about three years
ago.
I wrote this VSL for him.
It is still the industry leader.
I don't know anyone who's had this
consistent and long-term of a VSL.
Since three years ago, once he
started, he very quickly scaled up
to $700,000, has not stopped at
$700,000, has hit it every single
month.
He says that once he hits a mil,
he tried like a mil once and he
hit like $850,000 and was just
like, I hate it.
I don't like that amount.
And so he's like, $700,000 is my
sweet spot where I feel
comfortable and I can manage my
other businesses.
So all it took was just fixing the
intro.
That shows you the power of the
introduction.
I really didn't change much else
in the VSL, just the introduction.
So every video has a LAC, LAC,
lead, which is the introduction,
argument, which is the body, and
then close, which is the call to
action.
Lead, argument, close.
Every single VSL is like that.
So the easiest way for you to
write a highly effective VSL
script is to follow a framework.
I'm going to give you a framework
right now.
I said cover two.
I should say one.
So disregard that.
I'm going to give you one.
I thought about giving you two and
then I realized, you know what,
let's make it super simple and
give you one.
Okay.
So we're only going to give you
one.
And this framework is essentially
an outline for you to follow.
It's like a map of where you
should go with your writing.
Okay.
If you get the intro down, it's a
lot easier to move on to the next
step and the next step and the
next step and so on.
Right.
That's why we should follow a
framework.
It makes it really easy for us to
get the intro down, for us to get
the body down, and for us to get
the call to action down.
Solid.
Right.
So intro, body, call to action.
Okay.
Close.
So we should aim to be around five
to ten minutes for a B2B VSL.
Okay.
Five to ten minutes.
And when you have a really solid
creative brief and you pair that
with a little bit of some chat GPT
action and you have a really good
framework, you're making things
ten times easier for you to do it
on your own, for you to write your
own script.
Okay.
You don't need to go hire a
copywriter.
You don't need to go.
Like, it's super simple, guys.
I'm going to give you everything
you need to do to do it on your
own.
And we're going to use a little
bit of some AI as well, and you're
going to see how I think about
these things.
Okay.
So that is everything for the
general writing guidelines.
Here is your bread and butter
framework.
Okay.
So here's the framework, guys.
First and foremost, you are going
to state your offer and the
guarantee.
Pretty straightforward.
You state where your offer is and
you make the guarantee and you
give them a brief overview of
what's to come in this short
video.
A brief overview of what's to come
in this short video is your open
loops.
Open the loops for them.
And you state the offer and make
the guarantee.
If you don't have an offer, go to
Daniel's call.
If you don't have a guarantee, go
to Daniel's call.
You need an offer and a guarantee.
Oh, I don't have a guarantee.
Okay.
Do you have a disgusting amount of
case studies?
No.
Go to Daniel's call.
You need a guarantee.
Do you have a disgusting amount of
case studies?
Yes.
Okay.
You don't need a guarantee.
You don't need to state a
guarantee.
Okay.
If you just have like undeniable
levels of social proof, you don't
need a guarantee.
But if you do not have undeniable
levels of proof, you need a
guarantee.
Okay.
And if you do have undeniable
levels of proof and you have a
guarantee, that's good.
Like, that's awesome.
So then we're going to do
something called the IED intro.
Okay.
This is where we ask three types
of questions to open up the video.
Okay.
It's an identifier question, an
empathy-based question, and a
direct benefit statement.
Okay.
So an example of this, are you a
coach who sells a high ticket
offer ranging from $5,000 to
$25,000?
Identifier question.
Empathy-based question.
Do you ever feel like your cost
per book call is continuously
going up on ads and it's very
frustrating because you cannot
effectively scale with a high cost
per book call?
Kind of a wordy question, but I'm
just shooting off the cuff here.
Empathy-based, right?
I understand your situation.
They're like, yes, that's exactly
what I have.
Direct benefit.
What if I could show you how to
cut your cost per book call in
half without having to change
anything with your ads?
That's a direct benefit statement.
They're like, heck yeah, sign me
up.
I'd like that.
Okay.
So that's exactly what we're doing
there.
That's the IED intro.
If you know also an IED is like an
explosive device in the military.
So that's why we call it that.
Then what we go into is why is
this problem happening, right?
We go into the problem and we talk
about the real reason why the
problem is happening for them.
All right.
That's what we explain to them.
Hey, here's the real reason why
your problem is happening.
Okay.
You don't know this.
You think it's this.
It's actually this.
Here's the real problem.
I'm going to explain your problem
to you better than you can explain
it yourself.
You get that from really good
research.
Let's keep going.
What's the solution?
I'm going to not give you
everything right away.
What is the solution?
How do you reverse the problem?
How are you specifically reversing
the problem for them?
This is where we bring in our
product or our service and we show
them how to completely remove the
problem.
Okay.
Next section.
How is this solution different?
This is where we reveal our unique
mechanism.
It shows how we're different.
This is what we do differently,
right?
And we show how we're different
than 99% of the things the viewer
has seen.
And this is how we position
ourselves as a 1% solution.
Meaning you haven't seen this
before.
Undeniable proof.
You want to make it extremely
clear that you have results or
proof that people love your
product or service.
Okay.
Undeniable proof.
If you don't have that, sorry
guys, you're going to miss out on
having as powerful of a VSL as you
can have.
But that's okay.
You should come back later when
you do have undeniable proof.
It's not a make or break thing.
It's just going to make it a lot
easier for you to be able to get
book calls from this.
You're going to have to try a lot
harder with follow-up if you do
not have undeniable proof.
Okay.
And then last but not least, one
more direct offer plus ask.
This is where we make our final
direct offer to the viewer.
Tell them to take a specific
action, which is going to be
filling out a questionnaire,
booking a call, so on and so
forth.
Okay.
So now let's go write a VSL script
together following this framework
in the demo section of this
module.
So that's everything, guys.
Hope you found this useful.
All the best.
Bye now.