Alrighty ladies and gents.
So as you can see right here, what
we got is another doc.
This
is your framework.
Okay.
And this is going to have the
framework that I talked about in
the module.
And then as well, I'm going to
have the script right here.
Now yours is going to go right
beneath
that.
So let's actually just make that a
separate page, right?
Isn't the most annoying thing
about
Google docs is this stupidity
right here.
Look at that.
Oh, I want to go up one.
No,
you got to go right there.
So now we can actually go in,
right?
So here's the best way to do this,
guys.
You want to get this done super
fast.
Okay.
We're going to do file download as
a PDF.
Okay.
I now have the creative brief
finished.
So that's downloaded right there.
Okay.
Notice how
there's a client ascension one as
well.
Oh, I don't think you guys can see
that.
Interesting.
Yeah,
no, you can't see that, but
there's a download right there.
Okay.
So now what I'm going to do
is I'm going to go to chat.openai.
Okay.
And then as well, what I'm going
to do,
you guys can't see this, but this
is a tool called AI PDF.app.
Okay.
I already have an account.
I'm
going to have to log into it.
So let me give a second.
I'm going to pause real quick.
Okay.
So here I am
now inside of the doc.
So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to file upload and I'm going
to upload mine.
And you guys can't see it because
it's just the window capture on
here.
It's not the screen's
capture on there.
And you can see now I have this
and I can copy this.
Okay.
And I can save,
copy that, go back to chat.openai.
And I can say, here is a creative
brief.
Oh, let's make sure that you guys
can see this.
Here's a creative brief for my
services.
All right.
I would like for you to produce a,
and here is the big thing right
here.
We've got to say five
to 10 minute.
You're going to see why we don't
use chat GPT here in a second.
I'm just going to show
you guys the chat GPT, but you'll
see here.
We're in a second.
We don't that provide a five to 10
minute,
um, VSL script that pitches that
sells this service and follows
this framework.
Okay.
And then from there,
I will go here, copy and paste
this.
Boom.
So I'm going to, I need to like,
make it very clear for it.
So state your offer and your
guarantee
the IED intro.
Why is the problem happening?
What is the solution?
How is this solution different?
Undeniable proof, direct offer
plus ask.
Okay.
We're going to hand it to it.
And it's now
I'm going to produce it.
So it's searching the files.
All right.
Give me a sec.
Let me go and do that.
Okay.
So I saw what the problem was.
I didn't have plugins on.
So what you want to do is you want
to go and you want to hit this
right here.
So if you don't have it, I would
highly recommend paying
for the paid chat GPT version and
Claude as well.
We'll go into Claude.
It's like total guys, 40 bucks a
month, like, you know, make more
money.
So you can go here to settings and
beta, beta features,
turn on plugins right here.
So you turn it on and then that
plugin that you want to get from
the store,
you can go and go to plugin store,
but AI PDF is the name of the
plugin.
Okay.
And so now I can
go back to this previous example.
The reason why it wasn't able to
pull it is because it was trying
to search my files.
Um, but we want to do it this way.
So we go to new chat plugins, no
plugins enabled.
Let's turn on the plugins.
Sometimes it's weird.
It doesn't load.
Okay.
So you can see that the plugins
right there.
So now what I can do is paste
that.
Okay.
And now it's going to access that
using this AI PDF plugin.
Okay.
Now just give it a second.
I'll go ahead and pause this real
quick before it starts generating.
So you can see, this is why we
don't use chat GPT that for some
reason it really sucks with this
type of stuff.
I don't know why uploading
documents.
Like I just have not had a ton of
success.
I wanted to show you guys that
because some of you guys are going
to be like, well, why can't I just
use chat GPT?
So that's why, so here's what I
would recommend.
This is a much better tool.
It's called Claude.
Okay.
It makes it so easy for me to
upload a doc.
Take that and then I can do this
right here.
Yep.
Okay.
That follows the following
framework.
Okay.
And then I just need to format it
a little bit.
Give me one.
So I have it formatted, but here's
another
thing guys is that you can ask
yourself how many words can be
spoken in one minute.
Okay.
140 words per minute.
So if I want to do 140, let's say
I wanted this thing to be
five minutes long is going to be,
I don't know why I didn't just do
the math right there.
Okay, cool.
Thanks.
Appreciate it.
Google
700.
So I want this to be 700 words on
a 700 word long
and don't say script on this stuff
either.
Like I just, I'm doing that just
so you guys can see it,
but 700 word long piece of copy
that sells the service
I have included in the attached
creative brief
and follows this framework.
Okay.
So here's that.
Go
Bing, bing, bing, bing, bing.
Pretty fucking good, right?
So let me ask you a couple of
questions.
Are you an info
product business owner struggling
to get your email marketing, truly
connect with your audience and
really perform?
Do you feel like you're
overlooking a goldmine hidden in
your email list and have you
tried working with copywriters and
foot before, but feel they failed
to capture.
So there's a lot of like
little verbiage things that we're
going to tweak here.
That's causing me to like stumble
over my words
here.
Um, the reason most email
marketing falls flat is because it
lacks personalization.
Sending
blanket one size fits all messages
simply doesn't cut it anymore.
Your subscribers are barred with
hundreds of emails today.
We'll get to that again.
Most services fail.
They rely on templates.
Outsource
writers and a focus on sales at
the result.
Emails, in fact, non-wonder,
engage in implements.
This is
where our inbox when missing
methods send the part.
We don't just write emails.
Uh, we merge ourselves in
your world to understand.
Okay, cool.
We'd conduct in-depth interviews.
Yep.
How's the solution different?
Unlike other traditional services
are personalized is personalized,
not standardized.
We don't use
templates.
We craft versus emails.
Yep.
Um,
Okay.
Solid.
Boom.
I'm going to take this.
I'm going to come over to here.
And now
I've got a VSL script ready to
rock and roll.
I hate this so much.
This is like upsetting me to
a math.
What is the point of this?
Look, there's, there's no point
for that.
There's no point.
There we go.
Fucking hell.
Wow.
I don't even think that.
I think it's still there too.
What can I just
minimize this down to like a
eight?
Here we go.
And then there we go.
Let's go.
So now we have it
where our VSL script is like 20,
30%, maybe 50% done.
I mean, it depends on how nitpicky
you are,
but now I can just go in and tweak
this stuff.
So let's go in and let's zoom in a
bit.
I apologize.
Also if on the creepy creative
brief guys, if you were, if it was
hard to read it,
hopefully it wasn't, um, if you
have bad vision, you know,
whatever, sorry, your lack of
amazing
genetics is not my fault or your
age.
Okay.
So let's go in and let's zoom in
here.
So,
so I would say I guarantee, I
guarantee I can transform
your underperforming email list
into a powerhouse for engagement
conversions and revenue growth
with my personalized inbox
intimacy approach.
So all I'm doing now is I'm going
in and editing this and making it
better with my personalized inbox
intimacy approach.
I'll craft emails.
I will personally
craft emails that sound like they
came directly from you, um, which
will
allow them to allow them to
resonate deeply.
So we'll come back to this.
I don't really, this is like too
wordy right here, but I guarantee,
I guarantee I can transform your
underperforming email list and a
powerhouse for engagement
conversions
and revenue growth.
Um, with my personalized inbox
intimacy approach, I will craft, I
will personally,
I've personalized personally, I
will craft emails that sound like
they came from directly from you,
which will allow
resonate deeply with your
audience.
so I don't even think this really
matters right here, allowing
deeply resonate with your
audience.
Like, um,
so here's the 80/20 of this video
video with my personalized inbox
intimacy approach.
I will craft emails that sound
like they directly came
from you based on
your content and in depth
interviews that I'll
ducked with you personally.
And if you don't see it as a
substantial increase in open
rates, click throughs and sales,
the 90 days,
you pay nothing period, end of
story.
So here's what I'm going to say.
Now here's a couple of questions.
I like to ask you,
you know, whether or not
right.
Okay.
So let's just stop right there
before we go into the questions.
Let me go on camera.
I guarantee I can transform your
underperforming email list into a
powerhouse for engagement,
conversions, and revenue growth
inside your info product business.
All right.
Sound good.
Here's the 80/20 this video with
my personalized inbox intimacy
approach.
I will craft emails that sound
like they came directly from you
based on your content and in-depth
interviews that I'll conduct with
you personally.
And if you don't see a substantial
increase in open rates, click
throughs and sales,
then 90 days you pay nothing.
Now, here's a couple of questions
I'd like to ask you,
which will help you know whether
or not this service makes sense
for you.
Number one.
Are you an info product business
owner struggling?
Doing about doing at least
a hundred K a month consistently.
I don't think someone's going to
say to me, oh, I'm really
struggling to get my email
marketing to connect to truly
connect with your audience.
And you feel.
And you're struggling.
To find a solution for your email
marketing.
You know, honestly, I don't think
that we need to get into that on
the identifier question.
I think I can just go and straight
say, let's go back to my creative
brief.
See how we reason why we did this.
Right?
So we'll go back to the potential
questions.
And so I can go back here now and
say, are you an info product
business owner doing at least a
hundred K a month
with phone sales
Through a VSL
book a call funnel or low ticket.
I'm going to put this right here
selling high ticket items ranging
from 5,000 to $25,000.
Okay.
So here's a couple of questions.
I'd like to ask you to help, you
know, whether or not this service
makes sense for you.
Number one, are you an info
product business owner doing at
least a hundred K a month?
So in high ticket items ranging
from 5,000 to 2,000, $25,000.
With phone sales.
With a sales team.
Over the phone.
By leveraging a VSL book, a call
funnel or a low ticket Ascension
funnel.
Yes.
Awesome.
Keep going.
Do you feel like you're
overlooking a golden, a golden, a
gold mine hidden in your email
list
that, you know, you could do a
better job of, um, what's the word
for it there?
Better job of capitalizing on of
utilizing.
All right.
And last but not least, have you
tried working with copywriters?
Have you tried working with
copywriters, but felt they failed
to capture out that big voice?
Or have you been stuck?
Um, writing all your emails
yourself.
If you answered yes.
To all those questions, to those
questions.
That's because not all right.
There's that one where they may
need to never hire someone.
If you answered yes to those
questions, congratulations.
You're in the right place.
You're in the, isn't this the
tickety tickety tickety so
satisfying.
Maybe you hate it.
Sorry.
Deal with it.
Um, uh, if you answered yes to
those questions, congratulations,
you're in the right place.
Um, what I'd like to do over the
next, um, a few minutes
is explained to you, blah, blah,
blah.
I'll come back to that later,
right?
Because I don't even know what the
hell I'm going to explain.
Just let me have to delete all
this.
Okay.
So.
So here's, here's a good question.
Why do most people's emails?
Why do most people's emails get
ignored?
And result in a extremely, which
results in a low click-through
rate, which results
in an atrociously low open rate
and
atrociously low attributed
revenue.
Open rate and click-through rate.
So here's a good question.
Why do most people's emails get
ignored?
Which results, which results in a
atrociously low attributed rate.
Atrociously, which results in.
That's why atrociously low
attribute revenue, open rate and
click-through rates.
Open rates and click-through
rates, right?
The reason why is because
It's actually pretty simple.
Most email marketing falls flat
because it lacks personalization.
Sending blanket one size fits all
messages simply doesn't cut it
anymore.
Your subscribers are bombarded
with hundreds of emails per day
competing for their attention.
To stand out in the noise, your
messages need to feel like they
were written specifically for each
need to be extremely valuable
and pass something I call the
coffee test.
Everyone holds
their morning cup of Joe
sacred, right?
Would
your prospect, um, enjoy reading
your emails with their
Monday morning coffee.
Yes.
Um, for most
the answer is no, because their
emails
are just a wild pitch fest.
Or just an annoying pitch fest.
I think that's kind of where we go
to on that as well.
This is why most done for you
email services fail.
They rely on, um, um, don't work,
um, don't work all that well.
They rely on templates, outsource
writers and focus on sales over
value.
And the result is that the email
sound and the result
is that the emails
sound robotic, inauthentic, and
overly, and, and super promo-y and
okay, it's no wonder why
engagement plunders.
It's no wonder why engagement
plummets.
Under why engagement plummets.
Okay.
So let's see where we're at right
here.
Let's zoom out a bit.
So we got our intro down and now
we're moving into the next part
where we're explaining the
solution.
Okay.
So I now want to record and I'm
sorry, not record, but time myself
to see how long I'm at right here
for pacing.
Now I like doing this.
I know a lot of people that say,
you should just write the entire
time.
Don't stop writing.
I don't like doing that.
Um, that's my own personal method.
Again, like I said, everyone's
writing process is unique.
Mine is like this.
I like stopping and, you know,
timing it and seeing where I'm at.
So I'd like to be at about a
minute right here because I have
still some more to go.
Right.
I'd like to be for at least like a
minute, minute 30.
Okay.
So let's get started.
So I'm going to hit a stopwatch
and I'm going to read this out
loud.
Ready?
I'm going to restart.
Set.
Go.
I guarantee I can transform your
underperforming email list into a
powerhouse for engagement,
conversions, and revenue growth
inside your info product business.
Sound good?
Here's the 80/20 of this video.
With my personalized inbox
intimacy approach, I will craft
emails that sound like they came
directly from you based on your
content and in-depth interviews
that I'll conduct with
you personally.
And if you don't see a substantial
increase in open rates,
click-throughs, and sales,
then 90 days, you pay nothing.
Now, here's a couple of questions
I'd like to ask you, which will
help you know whether
or not this service makes sense
for you.
Number one, are you an info
product business owner doing at
least a hundred K a month,
selling high ticket items ranging
from $5,000 to $25,000 over the
phone by leveraging a VSL,
book a call funnel, or a low
ticket ascension funnel?
Number two, do you feel like
you're overlooking a goldmine
hidden in your email list that you
know you could do a better job of
utilizing?
And last but not least, number
three, have you tried working with
copywriters before
but felt like they failed to
capture your authentic voice?
Or have you been stuck writing all
your emails yourself?
If you answered yes to those
questions, congratulations, you're
in the right place.
What I'd like to do over the next
few minutes is explain to you
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
So here's a good question.
Why do most people's emails get
ignored, which results in
atrociously
low attributed revenue, open
rates, and click-through rates?
The reason why is actually pretty
simple.
Most email marketing falls flat on
its face because it lacks
personalization.
Sending blanket, one-size-fits-all
messages simply doesn't cut it
anymore.
Your subscribers are bombarded
with hundreds of emails per day
competing for their intention.
To stand out in the noise, your
messages need to be extremely
valuable and pass something I call
the coffee
test.
Everyone holds their morning cup
of joe sacred.
Would your prospect enjoy reading
your
emails with their morning coffee?
For most, the answer is no because
the emails are just an annoying
pitch fest.
This is why most done-for-you
email services don't work all that
well.
They rely on
templates, outsourced writers, and
a focus on sales over value.
And the result is that the emails
sound
robotic, inauthentic, and super
spammy.
It's no wonder why the engagement
plummets.
Boom.
So we're at right around 155.
We're at like two minutes there.
So a bit wordy here.
I want to get through the rest of
the VSL.
We haven't even done the blah,
blah,
blah.
But I know now with this section,
right, I can go and I can say,
"Hey, this is a bit wordy."
I'm going to yellow highlight it
here, and I can probably make it a
little bit better there.
So it'll probably be at like two
minutes and 30 seconds because I
didn't even do the blah, blah,
blah right there.
So now here's the thing.
If I can get through this in about
two minutes and 30 seconds,
then solid.
But I'm going to be honest, I
don't know if I'll be able to do
that.
We'll see though.
Okay.
So I can either A, reduce this or
B, speed this up here.
Okay.
So I'm just going to go right
into it and we'll see what
happens.
Kind of just figuring out as we
go.
So what's the solution?
Well, that's where our inbox
intimacy method comes into play.
So, what's the solution?
Well, that's a great way for me to
introduce myself.
My name is Nicholas Verge.
I'm a direct response copywriter
Who's been in the info product
industry
for five years now and have been
able to produce
one sec.
I can actually just copy and paste
it.
I just pulled this from the gamma
doc.
It's not close to it.
It's over 30 million dollars
writing for
for celebrity clients like Alex
Jones, Jordan Belfort and many
other underground names.
You don't know,
but they're quietly cleaning up
seven and eight figures, seven to
eight figures a year.
Seven to eight figures a year.
One of my main specialties
Writing it is writing email
newsletters, but not just any,
but not just any type that just,
uh, your average
run of the mill pitch, pitch,
pitch
newsletters.
My newsletters follow a
methodology I created called
the inbox intimacy method.
I don't just write your emails.
I immerse myself
In your world to ensure I
intimately understand your voice,
expertise and goals.
Okay.
I conduct in-depth interviews to
capture your unique perspectives
and all industry knowledge.
Industry knowledge.
And then
I probably look so autistic right
now.
Just fucking.
And then I transform your insights
into compelling emails that
balance emotional educational
content with promotional material.
This tactful balance balance
builds trust while keeping your
audience receptive and actively
engaged.
I don't really need to say this
question right here.
Unlike traditional services.
Some of the.
Unlike.
Most.
Copywriters who.
I don't know how to say this
exactly.
I'm unlike most copywriters who
are stacking.
You know, I can just actually say,
um, I don't use templates.
I don't use templates.
I don't work with a ton of people.
I don't use templates and I don't
work with a ton of people.
This is what allows me.
This is.
What.
Enables me to craft.
Bespoke emails tailored to you and
your audience.
Right.
This is what enables me to craft
bespoke emails tailored to you and
your audience.
This ensures that every message
strongly represents your brand and
identity.
So my newsletters follow
methodology.
I called the inbox intimacy
method.
I don't just write your emails.
I immerse myself in your world to
ensure I intimately understand
your voice expertise and goals.
I conduct in-depth interviews to
capture unique perspectives and
industry knowledge.
And then I transform your insights
into compelling emails that
balance educational content
with promotional material.
This tactical balance builds
trust.
I don't use templates.
I don't work with a ton of people.
This is what enables me to craft
bespoke emails tailored to you and
your audience.
Craft high quality.
Bespoke emails tailored to you and
your audience that provide.
Which provide.
You don't have to always say that.
Which provide a ton of value.
Okay.
This ensures that every message
strongly represent.
I don't know.
I think I need to say that.
That's what bespoke means.
This methodology.
Prioritizes.
Building long-term relationships.
Not just short-term sales.
Our focus extends beyond the inbox
to forge lasting connections
through value exchange.
This fosters customer loyalty over
quick connections.
That's what's going to foster.
This is what's going to foster.
This is what's going to foster
customer loyalty.
Help you accumulate.
Audience loyalty.
Audience loyalty and relation.
A better relationship with your
audience.
I'm going to say that.
Audience.
That's a way better relationship
with your audience.
With your audience.
Which will.
Result in way more sales.
in the long run.
My clients have seen.
My clients have seen astonishing
results from the service.
From this methodology.
And I've even.
Included a case study.
Down below.
Explaining.
Showing how one of.
Do 930,000.
By utilizing.
This high value.
Methodology.
Now.
Here's a question for you.
Here's one last question.
For you.
Do you want to.
Do you.
Second guys.
I'm going to pause this real
quick.
For one second.
I need to take a sip of water.
Okay.
So.
Do you want to transform your
email marketing.
With.
With this.
With my exclusive.
Now.
Do you want to transform your own.
Your.
Your email marketing.
With my exclusive.
No.
And so here's the thing.
I need to have like a guarantee,
right?
Do you want to transform your
marketing with my exclusive inbox
intimacy service?
My exclusive inbox intimacy
methodology?
By having me write your emails
with my exclusive inbox intimacy
methodology.
Right?
And like I said earlier, there's
no risk for you.
Okay.
Because if you don't...
Now, here's the thing, guys.
For this part where I'm saying
substantial increase, right?
I have disgusting case studies and
I have a ton of credibility and
I've worked with a ton of people
in this industry.
Jordan Belfort, Alex Jones, Badris
Cullian, even written for Caitlyn
Jenner at one point.
Like that was a big mistake.
But anyways, like I've been able
to work with huge names.
I've been able to produce a
disgusting amount of revenue.
So I don't need to be as
aggressive with my guarantees.
I could, but it's really hard with
the service because it's like,
dude, there's so many factors that
I can't play into it with this.
You guys should be aggressive with
your guarantees.
I'm just using my example here so
we can have something to actually
record on it.
But for the most part, guys, you
can go and apply this to your own
stuff and you should make it so,
right?
You have a very aggressive
guarantee on it because if they
don't match all the stipulations,
right?
You can go and say something else,
whatever.
I personally don't feel the need
to do that.
I would recommend you do that
though, because you probably are
in a different situation than I
am.
Okay.
Like I said earlier, there's no
risk for you because if you don't
see a substantial increase in open
rates, click throughs and sales
within 90 days, you pay nothing,
right?
So if you're open to exploring
that possibility, open to
exploring the possibility of
working with me, the possibility
of working with me, there's a
button below where you can check
out our quick, uh, you can fill
out.
Fill out a quick questionnaire to
discuss how we can boost your
email marketing performance.
Then, if you fill that out, you'll
be taken to a page where you can
book a strategy call.
So if you fill out a strategy
call, strategy call with my, uh,
strategy call with me to kickstart
the path to new growth, discuss
what it, whether or not this
service makes sense for you and
your business, right?
So here's the thing.
Now I have to send it.
Now I have to state this as well.
I only work with three clients.
The majority of my income from
consulting and one-on-one
coaching.
So I do not stack dozens and
dozens of done for you projects.
Um, because I don't have the time
for it.
Um, at the time of recording this
video, adding some scarcity here,
right?
Uh, at the time of recording this
video, I only have two spots
remaining for this service
service.
So if you're interested in blowing
up your email marketing in a good
way,
good way claim your spot.
Now click the button below below
to claim your spot, claim your
spot now before availability for
this before availability fills up.
All righty.
All the best by now.
Okay.
So I know that this was about two
minutes.
I think I may have been able to
hit this in under five.
There's a good chance that I did.
We're going to see now.
So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to go through and I'm going
to read this out loud and we're
going to see where I'm at.
It's a pretty fast script and it
pitches pretty quickly.
Now guys, you may have a little
bit more complicated of a script.
You may want to go for 10 minutes.
You may want to go for eight
minutes.
What I'm telling you is that the
better VSL is going to be five
minutes long.
Your audience is busy.
Okay.
If it's B2B that you're selling,
your audience is busy.
So don't take up a shit ton of
their time.
So let's dive in real quick on
doing the read.
So I'm 155 for this yellow part.
So let's see where I'm at.
Okay.
Zero seconds on the clock.
Ready?
Set.
One sec.
Ready?
Set.
Go.
I guarantee I can transform your
underperforming email list into a
powerhouse for engagement,
conversion, and revenue growth
inside your info product business.
Sound good?
I accidentally scrolled too far
down.
One sec.
I guarantee I can transform your
underperforming email list into a
powerhouse for engagement,
conversions, and revenue growth
inside your info product business.
Sound good?
Here's the 80/20 of this video.
With my personalized inbox
intimacy approach, I will craft
emails that sound like they came
directly from you based on your
content and in-depth interviews
that I'll conduct with you
personally.
And if you don't see a substantial
increase in open rates,
click-throughs, and sales, then 90
days, you pay nothing.
Now, here's a couple of questions
I'd like to ask you, which will
help you know whether or not this
service makes sense for you.
Number one, are you an info
product business owner doing at
least $100K a month selling high
ticket items ranging from $5,000
to $25,000 over the phone by
leveraging a VSL, book a call, or
low ticket ascension funnel?
Do you feel like you're
overlooking a gold mine hidden in
your email list that you know
could be doing a better job of
utilizing?
And last but not least, have you
tried working with copywriters
before, but they failed to capture
your authentic voice, or you've
just been stuck writing all your
emails yourself?
If you answered yes to those
questions, congratulations, you're
in the right place.
What I'd like to do is over the
next few months, I'm going to
explain to you blah, blah, blah,
blah.
So here's a good question.
Why do most people's emails get
ignored, which results in
atrociously low attributed
revenue, open rates, and
click-through rates?
The reason why is actually pretty
simple.
Most email marketing falls flat on
its face because it lacks
personalization.
Sending blanket one-size-fits-all
BS messages simply just doesn't
cut it anymore.
Your subscribers are bombarded
with hundreds of emails per day
competing for their attention.
To stand out in the noise, your
messages need to be extremely
valuable and pass something I call
the coffee test.
Everyone holds their morning cup
of Joe sacred.
Would your prospect enjoy reading
your emails with their morning
coffee?
For most, the answer is no,
because their emails are just an
annoying pitch fest.
This is why most done-for-you
email services don't work all that
well.
They rely on templates, outsourced
writers, and a focus on sales over
value.
And the result is that the emails
sound robotic, inauthentic, and
super spammy.
It's no wonder why the engagement
plummets.
So what's the solution?
Well, that's a great way for me to
introduce myself.
My name is Nicholas Verge, and I'm
a direct response copywriter who's
been in the info product industry
for five years now.
I've been able to produce over $30
million writing for celebrity
clients like Alex Jones, Jordan
Belfort, and many other
underground names you don't know,
but they're quietly cleaning up
seven to eight figures.
One of my main specialties is
writing email newsletters, but not
just your average run-of-the-mill
pitch pitch pitch newsletters.
My newsletters follow a
methodology I created called the
Inbox Intimacy Method.
I don't just write your emails.
I immerse myself in your world to
ensure I intimately understand
your voice, expertise, and goals.
I conduct in-depth interviews to
capture unique perspectives and
industry knowledge, and then I
transform your insights into
compelling emails that balance
educational content with
promotional material.
This tactful balance builds trust
while keeping your audience
receptive and actively engaged.
I don't use templates, and I don't
work with a ton of people.
This is what enables me to craft a
high-quality, bespoke email
tailored to you and your audience,
which provides a ton of value.
This methodology prioritizes
building long-term relationships,
not just short-term sales.
Our focus extends beyond the inbox
to forge lasting connections
through value exchange.
This is what's going to help you
accumulate a way better
relationship with your audience,
which will result in way more
sales in the long run.
My clients have seen astonishing
results in this methodology, and
I've even included a case study
down below showing how one of my
clients was able to produce
$930,000 in under a year by
utilizing this high-value
methodology.
Now here's one last question for
you.
Do you want to transform your
email marketing by having me write
your emails with my exclusive
inbox into that methodology?
And like I said earlier, there's
no risk for you because if you
don't see a substantial increase
in open rates, click-throughs, and
sales in 90 days, you pay nothing.
So if you're open to exploring the
possibility of working with me,
there's a button below where you
can fill out a quick questionnaire
to help discuss how we can boost
your email marketing performance.
After you fill that out, you'll be
taken to a page where you can book
a strategy call with me to discuss
whether or not this service makes
sense for you and your business.
Now I have to state this as well.
I only work with three clients at
any given time for this email
service.
The majority of my income comes
from consulting and one-on-one
coaching, so I do not stack dozens
and dozens of done-for-you
projects because I don't have time
for it.
At the time of recording this
video, I only have two spots
remaining for this service, and
yes, that's real.
So if you're interested in blowing
up your email marketing in a good
way, click the button below to
claim your spot now before
availability fills up.
All righty, all the best, bye now.
We are at four minutes and 33
seconds with the blah, blah, blah
section and with the, you know,
couple different fuck-ups that I
made there.
I think we're going to land at
right around five minutes.
Solid.
This is a pitch.
It effectively communicates the
problem, the solution, all this
stuff.
So what I'm going to do now is
just kind of go through and
fine-tooth comb, run through this
real quick.
Let's go ahead.
I don't need the highlight
anymore.
We don't need the highlight
Okay.
And let's just dive in and edit
this in an easy, oh, shit.
No.
This one right here.
Let's go to like 150.
Then use the bathroom real quick
and then I'll be right back, guys.
All right.
So let's do a quick little edit on
this.
So I guarantee I can transform you
in the best way to edit guys read
out loud.
Trust me.
This is one of the best ways for
you to be able to identify the
shit.
That's like, ah, it doesn't sound
right.
Right.
Or stuff you need to add in.
So I guarantee I can transform
your underperforming email list
into a powerhouse for engagement
conversion and revenue growth
inside your info product business.
Sound good.
Here's the 80 20 of this video
with my personalized inbox
intimacy approach.
This personalized seem no, I don't
think it should be.
I think it's methodology using my
inbox into my, I like this better
using my inbox intimacy
methodology.
I will craft emails that sound
like they came directly from you
based on your content and in-depth
interviews that I'll conduct with
you personally.
I like that a lot more.
And if you don't see a substantial
increase in open rates, click
throughs and sales within 90 days,
you pay nothing.
Now, here's a couple of questions
I'd like to ask you, which will
help you know whether or not this
service makes sense for you.
Number one, are you an info, are
you an info product business?
It's fucking time.
My brain's fried.
I've been recording for two hours
now.
So are you an info product
business owner doing at least a
hundred K a month selling high
ticket items ranging from 5,000 to
$25,000 over the phone by
leveraging a VSL book a call
funnel or a low ticket ascension
funnel?
Do you feel like you're
overlooking a gold mine hidden in
your, hidden in your email list?
A gold mine in your email list
that, you know, you could do a
better job of utilizing number
two, question number two, question
number one.
You know, you could do a better
job of utilizing question number
three.
And question number three, have
you tried working with copywriters
before, but they felt like they,
have you tried working with
copywriters before, but felt like
they failed to capture?
I like the like word there.
I felt like they failed to capture
your authentic voice or you've
just been stuck.
Stuck writing all your emails
yourself.
If you answered yes to those
questions, congratulations.
You're in the right place.
What I'd like to do is over the
next few minutes, what I'd like to
do over the next few minutes is
explain to you why people are
ignoring your.
I'm wondering if I even need to do
this year is like, I am trying to
give a summary of what's to come.
I think I could just do like this,
explain to you why most, and then
people's is kind of vague, right?
Most businesses email, I guess
this is why businesses emails get
ignored, which results in
atrociously low attributed
revenue, open rates and click
through rates.
And then show you a unique
methodology.
Okay.
I'm going to show you a, which I
developed that makes.
Here's an engagement and overall.
Overall attributed revenue.
I'm going to say, then I'd like to
show you a unique methodology,
which I developed a unique
methodology.
It makes it.
I'm going to just say, show you
how to easily see a significant
increase in engagement.
And overall, I'd like to show you
how to easily increase your email
lists engagement and its overall
revenue attributed revenue.
And last but not least, if you're
interested, help if you don't want
to do this yourself.
All right.
That's pretty good.
I think that'll bring us to about
five minutes right there.
So I've pre-frame them.
Like, let's kind of zoom out real
quick, guys.
What have I done?
I've done the intro.
Okay.
And then I've transitioned into
like, Hey, you're in the right
place.
Now I'm breaking down what's to
come.
And now I'm giving them the reason
why this problem exists.
Okay.
And then I'm going, I just provide
some more value here.
And this may even be something
that, you know, I could just get
rid of this.
Think about this.
Your subscribers are bombarded
with hundreds.
This is why most done-for-you
email services don't work all that
well, right?
They rely on templates, outsource
writers, and a focus on sales over
value.
They rely on templates.
And then the result is emails that
sound robotic, inauthentic, and
super spammy.
So I could get rid of this right
here.
It doesn't necessarily need to
have the cup of Joe test, but you
know, it's there.
Sending blanket one size fits all
messages simply doesn't cut it
anymore.
Your subscribers are bombarded
with hundreds of emails per day
and competing for the, that are
competing, that are competing for
their attention.
Okay.
So let's go back here real quick.
Most email marketing falls flat
because it lacks personalization.
Sending blanket one size fits all
messages simply doesn't cut it
anymore.
Your subscribers are bombarded
with hundreds of emails per day
that are competing for their
attention.
This is why most done-for-you
email services don't work all that
well.
They rely on templates, outsourced
writers, and a focus on sales over
value.
And the result is that the emails
sound robotic, inauthentic, and
super spammy.
It's no wonder why the engagement
plundits.
So what's the solution?
Well, that's a great way for me to
introduce myself.
My name is Nicholas Virge.
I'm a direct response copywriter.
Who's been in the info product and
fuck.
I didn't see that info product
industry for five years now.
And I've been able five years now.
I've been able to produce over $30
million writing for celebrity
clients like Alex Jones, Jordan
Belfort, and many other
underground names you don't know,
but they're quietly cleaning up
seven to eight figures per year.
One of my main specialties is
writing email newsletters, but not
your average run-of-the-middle
pitch-pitch-pitch newsletters.
My newsletters follow a
methodology I created called the
Inbox Intimacy Method.
I don't just write your emails.
I immerse myself in your world to
ensure I intimately understand
your voice, expertise, and goals.
It doesn't make sense for goals,
right?
To understand your voice, your
expertise, and the way you
specifically explain concepts,
I conduct in-depth interviews to
capture unique perspectives and
industry knowledge.
And then I transform.
The way I do this is by conducting
in-depth interviews to capture
unique perspectives and industry
knowledge.
And then I transform your insights
into compelling emails that
balance educational content with
promotional material.
This tactful balance builds trust
while keeping your audience
receptive and actively engaged.
I don't use templates and I don't
work with a ton of people.
This is what enables me to craft
high-quality bespoke emails
tailored to you and your audience,
which provide a ton of value.
This methodology prioritizes
building long-term relationships,
not just short-term sales.
Our focus extends beyond the inbox
to forge lasting connections
through value exchange.
This is what's going to help you
accumulate a way better
relationship with your audience,
which will result in way more
sales.
Let me say way more sales in the
long run.
My clients have seen astonishing
results in this methodology, and
I've even included a case study
down below showing how one of my
clients was able to produce
$930,000 in under a year by
utilizing this high-value
methodology.
Now, here's one last question for
you.
Do you want to transform your
email marketing by having me write
your emails with my exclusive
inbox intimacy methodology?
Like I said earlier, there's no
risk for you because if you don't
see a substantial increase in open
rates, click-throughs, and sales
in 90 days, you pay nothing.
So, if you're open to exploring
the possibility of working with
me, there's a button below where
you can fill out a quick
questionnaire to discuss how we
can boost your email marketing
performance.
After you fill that out, you'll be
taken to a page where you can book
a strategy call with me to discuss
whether or not this service makes
sense for you and your business.
Now, I have to state this as well.
I only work with three clients.
I only work with three clients at
any given time for this email
service.
The majority of my income comes
from consulting and one-on-one
coaching, so I do not stack dozens
and dozens of done 40 projects
because I don't have time for it.
The time of recording this video,
I only have two spots remaining
for this service.
So, if you're interested in
blowing up your email marketing in
a good way, click the button below
to clean up your spot now before
availability fills up.
You certainly could do this on
your own.
Writing high value.
Time to craft.
Well, let's be honest.
Do you really want to do that?
Probably not.
Again, probably not.
That's why you should book a call
with me.
So do that.
Probably not.
Which is why you should fill out
that questionnaire down below.
All righty.
All the best.
Bye now.
All righty.
So I'm going to get rid of this
because I added on some stuff at
the end.
And I just, it's not necessary.
Like it's kind of me explaining
the same thing just with a net
metaphor.
And there we go.
So I have it where this is.
969, which is five times 140 is
700.
Right.
And so I talk pretty fast though.
So I think I can move through it.
So I'm going to do one last time.
I'm going to make sure I'm right
around five minutes.
I'm not going to make you guys sit
through.
I'm going to pause it and I'll
time it because you've already
seen it twice.
And I'm just going to see, Hey,
how am I landing on this?
If I'm good, I'm good.
And then we can move on to turning
this into a gamma doc.
So let's go ahead.
Let's pause you guys.
And then I'll go and read this.
Four minutes and 45 seconds.
Oh, four minutes and 45 seconds.
Woo.
Let's go.
So guys, this is about 54 minutes.
So I would say about an hour, 10
minutes, maybe with pauses and
everything in between it.
So BSL script done.
Doesn't take fucking three weeks.
It doesn't take four weeks.
It doesn't take, you know, a
fucking month.
It's pretty simple.
So simple.
In fact, someone would say that,
that maybe isn't a client
assumption.
So guys, how did we do this?
Let's recap real quick.
We spent time on crafting a good
creative brief.
The way we get a good creative
brief is we have a good service.
Like that actually is good.
Okay.
We put all this information in one
consolidated document.
And then we provide a tool like
Claude with that creative brief,
give it the framework.
It gives us this.
We then go and edit it.
So we're at least 30% of the way
done.
And it gives us a good, like solid
foundation.
We can go and chip and refine it
as we keep going.
And then boom, we edit it, add
everything that we need to, remove
whatever we don't,
make it a little bit better here
and there, bing, bang, boom.
And now we got to finish script.
Now what we got to do is turn this
into a gamma doc and now go and
record an OBS video with it.
Ta-da, super easy.
So hopefully that was useful for
you guys.
You may be watching this and being
a little bit intimidated.
You'd be like, holy shit, Nick
just wrote a BSL script in under
an hour.
I've never seen someone do that
before.
Or holy crap.
Like I just, it doesn't seem like
I can write from that perspective.
I don't really do all that well,
um, writing like that.
And guys, the thing is those, I've
been doing this for five years.
So of course you maybe won't be at
the same like level of competency
and being able to just write
straight from flow.
Here's some tools I can recommend
to you that would help.
Number one.
Starbucks coffee, get a coffee,
nitro cold brew, caffeinate up.
It'll be a lot easier when you're
caffeinated.
Number two, just write.
Like literally just write, just
sit down.
You need to just set the time that
I'm going to sit there and I'm
going to write.
I'm not going to get distracted.
No text, no Twitter, nothing else
open.
All I'm doing is focusing on this.
And it'll be a lot easier when you
have that and not constant
distractions feeding in.
So guys, if you just write and
caffeinate yourself, maybe a
little bit of nicotine as well.
Um, it'll be a lot easier for you
to get this done.
Don't compare yourself to me and
you may be as good as I am, right?
Like a lot of you guys are
copywriters as well.
You may be as good as I am, but
it's literally just about getting
it done.
So you may take two hours.
You may take, you know, an hour
and a half, whatever.
It doesn't matter.
The time doesn't matter.
What matters is we got something
good done.
We spent about actually 50% of our
time now on the creative brief and
about 50% of our time on the
script.
Okay.
So now the production really isn't
going to take us that long.
It's actually super simple.
So let's keep going.
So I'm going to go ahead and also
as well, it would probably be
longer with the creative brief.
Had I not known what my offer was
already.
And had I not already sold this
multiple times to people and
already known how to provide it.
So I probably would be closer to
like 70, 30 or 60, 40 right now,
but.
That I already know what I'm doing
here.
So let's take that into account.
All right, you guys, that's
everything.
Let's now move on to the next
section where we're going to turn
this into a gamma doc and record
it.
So bye-bye.