Alrighty ladies and gents, boys
and girls, here we are talking
again about how to craft
and create a banger VSL for your
B2B service offer.
And so what we're going to be
talking
about today is the three different
types of VSLs you can produce and
how to know which
one is best for you and your
personality type.
Okay, so this is going to be a
very quick
module.
Very straightforward guys.
Okay, we're going to be mainly in
the demo section here
because I can only talk about
production for so long.
So now it's time for you to shoot
a VSL.
You only have so many options.
So I'm going to walk you guys
through a simple
flowchart.
I know you guys love flowcharts,
so I'm going to walk you through
one right
now.
Here's where we're going to start.
The question, are you good on
camera?
If the answer
is no, you're going to do a Loom
GammaDoc VSL.
Okay.
The reason why is because on Loom,
notice
how 25 to 33% of this screen is me
right now.
It's because I identify as someone
being good
on camera and I'm comfortable with
being on camera.
I like being on camera.
So I'm okay
with being 25 to 33% of the
screen.
Now, if you're not good on camera
and you're just like,
oh, that's just not what I do.
I just, I don't want, I think you
should inspect that limiting
belief.
But if that's the case and you
insist and you don't want to be
really on camera,
do a Loom GammaDoc because it's
going to be a very small circle in
the corner here, right
here.
You're going to be a little bit of
a circle and it'll be primarily be
the Google
Doc.
Okay.
Or the GammaDoc.
So that is the Loom GammaDoc.
The reason we use GammaDocs
is because they look better than
Google Docs.
Right now, what I'm shooting on is
GammaDocs.
Okay.
This wouldn't look as good as a
Google Doc.
Okay.
I think it looks better like this.
So there's a lot more graphics
that you can use.
I kept this pretty minimalistic
for the
client ascension team, but guys,
Loom GammaDoc.
Okay.
Very straightforward.
Now, are you good on
camera?
If the answer is yes, the next
question is, do you have a good
camera setup?
Do you have,
like me, a DSLR?
Do you have a good microphone?
If the answer is no, here's what
we're going to ask
you now.
I don't have this stuff.
You don't have that type of
equipment.
Awesome.
No worries.
Do you at least have a good laptop
camera?
Are you at least on a modern day
MacBook?
Okay.
Does the camera on the MacBook
look good?
Do you not look like a potato?
The answer is yes.
If you have a good laptop camera,
then you're going to do an OBS
GammaDoc.
What you're watching right now is
an OBS GammaDoc.
It is so simple to set up.
It's not complicated at
all.
Very straightforward.
Okay.
So if the answer is yes, I do have
a good laptop camera, OBS
GammaDoc.
If you don't have a good laptop
camera, you're going to do a Loom
GammaDoc.
Okay.
Now,
if you have a shitty camera,
that's what you're going to do.
If you don't have any camera
whatsoever, buy one.
It's 50 bucks on Amazon, maybe
less, 40.
So if you don't have a good
quality
one, let's say you have a MacBook
and you don't want to spend any
money on a good one.
And it's
just like an old MacBook and it
doesn't look good.
Just do a Loom GammaDoc.
It's fine.
You'll be a
little circle in the bottom.
Okay.
So no one's really going to notice
the quality.
Now, if you do have a good camera
setup, okay, you have a DSLR and a
mic.
The next question is,
do you have a video editor or do
you want to spend $500 to $1,000
on a video editor?
If the answer is no, again, you're
just going to do an OBS GammaDoc
like what I'm doing right here.
Okay.
That doesn't require any editing.
You guys have seen it.
Rough cut, everything.
It does not
require a lot of editing here.
Okay.
Now, if you are good on camera, if
you do have a good camera
setup, you have, you know, DSLR, a
mic, all that type of stuff.
Guess what?
You should do a teleprompter
direct-to-camera video.
Why?
Because it looks better than
everything else.
Okay.
And I'm going to show
you guys examples of this, but we
can get a teleprompter on our
phone using teleprompter app.
We can then put that next to our
camera or close to our camera.
And so we can then even just film
it on
our phone and do it that way.
Or we can just get a teleprompter
set up and we can shoot it that
way.
Now, here's the thing, guys.
Out of every hundred people that
watch this video, I would
recommend
that to maybe one or two people.
The reason why is because reading
a teleprompter is difficult.
It's not easy.
I have had to coach a lot of
people on how to read a
teleprompter on set,
on shoots, and even people who are
like really good on camera
struggle with it because it's not
the
easiest thing in the world,
especially with pacing and
understanding how to not sound
like a robot.
So very few of you are going to be
a teleprompter person.
Some of you will.
And if you believe
that's the case and you're that
person, message me individually.
Okay.
And I'll give you some advice
on how to do it.
I don't want to create a six hour
long module or two hour long
module or an hour long
module on teleprompters.
Okay.
If you feel like you are that
person though, you have experience
with it.
Awesome.
I'll show you how to set that all
up.
I'm going to talk about that in
one of the demo videos as well,
very briefly, but in the case that
that's not you.
And you're like, no, I don't want
to do that.
That's too much time.
And I don't want to spend that
much money on a video editor.
Usually someone
that's, you know, fairly early in
the offer.
They don't have like 30, $40,000
already in revenue.
They're not really trying to like
separate themselves from everyone
else.
OBS gamma doc.
Okay.
80 to 90% of you guys, I'm just
going to tell you to do the OBS
gamma doc.
Again, very few of you,
I'm going to tell you to do the
teleprompter.
So that's the way that you figure
out which VSL you should do.
Look at the flow chart.
Oh, is that easy?
Super simple.
Most of you guys are going to be
doing
OBS gamma docs.
I'm going to show you how to do
that in this module.
Okay.
Zoom up of the picture, zoom in.
So let's now go shoot some VSL
together.
I'm going to show you how
to set all this stuff up and how
to do everything.
And we're going to do that in the
demo section of
this module.
So that's everything.
All the best.
I'll see you in the demo section.
Bye-bye.