All righty ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls so now we are going
to actually produce our vsl
we are going to first start by
making our gamma doc okay so how
do we do that well as you can see
right here i have my script okay
and i have as well you don't see
this though i have the gamma
open so we're going to start from
this we're going to click here
we're going to go new from blank
okay and then what you're going to
do delete this right here don't
need to have that
and you will go and take this okay
and put it
you can do headline we'll do your
headline in a bit
so i'm gonna do this guarantee i
can do this now here's what you
need to do go here take this make
it into like heading two okay now
what you're going to do is you're
going to go into each individual
section and you're going to go and
you're going to hit this split
card okay all right and so i can
do
this again i think if i do it like
this all right so you can just do
that right there okay so what you
want to do is you want to split
the card you want to center this
on each section okay now i'm going
to
go do this real quick i'm going to
hit pause and i'm going to do this
for each line okay now i can do
it where some of them oops some of
them should be together like this
one hey sound good that's fine why
don't we not just like explain
this to you how to do it we don't
need to pause it so pause it again
or i'll uh split it again so you
can see hey i'm explaining this
section section by section
all right and when i present what
it's going to look like is this
we'll have our headline and it'll
be us on the left side and the
thing on the right side
and so it'll be like hey blah blah
blah blah i guarantee you're going
to want to watch this and why
well i guarantee i can transform
your underperforming email list
into a powerhouse for engagement
conversions revenue growth inside
your info product business sound
good so here's the 80 20 of this
video using my inbox intimacy
methodology i will craft emails
that sound like they came directly
from you
based on your content and in-depth
interviews that i'll conduct with
you personally
and if you don't see a substantial
increase in open rates
click-throughs and sales within 90
days
you pay nothing okay now see how
much better that looks and
obviously you guys like the camera
i need
to like adjust it so where i'm on
the left side this is on the right
side so on and so forth but like
guys this is so much text on
screen i see people do gamma docs
like this where it's just like
it's just so much text i
personally don't like it i think
that it's it's not good otherwise
you know
i i would do it myself but i don't
so what i'm going to do now is i'm
going to go through and i'm
going to uh separate this out and
just do that real quick for each
one and then i'll come back and
show you what it looks like okay
all righty so here we go didn't
take much time at all for us to do
this
and so now you guys can see why
don't i do this i'm going to show
you guys in real time
what this will look like so if i
take me right here and i do this
and then i do this and then we do
this
yeah how do i do where it's like
that and then i want to do option
cut cut right there i am right
there hi how's it going nick virge
here right and then i can go here
and then i'm going to take this
and i go and i do this a little
bit of that a little bit of some
schwitz a little bit of some
schlamiel
a little bit less
so a little bit of that there we
go
okay and i would probably do it
where i make the background go do
this really quick
color source okay we'll do a white
background okay put that behind
all this and then we'll change the
color
source select color we want it to
be i want to select the color uh
you're making this difficult obs
okay and then what we'll do is
we'll do option get rid of the
little purple thing
and then boom so now we have this
right here and watch this so i'm
going to go back to my gamma doc
right here
hey i guarantee i can transform
your underperforming email list
into a powerhouse for engagement
conversions
and revenue growth inside your
info product business does that
sound good if so here's the 80 20
of this
video using my inbox intimacy
method i will craft emails that
sound like they came directly from
you
based on your content and in-depth
interviews that i'll conduct with
you personally okay now if you
don't see a substantial increase
in open rates click-throughs and
sales the 90 days you pay nothing
now here's a couple questions i'd
like to ask you which will help
you know whether or not this
service
makes sense for you okay number
one are you an info product
business owner doing at least 100k
to 200k a month
selling high ticket items ranging
from 5 000 to 25 000 over the
phone by leveraging a vsl book a
call
funnel and i'm just realizing now
that it's a little bit off the
screen so we need to fix that a
bit
right so we don't want to have
that happening so we're just gonna
oh oops ctrl z no
make that go right now let's just
run through this real quick let's
see do all of them
all right so we see that it fits
on all them just want to make sure
and i would even recommend
making them all centered so it
like looks congruent and i'll do
that at the end but let's be
honest do
you really want to do spend your
time doing that okay so that's all
pretty good right and what i want
to do now is i maybe want to make
this look a little bit more
appealing and i need to do a
headline as
well and we'll talk about that
here in a moment so what i want to
do is i want to center this stuff
and then what i'd like to do is
i'd like to add some form of like
graphics or something just so
it's not just like a white
background and that's it so we can
do a white background that's fine
i'm going to do emojis because i
think emojis are great so i
guarantee i can transform your
underperforming email list into a
powerhouse for engagement
conversions and revenue growth
so how are we going to do that
well i could literally just do
this
and then i can go and i can go
this email and then
all right it does not look cute
and then if i make this centered
it'll probably look better
so i guarantee i can do that for
you and then we go to the next one
exit out of this
here's the 80 20 of this video
okay make this one
okay
oh
now what i want to do is i want to
go shift enter same thing here how
can i do it where
it's up
up all right and i can do this
so now when i go and i present
this
here's the 80 20 this video using
my inbox intimacy method right and
if you don't see a substantial
increase in open rates
click-throughs and sales in 90
days i will refund you in full
okay and then i'll
go and i'll do all the formatting
for it so you see how nice this
can look right how straightforward
it can look and just easy and to
the point um i just think it's the
best way to go about doing
this there's not really much that
you need to do here okay um now i
could do the exact same thing
and do a loom so let's take big me
here and let's minimize me
into a little thing right here hi
everybody i'm really tiny
and then we'll make this
the full screen okay so let's just
say
options so if we're going to do a
loom
we'll get the whole thing on here
right so it would be like that
right and then we just
have to do it where we present
this in full screen so you can go
right here and you can go
and hit present view and then you
can make it full screen right so
now there's no tab right there
and we would literally just go up
here and we would hit our loom and
i could do my camera
as my face i'm just gonna do for
the facetime camera and then boom
you guys can't see it right
now because i have obs running but
i could do a loom with this as
well okay but i think obs looks
better in almost all instances if
you're scared and nervous of
putting your face big like how i
did it
where it's half the screen do the
loom if not do the obs so that's
everything guys um i'm now gonna
go and finalize this and the last
thing let me make me big again um
stop this make me big make me huge
i'm now gonna go and i'm gonna
turn this into the final document
and the next thing you're gonna
see
is me producing it okay this is so
simple guys this isn't hard we got
this done in
a couple hours today nothing crazy
very straightforward not hard at
all right so
i personally think this is the
best route for you to be able to
get this stuff done
efficiently is assume that it's
easy don't assume that it's
difficult so next thing you'll see
is now
me completing this i need to run
home real quick and as you can see
my hair it's quite the mess right
now without this hat on so i need
to run home real quick and uh do
my hair because i don't want to
wear a client ascension hat in my
vsl it doesn't make much sense so
i will be back i'll record it
and that's the last thing you guys
will see all righty all the best
see you in the finished product
bye now