Alrighty guys, I'm going to show
you how to set up GammaDoc in OBS
so it looks super, super crispy.
So we're in OBS right now.
I'm going to start here.
I'll even just go ahead and delete
this
so we can start absolutely from
scratch.
I just wanted you to be able to
see my face.
It makes sense to have two videos
on.
So you're in OBS right now.
Okay.
What you're going to do
is you have a new scene.
You can even, let's just start
from absolute scratch so you guys
feel like
you're actually learning, right?
So we're going to have one scene.
Okay.
New scene.
And you
make this.
Okay.
Now what we do is we click this
little plus here, click plus.
Then we go to video
capture device.
Okay.
I'm going to call this camera.
You then choose the device.
Mine is called
the ZV-E10.
Notice if you use the ultra fine
camera display, it doesn't look
good unless you have a
really nice iPad or a Mac book
camera like I do.
This kind of looks half decent,
but at the same time,
I don't really feel like this
looks all that good.
Uh, I think that it's starting
from over
here too.
So it's my LG ultra fine display
camera.
You can use the FaceTime camera.
I don't really feel
like that is the best thing.
It's not bad, right?
It's not bad, but look how much
crispier this looks.
That looks so much crispier.
Impressive.
Very nice.
So I hit, okay.
Look guys, if you really need to
do it,
FaceTime's fine.
Like I'll do it even with
FaceTime, just cause all of you
guys are going to have
FaceTime for the most part.
You can see this doesn't look as
good as the other one, but all you
got to
do is hit this hit option.
I'm hitting option right now, and
I'm going to crop it in right
here.
Option
crop it in right here.
Okay.
So you can see now, Hey, look at
that.
I'm here and I'm on a FaceTime
camera and I have the lights on
lights are a little bright.
So I'm going to turn them down a
sec.
One sec.
There we go.
So you can see it works just fine
with the FaceTime camera.
Um, it doesn't look
as good though, as the other one,
which I'm going to show you right
now.
If I do another video capture,
where's the video capture?
There we go.
Another video capture device.
I'm going to go camera.
Good one.
Okay.
And then I go and I hit ZVE 10.
You can see in my opinion, this
looks, let's just do the
same thing.
Option, cut it, cut it side by
side.
In my opinion, this looks way
better than this one.
Now you may say, Hey, no, it
doesn't Nick.
I think this one's better.
Okay.
Well that's subjective.
So I like this one.
It looks better to me.
So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to delete this
FaceTime camera one, just showing
you guys that you can do it with
FaceTime camera and delete that.
Yes.
I wish to delete it.
And then we're going to go here.
Okay.
And as you can see, the camera is
right here.
So I'm going to pull in a little
bit.
So I'm a little bit more on it.
And now what I need
to do is I need to fill this other
side of the screen.
Okay.
And so what I'm going to do is I'm
going
to go to window capture, hit that
hit.
Okay.
And then what's the window that I
want?
Well,
as you guys can see, there's a lot
of different windows that we have.
And I don't think that we
need to do that, but we need to do
is not necessarily that.
Let me grab it real quick.
One sec.
All right, here we go.
So we have the display capture
open.
So I just put this on my other
display.
I have it happen.
Sometimes we're like the windows
won't pop up.
Oftentimes you just need to
restart
the computer.
Like if, if you didn't have OBS
open to start and you had the tabs
open first and
then do OBS, sometimes it doesn't
register it.
So I just did it where I put it
over on my other
monitor.
If you don't have another monitor,
just Google it, figure it out.
You'll figure it out.
I promise you guys, you're smart
enough for that.
So what I'm going to do now is I'm
going to take
this, right?
And we're going to make this fit
in our footage.
Okay.
So here we go.
So I want to make
this a little bit bigger right
there.
There we go.
And so you can see as I go
through, let's just test
real quick.
Look at that.
Okay.
Everything fits, but there's this
like unnecessary gap right here.
Right.
So let's bring this back over
here.
So there's just this unnecessary
back.
So what I'm
going to do is I'm going to go
option.
I'm going to crop this in.
Okay.
I'm going to crop this in a
bit.
We can still see if we go back
that everything's not getting cut
off.
Nothing's getting cut off
here.
Okay.
So now what we can do, let's come
back here.
We can expand this a little bit.
Okay.
So where you see these striped
lines right here, this is where
you're getting cut off.
So this is fine
right up until here.
I think even cutting this in a
little bit more, cutting this in a
little bit
more, we can make it a little bit
bigger, right?
So now we go and we can see
nothing's getting cut
off.
Nothing's going to cut off.
Right.
So now you can see, okay, Hey,
this looks good, but look at this.
You got this little purple bar
right there.
It doesn't look that good.
And we got a black
background.
That doesn't look that good.
Well, guys, it's super easy to
fix.
So here's what we're
going to do.
We're going to go to display
capture.
We're going to go here.
Okay.
So we're going to
properties right here.
Okay.
Crop.
Well, actually you don't even need
to do the crop that way.
You
can just do it this way.
So you can go option and then just
put it up a little bit, right?
No more
little purple bar from the, um,
uh, from the, the monitor and from
the actual tab.
And so now
what I need to do though, is I
need to make the background the
same color as this.
Okay.
So what
we're going to do is we're going
to click this and then we're going
to go color source and go, okay.
Okay.
And what we're going to do is
we're going to select the color.
We're going to make this white
because I chose white.
Okay.
And then here's the thing though,
guys, is we need to make this
fit right here.
And so we're going to go option,
keep it right here.
Boom.
There we go.
And we need
to make this fit right here.
So there we go.
Okay.
And now look, you could see, oh,
hey, Nick,
that's not the same color.
You're absolutely right.
So we're going to go here.
We're going to go select
color and look at this.
We have this little dropper right
here.
So we can pick the exact
shade of white and then we could
say, okay.
And so as you can see now, look at
how good that looks,
how to create a banger VSL for
your B2B service offer.
Bing, bong, bing.
And I can go through
my slides like that.
Isn't that look amazing.
It doesn't look amazing guys.
It's amazing, right?
Wow.
So super easy to set this stuff up
guys.
I think that this looks way better
than a loom.
If you're shy on camera and you
don't want to have your face front
and center and you're kind
of a baby, right?
Shucks.
But you know, I think that it's
the best way to do it.
And look guys,
even if I were to do it with
FaceTime, it's still look good,
right?
It's, it's going to look better
than a loom because everyone's
doing it on loom.
You don't know BS.
You're going to stand out a
little bit more.
Okay.
And people like when they can
actually see you, they know that
you're actually
a human being.
You're not just like hiding.
Okay.
So guys, that is everything for
today.
So super simple.
Another thing I would recommend is
if you have your mic, like me,
like if you have a Shure,
if you have anything like that,
you also want to go ahead and add
in an audio device.
So you're going
to go audio input capture, click.
Okay.
Same thing.
So mine's the Scarlet solo USB.
Okay.
And then the only other thing I
would do here guys is this, if you
go to properties or not on
property,
sorry, right here, this little
gears right here, you can see
there's this thing right here
where it says
audio input capture, right?
Um, what you want to do is you
want to make that mono.
I don't know why,
but for some, I'm not an audio
person, but for some reason it
makes it where only audio is
coming
out of the left side.
So we then also have this right
here though, this mic aux.
And so what we
want to do is we want to remove
this.
This is the mic from your
computer.
And so what we're going to do
is you're going to take this mic
aux, and we're going to lower it
all the way down.
So it will never
pop up.
All we're going to have is just
the audio from our, uh, microphone
popping up here.
So super
simple guys.
You can set this up in a couple
minutes.
I don't even do this for a living.
I'm not a tech person.
I'm really not.
As you can see, I was like
figuring out as I go here,
it's very easy.
I've recorded videos like this
every single time.
I'm like, oh, I forgot about
this for ever that super simple.
Okay.
But it's not hard.
So hopefully you guys found this
useful.
This is how you make a OBS camera,
uh, set up with your gamma doc.
So let's get started.