Alrighty guys, welcome back.
So we are in the production side
of things.
So I'm gonna be filming a VSL
today and I figured it would
actually just be best to literally
just show you guys how I film.
I'm in my office right now and you
can see I'm like, I'm just showing
you kind of the setup that I have.
But I want to show you from start
to finish how I would just set up
a set.
Okay, so there's two types of VSLs
you can shoot.
I mean, actually, there's endless
types of VSLs you can shoot, but
I'm only gonna be teaching two.
Not four, that's four.
This is two.
So two of them.
So we have a direct camera just
seated or you can be standing, but
I prefer seated.
Just so you can mess up a lot.
And so, you know, you want to have
plenty of wiggle room and not be
tired on your feet.
And then all of a sudden, like,
you know, it's an hour long shoot.
You're standing on your feet for
an hour.
Hey, you don't want that.
So I prefer sitting.
So I'll show you guys how to do a
D2C direct camera D2C.
And then I'm gonna show you as
well how to do a just more casual
style.
I call it Frank Kern VSL.
He was the first one that I saw
doing this where rather than
having this very professional
setup, he just kept it super
casual.
It'd be like him in front of in
his office, just on his iPhone,
holding it like selfie style.
And so I'll show you guys how to
do that as well.
So let's, let's just get started.
I'm going to kind of break
everything down for you guys.
So what we have right here is the
camera, but we're not going to use
this camera today.
The reason why is because normally
what we're doing is we are putting
a teleprompter hood on this and
then we're going to have this
phone as a teleprompter.
And he, well, there's a few
things.
One, I can't like film this and
then at the same time having the
teleprompter hood.
Um, so I was like, that doesn't
make much sense.
Um, but also, um, I want to show
you guys how to just do it with
your phone because I'm trying to
give you guys a cost effective way
to do this.
Not everyone has the benefit of
having a $1,500, uh, purely video
camera.
That's just really good at
shooting video, right?
Not everyone has that.
So I'm going to package this up.
Um, and I'm going to put this away
for now because we did not need to
have this in it.
And you know what?
This actually may be, oops, this
is going, this may be a really
good, uh, background prop for what
we're doing.
So, you know, we could literally
stick it up on the desk just like
this, right?
And boom, is that going to look a
little dumb?
Probably.
So I'm not going to put that
there.
Actually, I'm going to go ahead
and not use it as a prompt.
It was like the idea, the concept
of it sounded good, but the
execution was negative.
So I'm going to put this one away.
Okay.
And now what we need to do, let's
turn this around and let's like,
let's lower this.
There you go.
So what we have right here is my
lighting.
So there's a reason why I picked
this exact one.
So you can go, um, on Amazon and
you can buy these types of lights
right here, right?
Like these are the standard
lights.
Everyone buys.
When you look up photography
lighting, um, these are the lights
that come up, right?
These are hard lights.
This is a soft light.
You can convert a hard light into
a soft light.
They have kits for it.
Um, I just went ahead and I got
the best.
I don't like cheaping out on
equipment and I spend quite a bit
of time in production.
So it's useful for me to have just
the equipment, right?
Like I don't, I don't, I don't
need to, uh, I don't need to cheap
out.
And so I was like, I'll just get
the best one.
So, you know, these aren't bad,
um, but they are a very hard
light.
And so what you'll notice is that
when you're filming, you're going
to have these shadows underneath
your eyes on your, on your nose,
on your lips and your face.
Like they'll just have shadows on
it.
And because you know, I'm, if you
guys can observe closely, I'm
Slavic as fuck, like super Jewish
and European.
I get a big nose shadow and eye
shadows.
Cause I got this freaking like,
look how far in the sockets, my
eyeballs are.
So, you know, I, uh, I have
interesting facial features.
So I don't like the hard lights
for that exact reason.
So instead I'm actually going to
use this as kind of like a stand
and no, this is weird.
This isn't the conventional use of
this and my backpack out of the
way.
Um, but I'm going to do it this
So what I want to do is I want to
use for my backdrop, these guys
right here.
So I like these, these are good
for now.
So I'm definitely going to buy a
higher end replacement.
Um, but these are good for now.
These are a thing called sunlight
lamps.
Um, and so what you can see, and
I'll show you guys right now is
I'm going to plug in from a USB.
You just turn it on.
Okay.
And so I'm going to turn off the
lights and I'm going to turn you
guys over here.
So you can see, Hey, get out of
the way, Mr.
Microphone.
You can see what it looks like.
Kind of cool, right?
purple, green, orange.
You have this nice little line
right here like that.
And then watch this as well.
I can change all the colors so I
can go blue.
I can go orange.
I like orange, more orange, that
way more orange, purple, purple's
fun for work.
I like purple working green, green
and blue.
It looks like straight green,
blue.
Yeah.
So we got a lot of options.
So I like orange.
You can see me in the shadow.
I like orange.
So I'm going to go with orange.
Okay.
So orange is what I'm going to go
with.
Now, this light is not super
strong like this.
And so what I want to do is I want
to set up another one that's
hitting the wall just like that.
So I have a couple different
options that I can do right now.
I have two of these lights.
I could either set it up on that
stand just like that, or I could
just do another one on the other
side.
Now, I think just for simplicity
purposes, I'm going to do it just
over there.
You could totally have it where
both the lights are coming in like
that.
I'm just going to keep it like
right here.
So this is not a lighting course.
Um, you know, guys, there's
literal like college level
education that you can go through
for lighting.
And I'm not going to provide you
that.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to give you the bare
minimum that you need to get it
done.
And hopefully you're like, yeah, I
appreciate that.
All right.
So that is looking pretty good.
And we'll just.
All right.
And so you can blend the colors,
right?
You can do that.
I prefer not to just like orange.
I like orange.
Okay.
All right.
So we got those lights set up.
It looks pretty sick.
We got an interesting color.
So if I get out of the way, you
guys can see, we got this nice
color right here.
And what I want to do as well as I
want to lower it a bit.
So let's take these guys.
Let's see what it looks like.
We lower it just a bit.
We don't need as much on there.
We need it more right there.
Right.
And then we're just going to line
up these circles.
Boom.
That looks so much better, doesn't
it?
Than it being on the ceiling.
That looks awesome.
So now next steps would be my desk
light.
So, but I also installed into my
office setup.
You know, guys, you're not all
going to have the same setup as
mine, but I just figured I'd walk
you through mine.
I also have a lighting setup on my
desk.
And so you can see it flashes like
that.
Now with white, it just kind of
like murders everything.
Right.
So the only way I can change it is
on my phone.
So I'm going to pause this real
quick.
And then I'm going to change it to
the color I want.
Alrighty.
There we go.
And so we've got a nice, cool
orange backdrop.
Right.
You've got this LED light right
here.
You've got the lights on the wall.
It's looking really nice.
So what we'll do is we'll set up
right here.
What we want to see when I take a
seat is that there's no lights
hitting or there's no shadows
hitting that backdrop right there.
So I can talk and we're not going
to see any shadow work.
It's not going to be like we're in
Plato's cave philosophy joke for
my friends there.
There's just very, very simple.
The main thing that I like to
think about is I don't want
shadows in the background.
You can see there's not really
that many shadows.
There's a little bit right there
from the computer.
I'm cool with that because it's
mainly going to be right here is
the shot.
So I'm okay with a little bit of
shadows.
What I don't want is in the
background shadows like that.
And then I'm like sitting there
and it's, you know, I'm the shadow
as well.
That doesn't look good.
Okay.
It shows you don't know what
you're doing.
So you definitely want to do that.
Now let's get into the next steps.
I'm going to go ahead.
I'm going to turn on the lights in
here so we can be normal for a
sec.
But we'll definitely turn those
on.
So we will get to this lighting
right here.
This lighting last.
So you guys can see what it looks
like.
So next up is this right here.
This is going to be our
microphone.
So the microphone, I'm going to
link you guys all my equipment in
like one Google Doc.
Amazon links and everything.
But this is a Shure SM7B, I
believe.
Let's say it on it.
Oh, yeah.
SM7B.
Shure SM7B is like the go-to
microphone that all the big
podcasters use.
Everyone uses this one.
It's really good.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to set this up right
here.
Okay.
And then all I'm going to do is
just make sure that it's level
with my face.
Now, why do I use a mic?
Well, the audio quality of a mic
is a lot better than the audio
quality of, you know, your iPhone
camera, or even if you have a
camera inside or the microphone
inside your camera.
You have one of those handheld
ones like I do.
You know, the quality I found on
this mic is just like second to
none.
So I really like it sounds really
good in the videos.
And so that's why I use totally
not necessary.
This is absolutely an extra
detail.
But what I like to do is I like to
have it angled like this.
So I know that I'm speaking right
into it, even if I move around a
little bit.
Like the thing that's kind of
interesting about this mic is if
you move to the left too much, it
won't be able to pick you up.
You have to speak right into it.
So what I do is I just have it
like right here.
So when I'm talking, I'm basically
my, because my voice is going down
like this.
I am talking into it the entire
time.
You know, if you've got the camera
right here, blah, blah, blah,
blah, everything.
Okay.
So that's that.
Now, what are we doing to set up
the audio?
Well, that's where I'm already.
So check this out.
This is my board.
So what we have right here, this
is called an XLR cable.
So it's a little messy right
there, but don't worry about it.
Basically, this wire links into
the mic, right?
And then this links into here.
Okay, and then we just turn it on.
This is a Rode Apex Class A Servo
Biased Preamp.
So I don't know what the heck that
is, but this is just a soundboard
for it.
Oh, so I'm not plugged in right
now.
So let's go ahead and let's plug
this sucker in.
I need to get an extension cord in
here.
So go ahead and turn it on.
And all this is, is just the audio
levels for everything.
So we want to make sure this is
working.
So I'm going to snap right next to
this thing.
You can see those sound levels on
mic channel one.
That sounds good to me, right?
And then we have everything set
up, right?
So all I'd have to do is hit
record.
We're good to go.
Okay.
Does this make noise or still?
I think so.
Anyways, I'm going to have it on
the mic or on the headphones.
So here we are.
It's pretty much everything, guys.
The last step is going to be this
light right here.
Okay.
So I'm going to go ahead and just
show you guys what that looks like
from what we were doing earlier.
So let's go ahead and get you back
in there.
It's odd that the, uh, the iPhone
camera does not let you turn
around yet.
Like you can do that on Snapchat
and Instagram or you can do it on
the fucking Apple iPhone.
So let's go ahead on off the
lights, right?
Boom.
It's purple.
We don't want a purple.
We want an orange.
Cool.
And now what we need to do is we
need to turn on the lights.
So let's go over here, guys.
I'm going to show you this cool
lighting setup.
So I really like this because what
it does, put it right here.
I can control the percentage.
So look at this right now, the
room, like watch this, the room,
you can't see any of the lights.
So you can see the desk light
because it's really bright.
That's about it.
So like, okay, well, that does,
that's not what we want.
So what we're going to do is we're
going to go ahead and turn this
down quite a bit.
And look at the chair right there.
So what you can see is that as
we're getting darker, we're going
to hover it around.
4%.
Look how much better that lighting
looks.
We can actually see it.
And even if I go even lower,
right?
I go like just a little like that.
I could still keep a lot of that
good light in the background.
And also what I can do is let's
say I want to make it like
different lights, colors.
I could go cooler or I could go
warmer.
Right.
So because I'm using warm colors,
I would assume that that makes
sense, right?
To keep the light warm.
So I'm going to go ahead and do
that.
So I'm going to go ahead and take
this down to 4%.
4, 3, 2, right?
So let's see with 3.
You can still see me, but notice
the issue, right?
What's the issue?
This light is shining on my face.
So we need to scoot up a bit,
right?
And so we're going to be right
here.
Okay.
So our camera will be right here.
We'll be reading from that.
And that's pretty much it, guys.
So you can see now, the reason why
we use the soft light is so we can
have this nice backdrop and the
color doesn't fade out all the
way.
Like, obviously, I mean, just take
a look.
If we go to zero, it's brighter,
right?
The colors are brighter, but we
can't get away with that.
So we need to make it a little,
little higher.
So like 3%.
Okay.
So now the only thing that's left
is to set up our camera and to
record and to get going.
So I am now going to load my
script into my teleprompter and
I'm just going to go ahead and
record this script.
And so the next thing you guys
will see is going to be me
recording the thing.
All righty.
Here we go, guys.
So as you can see, I have it
loaded into my teleprompter app.
So it's very simple how to do this
next time.
Basically, we're going to go here
to our scripts.
I have a lot in here, as you can
see, and you're going to go to a
folder.
You'll make a folder, make a
script, and you just copy and
paste your script in here.
Literally, just download Google
Docs onto your phone.
Copy and paste the script from
Google Docs and teleprompter.
And boom, you're ready to go.
And so when you hit record, so I'm
going to turn on the rotate.
When you hit record, you can see,
hey, look, it's going to play.
And you can adjust the speed.
All right.
So this is slower, way slower, way
faster.
Okay.
Now, you can buy a remote.
I personally have a remote.
I think the remote makes this a
lot easier.
When you are doing a static shot,
like what I'm doing right now, I'm
sitting down in front of the
camera.
It's a lot harder to keep pace,
right?
But when you have, you know,
you're filming like this.
Let's say I'm filming a selfie
style video and I'm shooting it
like this.
You know, it's actually pretty
easy because let's say I hit play,
right?
I can slow it down.
I can be, hey, are you a high
ticket info product or coaching
business owner that's paying to
send traffic to a book call via
cell funnel?
Do you ever feel like you're
paying too much for book calls?
More than likely you are.
I guarantee you I can
significantly lower it, blah,
blah, blah.
See what I mean?
So you can slow it down.
You have control because your
finger's on it.
I actually, the trick I use is I
use my thumb.
I find that it's a lot easier to
use your thumb to film it like
this, right?
And it looks a lot more natural
because you're just holding your
phone, okay?
So you do that.
You can use your finger like this,
speed it up, slow it down, right?
However you need to do it.
So that's everything for the
recording and everything looks
like it's recording right now.
So when I hit stop, it's going to
go and it'll show me what it looks
like.
I can slow it down.
I can be, hey, are you a high
ticket, right?
So that is everything, my friends.
So all you got to do is you just
got to shoot now.
Okay.
So here we are now, we're about to
film this.
And what's the issue that you guys
noticed?
Can you see it?
What is it?
There's a shadow right there on my
forehead.
And so it's very clear to me that
I've got to change this a little
bit.
I'm going to move this in.
I'll move this in.
Now let's see if that same shadow
is there.
Almost hardly not.
You can see it.
I'll move my head.
Now looks pretty good, right?
So that's that.
So now what we need to do is we
need to film.
So now we're going to move into
filming.
And so the only thing I don't like
is I don't like this corner right
here.
I think this looks kind of shitty.
As you can see, like the wire and
like this.
So what I'm going to do is when I
record this, I'm going to just
film it like this.
But I can punch in in post.
So what that means is when I go in
and move into the video editor, I
can push in a little bit.
And so these corners aren't going
to be there.
And it's going to be more around
like right here.
Okay.
And I can just stretch it out a
bit.
So let's just get into right and
get right into filming.
And yeah, pretty much everything
that we need to cover on setup.
This is a pretty good setup,
right?
This looks professional.
It looks good.
It looks like I know what I'm
doing.
And it just looks clean.
That's it.
So let's go ahead and let's just
film the VSL.
And so the next thing you guys
will see is the VSL itself.
Are you a high ticket info product
or coaching business owner that's
paying to send traffic to a book a
call VSL funnel?
Do you ever feel like you're
paying too much for book calls?
More than likely, you are.
In fact, I guarantee you, I can
significantly lower your cost per
book call and make your VSL funnel
more profitable without touching a
single ad.
And if I can't beat your current
metrics within 90 days, I'll work
with you for free until I do beat
those numbers.
My name is Nicholas Verge, and the
way I'm able to guarantee this is
by utilizing my VSL optimization
system, which I've developed on
the journey of producing $30
million for my clients' VSLs.
Over the course of five years,
I've been in the trenches,
writing, filming, and working with
editors to produce VSLs with
celebrities like Jordan Belfer and
Alex Jones,
but also with numerous info
product business owners you
probably don't even know who are
quietly cleaning up seven to eight
figures a year.
This system I've created contains
over 65 possible split tests we
can implement on your VSL that I
guarantee you will give you a lift
in conversions.
Most of the time, all it takes,
though, is two to three split
tests out of the possible 65 for
us to see a dramatic change in
results.
I'll be sure to show you some
proof here in a moment, but real
quick, I want to talk about the
wonders this optimization system
can work on your VSL funnel.
I want to talk about who this is
for and who this is not for.
Okay, so this is for you if you
already have a VSL funnel that is
selling a product between $2,000
and $20,000 and your business is
operating at $100K a month
minimum.
This is for you if you're already
running paid traffic to your
funnel, whether that's going to be
Instagram, Facebook, YouTube,
whatever it is.
And this is for you if you already
have a sales team in place to take
on more book calls.
If all that checks out, awesome,
this video is for you.
If, however, you don't have a VSL
in place, if you're not operating
at a minimum of $100K a month, if
you don't have a sales team ready
to go, this video is unfortunately
not for you.
Okay, the reason I focus on
business owners who have all this
in place is because in my
experience, these are the people
that are most likely to see
results from my VSL optimization
system.
For example, this system has
worked wonders for my previous
clients, like Tim Sanders, who
runs an Amazon FBA biz op coaching
offer.
Tim came to me with a VSL that had
a conversion rate of around 3% and
was generating book calls for
around $300 a pop.
After implementing a round of
split tests into his VSL, we got
the conversion rate up to 11.6%
and his cost per book call down to
$110.
And this is what made it possible
for Tim to actually scale from
$500K a month up to $700 to $800K
a month consistently.
And then there's also my previous
client, Quasi Joe here, who runs a
coaching program that's a mix of
personal development and
spirituality as well.
Quasi's VSL had a conversion rate
that was hovering right around 2%
at a cost per book call at around
$300 a pop.
All it took was one round of split
tests with his VSL to skyrocket
his conversion rate up to 16%.
Okay, there's Courtney Fletcher,
who runs an e-com biz op offer
tailored for women.
She was already doing well, but
all it took was one round of split
tests.
She went from an 11% conversion
rate to a 16% conversion rate.
Want to know why all these
different business owners were
able to see such a significant
boost in their funnel performance?
Me.
No, I'm just kidding.
It's because they all suffered
from the same problem, friction.
So what I want to talk about in
this video is how friction holds
your VSL back from its full
performance.
But there's a chance you may not
care about that, right?
Maybe you're ADHD like me.
You've heard what I have to say.
You like my track record.
You see the value in having
someone like me run split tests
against your VSL.
If that's the case, you don't
really care about the problem or
my system or anything like that.
You just want the end result,
which is a better converting or
profitable VSL that brings in
pools of your ideal customers.
If that's all you want, you know
the deal.
You can click that button below
this video, fill out an
application, blah, blah, blah.
Book a call with me.
That's where we're going to
discuss what it would look like to
beat your current conversion rate.
But if you do want to discover the
overarching problem that's
plaguing your business and the
performance of your VSL, stick
around.
I'm about to drop some value
bombs.
Okay, so here's what you need to
understand.
There are wrong types of friction
and there are right types of
friction.
The right type of friction keeps
the wrong prospects that you don't
want from getting in your sales
funnel.
But the wrong type of friction
keeps the ideal prospects that you
do want from getting in your sales
funnel.
Think about this for a second,
guys.
The biggest businesses in the
world all focus on removing
friction from their sales process.
Why aren't you doing the same?
For everyday people needing to go
buy something from the store,
that's a lot of friction.
You have to get up, get in your
car, drive over there, go find the
thing you need, and so on.
Amazon made it frictionless for
people to buy whatever they want.
Another example is you used to
have to go to Blockbuster or
Redbox to watch a movie, right?
Netflix made movie night
frictionless.
You don't got to go to the movie
theater, no location, just at
home.
And back in the day, if you needed
to go somewhere and you didn't
have a car,
you either had to call a cab that
would take forever to get to you
or call a friend.
But Uber made it frictionless for
someone to get transportation
quickly.
Friction is what prevents people
from buying and taking action.
And I guarantee you, chances are,
your VSL has some form of
unnecessary friction in it, okay?
This is causing your ideal
prospects to not take action on
booking a call with you or buying
your product or service.
It could be that certain parts of
your VSL are boring.
Maybe it's that it's not very
visually compelling.
It's just a static camera shot of
you talking for 35 minutes.
And as a result, people get bored,
go back to Instagram, TikTok,
YouTube, visually stimulating
stuff.
It could be that certain parts of
your VSL script are not compelling
enough and the viewer doesn't
understand or see the value in
continuing to watch your sales
presentation.
They're like, how does this apply
to me?
It could be that the offer you're
presenting in the VSL is just not
compelling enough.
People are watching the video, but
they don't have a desire to book a
call or buy anything from you.
These are all different types of
friction, but the list is
literally endless.
So here's what I want you to
imagine.
What would it be like if we
removed all the bad friction from
your VSL?
If we made it so more people
actually wanted to stay and watch
your VSL?
If we prevented unnecessary
drop-offs from your viewers?
And if we increased the amount of
people taking action at the end of
your VSL?
What would that do for your
business?
You'd be probably checking your
sales Slack channel and see piff
after piff after piff coming in at
a volume you haven't seen before.
Checking your ad account, you'd
actually be happy with the metrics
you're seeing.
And you'd have way more revenue
coming through the door, but more
importantly, you'd just be more
profitable.
That means more money staying in
your bank account, all because
your VSL doesn't have any
unnecessary friction attached to
it.
Okay, so how can you remove a
majority of the friction inside of
your current VSL funnel?
Well, first things first, you've
got to diagnose the problem,
right?
Like I said, guys, I can't say for
certain what type of friction is
holding your VSL back from its
full potential.
The only way I'd be able to tell
is by actually watching the VSL.
And that is the first step I walk
every client through before we
even talk about running any split
tests together.
Because there's a possibility that
maybe your VSL isn't the
bottleneck in your sales process.
I can't say for certain until I
take a look at your business.
Okay, so what I'd like to do is
I'd actually like for you to send
me your VSL.
I'd like to watch it.
And then what I'd like to do is
create a complimentary VSL
friction audit for you.
We can discuss that together on a
call.
If I feel like I can help you, and
more importantly, if you feel like
I can help you, what I'd like to
do is take my list of 65 split
tests, pick three to five of them
that we can deploy based on the
friction I've identified.
And, you know, maybe my initial
split test won't give us the lift
we're looking for.
That's okay.
That's the case.
We just pick another three to five
different split tests.
Give it another shot.
Regardless, like I said earlier, I
guarantee that I'll be able to
beat your current conversion rate
in under 90 days.
That's more than enough time to
run one to three rounds of split
tests.
And I have yet to see a VSL that
doesn't see improved performance
after those one to three rounds.
It could be that we need better
visuals.
And if that's the case, I'm going
to put my team of video editors to
work on editing your existing VSL
to make it look way better.
It could be that we need a better
script.
And if that's the case, I'm
rolling up my sleeves and I'm
going to revise your script for
you.
I mean, it also could be that your
VSL needs more direct to camera
footage like this.
And if that's the case, I'm going
to book a flight.
I'm going to hire my crew and I'm
going to come to where you're at
and I'm going to film a VSL with
you.
Again, the only way for me to say
for certain what your VSL needs is
by doing an actual diagnosis.
This is why I don't charge a flat
rate because you can see from what
I've just explained, everyone's
VSL is different.
So here's how you can get your
very own VSL friction audit.
Look below this video, hit a
button, click that button, make it
an assessment, fill out the
assessment, see if it makes sense
for us to hop on a call.
And before you do that, I just
want you to really think about
this for a second.
How much money are you losing or
leaving on the table every single
day by running ads to a VSL that
has unnecessary friction attached
to it?
And this may piss you off a little
bit, but also how many of your
viewers are watching the first
three minutes of your VSL dropping
off because they were bored.
And then later in the week,
watching your competitors VSL in
full because it was compelling and
buying their product instead of
yours.
All these problems can be
mitigated by removing the friction
in your VSL.
You doing nothing and not filling
out an application for a VSL
friction audit ensures that you
will continue to suffer from these
problems.
Now, you go and try and solve the
problem yourself.
Well, let me ask you this.
What business are you in?
Probably not the VSL business like
me, but if you are the type of
person who wants to do everything
themselves, regardless of the fact
that an expert like me can get it
done better and faster for you,
all the best.
I'm not your guy.
However, if you do want expert
help, you want to ensure that
you're able to get better results
from your VSL in under 90 days so
you can have a more profitable
business.
Good news, I am literally
guaranteeing those results for
you.
All you got to do is fill out the
application down below, schedule a
time to chat, and we'll go from
there.
Again, if I don't think I can help
you, I'm not going to pitch you
anything.
If I've identified that your
problem is elsewhere in your
funnel, I'll just send you on your
way with a list of credible
referrals who can help you with
your specific problem.
I have sales guys, media buyers,
funnel builders, and more in my
referral network, and I'm more
than happy to share them with you.
But if I do feel like I can help,
I'll extend an offer to you, and
if it makes sense, we can get
cranking on producing a new VSL
that blows your old one out of the
water.
Okay, so what do you have to lose?
Click the button below, fill out
that application, book a call, and
I'll speak to you soon.
All righty, all the best.
Bye now.
And all righty, guys, that is
everything.
So if you wanted to do it just
like this, if you wanted to shoot
a video like this instead of
having a professional setup like I
have with like a backdrop and like
you direct a camera and
everything, you can totally just
do it like this.
You can do it with you filming,
walking around the office, you can
do it with you walking down, you
know, a street.
I like backgrounds.
Really good to do it in nature,
and too, if you want to do it like
that, a nice big backdrop, forests
or whatever, desert, whatever you
want to do, mountains, lake,
something like that.
Like pretty backdrop is always the
way to do it.
So if you're going to do it like
that, you know, don't just do it,
hey, if you're a book a call, VSL
funnel owner, like you don't want
to do that, right?
You want to have it where there's
some sort of a backdrop, some sort
of a scene.
So I like the direct camera
because I can do lights, all type
of stuff.
So that's everything, guys.
That's everything I got for you
today.
I hope that was useful for you
guys.
Again, you want to do it like
this?
Cool.
Just swap it out.
I would always recommend, though,
if you're going to do the direct
camera stuff and you want to look
like this, invest in good
equipment, buy good cameras, buy
good mics, buy good lighting, all
that type of stuff.
I think is the saying, right,
we're not rich enough to buy
shitty things because then you got
to buy it twice, right?
So might as well just buy the good
stuff first.
So I'll put together a list for
you guys of all the equipment that
I use and just some
recommendations and some stuff.
But, yep, there you go.
Minimum viable VSL production.
All right, you guys, all the best.
Peace.