Nice hey if you're a business
owner that sells a high ticket
product ranging from three
thousand
to ten thousand dollars and you're
already doing about a hundred
grand or more a month
i'd like to share with you an
email strategy that mimics what
people like alex hermosi
sam ovens and even gary v are all
talking about so if you want to
have a super loyal following
just like them listen up now this
definitely goes against what
pretty much everyone else
is recommending when it comes to
email marketing and that's because
i prefer to focus on long-term
thinking while everyone else is
focused on short-term thinking
kind of like investing so here's
the main point of this video your
email list should not be a
short-term investment for you it
should be
a long-term investment you've got
to think long-term with it guys
because the people you're emailing
on
your list aren't ready to buy
right now right well what most
people recommend doing is
basically pitching
them over and over and over and
over again until they are ready to
buy now does that work sure but
here's the question most people
don't ask what's that costing you
here's i'd like you to do go to
your email service platform active
campaign hubspot or whatever and
put a filter on it to see how many
inactive subscribers you have
meaning people who haven't opened
your emails in the last 30 days or
so
right then take that number and
multiply it by your average cost
per lead that you're seeing on
platforms
like high rose or your facebook
ads or youtube ads okay two
dollars five dollars ten dollars
whatever it
is multiply those two numbers
together and that's how much this
strategy has cost you thus far
because realistically you could
have probably cut that number of
inactive subscribers down by at
least
half had you followed the strategy
i'm about to lay out for you in
this video no one can have a
hundred percent
active subscribers right okay so
the best way for me to explain
this strategy to use like this
you've got a mailbox right a
physical mailbox at your house you
go and check your mail at your
house
or your apartment or wherever you
live and you take the mail out you
split it into two categories right
you have the mail that you're
actually going to open and then
going to
throw away okay so the mail that
you're throwing away that's kind
of like the emails that land in
your
spam or promo tab they never get
opened anyways you got your pile
of mail that you should open
because it looks important right
so what happens is that sometimes
you open a letter and you go ah
it's just a pitch you thought it
was important but it's actually
not so you toss in the trash right
well the emails you're sending
your customers are no different
than that they open the email
read it see it's a pitch exit and
after enough times of repeating
that process they leave right
they unsubscribe or they stop
opening it you end up in promos
they don't open your emails
anymore
well what most people are doing
inside of their email marketing is
just trying to squeeze as
as much profit as possible in as
short of a time frame as possible
now look this tactic can work
right it can make money it's a
volume game if you're getting
10,000 new leads every single
month inside
of your email list from people
that didn't buy or didn't book a
call from you from your funnel
it's
pretty easy for you to be able to
use automations and campaigns and
be able to squeeze out you know
10 20 sales out of it right that's
great works super well but here's
a question for you do you think
that the people on your list are
stupid seriously do you think that
they forgot about the fact that
you're selling them something and
that they don't know how to you
know go to your website or to your
funnel and book a call you don't
believe that right well then why
do you keep hounding them every
single
email book a call book a call book
a call book a call look i'm not
saying you shouldn't ever pitch
your email list what i'm
suggesting is to actually try and
form a real relationship with the
people
subscribe to your newsletter see i
have a different belief on where
the industry is going right now
we've
had this race to profits over the
last four or five years inside of
the info product industry
but now where we're going is a
race to the relationship people
are buying from the person
that they trust the most see
people have a natural resistance
to a sales process because people
don't
want to be sold guys they love
buying things but they hate being
sold things because people don't
like
the pressure of having to buy
something right then and there
this is where long-term thinking
comes into
play if we focus first on creating
an emotional relationship with the
person creating an actual bond an
intimate bond with that person
over the course of time you're
going to get more sales than that
pray and spray pitch pitch pitch
methodology because the people who
would have bought from
that needy methodology will still
buy from you using this way more
intimate style of email marketing
and on top of that you're not
causing people to get annoyed and
drop off your list they're
actually
still going to open your emails
and chances are over the long term
a lot of those people can turn
into
buyers so most people should be
running their email list like this
but they're not so why is that
outside of them maybe not even
understanding this well there's
two reasons i can think of one is
that
most of the copywriters and
marketers managing email lists are
not even capable of writing types
of
emails that build intimacy most of
them have zero eq whatsoever
they're absolutely awful at being
able
to connect with people on an
emotional level they don't
understand people they don't know
the triggers
that get people to actually want
to create an intimate relationship
with you and most of the time
they're not writing from your
personal experience they're
writing solely off of theoretical
concepts
they'll take some concept let's
say it's like how a house is made
and let's say you have a coaching
program where you're teaching
people how to build an amazon fba
business right so what the email
copywriter goes and does is he's
like oh you know what i'll explain
how to build an amazon fba
business
and how that is just like building
a house super lame guys people
don't want to read that they want
to
read about how when you started
your business you had a hundred
dollars to your name but you knew
you
could make it work they want to
hear about that cold lonely night
when you slept in your car because
you got evicted from your place
they want to hear about the time
you cried having to tell your kids
that you couldn't get them
christmas presents because you had
no money they want to hear about
the
first ten thousand dollars you
made and where you went to go
spend that money people want to
hear
about real stuff your experience
your story that's what everyone
wants to hear and i believe
everyone
has a story that's worth telling
and that's what creates an
intimate connection not
theoretical concepts
in an email so the other reason
people aren't implementing this
style of newsletter is because
they feel
like they have to go and write
these types of emails they can't
have someone else write them for
them
right i mean but you're a business
owner you don't got time for that
you have coaching calls you have
all sorts of meetings you have
your life and a million other
things that you have to do right
you don't have time to be writing
a newsletter every single morning
or every single night or whatever
it is well that's exactly why i
started inbox intimacy this is a
full ghost writing newsletter
service that is all about having
that intimate connection with your
email list by providing them
valuable content intimate stories
and the occasional call to action
80 of what we focus on is building
that intimate relationship so that
when we do pitch they're totally
bought in on what you have to say
right what we do is twice a month
you and i are going to get on a
call and almost going to serve
like a therapist for you and we're
going to talk about your life
we're going to talk about you
we're
going to talk about your business
we're going to talk about where
everything started for you what
sort
of limiting beliefs you have when
you were first getting started
what you thought was true but
later found
out was false all types of
questions like that we're going to
talk about that so i can help
better
understand you i'm also going to
go through the material inside of
your program and understand the
different concepts you're
explaining and ask you questions
about it i then take the
recordings of
these calls transcribe them and
take your words and use my magical
writing wizardry to write up
emails
which are then sent to your
audience and without a doubt the
emails are going to sound just
like you
i've done ghostwriting for tons of
different people like alex jones
jordan belford caitlin jenner
all these different personalities
i've been able to nail all of
their voices so i guarantee you
that i can nail
what you're going to do so i'm
kind of a chameleon like that so
here's the thing what i'm
explaining
right now is not for the
short-sighted person this is for
the person who's focused on a
long-term
vision it's for the person that
actually wants to build an
intimate relationship with their
email
list and they know that this is
what's going to be the most
profitable decision they can make
in
regards to their email marketing
so if that's you i would love to
have a discussion with you about
how we
can work together to be able to
start actually building a
relationship with your list and
stop
burning the leads you're paying
for so down below there's a button
you can click that'll take you to
my calendar where you can find a
time that works best for you to
chat answer a few questions and
boom
you're booked in assuming that i
think you have a good product
you're a cool person you sell
something
that's ethical and i feel like
you're a genuine person i can work
with i'll definitely reach out to
you ahead of time and let you know
that i'm looking forward to our
call if not i'll cancel the call
because i don't want to work with
you sorry that some people are
just like that but chances are
if you made it this far that's not
you so click the button below book
that call and let's talk about
how to build a real relationship
with your email list all right
talk soon bye