Are you making this major mistake
with your email list?
Hey, here's a guarantee for you.
I can transform your
underperforming email list into a
powerhouse for engagement,
conversions,
and revenue growth inside your
info product business.
Sound good?
Okay.
If that's the case, here's the
80-20 of this video.
Using my inbox intimacy
methodology, I will craft emails
that sound like they came directly
from you based on your content and
in-depth interviews that I will
conduct with you personally.
Okay.
And if you don't see a substantial
increase in open rates,
click-throughs, and sales within
90 days, I'll refund you in full.
Simple as that.
So here's a couple of questions
I'd like to ask you, which will
help you know whether or
not this service makes sense for
you.
Okay.
Number one, are you an info
product business owner doing at
least 100K a month selling
products
ranging from $5,000 to $25,000
utilizing a VSL book a call funnel
or a low ticket funnel?
Or number two, do you feel like
you're overlooking a gold mine in
your email list that you know
you could do a better job of
utilizing?
And number three, have you tried
working with copywriters, but they
failed to capture your
authentic voice or you've just
been stuck writing the emails
yourself?
Well, if you answered yes to those
questions, congratulations, you
are in the right place.
So what I'd like to do over the
next few minutes is explain to you
why most businesses' emails
get ignored, which results in a
atrociously low attribution rate,
open rates, and click-through
rates.
Okay.
And then I'd like to show you how
to easily increase your email list
engagement and its overall
attributed revenue.
And then if you're interested,
I'll show you how I can help if
you don't want to do this
yourself.
Now, the reason why people's
emails get ignored is actually
pretty simple.
Most email marketing falls flat on
its face because it lacks
personalization.
Okay.
Sending blanket one size fits all
messages simply does not cut it
anymore.
Okay.
Your subscribers are bombarded
with hundreds of emails per day
that are competing for their
attention.
And this is why most done-for-you
email services don't work all that
well.
They rely on templates, outsourced
writers, and a focus on sales over
value.
Now, the result for that is emails
that sound robotic, inauthentic,
and super spammy.
It's no wonder why the engagement
rate plummets.
So what's the solution?
Well, that's a great way for me to
introduce myself to you.
My name is Nicholas Verge.
I'm a direct response copywriter
who's been in the info product
industry for five years now.
And I've been able to produce over
$30 million working with clients
like Alex Jones, Jordan
Belfort, and many other
underground names who are quietly
cleaning up seven to eight figures
a year.
Okay.
And one of my main specialties is
writing email newsletters, but not
your average run-of-the-mill
pitch, pitch, pitch newsletters,
right?
My newsletters follow a
methodology I created called the
inbox intimacy method.
I don't just write your emails.
I immerse myself in your world to
ensure I intimately understand
your voice, your expertise,
and the way you specifically
explain concepts in your industry.
The way I do this is by conducting
in-depth interviews with you to
capture your unique
perspectives and industry
knowledge.
And then I transform your insights
into compelling emails that
balance educational content with
promotional material.
And this tactical balance builds
trust while keeping your audience
receptive and actively
engaged in your work.
I don't use templates and I don't
work with a ton of people.
This is what enables me to craft
high quality, bespoke emails
tailored to you and your audience,
which provide a ton of value to
your audience.
And this methodology prioritizes
building long-term relationships,
not just short-term sales.
Our focus extends beyond the inbox
to create lasting connections
through value exchange.
And this is what's going to help
you accumulate a way better
relationship with your audience,
which will result in more sales in
the long run.
My clients have seen astonishing
results from this methodology, and
I've even included a case study
down below showing how one of my
clients was able to produce
$930,000 in under a year
by utilizing this high-value
methodology.
Now, here's one last question for
you.
Do you want to transform your
email marketing by having me write
your emails with my exclusive
inbox intimacy methodology?
And like I said earlier, there's
no risk for you because if you
don't see a substantial increase
in open rates, click-throughs, and
sales within 90 days, you pay
nothing.
So if you're open to exploring the
possibility of working with me,
there's a button down below
where you can fill out a quick
questionnaire to discuss how we
can boost your email marketing
performance.
And after that, you'll be taken to
a page where you can book a
strategy call with me
to discuss whether or not this
service makes sense for you in
your business.
Okay?
I have to state this as well.
I only work with three clients at
any given time for this email
service.
It's not fake scarcity.
That is real.
A majority of my income comes from
one-on-one coaching, so I do not
stack dozens and dozens
and dozens of done-for-you
projects because I don't have time
for it.
So at the time of recording this
video, I only have two spots
remaining for this service.
So if you're interested in blowing
up your email marketing in a good
way,
click the button below to claim
your spot now before availability
fills up.
You certainly could do this on
your own, writing high-value
emails consistently for your email
list, which will take a ton of
time to craft.
But let's be honest, do you really
want to do that?
Answer is probably no, which is
why you should fill out that
questionnaire down below.