Hey, are you trying to navigate
the world of digital marketing and
direct response?
Maybe you're a marketer who wants
to improve their skillset, or
maybe you run a business
and you handle all the marketing
yourself.
If that's the case, you're in the
right place.
Okay.
I don't want this video to be like
a 30 minute long nightmare story
VSL or anything like
that.
So let me just cut to the chase.
I'm recording this video for you
to help you navigate
my homepage.
Okay.
But first things first, who am I?
Why should you listen to me?
My name is Nicholas Verge.
I've been in the world of digital
marketing for five years now
as a direct response copywriter.
During my career, I've been
directly responsible for
producing right around $30 million
in client results.
And I've had the privilege of
working
with all sorts of clients from
celebrity ones like Alex Jones and
Jordan Belfort to the ones
who behind the scenes are keeping
it low key and they're quietly
cleaning up seven to eight
figures a month.
Now I've worked on everything from
email automations to video sales
letters.
And I've worked with a wide range
of clients from the physical
product world to the info
product world.
I've been able to dedicate my
career to figuring out the world
of digital
marketing, specifically direct
response, copyright.
And that's what I'd like to help
you with.
And there's two ways I can help
you.
Okay.
So there's a done for you capacity
and there's
a do it yourself format as well.
If you're interested in finding
out more about what it would look
like for me to come into your
business and help you optimize
your existing marketing systems
or help you create new ones.
There's a section right below this
video titled agency.
All you
got to do is click that you'll be
taken to a separate page with the
video to watch.
That's going to show you next
steps for having a one on one
discovery session with me.
Now my done for you services are
not cheap.
In fact, they are reassuringly
expensive and my
packages start at $20,000 all the
way up to $50,000.
And my retainers start at $5,000 a
month
and move all the way up to $15,000
a month.
So if you're not comfortable
paying those kinds of rates
for a consultant to come in and
improve your business's ability to
bring in new customers,
well, probably it's not for you.
However, the products and courses
section could be pretty good
for you.
Unlike a lot of online gurus who
make courses that are vague and
filled with nothing.
I like to pride myself on making
extremely high quality courses
that are better than most
people's group coaching programs.
Okay.
It's really high quality stuff.
So you may want to
check that out as well.
But this video is not a sales
pitch for my programs or for
anything
like that.
It's to help you navigate my
website.
So if you're a business owner who
wants to work
together on a project, you can
click the agency button below.
If you're interested in the
products
and courses I have for sale, you
can click the products and courses
button down below.
And
if you're just interested in
learning more about me or wanting
to join my newsletter, you
can do that by scrolling a bit
further down this page.
Okay.
Oh, and if you wanted to follow
me on any social media platform,
pretty easy to find.
Just search at Nicholas Verge or
at
Nick Verge and you'll see me.
Okay.
That's a brief introduction to me
and what I got going
here on this website.
So that's everything I wanted to
share today.
All the best.
Bye now.