All right.
So what we have here is a
financial analysis of a lead gen
system.
Let me try to make this smaller.
So now what we have here is we
have automated cold email.
We have free work.
So I'm just going to quickly walk
you through these.
I'm going to give you access to
this sheet so you can fuck with
it.
You just got to make a copy of it.
So like what's going on here?
So this is simulating costs,
result projections and ROI
calculations based on automated
cold email.
So the bright green ones are ones
you can influence.
So let's assume we're sending 500
cold email.
And this will dynamically update.
So I think that to 800, all this
changes, right?
So we're going to assume $500.
I'm sorry, 500 cold emails per
day, 28, 70 days in a month.
This is what this comes out to in
cost per month.
Now, if we assume a 3% response
rate, a 20% positive response
rate, you get 30% of those 28
positive responses to book a call.
That means you got eight calls.
Your cost per call is $59.
You close at 20%, you close two
people.
So if your average monthly revenue
for each client, even if your
performance basis, this counts
your performance basis was $2,000.
You have a 70% margin and your
average customer stays for five
months.
That means your, your LTGP, your
lifetime gross profit per person
is $7,000.
It costs you $296 to acquire them.
Now this is not accounting for
your time.
This is not accounting for time.
So you have to understand that as
cold email is pretty time
intensive.
That means your LTGP to CAC is 24,
right?
So that's, that's like stupidly
good.
Um, now the, the problem though,
what most people don't understand
is, is when you have, when, when
numbers like this, like a response
rate is this low or a positive
response rate is 20, this severe,
like if you put, put five here,
this severely impacts the
cashflow.
So like, let's, let's, let's just
look at this if we're, if we're at
3%.
So what people got to understand
is like week, week one, because
you got your sales cycle, you
can't influence this by, by the
way.
I didn't, I did not make this
editable.
So you like, you pay for the
stuff, you have the two week
warmup.
So it's not even until
theoretically month six that you
start signing clients, right?
So 2,352 in week six, six weeks
later, right?
And then now week 10, you got
clients week 14, you got clients.
And then that shit goes all the
way down over to, to, to week 20.
You see what I mean?
So what that means is that this is
how this works out.
So month one, negative 593, month
two, 1800, month three, 4,000,
month four, 9,000, month five,
18,000.
So it's like, if you're running
this one, you go negative, you're
not making shit for six weeks.
And then even when you do start to
make something, it's not a lot at
all.
Month three, isn't a lot at all.
And you don't even start making
any kind of substantial return in
any capacity whatsoever until
month four.
You see what I mean?
And then month five is when shit
starts to get, this doesn't
account for churn.
Churn is not in this calculation
right here, right?
Now you can see over here, all of
the, all the influenceable
variables.
I put what they're influenced by
over here on the right.
So it's like a cheat sheet for
you.
But this is how this works.
So if you fuck with this, you can
see like what happens over 20
weeks,
because now if you send this up to
3000, like what happens now, now
you're making 52 grand over 20
weeks instead of 34 grand.
You see what I mean?
Like, this is, this is how this
works, but you just have to be
like severely cognizant of what's
going on here.
Now, now, as I said earlier, this
does not count for your time.
Like, and, and just like the
stupid fuckery that goes on with,
with, with cold email.
Like obviously cold email works,
but like, it's a pain in the
fucking ass to do that shit.
Like it really actually is to do
some high volume shit.
Now let's compare it.
Like, if you don't want to do
that, like, let's compare this to,
to free work.
So like, I got another sheet over
here for free work.
So now the mechanisms to reach
clients in this are manual cold
email, manual IG DMs, manual
LinkedIn DMs, and manual Twitter
DMs.
Cause they're all $0 each in hard
costs.
Obviously it has your time.
Now we can make some assumptions
here.
How much does it cost you to
fulfill the free work?
And this would be the equivalent
of buying leads on cold email or
ad spend.
You see what I mean?
It costs me $100 to create the
free piece of work, right?
Because you have to imagine that
you would outsource the creation
of the free piece of work.
So if you're a Clavio email agency
or some shit, and you're like,
Hey, I'll design you a free email.
Right?
It might, you might have to pay
your editor or your, I'm sorry,
your designer and your copywriter
a hundred dollars to get that one.
You see what I mean by this?
Now, if you do, if you do, uh, so
how do we, now the free work to
meeting, right?
Let's say it's 35%.
And then the people you do get on
there, they closed at 40% because
they already see your work.
Now they probably used it.
Right.
And now you're closing them for an
average of $2,000 a month.
Your gross profit on the 2000 is
70% on average to say for six
months.
That would mean that your lifetime
gross profit is 8,400.
And now you can fuck with this
variable by like one, how much
does it cost you to do it?
You know what I mean?
And then that influences the cash
over here.
So like 100, let's just go back to
this.
Now let's say if you're doing 15
pieces a month, you'd have to be
spending $1,500 per month.
And with these numbers, you'd be
getting five calls booked and
you'd be closing two people.
And your cost to acquire customer
will be $714, right?
Now, if you're comparing this
against cold email here, you got
to understand that if like this,
this shit, this right here, this
could very well be like fucking
1%.
And this could be like 10%.
You see what I mean?
So it could send your fucking,
like you would need to send like
such a substantial and then the
cost per call and the cat goes up
here too.
You see what I mean?
So you got to be cognizant of
that.
If like cold email isn't
specifically working for you,
you're like, okay, well, let's try
a different marketing channel.
You see what I mean?
So like let's try the free work
thing, right?
And now you can influence this.
But another thing you have to be
cognizant of is that you have a
sales cycle.
You see what I mean?
So like what happens, like week
one, losing money, week two,
losing money, week three, losing
money.
And at this point, because you're
a human, you're like, fuck, this
isn't working.
I've been doing this for 20 days,
spending my own money in my own
time.
And then finally, you fucking
close someone in week four.
You see what I mean?
Like that's how that works, right?
And then if we model this again,
it's month one, $1,400, month two,
$4,000, month three, $7,000, month
four, $10,000, and then $13,000,
and then $16,000 a month.
You see what I mean?
And this is calculating the gross
profit and the cost, right?
So like now, what stops you from
doing this though is this $1,500.
They don't want to sit here and
lose money for three weeks.
Cause you're like, oh, that's not
going to work, but it will, if you
know your numbers, if you just
know the numbers, if you just
track the numbers, you can model
what's going to happen.
You see what I mean?
So like, let's send this to 30.
What happens now?
Month one is 2,800.
Month two is fucking 8,000.
You see what I mean?
Like you can, you can influence
this stuff.
And this is, this, this tends to
be easier to scale.
And you can obviously mix these
two, and then you put a mechanism
to reach clients and it's like
automated cold email.
You see what I mean?
Now the only, the only caveat you
have to, you have to be cognizant
of here is that if you're doing
high volume cold email, you might
start reaching a substantial
amount of shitty clients.
You really only want to be doing
this for like fairly high level
people.
So you are going to do this with
cold email.
You want to make sure it's 10 plus
employees, but you really don't
want to be doing, you don't do
free work for people who can't
afford it.
Don't do free work for poor
people, but don't do that.
Some random person has a hundred
followers.
Don't fucking do that shit.
They have to be making money.
They should be making $10,000 per
month or more.
You see what I mean?
But you can just play with these
variables.
And like, what if I did literally
fucking three pieces of free work
a day, 90.
So that would mean you're spending
$9,000 a month to have this shit
done.
And like, let's say this was even
150.
You're spending $13,500 per month.
Like you legit, you go negative
fucking hard before you even sign
someone right here.
Look at week one, two, and three.
Hard.
Like real negative.
Like $10,000 negative.
Right?
But what happens?
Like you fucking rocket yourself
in month two, month three, month
four, month five, month seven.
You see what I mean?
This is what happens.
So I'll give you the link to this.
You just kind of duplicate it.
Just make a copy.
You're only going to have viewer
access duplicated.
Then you have editor access.
Only fuck with the green
variables.
You see what I mean?
Those are the ones that you can
influence.
And they're influenced by all of
this over here.
And that's it.
All right.
Love you.
Bye.