Okay this video is gonna be about
the tech stack required to run a
mass
outreach cold email campaign
because up to this point you now
know how to write
a really good email script and you
know how to make a good offer over
email to
get people interested the purpose
of this video is to show you how
to
basically reach out to as many
people as you physically can using
domains
inboxes ascending tool a lead list
basically different automations
and
software so that you can reach out
to thousands of people without
sending
emails one by one by hand because
nobody has time for that and you
know quite
frankly it would be miserable to
do this outreach one by one so
here we go right
first and foremost you need a
sending software like the one I
have pulled up
in front of me here you can either
go through list kit which is the
data
company that I'm a co-founder at
and Daniel also in the program is
a co-founder
at I'll give more details on that
later in the video but first
things first you
need to sign up for a sending
platform that can send you know
hundreds if not
thousands of emails a day on
autopilot like you see pulled up
in front of me
because these are the campaigns
that I'm running for my own
company list kit and
you can see since July we've sent
30 like over 50,000 emails
completely
completely automated and generated
you know hundreds of positive
responses and
leads in the door so sign up for a
sending tool like smart lead we do
have an
option for list kit which I'll
talk about later but first and
foremost you have to
sign up for a tool that will
actually help you send the emails
on autopilot
literally type this into your
browser sign up for an account and
you'll be off
and running on that front now
here's the really tedious annoying
part of cold
outreach cold email in general
which is setting up domains and
inboxes to send
emails for you because you don't
want to send cold outreach
messages from a
single inbox at scale because
that's the easiest way to go to
spam the business
email that you set up will be you
know marked as spam and you won't
even be able to
email customers or clients or
co-founders or employees you don't
want to do
that you never want to send emails
from your main business domain you
want to set
up fresh domains for the outreach
and what do I mean by this well if
you look
here our main business URL is
listkit.io my business email is
Christian at
listkit.io you'll notice none of
these domains are listkit.io
they're random
combinations of domain names that
allow us to set up hundreds of
domains at a time to
run the outreach right like
listkit try listkit join get
listkit use listkit
listkit LLC listkit co listkit one
like a bunch of different
combinations of our
business name with like prone or
prefixes and suffixes that allow
us to set up
hundreds of of domains and then
obviously you can't send an email
from a
domain you need an inbox so on
each domain is two inboxes one
under me and one under my
partner Daniel right and this
allows us to send thousands of
emails a day while only
sending eight emails per inbox to
stay compliant and under the radar
of Google and Microsoft
because the last thing you want to
do is wind up in spam and get no
responses to your emails
and basically have to start the
process over so you need a sending
tool domains and inboxes
And then the last thing is going
to be the leads.
Where do you actually find a list
of people to reach out to?
And that's where ListKit comes in.
We are a B2B database company that
has hundreds of millions of email
records across any industry you
could think of.
So let's say you're going down the
ads and funnels path and you want
to make ads for consultants,
right?
Just a random industry.
I would go into consulting as the
industry.
I only want to target people in
the U.S., right?
And just like that, I have a list
of over 800,000 people in front of
me that I can pull from.
You can filter based on industry,
employee count.
Like let's say I want to only
target smaller consulting
companies.
Okay, great.
Right?
207,000 people that fit my filters
so far.
Then let's say we only want to do
sales, marketing, growth, like
different keywords that the
business operates under.
Okay, cool.
So we now have 8,300 sales and
marketing consultants that I can
pull from to get a list of their
email addresses so I can reach out
to them and get them interested in
my ads and funnels, right?
Using the scripts that we talked
about in the previous couple
videos.
So literally as easy as clicking a
couple buttons.
Let's say I want 50 credits to
start.
I click redeem.
I'm going to be sent an email with
a CSV file of 50 email addresses
that I can then plug into a
campaign and reach out to.
How do I plug it into a campaign?
Well, pretty simple.
You go over here in the sending
tool that you sign up for.
You create a campaign and then
create campaign.
You're going to import the leads,
drag and drop.
I'll pull up a random CSV that I
have to show you how it works
because I pull from list kit just
about every day.
Okay.
So here is an example CSV file
that you will get from list kit
emailed to your inbox.
Once it's ready, you literally
download it, drag and drop it to
this box.
And you now have a list of leads
pulled into the platform, um,
ready to go.
And then I'll, I'll actually write
the sequences first and then
import the leads and I'll show you
how everything comes together.
So let's just say, um, I'm doing
the ads and funnels path and I'm
writing my scripts real quick.
You would just literally copy and
paste the scripts that you wrote
following my other video and paste
them into here.
Um, you know, we can, we can, we
can help you sign 10 clients a
month with an ad system, right?
I'm not going to, I'm just going
to go quick here to, to show you
what exactly it looks like to put
the scripts into the sending tool.
Um, I actually went ahead and
created five sample ads for you to
take a look at mind if I share the
ads here, right?
Let's just say all my, I put all
my variants in here, A, B, C and
D.
Um, I have the three-step email
sequence in here.
Okay, great.
Right.
I now have a three-step email
sequence with copy that I copy and
pasted from my Google doc
following the video that I made a
few, few videos ago, right?
Everything's ready to go.
The copy's in here.
I'm going to drag and drop my
leads.
I'm going to let these leads
import.
And that's pretty much all you
need to do to set up a cold email
campaign.
Like once you have the messaging
and the strategy pulled up in
front of you, you're basically 80%
of the way home.
You just have to set up some very
boring, tedious, technical stuff.
Um, I like to call it like the
strategy and the offer is like the
house and the foundation of the
house is the boring stuff.
The leads, the inboxes, the
domains, the sending tool, all of
the things in the foundation serve
as, um, you know, fuel to get your
message to as many people as
possible.
Right.
So once the CSV file is imported,
all I do is choose some campaign
settings and I launched the
campaign and I'm pretty much off
and running.
Um, and in a future video, I'm
going to show you how to basically
handle responses because people
aren't just going to come back to
you and say, yes, I would love to
work with you.
Like what's your, send me an
invoice.
I'm ready to sign up.
They're going to ask you
questions.
They're going to be skeptical.
You're going to have to overcome
objections.
Um, but once you get the campaign
launched, you're basically 90% of
the way there.
Um, okay.
So all the leads are uploaded.
The copy is here, right?
I'm going to go to campaign setup
and select my email inboxes real
quick.
Um,
Like, okay.
All my inboxes are here.
Um, we have a ton of inboxes
because we send a lot of volume,
select all of them, apply
selection.
Okay.
I've selected my inboxes, um,
campaign scheduling Monday through
Friday.
Um, you want to make sure that you
change this setting, max number of
new leads reach per day per
campaign, because if it's a
hundred, you're only going to send
a hundred emails in a day.
And that's going to cause massive
frustration when you're like, why
isn't my campaign sending enough
emails, which is very annoying.
Um, and then I always do New York
time for the time zone, save.
And then campaign settings.
Um, we don't want to track opens
or link clicks.
Just take my word for it.
You do not want to track either of
those because they basically set
off a red flag to the email
inboxes, Google and outlook that
you are a cold outreach person.
And we don't want that.
Um, and then you can basically do
a spell check here that
everything's set up properly.
Obviously I just put a bunch of
random stuff in a lot of the
angles for the sake of time, but
everything is set up.
If all your copy looks good with
the text replacements pulled in,
because you'll see this bracket,
first name, underscore name,
bracket, bracket looks like this
when it's actually ready to go,
because it's going to pull in the
prospect's first name.
If everything looks good to go,
you would just click launch
campaign or schedule campaign
right here and your email
campaigns would be started, right?
Simple as that.
Everything's ready to go.
Um, and then you'll move into the,
the mode where you're handling
responses, testing new ideas,
testing new offer angles.
So there will be more videos in
this module about how to test new
copy, um, how to do inbox
management and actually respond
back to people to get them on the
phone with you.
Right.
Because the only goal of a cold
email campaign is to get somebody
to say yes to a call with you and
then you book them in on your
calendar.
Right.
So those will be the future.
The videos that come after this is
how to actually convert calls from
your campaign.
Um, but real quick, you're
probably saying, how do I set up
these domains and inboxes that
you've been talking about the
entire call?
Um, and the answer is really
simple.
You can either do it all by hand
where you set up inboxes one by
one.
Um, and there's a really good
video from one of our colleagues,
Matt Lucero coming up next
directly after this video.
That will show you the process of
setting up inboxes one by one with
Gmail.
Um, it's a huge pain and it's, you
know, quite frankly, not worth
your time.
But if you know, your, your
budget's tight and you want to
conserve capital and you want to
save money, doing it one by one is
what I would advise to you.
Um, just because it's going to be
a lot of labor, but it's going to
be, you know, a very minimal
amount of investment.
Um, or you can come over to the
list kit cold email setup that we
have available where we set up the
entire process for you with
domains, inboxes, a list of leads,
copy, um, and the sending tool all
configured completely for you.
Right.
So instead of following the video
that comes next from Matt to get
domains and inboxes and signing up
for an outreach tool and doing all
this yourself.
If you're just like, I just want
you guys to handle this for me, we
can handle it for you, right?
Just come to this link.
It'll be in the description of
this video.
And basically all you do is choose
a plan depending on how many
people you want to contact in a
month.
Let's say it's 10,000 people a
Um, you would pay us an upfront
setup fee that covers the many
hours of labor, you know, required
to set up domains and inboxes and
the initial tech costs.
And then you just pay monthly, um,
to run the system.
And these monthly costs are very
similar to what you would pay to
run the campaign on your own.
Like it's either you do it on your
own and you save some money on the
upfront setup fee, or you pay us
the setup fee and have our team do
the labor for you.
So you can focus on other areas of
the business.
Right.
And then the monthly cost is
pretty much around the exact same
as what you would pay to run this
system on your own with the
domains, the leads, the inboxes,
the sending tool, right?
All of it's bundled up into these
monthly fees.
So completely up to you.
Um, if you want to dive into
Matt's video next and run that
process yourself, feel free.
If you want to use our setup and
let us do the two week process of
getting domains, getting inboxes,
warming everything up, hooking it
all up to a sending account.
That looks like this.
Um, basically a to Z, the link is
in the description of this video.
So you can sign up there.
Um, either way, we want to make
sure that you actually get a cold
outreach campaign up and running
as fast as possible because the
whole goal of this entire module
is to help you get initial leads
and calls on your calendar and
close deals.
So hopefully this was helpful.
This is the underlying tech stack
that, you know, powers a cold
email system to where you can
reach out to five, 10, 15, 30,000
people a month and get them
interested in your ads and funnels
or email marketing services.
So hopefully this was helpful.
I'll see you guys on the next
video after Matt.
Peace.