Okay, I could sit in a Google Doc
all day and show you different
examples of what could work
in a campaign, or I could pull up
an example of each offer path and
show you winning campaigns
that already exist and are
generating real results for real
businesses.
So starting with
email marketing, a client of ours,
who the guy is also a good friend
of ours, he's been in our
program for a while, he basically
does email marketing for
e-commerce brands.
And if you're
following the email marketing
path, this is almost exactly the
same service model that you
will be running with your
business.
So this interface is the sending
tool that we use to
reach out to thousands of people a
month on autopilot.
And this is what the dashboard
looks
like.
It shows you how many people
you've contacted, how many replies
you have, and how many total
replies you have.
So reaching out to 8100 people,
they've generated 33 positive
replies, which is a
very good output.
Um, I like to say that anything
over one positive reply per 500
emails is good.
And this
guy has one positive reply per 247
people contacted.
So, you know, crushing it, this is
a really good
metric to shoot for.
Um, and if we look here, you can
even see based on the AB testing
that he's running,
which of these angles is
performing the best.
So let's just go through the
actual messaging and see
what's working.
So, you know, if you, in the last
video, I was just going over
basics and examples of
what a good campaign looks like in
this video, I want to show you
from a to Z, what is a successful
campaign looks like with subject
lines, follow-ups, AB testing the
whole nine yards, right?
So here is
variant a of their campaign.
So half of the prospects will get
variant a, the other half
will get variant B, right?
Very simple AB testing, different
emails go out to different people
to
see which one performs the best.
Here's the entire email, right?
Hope you're having a solid
Wednesday
reaching out because we can help
you add 40 to 50 can revenue per
month for your brand offer with
email marketing that actually
maximizes sale and profit, right?
So direct offer that Daniel talks
about plus if you don't see 40 K
in 90 days in revenue, you don't
pay that simple offer and look
at what these guys did the way
that they built their puzzle or
their fishing line or whatever you
want
to call it is they did direct
offer guarantee.
And then they still used a lead
magnet.
So they used
a direct offer.
And then instead of pitching a
video, they just pitched a lead
magnet.
I even went ahead and revamped
your welcome series email to
optimize it for more revenue.
Mind if I shoot
over the design here, right?
So that's a pretty clever way of,
um, framing their offer.
They pitched
a guarantee 40 to 50 K in sales,
um, lead magnet, redesign your
welcome series email.
Variant one B is
very similar, but it's a little
bit different, right?
Actually, I don't know if this is
any different.
Hold on.
We can help you add plus.
Okay.
So these, these are very similar.
Let's go into one C.
Um, and also really switching up
is some of the, the filler as in
no generic AI copywriting or
inexperienced designers.
We even redesigned your welcome
flow to show you what we do
differently.
Cool.
If I share the design with you
here.
So when all of these variants,
they're saying the same
thing, you know, I, all they want
to do is get a welcome flow
redesign over to the prospect.
And they're
just mixing and matching puzzle
pieces to see which angle performs
the best.
They're literally
following the exact thing I was
preaching in the previous video.
Email two is similar.
Um,
so in their followup email,
basically all this is, is the
first email in the sequence goes
out to
Jennifer, right?
Hope you're having a great
Wednesday subject line question
for Jennifer
offer guarantee lead magnet, very
simple email signature, first and
last name, co-founder at
the business.
Um, if this email doesn't get
responded to, they send out a
followup email,
which is automated by this
software four days later that goes
out and all's the followup email
says
is Jennifer.
We redesigned your welcome floats
email to optimize it for more
conversions.
Mind if I share it with you here
so you can see what we do
differently.
Um, and that's the entire
followup email variant a and
variant B read it revamped your
welcome flow email to optimize it
for more
revenue.
Mind if I share it with you here
to see what we do differently.
It's funny how basic
I said that in the previous video.
So we do three email sequences,
email one, email two, email three.
Um, after email three, we just cut
it off and move on because people
aren't going to answer if they
don't answer in three emails.
The third email, I saw a couple of
things with your welcome series
email
that are damaging your
conversions.
So I revamped it to optimize it
for more revenue.
Mind if I share
the email design with you here and
three B is almost the same exact
thing.
So if you're in the email
marketing path, pause the video
throughout this, um, and just look
at the copy that they're using
for emails one, two, and three
along with the subject lines
question for Jennifer question
for.
So it's the
same subject line.
Um, pause the video, write down
the copy, add your own tweaks into
it and use these
messages in your outreach because
it's working for an email
marketing client of mine.
Now let's get into the
content side of things because
this client of ours sells, um,
LinkedIn content and ghost
writing,
which is very similar to what
you'll be selling.
If you're following the content
path,
I actually want to see which of
their email ones got positive
replies.
It looks like email one D is the
winner.
So let's see what email one D
actually says.
Um, okay.
Your competitors are getting leads
from LinkedIn and they're probably
not as qualified
as you are.
We write content that positions
coaches and consultants as the
go-to expert in their niche.
One client got 63 leads in 30 days
offer.
We write content that does X, Y,
and Z.
One of our clients
got this result.
Want me to send over a video
outlining how we would do this for
your company.
That's it.
Direct offer video pitch.
One of the puzzle piece
combinations that I showed you in
the
previous video.
Once again, cause it works, right?
So pause this, take a note of what
this person is
saying in the email.
Um, and we'll move on to email two
and three.
So two B and three B are each
doing
very well.
Email two B we help business
consultants eliminate the content
creation bottleneck.
That's
keeping them from scaling with
social content.
One client went from 12 to 50 K
months because LinkedIn
content brought him qualified
leads.
Want me to send over a video
outlining how we would do it for
you.
Same concept, pitching a video.
And I'm sure three B is similar as
well.
Who handles business development
for your company?
We help business consultants get
qualified LinkedIn
leads with content.
I recorded a video.
Mind if I send it over puzzle
pieces, once again, hook offer,
how are you, are you pitching a
lead magnet or a video?
And it works over and over again
for all of
the business paths that we offer
in this program.
Um, the signature, once again,
very simple.
First and
last name, company name, please
reply, apply no thanks if you're
not interested.
And the subject
line is, um, so in the email
marketing path, they used question
for first name as a subject line
in the ghost writing path and the
content path.
They they're using LinkedIn leads
for consultants.
They're using two things about
LinkedIn, um, company name, X
company, new pipeline, very simple
subject
lines that you don't really need
to worry about.
I'll throw a list of subject lines
down below in the
comments.
Um, okay, ads and funnels.
So this client sells lead
generation to real estate and the
way
that they're pitching their ads
are with, um, are with just
benefit based messaging.
So let's see which
angle is working here.
Um, first name X, your agency
name.
So if you're watching this and you
want to
make a good subject line, just do
Christian X email agency intro
seller leads, um, new pipeline,
right?
That's a really good subject line.
Another really good subject line
is just need seller leads,
need content, need email marketing
help, stuff like that.
Um, but let's see what the actual
message says.
We've helped hundreds of real
estate agents or investors find
sellers over the past five years.
Our leads come from people
actively looking to sell their
properties, giving you higher
conversion
rates than cold prospects.
We compete on price and volume.
So you get more leads for less
money.
Interested in seeing what leads we
have in your area.
This is a good call to action that
I haven't talked
about yet.
Instead of pitching a lead magnet
or a video, I mean, this is a lead
magnet, but interested
in seeing what leads we have
available in your area that create
that intrigue is getting people
to say, yeah, I want to learn
more.
Cause what leads do you have?
I'm very interested.
Right?
So
direct offer.
We help investors find sellers.
Good call to action.
Do you want to see what leads
we have available in your area?
Right?
Same thing with email too.
Most companies charge premium
prices for low quality prospects,
but we compete on price and
volume.
Our leads are motivated homeowners
looking to sell, giving you better
conversions and cold outreach.
Mind if I send over our current
pricing and inventory?
Thanks name of the business or
first and last name, name of the
business.
Right?
Um, once again, the puzzle pieces
are the same, no matter which
service you're selling,
right?
Email three who handles lead
acquisition for your real estate
deals.
We provide high quality
seller leads to investors.
Um, we're helping several
investors get motivated seller
leads this month.
I've put together our current lead
selection and rates for your
market.
Would it be valuable if I share
that with you here?
So if you're running, um, ads and
funnels as a, uh, you know, agency
path,
pause this and check out what's
working for this specific
business.
Because in this case,
they're not even mentioning the
fact that they're running ads or
just saying what they can get for
the business motivated seller
leads, dental leads, um, whatever
type of business model you're
reaching
out to.
It could be an agency.
You could be reaching out the
software.
You could be working
with consultants.
Just take this, you know, keep
this in mind when you're writing
your emails,
you can still do a lead magnet
approach and say, Hey, I put
together a list of five ad scripts
or a list
of five templates or a funnel
build out.
That's still going to work, but
you can also go benefit
heavy and say, Hey, we can get you
25 seller leads in your market
this month, fully guaranteed,
or you don't pay.
Um, you know, do you want to see a
video?
So I'm just giving you examples of
campaigns that are actively
working.
So you see real world applications
of what I just taught you on the
previous video.
If you want to go off on your own
and try new stuff by all means,
please do.
But I'm just showing you what's
worked for actual business owners,
um, in our client base.
So
AI automations, a lot of you, you
know, chose the AI automations
path probably, and you want to see
what's working for that, um,
agency path over cold email.
Here you go.
We can guarantee you five new
clients a month with our AI sales
system.
We use N8N chat GPT and make to
automate nurturing,
follow-ups and meeting scheduling.
So your team can focus on closing
deals.
I created a quick video
showing you exactly how this
works.
Do you want to see it?
Same principle that I've been
showing you the
whole time, direct offer video
pitch, go for the, the, the
response, right?
Here's a different way to, to
structure the same thing.
I created a video demonstrating
how our AI
sales system helps companies sign
five extra clients every month.
Guaranteed.
The video shows
how we use N8N chat GPT and make
to automate your qualification and
follow-ups.
Do you want to see
the demo?
So here, I mean, hopefully this
video gives you context.
Like the video that I did
previously
showed you the templates of how to
write good cold emails.
This video shows you the actual
cold emails
in action.
Like here's a good, I want to go
through the inbox here real quick
to show you what prospects
will actually respond with when
you use these templates.
So this is the campaign.
Let's go to interested.
Okay.
Here's the email marketing path
with actual responses in their
inbox.
Um,
I read it just now.
My week is usually short.
I'm making this for review
next week when I have more time.
Okay, great.
Um, this guy said, would love to
have a call about this.
Let me know.
Good response.
Daniel said,
can you give me a ballpark pricing
structure?
Um, it looks great.
Stuff like that.
Jay said, we will contact you
after they've had time to review.
Amy said, okay, yes, please.
So like you can see when you have
a really good pitch with a lead
magnet or a video or a redesign
of an email template, people will
respond with interest and they
want to learn more from you.
And they're actually excited to
hear from you, even though you're
a complete stranger.
Sure.
Go ahead.
Thanks.
Exclamation point.
They're excited.
Sure.
Good answer.
Linda said,
okay, I'll bite.
I'd love to see your improvements
to my welcome email.
Corey said, sure.
Would love to see it.
Janice said, um, okay, they can't
afford it.
That's not our
fault.
Adam said, feel free to send it
over.
Right.
So you guys, like I'm giving you a
behind the
scenes look of successful cold
outreach campaigns that my clients
are running with the exact
services
that you are selling.
All you have to do is replicate
what they're doing.
Go back in the video,
pause it, see what they're using
in their scripts, model your
scripts after their scripts.
Don't copy them word for word.
Think on your feet and you will be
able to get responses in your
inbox
that look like this.
I'll make a video going over the
technology stack.
So you actually,
you know, understand what the
hell's going on here.
Like, what are all these
responses?
What do I do?
How do I get people on the phone?
We will dive into that.
I'm just trying to build
the foundation for you of how to
write really good outreach
messages that actually get
answered.
So in the next video, I'm going to
go over, um, how to use AI to
write your scripts, because if
you're
watching this, like I said, I
wanted to give you, um, the, the
understanding of the actual skill.
I wanted to teach you how to
actually write cold outreach
messages before I show you how to
use AI,
because if you're using AI without
the actual skill underneath,
you're not going to know if the AI
is
giving you good or bad outputs and
it's going to be pointless.
So let's dive into the actual AI.
So you can basically supercharge
your messaging and create it in
seconds, um, with automation,
even though I just gave you
winning scripts.
Um, if you want to test new stuff,
this AI will show you
exactly how to do it.
So let's dive into the AI
copywriting video coming up next.