Okay, let's dive in.
So in this video, I'm going to
show you how to number one, create
a good offer for cold outreach and
number two, pitch that offer in an
email or a DM that
gets people interested in learning
more about what you do.
So up to this point, you've seen
Daniel's videos on offer creation.
Keep what he said in mind when you
watch these videos
because the idea of an offer,
right?
30 calls a month, 10K in revenue,
10 new podcast appearances,
100,000 followers on LinkedIn,
whatever the offer is, is great.
But I also want to show
you how to create an offer around
a lead magnet or a free piece of
work or a service delivery
that will get people interested in
hearing what you have to say.
Even if you're a brand
new business owner, even if you
have no past experience and you
have no case studies, because
if you're watching this, once
again, that's probably the case
for you.
So I'm going to
show you how to get around the
fact that you're a complete
beginner and have, you know,
basically
build trust with established
business owners, even though
you're brand new to the business
world, right?
So here is how I am going to, you
know, basically break this down.
I'm going
to do, I'm going to write a cold
email and a cold outreach script
for every single offer
in here one by one, and I'll break
it down.
So if you want to go to your
specific agency
path, feel free to skip ahead in
this video.
If you want to just consume this
entire video
and learn the process of writing
cold outreach, which I would
highly recommend, please just
sit down, put this on 1.5 X speed
and watch me go through every
single agency path.
So
you can get a feel for the process
that I follow because it's pretty
much the same thing every
time, but just different, um, you
know, circumstances based on
what's being sold.
So let's dive in first ads and
funnels, right?
You are selling somebody, um, on
Facebook ads,
funnel creation, the whole nine
yards of generating leads with
paid advertising.
Um, so what are
some of the potential lead magnets
that I can create here?
Potential offers lead magnets,
right?
What can I possibly pitch to
somebody to get them interested in
hearing what I have
to say?
Well, sample ad creatives, right?
What does this mean?
You can reach out to a business
owner and say, Hey, I can create,
um, you know, five ad scripts for
you.
Let's do ad scripts,
right?
Sample ad scripts, sample ad
creatives, right?
Um, add templates, a free funnel
build
out.
Um, and let's just keep it right
there.
Let's keep it simple for now.
Basically what
I'm doing is picking out
bite-sized services that I can
offer to a business owner for free
to get them to say yes and trust
me and let me, you know, prove
myself as a service provider.
And in this case, an ad and funnel
marketer, um, to then get them on
the phone, you know,
to sell them on my services.
So what would this look like?
I created a, you know, a swipe
file
of five high converting ad scripts
for you to take a look at using
the, um, you know, case studies
on your website in the actual ad
body.
Mind if I share the file with you
here or the scripts
with you here, this is a cold
outreach message.
You could use this two line thing,
this two line
script right here and go DM it to
30 people and cold email it to a
thousand people.
And I would
like to bet that you would get
somebody to raise their hand and
say, yes, I want to learn more.
Why?
Because you're offering free
services upfront to a business
owner.
You're not asking for anything
in return.
And all they have to do is say,
yeah, I'll take a script that
gives you the green light
to go out and create five really
good ad scripts.
It doesn't have to be five.
It can be three
ad scripts for a business owner,
um, to get them interested in what
you sell, right?
Key thing to note when I'm
pitching this lead magnet, a free
service delivery is called a lead
magnet in the marketing world.
Um, just like when you walk into
Costco and they offer you a free
sample, that's a lead magnet.
Um, you don't have to pitch three.
You could pitch
five.
You could pitch 10.
There's no rules.
You could pitch one if you want.
I just like to do
five or three because they're
clean numbers.
Um, the key thing to note here is
the ad scripts are
not written yet.
You don't have to go out and
create the five ad scripts for the
entire list
of leads in your campaign.
You can just send this message out
to as many people as you want.
And then
whoever answers you, then you go
out and create the ad scripts for
those specific people that have
showed interest in what you're
pitching them.
Right.
Um, so that's a sample ad scripts,
lead magnet
ad creatives, which is like the
video, um, or the static ad,
right?
What you actually see on the
Facebook feed.
Um, I created five sample.
Let's just say I made, I made five
sample ad creatives
for you, um, using the graphics
and testimonials on your site as a
guide.
Um, mind if I share the
creatives here so you can test
them out on Facebook.
Same.
It's like the, the formula is very
simple.
Once you have the lead magnet in
mind, you just say, Hey, I created
a list of scripts, a sample ad
creative, an ad template, a free
landing page funnel.
And then you just ask if they want
to see
it.
And that's really all it comes
down to with cold outreach to get
somebody interested.
I'll go
into some examples in a later
video, but this is all it really
takes to get good at cold
outreach.
And you're probably watching this.
Like, is this dude for real?
I thought I have to use
like the, the pain point framework
and the, the storytelling
framework and all this other stuff
I see online to get people
interested.
The best outreach messages in the
world are extremely short
and to the point, like two
sentences max.
So what you're seeing in front of
you, these two sentence
scripts are what work the best in
the market based on thousands of
emails that I've sent over
the past couple of years.
It's crazy to believe, but this is
the case, right?
So all of these,
if you're, if you're following
this agency path with, which I
would say a lot of you probably
are,
basically you can test all of
these and see which one does
better.
And then just offer it over and
over and over and over again,
until you have a client, five
clients, 10 clients, right?
At,
you know, add templates.
Hey, I put together, um, a library
of ad templates that you can,
use, um, on, I don't actually like
add templates that much at all
because you can't make it specific
to their business.
So honestly, one of these three,
um, lead magnets is going to work
the best
for ads and funnels.
I put together, um, a sample
funnel for you, um, with, with
your case studies and
testimonials listed out on the
page.
I guarantee this funnel
out converts your existing website
in terms of books, calls and
conversions or in close deals.
Mind if I share a quick video
breaking down the funnel for you?
Mind if I send over a link to the
funnel and a quick video breaking
it down
for you?
Boom.
Right.
There are, you just in probably
seven minutes, you watch me come
up with
three separate lead magnet scripts
that you can go out and use on
Instagram DMS on LinkedIn, um,
over cold email.
Um, and it really is that simple.
Why am I starting here?
Because I want to get you
in the mindset of, okay, how do I
offer some sort of upfront value
to a business owner to get them to
say yes to what I'm trying to
offer them and get the
conversation started all
throughout the rest of
these videos.
I will show you how to actually
lead this conversation towards a
sales call and a closed
deal.
But for right now on this video,
the only goal that we have, you
and I, the only goal that we're
striving towards is getting
someone to raise their hand to
your message and say, yes, please.
I want to
learn more.
That's it.
That's the only thing we're
worried about right now.
Um, now actually I lied.
We can do a video audit.
So when I'm using, when I'm
writing, uh, scripts for any
offer, I either go
down one of two paths.
I either pitch a free service
delivery, like an ad script or an
ad creative or a
funnel, or I pitch some kind of
video.
What do I mean by that?
Here's what I mean by that.
Hey Christian, I was checking out
your website and I noticed a few
things
with your landing page that may be
costing you conversions from
actually, okay.
So this isn't the case of you're
building them a funnel.
I recorded a quick video
video breaking down the causes and
how to fix them.
Mind if I share the video here.
So what is this?
I'm basically critiquing their
existing website.
And then once they say, yes, I'll
see the
video.
That is when you pull up their
website.
Like, let's say I'm critiquing,
let's say I'm critiquing
list kit.
Um,
and I'm a co-founder at list kit.
So let's say I responded to this
message.
Oh, Hey Tom, that sounds good.
Like I'll take a video.
You would come in here, fire up a
video going over my website and
then show them the
sample funnel that you built out
for them and say, Hey, instead of
using your website to generate or
drive
leads from your ad campaigns, you
can use this funnel instead.
Right?
My camera just died.
Give me a second.
Okay.
My camera just died mid video.
Um, but what I was saying is
you're basically picture this as
like
you're throwing out a fishing line
with some bait on it.
And all you want is a person to
bite the bait
and take the bait and say, yes,
I'll learn more.
And then you can figure out
everything after, right?
Um, basically getting them to say
yes and then opening a
conversation and then you can
actually
go out and fulfill, make a, make a
funnel for them, make a video for
them and get them to be like, wow,
this is really interesting.
Let's hop on a call so you can,
you know, sell me on your
services.
Hopefully that all makes sense.
Um, now on the flip side, instead
of pitching a lead magnet,
we can just go right for the
offer.
Like Daniel has been preaching to
you guys earlier
in this program, direct offer
templates.
Instead of going for a lead
magnet, um, you can just go for a
direct offer, something that looks
like this.
Hey, Christian, um, saw you're the
founder at list kit.
We can generate you 15 new clients
in the next 60 days with a, um,
Facebook ad campaign guaranteed,
or you do not pay.
This is the classic straight to
the point offer that Daniel has
been preaching
to you guys.
Um, you don't need to manage or
you'll have everything set up for
you.
Um,
ad creatives, meta ads, manager, a
funnel page, tracking pixel,
ETC.
You just take calls with the
leads.
We from
We book from the ads mind.
If I share a quick video, um,
going over and add strategy I had
in mind for you, right?
So what am I doing here?
Instead of pitching
a free deliverable ad creative
funnel ad script, I'm pitching my
services directly using the offer
framework that Daniel has taught
you previously in this program, 15
new clients in the next 60 days
guaranteed, or you do not pay.
You get everything set up for you.
Ad creatives, meta ads manager,
a funnel page tracking pixel.
You just take the calls we book
from the ads.
Mind if I share a video
going over an ad strategy I had in
mind for you, right?
What you guys will start to see is
cold outreach is basically like a
puzzle.
Like this is a puzzle piece.
This is a puzzle piece.
And this is a puzzle piece.
You can just plug and play
different things until you find a
winning piece of copy.
Cause like you could test this out
and it could get zero responses
and you have to test something
new.
All you have to do is plug and
play a different puzzle piece.
Like let's say this, let's say
this
message isn't working at all.
Like it's not getting any
responses.
You're not hearing back from
anybody.
You can just take these puzzle
pieces out and plug in this puzzle
piece.
Mind if I share a quick video
going over the ad creatives I had
made up for you, right?
So literally by deleting one
sentence and changing the call to
action here, I now have a new
message that I can go pitch to
people.
So like
The main puzzle pieces of cold
outreach are
What am I offering?
Is it a lead magnet?
Is it a video?
Is it a direct offer?
And then how am I pitching it?
Am I pitching a video?
Am I pitching a link to a funnel?
Am I pitching
the scripts?
Like what am I actually offering
as the next step that somebody can
say yes or no to
to get them interested in what I
have to offer?
Notice how it's never a statement
at the end.
Every email that you ever send
should end in a yes or no
question.
Mind if I send this over?
Would you be open to seeing this?
Interested in checking out a quick
video going over an ad strategy I
had in mind for you.
All of these angles no matter what
you try are going to
Have a pitch at the end a yes or
no question to get people
interested.
That's a given, right?
Hopefully this is making sense
If you're worried about things
like subject lines
Don't worry.
They're inconsequential.
I'll break it down to you in the
next video
But i'm just trying to get you to
understand
The mindset around cold outreach
and how to say things over email
that will get a random stranger
To raise their hand and say yes to
what you're selling right email
marketing very similar service
Let's start with the lead magnets
once again because I want to
follow the same you know principle
for all these
Lead magnets sample email flows
sample
Um email designs a free
Email flow build out and a video
audit because you can just audit
their existing email stack, right?
So let's go into each of these
Starting with sample email flows I
created a swipe file of five
sample email flows
For you to take a look at using
your best customer reviews
As
The highlights of each email
Mind if I share the
Flows here to see if this might be
interesting
Boom that's a lead magnet
Sample email design
um
I put together
A sample email design template
You can use in your welcome flow
promotional
Emails and black friday cyber
monday
Sale coming up soon
Mind if I share the design
template
With you here
Same principle i'm offering
something up front that's valuable
and free and seeing if the
prospect bites to learn more
A free email flow build out.
Hey, I created a three-step
Klaviyo
Flow
Or three-step welcome flow
For your brand
Um
You know focused on your customer
Reviews and top selling
Products
You know not relying on discounts
Interested in checking out the
Email flow to see if this might be
Worth a chat
There you go
Email marketing three different
lead magnets that you can use to
go out and get people interested
in learning more about what you
sell
Right
Let's say I want to do a video
audit
Hey, I opted in to your email list
and noticed a few things that are
Likely hurting your conversions
with new customers
I recorded a quick video breaking
down the causes and how to fix
them
Mind if I share the video here
Okay, great
I now have four different
variations of the same strategy
that I can go out and test in the
marketplace
To get an e-commerce brand or a
software company to say okay, sure
I'll bite and I'll take the email
template the flow the video right
Now let's say you want to go for a
direct offer like daniel preaches
instead of
A free lead magnet we can do that,
too
Right
Hey christian, um
I you know we can help you
Generate
50k in sales from your email list
In the next 60 days guaranteed or
you don't pay me
Your entire klaviyo
Account will get an overhaul
With redesigned welcome flows
Re-engagement
Flows and emails designed to boost
Your average order
Value
Interested in checking out
A quick video going over
A
Interested in checking out a quick
video going over a
Klaviyo or an email marketing
Strategy I had in mind for you
Right, so instead of going for the
lead magnet i'm going for a direct
offer
Right and you can mix and match
this however you want
You can change what your guarantee
is you can change what you're
offering like there
To reiterate there are no rules
with what you say in the email you
can offer whatever you want
Your only concern is figuring out
what are the combinations of
sentences that are going to get
people to raise their hand and say
yes
This sounds good.
Tell me more.
That's it.
That's all you're looking to do,
right?
Is it going to take some patience
and some testing probably
But that is you know, this is
going to be your main focus early
on as a business owner
Is just figuring out what you're
saying in the emails and in the
dms to get people to say yes
Right, maybe it's 50k in sales
guaranteed.
Maybe it's
You know
100 new customers a month.
I don't know what that is going to
be because i'm not
A genie you're gonna have to go
figure that out once you launch
your campaign
And i'm going to show you some
real world examples
Of each of these services in
action with our clients
Because we do have clients that
are getting results already from
cold outreach with all these
Different services.
Okay, so moving on
So
Lead generation
If you're watching this from the
lead generation path
Please refer to the lead
Generation path in the learning
platform
So if you're here from the lead
generation path, I basically
already went over
Every single video in this module
in your path
Like everything is covered
In
I'm not going to go into it now,
but every single piece of
information here is already
covered in the lead generation
path
Because your entire business model
is cold outreach.
So you have to get really good at
it
So if you're watching this from
any of the other paths
I would also recommend checking
out the lead generation path in
your free time
Because that's my most in-depth
training
With tons and tons and tons of
content
On how to get good at cold
outreach, right?
So even if you're selling a ai
automation or ads and funnels or
email marketing
It's still in your best interest
to get really good at lead
generation as a service
Because that's how you're going to
generate leads for your own
business, right?
So
If you're here from the lead gen
path, go watch the videos that are
in your path
And if you're watching this from a
different path
I would recommend still checking
out the lead gen path
Just because of how good it is
with the content.
So
Moving on to content
Right.
What are your possible lead
magnets for a content business?
Pretty simple sample linkedin
posts
Sample blogs
Short-form video scripts
Social media profile audit, right?
It's the same couple of things
over and over again just based on
what you're selling
So like
I put together five sample
LinkedIn
Posts you can use to build
authority
on the platform and generate
Inbound demand from your existing
audience
Mind if I share the linkedin the
posts with you here
Feel free to post these on your
account
If they look good, right?
Actually, no, let's not say that.
I don't want to say that.
That just sounds like needy
I used content from your website
existing social posts and PR
To write each of these posts, okay
If you're a content agency, you
can also write blogs.
Hey, I wrote three
Sample blogs for your website
Going over
Common topics in your industry
And showcasing your expertise
On each topic
These blogs
Will give you a big seo boost seo
is just search engine optimization
who comes up first when you type
in best lawyer
In tampa, right?
This is what seo is
It looks like a list actually has
the best seo
Best lawyers near me, right?
Any business owner wants to show
up on the top of the google
searches
So if you say hey, I can give you
a big search engine optimization
boost
And we'll help you
Up here in chat gpt
And clawed searches as well
because
AI is all the rave right now and
if you're coming up on chat gpt as
Best lawyer in town
That's going to make you a lot of
money and these blogs can help
make that happen mind if I share
the blogs here to see
This is a fit, right
Okay, cool
Let's do one for
Short form video scripts because
if you're a content agency,
there's a lot you can do
With content creation to get
people interested in what you're
selling
I wrote up three viral short form
video scripts for you
That can be posted on tick tock
Instagram and linkedin
Mind if I share the
Scripts with you here.
Okay, great
Now social media profile audit.
I was checking out your linkedin
profile and noticed a few things
that are
likely
hurting your
Let's just say that might be
leaving
a bad first impression on
potential customers
mind if I share
Or what is the cta here?
I
Recorded a quick video breaking
down the causes and how to it's
always the guys
It's the same playbook over and
over and over again, and it works
All the time you don't have to
reinvent the wheel here
You just do what's already working
and this doc is going to be linked
below the video
So you can just literally copy and
paste what i've written for you
and put it into into action
Okay, what's a direct offer for
content?
We can help you
Add 10 000
New followers actually now let's
do calls we can help you book
10 sales calls from your linkedin
profile in the next
60 days guaranteed or you don't
pay us
You'll have an entire content
strategy
Built out for you
um, you know long form
posts blogs
video scripts and
We'll post everything for you
You don't
lift a finger
Interested in checking out a quick
video going over a linkedin
strategy I drew up
Up
For you
Okay, great.
Let's go into ai automation then
we'll get out of here
Because this is
If you're still watching this,
thank you for being attentive and
paying attention
But I want to go through every
single agency path so that you
have a winning script off the bat
Okay, what are lead magnets for an
ai automation business?
Sample ai flows
Automating different
parts of the business
And let's do a
An ai audit
Okay
I put together
a sample
And I think the best way to go
about an ai automation lead magnet
is just saying like you can
automate different parts of their
business
I put together a sample n8n flow
that automatically
posts
Content to each of your social
platforms
With the click of a button
So you can distribute
content to ig tiktok
Facebook
And youtube instantly
Mind if I share a video of
The flow
In action
So you can see how it works
I really just think like for ai
automation
You're just going to want to
Take a bunch of different use
cases
And see what people resonate with
the most
I put together a sample n8n flow
that automatically
You know transcribes your
Long form video
Content and creates 10 to 15
Content pieces
Out of it
Mind if I share the video the flow
in action
So you can see how it works like
Just figure out what kind of
things people want automated in
their business
And that's going to be your entire
outreach strategy
I put together a sample n8n flow
that
You know takes your sales call
recordings and
Scores the call so you know which
sales reps are performing the best
right like
AI is so new and so attractive
that you don't really need to
Offer
A swipe file of email flows or a
swipe file of this you can just
say hey
I put together an n8n flow that
does this and this
Do you want to see a video of it
so you can see how it works?
And then a direct pitch would be
something like
You know we can help you save 10
hours a week
On content creation by or with and
n8n flow
That automatically posts your
content to each of your social
platforms with a click of a button
You'll be able to
Distribute content to instagram
tiktok facebook and youtube with
the click of a button
Mind if I share a video
So okay
Hopefully if you watch what you're
still here from the beginning
You can basically tell
My templates are the same
throughout right?
Overall template is
I created
X
Lead magnet for you
Mind if
I share x lead magnet
With you here
Or if i'm doing a direct pitch
i'll say we can help you
accomplish x
You know calls revenue time
followers
Leads right we can help you
achieve this thing book more calls
get more revenue save time get
followers get leads
In why time frame 60 days 90 days
30 days
fully
Guaranteed
Then i'll do an explanation
Of the service
You know basically a line that
explains what the business
actually does
distribute content to instagram
tiktok and facebook with the click
of a button and then cta
video
sharing the resource
Etc
Right, so
Copywriting for cold outreach is
basically a template system
Like people try to over complicate
this
But you can basically boil it down
to a few key pieces that you want
to reiterate in every single thing
that you ever test
So this is the most important
video of lead gen in general
Because this this video just
taught you how to actually
pitch
Something
In a cold outreach message email
linkedin twitter
Instagram dms and get somebody to
say yes, I want to learn more
You're going basically creating
demand for your business out of
thin air with the written word
In a formulaic way based on the
the templates I just showed you so
This doc is down below and you can
literally copy and paste it if you
want
Or you can use it as a guide a
guideline for your own lead
magnets think on your feet use
critical thinking don't just copy
me
Come up with your own
methodologies
And then
Start generating leads so in the
next couple videos i'm going to go
into real world examples of
successful campaigns
How to get a list of leads how to
automate this with an outreach
campaign how to do cold dms
How to book meetings the whole
nine yards so let's keep going
let's just keep going we're going
to keep trucking along let's get
into the next video