What's going on guys?
Welcome to the lead generation
section of AI assisted agency.
My name is Christian
I'm a co-founder at the program
and at client ascension and at
list kit
And for context, I've written cold
outreach campaigns for thousands
of businesses over the last four
years
I'm responsible for multiple seven
figures in revenue all from cold
email and cold dms
Based on what i've taught people
and what i've implemented for
people myself
And I want to show you everything
that I know about cold outreach
writing good emails answering
people
Booking meetings closing deals and
scaling your business because if
you're watching this right now,
you're excited
You just learned the agency path
that you want to go down whether
it's email marketing or content or
funnels and ads
No matter which one you chose
These next couple videos are going
to show you how to actually
generate interest in what you're
selling
Without wasting a ton of time
You know posting in facebook
groups and posting on social media
and waiting for your first couple
calls to come through the door
No, you're going to go on offense
and reach out to people every
single day
Hundreds if not thousands of
people every single day to get
people interested in what you're
selling
So you actually gain momentum
quickly and start signing clients
And collecting your first couple
of invoices because there's
nothing worse
From experience then starting your
own agency being excited to go and
you know
Get your first couple clients and
then having no idea where to look
to actually find those clients
because four years ago
I didn't know about cold email at
all and I was using facebook
groups and you know
basically
Relying on luck to to find a
client and guess what?
I didn't find any clients going
down that route posting in
facebook groups every day
connecting with people on social
media
Providing value and hoping that
people dm me that stuff never
worked what actually works is cold
outreach
Dms emails cold calls linkedin
messages and going on offense to
find your first couple clients
So I want to show you how to
actually write a really good
outreach message
Using the offer that daniel has
taught you using some of the
practices that i'll show you how
to
You know deploy with emails or
video pitches over emails free
samples of your work
guarantees risk reversals
Basically making it as stupid
simple as possible for you to run
an outreach campaign
and sign your first couple clients
because
The thing that catapults your
entire business journey is going
from zero to one
You know starting an agency at
zero and going all the way to one
signing a client because once you
sign your first client and get
them
Good results it builds this really
big snowball of more confidence
more experience case studies word
of mouth referrals
And as you keep snowballing it
becomes easier to get clients.
But right now where you sit
Is you know crunch time because
you need to go out and sign your
first client if you want to stay
motivated and actually
You know grow your business right
because the biggest
The biggest hesitation point that
I see with any new business owner
is they just don't know where to
start
Okay, I know email marketing now
How do I actually go out and sign
a client and they just sit there
and you know
Procrastinate and they're
paralyzed with analysis because
they just don't know what to do
I'm going to remove all of those
Self-limiting beliefs and doubts
and just give you the exact
framework that you need to follow
To sign your first couple clients
I'm going to give you the
principles of writing a good cold
outreach message so that you have
An understanding of it because I
would rather teach you how to
write them on your own before I
introduce you to the ai that we
have
Available for you
And then i'm going to show you how
to use the ai to write really good
outreach messages to do research
on companies
And to basically, you know make
your life easier
When you're doing the outreach, so
i'm going to teach you how to fish
and then i'm going to give you a
fishing pole that is supercharged
To catch a lot of fish at once so
that you know how to do it if you
had to go back to the old way
But you're also going to be able
to take that knowledge and apply
it to
The ai supercharged fishing pole
that i'm going to give you later
on in this video module
so long story short
These next couple videos are going
to show you
How to write really good outreach
messages and craft good offers
like 10 calls a month guaranteed
or you don't pay
50k from your email list
guaranteed
Video pitches lead magnets
Basically all the fundamentals
that you need to get results right
off the bat
Even if you have no experience and
even if you're brand new and if
you're watching this that's
probably the case
for you, so
Let's dive in i'm going to start
out with some copywriting
techniques and methodologies
Then i'm going to show you how to
use ai to supercharge your copy
do individual dms and emails mass
outreach where you can send
thousands of emails a day
Using technology and domains and
inboxes and ascending tool
I'm going to show you how to get a
list of leads
Because the big thing that I hear
is like where do I actually find a
list of people to reach out to?
You're in luck because i'm also a
co-founder at list kit which is a
b2b database company with millions
of email records in a single place
So by the end of this module, you
will be
Capable of generating leads and
sales calls for your agency
Self-sufficiently without relying
on luck without relying on
referrals
So you can go like I like to say
on offense and you know take this
business
I don't want to say by the balls
but i'm going to say by the balls
and go on offense
Instead of just waiting around for
your first couple meetings to fall
out of the sky
I'm going to show you how to go
out and get them right with
Basically math because i'm going
to show you how you know if you
send enough emails in a day and
enough dms in a day
You will
Get positive responses and have
new leads in the door
So without further ado, let's get
into the copywriting portion of
this
Then we'll talk about some
technology that you can use to
automate all this
I'm going to show you the ai
script writing bot that can help
you write cold dms and cold emails
in the blink of an eye
And then i'll give you some real
examples of successful campaigns
that my clients are currently
running
To generate leads for their
business.
So no matter which
Agency path you have chosen i'm
going to show you how to write
cold emails for that path
By hand and then with ai and then
supercharge all of this with an
outreach campaign that can reach
out to
500 a thousand five thousand
people a day so you can start
getting early wins and signing
clients
Without a lot of downtime or
second thoughts or like is this
really for me?
No, we're gonna go on the offense
here
Let's dive in i'm excited to show
you what I got.
Let's get into it