All right.
Now I want to show you what
happens once somebody responds
positively to your email because
up to this point, all I've talked
about is getting the initial
response from a prospect, but the
job is far from finished.
So let's say I'm reaching out to,
um, a group of restaurants, trying
to sell them my social media
marketing services.
Once the restaurant owner says,
yes, I would like to learn more.
That is when you need to kick it
into high gear and get the job
finished to get somebody booked in
for a sales call with your client
or for yourself.
If these are your own campaigns.
Um, so I want to walk you through
a number of scenarios where people
have responded to my emails and
how I've handled these responses.
To get them booked in for a
meeting.
So pulled up in front of me is
what the inbox of the sending tool
looks like.
This is basically where all of
your conversations are housed with
different prospects.
Um, and I checked this religiously
twice a day to see if there's new
inboxes.
It's like checking my phone a
couple of times a day.
Um, you know, it's like a Twitch
where I just checked the inbox,
hoping for that dopamine rush of a
new interested reply.
And once I get a reply like this,
um, I want to guide you guys.
through how to get these
objections and pushbacks handled
until they book in a call with
you.
So we reached out to this person
and said, we can get you 10 new
prospects a month that are
interested in your agency services
all from a loom video, cold email
approach.
Can I send you a video breaking
down this strategy?
Um, and he said, all sounds very
good.
Just depends on the investment for
me right now.
Here's where you have to be a
savant and have, you know, finesse
and get people to, you know, buy
into what you're doing and
overcome objectives.
So here's how we came back, right?
We said, hope you're doing great.
I wanted to get back to you and
walk you through pricing a little
bit.
Here's a breakdown of the cost.
This breaks down everything for
you.
Basically at list kit, we have
cheaper rates compared to other
agencies because we're only a data
company.
I have a few case studies that
break down the prices.
So let's, this is actually very
long winded.
Um, because transparently we had a
new employee on my team handle
this response and I would have
made this a lot shorter.
Um, but either way he comes back
and said, it looks amazing, but I
can
not afford the monthly.
Then on top of the domains, I'm
sorry, but I'm trying to get back
up from being scammed and losing
all my business building for this
year.
Um, so kind of a, you know, sad
story for this guy.
Um, and then I said, I hear you,
Mark, you won't find a more cost
effective cold email solution on
the market.
So feel free to reach out once you
have that first client signed.
Um, he didn't answer.
So the key thing to note here,
guys, is if somebody ghosts you,
it's going to happen a lot where
you reach out to them and try to
get the call book.
And they just don't book the call
in.
Um, you're going to have to follow
up repeatedly, repeatedly and
repeatedly.
So this guy didn't answer us on
July 16th.
So on August 7th, which is way too
long of a gap, this should have
been a lot shorter of a, a time
gap, right?
We said, Hey Mark, what a 15
minute call really be that bad.
I have all next week.
If you want to grab a time
calendar link.
Um, so basically following up over
and over again until somebody
either books in or tells you to
politely screw off.
And he ended up booking in through
this link.
And once again, we had a new hire
on our team, call him Betty
instead of Mark, which is a very
unfortunate mix up.
Um, but anyways, saw you grab time
at 3 PM Eastern on the 11th.
You'll be speaking with my
partner, Evan.
In the meantime, could you confirm
the calendar invite and watch this
13 minute overview of our system?
Here's the link to the video of
our system.
Let me know if you have any
questions in the meantime.
He said, for starters, my not, my
name is not Mark or my name is
Mark, not Betty.
My booking was for noon, not 3 PM.
Just be sure.
That was my fault.
I just talked to Evan.
Looks like it wasn't confirmed.
Um, sounds good.
Talk to you then.
So once again, this is somebody
from my team having a bit of a,
you know, rookie beginner moment
with some of the things he said,
but the call is booked and it was
forwarded to my sales team.
Um, I'm going to link the video
down below.
Basically what I send to everybody
that books in.
It's basically a quick overview of
the entire system that we sell.
And you want to have this ideally
for your own business and your
clients.
So when somebody books a call with
you, you can then reach fall back
out and say, Hey, Tom, thanks for
booking in.
Please watch this quick five
minute video overviewing our
services.
So, you know, if, so you're ready
to go for our call.
If this isn't a fit, no worries.
We can cancel the call, but just
want to make sure that we're on
the same page.
Right.
That's what you want to do to.
Prepare somebody to get on the
phone with you.
Um, let's go through some other
examples.
This is all the way back from
December of last year.
Hey, I saw you're a key player in
your company's growth efforts.
We have 626 million B2B email
leads in a database similar to
Apollo.
I compiled a list of 50 leads,
right?
So we reached out with our initial
message.
He said, thank you for reaching
out.
I'd be happy to connect and
discuss further.
Let's set up a meeting.
Feel free to share the list.
Right.
Sent the list over.
Here's a list of 50 decision
makers at SAS companies who could
benefit from your workflows.
Here's the list.
Right.
So whenever somebody answers, you
want to just get right to the
point and move the conversation to
a call as soon as you possibly
can.
Don't waste time, you know, giving
a long X long winded answer.
Just answer their question.
Like feel free to share the list
here or handle their, you know,
basically fulfill their ask.
He's asking to see a list.
Sounds good.
Here's the list.
And then I push for a call right
away.
How does tomorrow or Wednesday at
noon Eastern work for a call?
So I can give you a walkthrough of
our database.
If it's easier, feel free to grab
some time on my calendar here with
a link to book in with us.
And he never answered.
So the next day I said, how's
tomorrow at 9 a.m.
Eastern work?
My calendar is wide open.
Feel free to shoot over a few
times and I'll get it booked.
Right.
So instead of just sending one
email and this is a good lesson to
learn, instead of just sending one
email and calling in a night and
not following up ever again, I
followed up the next day saying,
hey, how's tomorrow at nine work
instead?
He says, apologies for the late
response.
I've been out of town and would
love to arrange a meeting at the
earliest opportunity.
Would December 19th work?
Please let me know.
No sweat.
I've got 10 and two open to either
of these work.
He grabbed the time on this link
and the call happened and that was
handled.
So basically what I'm trying to
show you guys is when somebody
answers, it's not going to be as
easy as, yes, send me your
calendar so we can book in.
People are going to ask questions.
What's your pricing?
Has this worked for other people?
What kind of results can I expect?
And people are also going to ghost
you and you're going to have to
follow up several times.
Like here's a good example.
I thought right here that this
would be a layup.
He would book the call.
No problem.
We'd be on our way to a sales
call.
No reply.
Instead of being mad and sulking
and giving up, I followed up the
next day and then he answered
right away.
How's December 19th looked?
Call got booked.
We went from there, right?
I can go through dozens of these
examples.
Here's another one.
Hey, Christian, is your model
retainer base or pay per lead?
Kind of an open-ended question and
I was very upfront.
Hey, neither actually.
You pay a one-time setup fee, then
you pay the monthly cost to keep
the system running.
We don't profit a cent on the
actual service.
Our only goal is to get you onto
our data software list kit.
You won't find a cheaper solution
on the market.
Are you open to a call to discuss
in more detail?
Let me know what time that works
here.
Just how, like when I was
introducing the initial cold email
writing to you guys, it's the same
process every time with hook, case
study, call to action.
Same thing is true with following
up with people.
Answer the question that they ask
and then push for a call.
So I answered his question by
saying how our pricing model
works.
And then I said, are you open to a
call tomorrow or Thursday so we
can discuss details and pricing?
Let me know what time that works
best with you or grab time here.
He comes back.
Awesome.
Thanks for the info.
Book the meeting.
I come back with, saw you booked
in on Thursday with my partner.
Can you please accept the calendar
invite?
Let me know if you have questions.
Perfectly executed conversation
there.
Right?
Just to go through a few more of
these.
So, he said, yes, would love that.
Let's connect in the new year.
On New Year's Eve, he actually
said this.
Hey, Alex, happy new year.
Hope you had time to rest and
enjoy time with your family.
How does Monday at 11 a.m.
Eastern work on your end for a
call?
If it's easier, grab time here.
He said, please confirm.
Thanks, Alex.
And I actually didn't answer until
later in the day.
I dropped the ball here just now
seeing this.
Looks like you're in Dubai.
How does 7 a.m.
Eastern work?
He comes back.
Hey, I missed this email too.
I'm currently in London.
I say, does 1 p.m.
Eastern?
No, it doesn't work.
But 8 or 9 a.m.
Eastern does work.
Hey, brother, just scheduled you
in for 9.15 a.m.
with my partner, Henry.
Thank you.
Received.
Right?
So, like, moral of the story here
in this nine-minute video is when
you get a response from somebody,
it's never going to be as cut and
dry as, let's hop on the phone so
I can give you my money.
You're going to have to weave your
way through objections and answer
questions
and get through the logistics of
booking people in until you have a
call booked.
So, in the next video, I'm going
to go over what to do if your
messaging isn't working,
like how to test new stuff.
And I basically want to make a
video for every possible scenario
where things are not going right
so that you can fix them and
improve on them and iterate them,
right?
So, like, this is very detailed,
in-depth stuff, and I want to give
you all of it that I can possibly
give you
so that you are equipped with the
knowledge to run this business on
your own.
And if you have an issue, you can
come into this library of videos
and find an answer to your
question.
So, I hope you're following along,
and this is entertaining and
insightful
because this skill of getting
people booked in is literally a
million-dollar skill, right?
So, here's an example of a really
easy scenario.
For sure, I'll take a look.
If I don't get back to you, here's
a link to my calendar.
Hey, Michael, just scheduled you
in.
That's a layup.
Not every call is like this by any
stretch of the imagination, right?
Promise, probably will be in
Thursday or Friday before I'm
available.
I'll have to lock in some
appointments.
I promise you I'm not blowing you
off.
I will take the meeting.
Also, can you send me a list of
the industries you guys have?
Sure thing.
Here's a list of the industries we
get great results reaching out to.
Hey, I saw you booked in with my
partner, Eddie, for tomorrow.
Oh, shoot.
I booked the appointment but
didn't realize it was at the time
with somebody else.
What does your schedule look like
tomorrow?
No, it's perfect that you booked
in with Eddie.
He oversees sales for us.
I'm a co-founder here, so I
couldn't care less about getting
the credit.
Oh, good.
I thought another sales rep was
trying to snake your deal, so I'm
glad you clarified.
How did it go with Eddie?
Eddie is great.
I had to reschedule the follow-up.
So, yeah, just plenty of examples
of back and forth here.
And I'm even going to put a link
down below to a sales vault, which
is 100 conversations
just like this, managing responses
from people and going back and
forth.
So you guys can get really, really
good at writing the initial email
and then responding
to people until they book a call
with you.
So let's move on to the next
video.