All right.
In this video or set of videos,
I'm going to be walking through
and showing you how
you can set up cold email accounts
through Google.
So you can actually send your cold
email campaigns
and how to connect it through
SmartLead all in this kind of one
video.
So I'm going to try and
get through this as fast as
possible.
So the first thing you're going to
want to do is actually
establish the domains you're going
to want to use to send the cold
emails from.
So go over to your
favorite registrar, PorkFun,
GoDaddy, Namecheap.
It doesn't really matter too much.
And the settings
are pretty much all in the same
place.
If you want to follow along with
me, you can use PorkFun.
I'm just doing one domain for the
sake of this video because I don't
want to spend a bunch of money
because I already have a bunch of
accounts already set up.
But first, you're going to go and
establish
number one, how many accounts you
want to set up.
And then number two, buy the
domains that correspond
with that.
So if you want to send, let's say,
you know, 500 or so emails a day
with 20 cold email
sends per inbox per day, that
roughly comes out to 20 or 25
email accounts and send one
domain.
I like to have two inboxes per one
There's a lot of speculation on
it.
Should you have one inbox per one
domain, two inboxes, three, five,
whatever.
I like to err
a little bit on the side of
caution and do two.
I know some people do one, some
people do four,
some people do five.
If you want a super simple thing
to follow along with me, you can
just do two.
And that's what I'd recommend is
do two or one.
I wouldn't recommend adding a
bunch of domains
to one inbox.
So first you're going to establish
how many inboxes you want set up,
then divide that by
two to figure out how many domains
you want, and then go ahead and
find your domain.
So all that
you have to do, and there should
be a video link somewhere.
And if you just Google, if you
Google
Matt Lucero, cold email domain
ideas, you should find a video
where I kind of explain all I'm
doing
is basically just inserting a
domain and asking chat GPT and
saying, Hey, give me a bunch of
different
variations of this domain.
And then you can look them up in
your favorite domain registrar and
go ahead and
check out.
So I'm going to go ahead, pause
and purchase this domain, and then
we can go and
actually set it up.
All right.
So we went ahead and purchased
this domain here.
And so you can see
it's all set up or it's all
processing right now.
And so in the meantime, while it's
processing,
we can go and start getting our
Google workspace up.
So how do we set up the Google
workspace?
First
thing we need to do is establish
the admin account.
So this is the central place.
You're going to be
purchasing all your other email
accounts from like how you can
say, Hey, I want to assign this
email
account to this domain.
So this is where you're going to
be setting up and purchasing it.
And this
is also where you're going to be
connecting your domains and just
managing all this stuff through
Google.
So you might already have one of
these set up for like your typical
email sending.
I would set
up another different one for these
for the cold email stuff.
So first I'm going to go over to
pricing.
And the reason why I don't just
jump in here.
And by the way,
workspace.google.com, this is the
website you want to go to.
Reason why I go to pricing first,
instead of just like jumping
straight in
is it's going to like pitch you
the high end thing and you have to
like downgrade it.
So if you go to
pricing and you press start trial
on the $6 a month one, now you can
get started and make your admin
account.
So I'm just going to call this a
Nevo.
I'm going to say we have 10 to 99
employees.
I just do
this as a matter of caution
because we're going to be adding
like 10 accounts to it.
So it's like, Hey,
we have 10 employees.
It kind of lines up.
I don't really think this matters.
We're going to press
next.
It's going to ask for my name.
So Matt, Lucero, current email
address.
And so this is
where you can plug in a email,
like a Gmail or another email
account, or, you know, really any
other email account.
I'm going to plug in one of my
other cold email accounts that I
use so that I just
have like something different
than, you know, all the other
admin accounts I'm going to have
set up.
So give me two seconds here.
All right.
So I plugged in a Google account.
Let me actually grab a
different one.
Hold on.
All right.
So I just picked a different one
of my Google workspace accounts.
And so you can see here, do you
want to set up a Google workspace?
I'm going to say, yes, use this
email.
And then let me actually go over
here and grab the, the code that
sent.
So basically what we're
doing here is we're just saying
like, Hey, we already have like an
email account existing.
You can plug
in a Gmail and outlook, whatever,
just any sort of email account
that you can start off with.
Let me grab
the code that it sent here.
All right.
So I got the verification code
going to plug it in here.
And so now it's going to ask me
for a password.
So pretty straightforward.
Just go ahead and throw
it in a password.
All right.
So I went ahead and generated a
password.
And so now it's, this is what
I'm saying here.
If you would have went to the
pricing page and just went
straight in, it would have
recommended you a different plan.
So we're going to press try free
for 14 days.
And now it's going to
ask you to review and check out.
And so this is where you're going
to enter in all your business
information and credit card
information.
Again, pretty straightforward.
I'm going to go ahead and
fill this out.
And then we can jump in on the
other side, whenever I have it all
filled out.
All right.
So we entered in our credit card
here and we can press skip for
now.
All right.
And so now you can see we have the
Google workspace set up.
So now we're going to jump
in and actually create the email
accounts.
All right.
So we're going to go over here in
the top,
right.
And then scroll down and press
admin.
And then that's going to take us
to our admin.
It's
going to say, welcome to your new
account.
You're going to press, I
understand.
And then now you are in the admin
panel.
So this is the admin account.
This is where you can set up
and add domains and do all that
kind of fun stuff here.
So now I'm going to show you how
you can add
your domain or add an email or a
whatever account.
So you can, or a domain, I mean,
add a domain
into here.
So then you can add a user and
create the actual account here.
So first we're going to go
over and scroll down and you can
see over here in this domain
section, you're going to press
manage
domains.
And you can see first it's
prompting here to verify your
domain to unlock features.
So it's
basically asking us like, Hey, do
you actually own this, uh, by an
Evo account or this other account
that I use, uh, just to set this
thing up.
And so it's going to ask for a TXC
verification.
I'm going
to press agree and continue.
And so all it's going to ask me is
to basically put, uh, so some code
in
my DNS saying, so I'm going to
copy this and then go over to pork
bun, and then I'm going to find my
domain here.
So this one is by an Evo.
And then you can see here.
All right.
So this is by an Evo.
We're going to press details.
We're going to go over to the DNS,
and then we're going to add this
in
as a TXT record.
So you, all you have to do is just
follow the steps.
So, uh, copy this TXT record,
and then let's double check, uh,
at for the host alias.
So at answer, add this over here.
And so
we're just plugging this in saying
like, Hey Google, we actually own
this, uh, and here's some proof.
And so we can press this.
Uh, it'll take a second to verify.
And then you can see verifying
your TXT
record.
It might take a couple of minutes
and it might also say like, Hey,
this isn't verified.
And you
just have to press it again
because it might take a second,
uh, for it to update.
So we're going to
wait for this to verify and we'll
come back when it's done.
All right.
So you can see now it confirmed
it.
Great job.
Google can see the updates you
make, uh, confirm verification.
And then now we're
upset, uh, all set here.
So updating your Google workspace,
this might take a few minutes.
In the
meantime, while this verifies, we
can actually start to add our DNS
settings.
So, uh, in the meantime,
you want to add your DMARC and
custom domain tracking.
So these are really easy to add.
I have a sheet here where you can
just copy and paste this in.
So, uh, we're going to
go over here and set up our DMARC
record.
All you have to do, uh, is copy
and paste on the
sheet here, DMARC underscore for
the host.
Uh, this is a TXT record, which is
already set
and then paste this in for the
answer.
And again, whether using GoDaddy,
Porkbun, uh, whatever
domain registrar, this is all
going to be pretty much the same,
like all these settings and where
you find stuff.
There's a DNS settings record
somewhere.
And all of these registrars is
pretty
straightforward.
So now we're going to go on to
custom, uh, domain tracking.
This is another
thing.
So DMARC, this just is another
thing that helps us
deliverability, uh, for your
domains and
then custom domain tracking.
This is basically connecting it
up.
So whenever you add this into
smart lead, if you want to track
open rates, which I don't
particularly recommend, I
personally
have that off because it helps us
deliverability that you could have
that set up.
But, uh, I just
add this as basically a safety
measure, not because it's
necessarily like an urgent
priority.
Um, so
your domain has been verified,
begin activating Gmail.
Um, cool.
So let's go over here and actually
create some new users here.
So it's asking to let's continue
here.
So it's asking to do it under this
by an Evo account, which I'm not
actually going to do.
Let's go out of here and let's add
a new domain.
So I added in with another
professional domain.
It might prompt you to like add
your other domain
in right when you set this up, but
we're going to go ahead.
So this is a, uh, not the account
that I
want to set up the domain on.
So I'm going to add another domain
here.
So I'm going to press add domain
and then we're going to add
another domain.
So this is the separate domain
that I have set up here,
the different one, an Evo
teams.com.
And then we're going to plug it in
here and we're going to add
this as a secondary domain, uh,
and we're going to add domain and
start verification.
So this is where you can go
through, uh, and you're going to
add all 10 or whatever domains you
want
to add.
And so same thing here, it's going
to ask, uh, to do some DNS stuff.
We're going to go to the
next setting.
We're going to copy this
verification code.
We're going to go here.
We're going to make it
a TXT record.
It's going to ask us to paste it
in here.
Um, and then put at in the host
name and press
add same situation.
We're just telling Google like,
Hey, we own this and here's proof
of that.
So, uh, while it's going to wait
for that, we're going to wait here
again.
All right.
So you can see
that it was able to add it after
it verified it.
So this is awesome.
So now we have a couple of these,
uh, steps check that we talked
about in the intro video.
So first we have the domain, we
have the
admin account.
Now we connected the domain to the
And so now we're going to want to
create the users.
So we can go ahead and press up
here and press add new user.
So go on the left
hand side users, add new user.
And then this is where we can make
the, uh, account here.
So I can
say Matt zero.
We can have it named Matt and evo
teams.com secondary email.
So this is where it's
going to send over the sign-on
instructions, uh, which it looks
like you don't need to fill this
out.
So you can fill this out and then
you can add a profile picture.
Um, you can have it generate a
password, create a password.
It doesn't really matter.
Uh, I'm just going to press add
new user
here.
And so you can see here's the
account I created.
Here's the password.
I'm going to copy
the password and, uh, paste it on
another tab here.
So we're going to press done.
And so now we have our
first user created.
So if you want to do this, all you
have to do to repeat the step,
let's say you
want two users on this domain, go
back here, make another one, Matt
Lucero.
And we already have a
Matt.
And so you can see it auto filled
with Matt Lucero.
We don't need to do that.
So, uh, I'm
just going to stick with the one
that we just created.
So you can see now we have the new
account.
This is what we can go ahead and
connect to smart lead.
Now, in the meantime, if you want
to add a
profile picture, so you can see, I
didn't add a profile picture in
the other section.
Uh, you actually
have to enable this because for
whatever reason, by default, uh,
Google admin has it disabled.
So there
should be a profile picture.
Um, or maybe it's, I think it's
directory settings.
Um,
yep.
Directory settings, profile
editing, and then you can enable
it.
So like people can change their
own profile picture.
So I'll press save there.
Um, so anyways, now we're here, we
got this all set up.
And so now we're going to log into
the brand new account we just
created.
So we're going to go over
here.
We're going to press, uh, add
account.
We're going to log in.
So this was, let's go back to the
account here.
Cause I already forgot what it
was.
Matt at nevo teams.com.
We're going to copy this.
Uh, we're going to paste it here.
And then we're going to copy the
password that they generated for
us and paste it.
And then it's going to ask for a
phone number verification code.
So you can just punch
in your own phone number.
Um, if you want to use a different
phone number or like a burner
phone number,
there's a bunch of websites where
you can like kind of generate
these in one of them is, uh,
text verify.com.
So you can see this is like a
website.
Uh, there's another one.
Uh, let me,
let me go verify it real quick.
Um, through a phone verification
tool.
All right.
So I rented a phone
number.
And so to be clear here, the
reason why I'm using a phone
number rental thing instead of my
personal phone number is because
again, I've used my personal phone
number for a zillion of these
accounts.
So I just like using one of these
websites.
So all you have to do is just go
on to
text verified SMS pool.
There's like SMS PVA.
If you just Google like phone
number rental,
one-time code thing, uh, you can
check one of those out, but
basically I just sent it, uh,
it gave me a phone number that I
could use for like Gmail.
And I'm just going to paste in the
code that
it gave me here.
And so now it's going to say,
welcome to your new account.
Let's log into the
account and let's create a
password.
So I'm going to go back and I'm
going to create a password for
this
account.
Awesome.
So I have the password here,
change the password.
And now we should be able
to log into our Google account.
So it's kicking me out here
because I am in the admin panel
and we're
logging in from the account, which
we just created, which doesn't
have admin access because it's
like
a sub user.
So it's kicking me out and saying,
Hey, you can't log in here.
But if we go over to
Gmail, if we go and click into
this account here, and now we
press into Gmail, we should have a
nice,
pristine Gmail account that we can
log in on.
So this account is already set up,
uh,
Matt at an Evo teams, fresh Gmail
account.
Uh, and this is a nice little
interface that we can use
to set everything else up on.
So now if you want to change the
profile picture, you can press
this
nice little pencil and add a
profile picture, do whatever you
want.
Not necessary.
Nice to have
sometimes.
Um, but this account is all set
up.
And so now we want to connect it
to smart lead.
So
we're going to go over to smart
lead.
So I have a smart lead account I'm
logged in on,
and we're going to want to press
add account, and then we're going
to press Gmail.
And so whenever you try and add a
Gmail account through, uh, OAuth,
you are going to need to add
this client ID code and smart lead
makes it super easy.
Uh, let me pause my Slack
notifications.
So yeah, smart lead makes it super
easy.
All you have to do is just follow
these instructions here.
So head over to your admin panel,
just press this button.
So it's going to throw us back to
our admin
account and we're going to log in,
uh, with the admin account we
created.
And we're going to go,
uh, press, I understand.
And then awesome.
So now we're in the admin account
and we can configure
apps here.
And so all you have to do, uh,
basically what happens if you
don't paste this in, if you just
press like connect account, and
then you try and log in, it'll
give you an error and say like,
Hey,
this app has been blocked because
that app has been restricted.
So you need to enable smart lead
to be able to
connect your Google accounts.
So the way you do this add app
OAuth, and then you paste this
thing
that they just gave you here.
Uh, you're going to press search.
You're going to press select.
You're
going to take this box, select
again, continue trusted.
I'm going through this really
quick.
You can pause and slow down.
All you're doing is saying, yes,
yes, yes.
Get me to the end of this.
So now we have smart lead all set
up and configured on this admin
account.
So this admin account hosts
these two accounts.
And so these two accounts or
however many accounts you add to
this admin panel,
it'll be cool to add to smart
lead.
So now if I go back to smart lead
and I press connect account,
it'll pop up with the two accounts
I'm logged in on.
And if I go to this freshly made
an evo teams
account, it will let me log in.
So if you don't have this enabled,
allow, allow next.
If you don't
have this enabled, it'll pop up
with an error right there and say,
we can't connect this account.
But
since we have it set up properly,
it was able to connect this
account.
The account is connected
properly.
And now we can set up all the
different settings.
So this is all set up.
All right.
So the
council set up.
So now we're going to go back a
couple of steps and set up a
couple more records
that we need to set up before we
get everything going.
So I jumped ahead a few steps.
We're going
to go back a couple of steps and
go back to pork bun and start
setting up a couple more records.
So
I had this in my doc here.
I don't know why I missed this,
but we can also set up our SPF
records
here too.
So you can do that with the DMARC
and the custom domain tracking.
All you have to do again
is paste these records.
And so we're going to copy and
paste the app and a copy and paste
the SPF
record here.
And so what, there's three records
that you need for deliverability.
There is SPF,
there's DKIM and there's DMARC.
SPF and DMARC are pasted in just
like these records,
like I did here in this video, we
can just press add and our SPF is
all set up.
Now for
the other one DKIM, you have to go
in and actually generate a key.
You can't just copy and paste
that.
So if we go over back into our
admin panel and we type in DKIM,
it should give us DKIM
authentication.
And then now we have to generate a
DKIM record.
So we're going to select the
domain we want to do this
for and Evo teams.
Again, all these steps I'm showing
you, you have to repeat for the
different
accounts.
So whenever you create an account
and you need, the only one you
don't need to repeat is the
the stuff that's on an
organizational level, like that
smart lead copy and paste code.
You do that
once per admin account, the
profile picture enable that's
across the admin account.
So anything you
add is good to go.
Now, when it comes to the DKIM,
you need to do this for each
domain.
For the SPF,
you need to do that for each
domain.
And for the custom tracking and
the DMARC, you need to do that
for each domain.
And then for logging into the
accounts, you have to log into
each account,
connect it to smart lead.
I'm just doing it for one account
for the sake of simplicity.
Otherwise I'd just be repeating
all the steps over again.
And now to set up the DKIM, we're
going to
go over here, select the domains.
We're going to press generate new
record.
We're going to press generate.
And then you can see here, it
gives us a nice, neat record that
we can go ahead and add back in
here.
So you can see same deal, TXT
record.
That's the host name.
And then we're going to go over
here,
TXT value body.
Now DKIM, a little bit more
annoying than the other records.
We're going to press add
here and I'll show you what I
mean.
So we're going to add it in and
you can see here, it may take up
to
48 hours for DNS changes to fully
propagate.
So we're going to press start
authentication.
And I have a feeling it's going to
say that the, maybe did it just
work?
Let's press, got it.
Stop authentication.
Let's see here if it
authenticates.
Usually most changes will take a
few minutes.
Usually this might take 15 minutes
to get set up.
Like I've seen it say, it says up
to 48 hours,
but if you have issues setting up
the DKIM, like you get an error at
this step,
then you need to go back, like
just wait a few minutes, go back
and try and authenticate again.
And then lastly, if you keep doing
it, let's say you paste in the
record, you press start
authenticate,
it doesn't authenticate.
And then you come back and you try
it 15 minutes later and it still
doesn't do it.
You can regenerate a new record
and do it over again.
All right.
So I just regenerated.
I tried to make it.
So it showed it as an example, but
you can see here,
email authentication, not
verified.
So if you're getting this error,
wait 15 minutes and come back.
You can see we're still getting
this error.
So paste this in.
I just saved it as like a new
record.
It looks like the first time it
actually did do it right away,
which is pretty, pretty cool.
But looks like this time it's not
being as happy and what I see
across a lot of people.
Oh, it looks like because I
actually put the wrong domain.
So you can see here, stop
authentication.
So this one actually did work
properly and I just messed it up
again.
But anyways, go to the domain,
paste the record in, press start
authentication.
If you get that red error, wait 15
minutes, try redoing the record.
Otherwise, if it authenticates
like this, you're good to go.
Just let it do its thing.
So those are the last two things.
Now inside of smart lead, you have
the account.
This is where you can configure
the settings.
The first thing you want to do is
enable warm up.
So this is just saying like, hey,
smart lead, add it to the warm up
network.
Always keep this on.
I like to have the following
settings and always, always,
always just make sure
that you double check because
these videos are, you know, I'm
making this video right now.
It's July 18th, 2024.
Some best practices might change.
So always confirm like, or I
should say, always confirm.
You can go to one of the coaching
calls and just hop on and be like,
hey, Matt,
just want to double check.
Like, hey, are these settings
still good?
All these are the things I'm using
right now.
I do 20 cold per day, 14 minute
time gap.
This is where you can add your
signature.
So you can do first name, last
name title at company.
So I could say founder at an Evo.
Then you can add your tax based
opt out disclaimer.
If you don't want
to get any more emails from me
respond with no, thanks.
And I won't email you.
So you're just saying, hey, this
is an opt out custom domain
tracking.
This is what I was talking about
before.
If you go back and you go and copy
this here, you don't need to copy
it.
But this is just a fast way of
doing it.
You just paste email tracking dot
this your domain dot com.
Press check status.
So this is basically, well, it
might take a second here.
Email tracking dot Evo teams dot
com.
Sometimes this might take a second
too.
So give it it might might take a
minute.
But anyways, I'm going to press
save reset.
Check status again.
All right, cool.
So might take a second email
tracking.
I'm going to double check.
Uh, open dot so lead track email
tracking dot Evo teams dot com.
Strange.
Usually this, this goes right
away.
Let me pause and try and figure
this out.
Oh, look, looks like I just had a
space at the end here.
That's why that didn't work.
Awesome.
All right, seen and verified.
We're going to press save here.
And so this is all set up.
So you only need to do this once
per domain, not per inbox.
So like if you have two inbox in
one domain, you do it once each
domain
because it's in the DNS settings.
Warm up.
This is where you can configure
that we're going to enable warm
up.
These are the settings I like to
use.
I like to do 30 warm up emails per
day.
I like to randomize it between 20
and 30 with a five day ramp up.
Set the reply rate to 50 and then
leave this off.
And then we're going to press
update.
And so now this account is all
connected to smart lead.
It's all set.
Ready to go.
That's how you connect a Google
account to smart lead front to
back.
Open a close.
You, uh, I, hopefully you stuck
around with me here for all of
these 20 minutes
and you were taking notes.
I try to get through this as quick
as possible, uh, because there are
a lot of steps.
All you have to do is just repeat
this for each one of the domains
that you have,
and then you should be all set.
So that's how you set up Google
accounts.
If you have any questions, ask one
of your student success coaches or
show up at one of my calls.
And hopefully that was really
useful.
Appreciate you guys.