Okay, let's say that you run a
campaign and your inbox is
completely empty and you're not
getting any responses like the one
I went over in the last video.
That means your copy is just not
good enough and you need to update
it
So here's how to update your cop
your copy.
So you actually fill your inbox
with replies
Here's an example of a campaign
angle that did not work at
All to the point where I had to
turn it off
So here's how to test
New angles for your campaign,
right?
Because here's the reality of
things not every single piece of
copy
You work is gonna get results.
It's just not gonna happen
But that's part of the game and
the real good cold emailers know
how to troubleshoot and test new
messaging to get things back on
track
So what would I do in this
scenario to get this angle to
work?
I would just make it a lot
simpler, right?
I think this call to action of a
video going over a cold email
strategy
Email strategy for you and some
results we've got for web design
agencies is a little bit too
Detailed so what I would do as a
test is something like hey first
name
Icebreaker.
Are you looking for more web?
Design clients right now
I can help you generate 10 to 12
new leads a month
looking
for a new website
All from a cold outreach campaign
I recorded a video
Explaining what this campaign
would look like
Mind if I share the video here,
right?
So the first thing that I do
whenever a piece of copy is not
working is
Is I rethink the call to action
and make it much simpler because
chances are the person just
doesn't know or they don't see the
value in
Saying yes to what I'm asking a
video going over a cold email
strategy for me and some results
for clients like mine
It's a little bit long-winded.
It's a little bit, you know
open-ended instead
Hey, I can get you 10 to 12 new
leads a month looking for a new
website all from cold email
I recorded a video explaining what
this would look like mind if I
share the video here
Much more simplified and easy to
consume
That's just how you're gonna get
better results with your campaigns
and even still this might not work
You're just gonna have to test and
test and mix and match and test
different things until you land on
a winning angle
like I have here
With 20 positive replies from
email 1d compared to 1 3 and 10
Or 1 3 and 4 on the other angles,
right?
So I literally did this in real
time and
Found that this angle didn't
really work
This angle didn't really work
This angle didn't really work, but
this angle email D worked really
well.
Why did it work so well?
Are you taking on new clients
right now?
We can deliver you 10 and 12 new
prospects a month all from cold
email looking for a new website
Want to see a video breaking down
our strategy and some results
we've gotten for our web design
clients, right?
So can I sit here and tell you
why?
This angle did significantly
better than this and this and this
I can't I really can't because
sometimes clients will come to me
With insanely long cold emails
that are just not well written and
I can tell right away
This isn't gonna work, but
sometimes I couldn't tell you why
certain things work and certain
things don't so that's why you
just have to
Consistently test and find new
ways to to frame your offer,
right?
I'm using an icebreaker.
I'm not using a question
icebreaker here
I'm not using a question here.
I'm not using a question here
So maybe this angle I was using
the question icebreaker to get
people to answer and it was
working, right?
Maybe the subject line was better
quick question didn't work
quick question didn't work, right?
So maybe
It was the opener being a question
um
Maybe it was the fact that I said
10 to 12 new prospects a month
looking for a new website build
compared to 12 new leads a month
compared to
Yeah, so like literally
Cold email is a funny funny game
because all the angles that are
well written look like this three
sentences
nothing to them really
um
But some just get better responses
than others like you can see i've
reached out to 7600 people and
i've got 20
People to say yes one and every
one in every 384 people wants more
information
And that is a very very solid
Throughput that I should keep
working on and keep building on
This one is a clear loser
I only got one response out of
1100 people
um
This one three responses out of
1100 this one four responses out
of 1100
On paper, these are actually not
bad, but I turned them off a long
time ago and people just trickled
in over time
So when I updated this it was like
10 to 1 to 1 to 1 and d was a
clear winner
So I shut everything else off and
just ran with the winning angle,
right?
So when you're testing
What to look out for when testing
new messaging
Changing up the icebreaker
Should it be a question?
Should it be?
Statement like
saw
You're in charge of
Company names
Marketing like should it be one of
those options?
Um
Testing new call to actions
Should you pitch a video?
Or a sample piece of work?
Or
A video going over a specific
Strategy, right?
Testing new offers
Offers
Pitching
Um calls versus leads versus sales
Verse
Prospects
Um
Right, so those are the main
things you want to switch
What did I test in this angle that
got such good results?
It was the icebreaker that was
different and it's the call to
action that's different and the 10
to 12 new prospects offer
That's different.
So
You know
This is probably irrelevant to you
when you're just starting out
But once you guys start running
campaigns
Um and seeing results come through
And testing and trying stuff for
new clients
You're going to come back to this
video like oh what christian is
saying makes a lot of sense
And I need to keep testing
different things
That i'm saying to get better
results
Like you can see here
In email too, i'm pitching a video
straight off the rip
I created a video going over a
cold email strategy for you
Whereas in the other one i'm
testing
An offer we can deliver you 10 to
12 prospects
Case study video pitch and this
one is doing better
Because it's clear
That 10 to 12 new prospects per
month interested in a new website
build all from cold email is a
very very
Um enticing offer to people that
they want to raise their hand and
say yes to so
Hopefully this was valuable to
show you guys what you need to be
testing with your messaging to get
better results
We're going to go into the
targeting later on but I want to
give you a master class in
messaging right now
So, you know exactly
What you need to be saying to get
people to raise their hand
And in the next video
I'm going to show you guys how to
film a video to get people on the
phone
Because if you see a lot of my
angles
I'm pitching a video in the email
So when someone says yes to my
email
How do I actually go out and film
that video?
I'm going to show you exactly how
to film that video in the next
Video of this training so see you
there in a second
Thanks