All right.
So the next video is going to be
about positioning your offers.
There's multiple
different types of offers you can
make as a content agency owner.
But the main thing to keep
in mind is just the ROI that we're
pitching.
So I actually already recorded a
video on this,
so I'm going to cut to it.
But before I cut to it, I just
want to give you guys some extra
context and information.
So the current offer we run with
is we basically guarantee sales
calls.
So there's a results triangle.
I mean, I know this isn't a
triangle in here, but you can like
imagine it being a triangle and
guaranteeing money is the
strongest form of an offer.
Guaranteeing
clients is next and then sales
calls after that and then leads.
It just gets weaker as you go
down.
We don't want to be as a content
agency saying, I'm going to make
you five videos or something like
that or per month or four YouTube
videos a month.
No, you need to say, I'm going to
get you five
clients a month.
I'm going to get you 10 to 30
calls a month.
I'm going to make you 50K,
whatever
it might be.
I know you probably have some
predetermined thoughts about
having a guarantee
like you're scared you're not
going to get results because
you're a beginner.
Well, guess what?
You
have no social proof.
So either you put on a guarantee
or you're going to outreach for
like
12 months or something and not
sign someone.
Yes, you can sign someone without
a guarantee,
but why would you want to make it
so much harder on yourself?
The reality is if you have a
guarantee,
it's the difference between
signing 100 clients and refunding
one or two and signing only 20
clients.
You would have made an extra
million dollars.
So it's like you might as well do
it.
Who cares if
you refunded like a little $3,000?
It's worth the extra million.
So yeah, I'm going to cut to the
video now that goes over it.
And if you guys have any
questions, just let me know.
What's up guys today.
We're going to be talking about
offers.
So when I started my content
agency,
I had an offer where I was like,
I'm going to repurpose your long
form videos into short form
videos.
Now this was cool and it got my
foot in the door, but what ended
up happening with the first
person I closed is that I didn't
even close them necessarily on
that offer.
I ended up closing them
on something else, but we'll get
into that in a bit.
This exact offer strategy is how I
closed my first
client within 23 days.
And it's also how I scaled it to
15 K a month within 90 days and
how I hit
93.5 K a month in 15 months.
And I hit 132 K a month in 25
months from launching.
So today I'm
going to reveal everything related
to your offer.
The number one mistake that you
are probably making
right now with your offer as a
video agency owner is you're not
pitching an end result.
So when you pitch
people, they don't care about 30
short form videos, they don't care
about freaking four long
form videos.
They don't care about your
repurposing their reels.
No, they care about what they're
going
to get out of the videos.
Even if they're paying you for a
simple, simple service, such as
editing,
you need to think to yourself, why
is this person giving me money?
And they're giving you money
because they want to make more
money out of it, right?
They're thinking of your service
as an
investment.
So if you're not pitching it that
way, you're not pitching straight
to their desires.
And if you're not pitching to what
somebody wants, you're going to
make less money.
Because imagine
somebody wants to buy carrots, and
then you start talking about like
the green leaf part on the top
of the carrot, right?
You're not pitching them what they
want, but rather you need to pitch
what they want,
which is the carrots.
That was a really funny random
example that I just came up with
on the fly.
But I digress.
So the main thing people want is
money.
If you're pitching a service-based
business
or an online coach, you know,
people want clients.
So you can guarantee, hey, I'll
get you this amount
of clients per month.
Or you can say you'll get them
this amount of sales calls.
Or you can say
you'll get them this many views as
well.
There's basically a ranking,
right?
The higher up you go on
the circle, which is more
aggressive of a claim, or I should
say the triangle.
The higher up you go on
the triangle, the easier it's
going to be to sign clients
because you're making a more
aggressive
claim.
So all the way at the top, we have
pitching clients and are just
guaranteeing money, actually.
Like you say, hey, I'm going to
make you $50,000 basically, or you
don't pay, right?
That's going to
be the easiest thing to sell
because you're pitching as close
as you can to the person's
desires.
They want
to make money.
And the next one level down, which
is pretty much equal to money, to
be honest, is you
say, hey, I'm going to give you
this amount of clients through
Instagram, through YouTube,
through
whatever, through whatever type of
system.
And then one level down from that
is you're going to get them
qualified sales calls.
And then one level down from
qualified sales calls is leads.
I don't ever
recommend anybody guarantees
leads.
And then one level below leads is
views.
So with views, I'm not a big
fan anymore of like telling
people, hey, you're going to get
this amount of views.
It's just a
personal preference thing.
Because at the end of the day,
there are people who want views.
There's
people who are like, hey, I just
want to make, I want to get 100
million views a month, or I want
to
get 50 million views a month or
whatever.
And we have clients who we've
gotten millions of views for
before, and they're really happy
with the views.
Also, as a result of the views,
though, they're making
money.
And the real thing they wanted to
get by getting the views is money.
So I prefer just pitching
closer to money, if that makes
sense.
So you can definitely pitch views,
nothing wrong with it.
I
just like going a bit higher up
than that.
Because why do they want views to
make more money?
And then
next, underneath views, we have
just pitching the actual
deliverable, meaning, hey, I'm
going to get
you 30 videos a month, I'm going
to give you four videos a month.
The problem with pitching the
deliverable is now you're like a
really cheap commodity, you don't
know how to make money from
videos,
and you're going to get lowball
down to shreds.
It's much, much better to go
higher up on the
triangle.
So when you apply this principle,
and you figure out what you're
going to offer people,
you need to put it into a
sentence.
And what this sentence typically
looks like is I'm going to get
you XYZ end result in ABC
timeframe, or you don't pay.
So essentially, it's like, I'm
going to give you
this result, you put the result
there, you can also say through
the name of the mechanism.
So
let's put this into into an actual
sentence.
So it'd be like, we'll get you 10
to 30 qualified sales
calls per month, through YouTube
sales funnel, or you don't pay.
The YouTube sales funnel part is
like
the unique mechanism.
Try and come up with your own
thing.
Don't just rip other people.
I don't use this
offer anymore.
I went like even higher up on the
triangle.
So I'm just using this as example
purposes
for the video.
And you can apply the same concept
to any business, right?
It's just we'll get you this
end result and you have to
guarantee it.
Now I know you're probably
thinking, oh, Eamon, why do I have
to do a guarantee?
You know, it's scary or all these
types of things.
So if you have no social proof or
a
very low amount of social proof or
you're new in the scene, you need
a guarantee and or I don't want to
use the word you need it because
frankly, you don't you can still
get by without a guarantee.
But it just
comes down to how much money you
want to make and how quickly you
want to make it.
Because if you have
a guarantee, it's five times
easier to get people on the phone
and getting people on the phone
with
you on a sales call is the hardest
part.
And then once you get them on a
sales call, you just have to
close them and the guarantee will
help you a lot.
And your refund rate will be low
because with content
nowadays, if you know what you're
doing and you know how to make the
right videos and come up with good
ideas and structure videos, you
can get people results.
And as long as you're doing a good
service
for people, your refund rate is
going to be extremely low.
And when you look at it, like
let's say you
have a guarantee, you sign 100
agency clients and you refund one
versus if you had no guarantee,
but you would have only signed 10
clients, you refunded zero, but
you missed out on the other 90
clients
or so.
So that's sort of the visual I
want you to paint in your head,
even if your refund rate was as
high as
you know, you sign 100 clients and
you refunded 30, like you still
would have made more.
And yeah, you would
have made more than that.
I know some people in the comments
can be like, Oh, but you have
higher costs
because you still fulfilled for
those people refunded for you'll
still have made more than the
people who had
no guarantee.
It's literally such a no brainer.
Way later on, like once you you
get more money, like sure, maybe
you
can remove it, but it's best to
just put all the cards in your
favor and actually do like what's
going
to make you the most money now.
So that's most of the stuff I
wanted to say about offers.
Let me just
think if there's anything I
missed.
One other thing is the language
you use in your offer should be
easy
to understand by your target
demographic.
So let's say you're working with
like personal injury lawyers,
right?
They don't use the word clients,
like rather they use cases like,
Oh, how many new cases do we
get per month or whatever?
So you want to make sure you're
using specific language that your
target
demographic would understand
inside of your offer.
If financial advisors have this
specific term, like
they say accounts or something, or
they say there's a specific term
for them.
It's like AUM.
It means
like how much total money they're
managing.
You use those terms.
So whatever your target
demographic
cares about in the specific
vocabulary as well, you use it and
do the same thing in your
marketing as
well.
You need to use the language that
your prospects will understand
because this is instantly going to
make you look like, you know how
to work with their niche.
Like if you're pitching financial
advisors
and you're, you're using the
language they use on a day-to-day
basis, they're going to be like,
okay, this guy, he's in the world
of financial advisors.
He's not just some random Joe
Schmo.
Let me go and work with him.
Make sure you're pitching an end
result because nobody buys videos
to buy videos unless it's a
passion project.
And those are just one-offs
anyways, but nobody buys
videos just to buy videos.
They buy videos to make money or
at least 99.9% of your customers
will
have that intention.
So you might as well speak
directly to their desires because
you will make
more money doing so.
I have a free group in the
description with a free course as
well that I'm
cooking up.
There's a ton of free videos in
there already, but I'm cooking up
a free course right now.
And then if you want to work with
me one-to-one, that's also linked
below and that's it.
Peace out.