Okay guys so today we're going to
talk about how to make content
that gets clients so you guys all
need to be posting content at the
same time as you're doing your
outreach because what happens
when you outreach people is
they're going to click into your
profile before responding to you
and you know you probably already
have no social proof maybe a
little bit so having content is
like literally it can be the
difference between you signing a
client in 21 days versus like four
months so just make sure you're
posting ideally you're posting
four youtube videos a month
ideally eight but four is fine um
starting out and then because you
have to manage your time and
stuff right um try and pick
another platform as well like
twitter or linkedin if you have
some extra
time um but really focus on
posting youtube videos for sure
you can also do instagram reels i
found it
pretty difficult to get done for
you agency clients through ig
reels though so i recommend just
making
one pinned reel just so when
people visit your profile they
have something to see about your
offer your social proof etc but
for the most part you'll be
focusing on your youtube content
that's
where the highest roi is for
yourselves and for your clients um
as most of you i assume will be
offering a youtube service so i'm
going to cut into a video i
recorded talking about how to sign
clients from youtube or more
specifically how to make content
that gets clients look i'm going
to be
straight with you there's a
specific way to create youtube
videos that consistently attract
high paying
clients and most people are doing
it completely wrong we use this
exact system to help one of our
clients
go from 30k to 75k per month in
just 120 days and no it wasn't
because he went viral or had some
crazy
expensive setup we even have other
case studies like simone just
booked 250 sales calls in the
first two
weeks of the month you heard that
right 250 sales calls in 14 days
didn't go viral no expensive setup
nothing like that the youtube game
is about creating videos that
actually work and get clients
knowing
what topics to cover how to
structure them so people keep
watching and how to package them
so your ideal
clients can't help but click i'm
going to break down that entire
system so you can steal it and
start booking
calls with qualified prospects
consistently step one is coming up
with video ideas that actually get
you clients and this is where most
people mess up right from the
start they create content that
gets
views but doesn't get clients and
there's a humongous difference
okay so here's content that gets
views day in the life of a seven
figure entrepreneur moving from
vancouver to dubai something like
that
now content that gets clients is
like how i scaled my consulting
business to 50k a month in nine
months
using youtube for example you see
the difference one is
entertainment attracting peewee
brain people
who want this lifestyle but don't
want to work for it the other
one's education that positions you
as
the expert and who's going to
watch this right someone who wants
to also scale their consulting
business through youtube now
here's the three video funnel that
works okay the top of funnel
categories
in the action-based how-to video
so here's what i did for my
coaching program which is my
second
business so these are your
step-by-step tutorials people are
literally typing these phrases
into
youtube search okay how to get
your first high-paying client how
to price your consulting services
how to create a sales funnel that
converts the key is being specific
don't just say how to get
clients say how to get your first
5k client in 30 days without cold
calling whatever it might be
quick tip go to youtube right now
and type how to your expertise see
what auto completes those
suggestions you can turn them into
video ideas now your middle funnel
is going to be educational why
videos so this is one i did
targeting agency clients and
talking about the real reason
prospects
ghost you after sales calls i was
educating the viewer i'm telling
them hey you need to make youtube
videos because then people are
going to trust you more and like
you more and they're not going to
no show you that's the premise of
the video so these videos position
you as an authority who
understands the industry better
than everyone else so you could
say why most coaches fail to scale
past
10k a month and what to do instead
why cold outreach doesn't work
anymore use this instead why i
stopped
taking clients under 5k and you
should too these aren't tutorials
but they're insight pieces that
show
your unique expertise and
methodology and then the final
category is going to be bottom of
funnel
social proof content so this is
where you separate yourself from
every other coach talking about
strategy
you show actual results so you're
going to do this through client
interviews so you can film a 15
minute call with a successful
client and ask about their
transformation their results and
what it was
like working with you you can use
riverside.fm to record this and
the next is going to be a case
study
breakdown so for this one you're
not actually going to have the
client in the video it's going to
be just you
breaking down step by step how you
got in this result now if you want
to know how to research what your
market actually wants here's how
you find out because you don't
want to be guessing okay you're
going to check your
dms and emails what questions do
people ask you most often each
question is a potential video so
for
example if a lot of people ask me
hey amen is it worth it to do
youtube shorts i should probably
go
and make a youtube video about
that because if one person has
that question anywhere from a
thousand
to a hundred thousand people plus
have that exact same question but
they're just too scared to ask
or they haven't asked yet now next
you're going to want to look at
your sales calls and see what
objections are coming up
repeatedly what do people get
confused about make videos
addressing those exact
points spy on your competition
what videos are getting the most
engagement in your space
make better versions with your
unique angle and finally you'll
use actual search data you can use
tools like vidiq so you can see
what people are actually searching
for but honestly nowadays you
just have to type in the youtube
search bar and see what auto
completes or just look at the
videos
that come up when you search on
youtube you don't even need to use
a tool now step two is the script
structure that keeps people
watching so here's the thing you
don't want to script everything
word for
word or you'll sound like a robot
but you do need structure okay so
the hook is anywhere from zero to
30 seconds this makes or breaks
your video so you literally have
30 seconds max to convince
someone to keep watching keep it
short especially if you're selling
a b2b service the last thing you
want to do is some elaborate two
minute intro now pay off the click
if your title says how to get your
first 5k client immediately
confirm that that's what you're
going to show them and then you're
going to
want to add quick social proof
mention a result or case study to
establish credibility so here's an
example look i'm about to show you
how to land your first 5k client
in the next 30 days this is the
same system i use to help my
client sarah go from 0 to 15k a
month in 90 days and by the end of
this
video you'll have the complete
roadmap now for the body which is
the bulk of the video the middle
part
you're going to want to use bullet
points and not full scripts write
down your main points then
elaborate naturally when recording
this keeps you sound and
conversational you'll also want to
weave in
social proof naturally throughout
so don't save all your case
studies for the end or that little
piece
in the hook just sprinkle it in
throughout the video you'll also
want to sell them on the next
section so at
the end of each point tease what's
coming up next so like but knowing
how to price is only half the
battle in a minute i'll show you
the exact script that gets clients
to say yes immediately that's an
example and then you're going to
do your mid video cta around the
30 to 50 mark this is where most
people
completely miss the boat they
either have no cta or wait until
the end when 80 of their viewers
have
already clicked off the video
place it strategically around
one-third to halfway through your
video
make it feel natural don't just
randomly interrupt your content
and transition into it smoothly so
here's a quick
example by the way if you're an
online coach or agency owner or
consultant making over 30k a month
and you want me to make you videos
completely done for you just hit
the first link down in the
description i'll do everything
ideas scripts editing thumbnails
seo posting you just have to
record for
two to three hours per month but
that's it back to the video that
was my mid body cta so if you're
a coach consultant agency owner do
that but the outro here which is
the final 30 seconds you're going
to
sell them on watching more of your
content you're going to recommend
them a specific related video so
don't just say like check out my
other videos you can if you want
if you don't have anything
specific
to point them to but it's better
if you tell them a specific video
also reinforce your main call to
action from earlier in the video
and then if you're going to ask
them to subscribe like just do it
very
quickly you know don't dwell on it
too much you know hey make sure
here what i'm saying is like
push them to book a call join your
webinar or free group whatever it
might be now step three is
creating thumbnails that actually
get clicks your thumbnail is the
first thing people see and it
determines whether they click or
scroll past and here's what
actually works the psychology of
click-worthy thumbnails is very
simple people process images in
three seconds or less actually
much quicker than that to be
honest if they can't understand
what your video is about they
instantly
won't click so if you look at this
okay the top video which is the
one we made when you type growth
operator is a nice green cool
thumbnail has like big text on it
like you can look at the thumbnail
know
what the video is about but when
you look at the two other
thumbnails like you're kind of
like i
don't know what this is about
necessarily not to say that these
videos performed well or this guy
doesn't know what
he's doing you know the videos
performed great but ours performed
really good it's because we have a
good
thumbnail good title good hook
good everything bright thumbnails
stand out okay most people browse
youtube
in dark mode as you can see here
so brighter thumbnails naturally
catch more attention as
you can see here you know i'm
wearing a red hoodie here i'm not
actually wearing a red hoodie my
hoodie
was black we just turned it red
you know i got like big phones
here i got like blue white
everything
is very bright numbers get more
clicks okay so write five thousand
dollars instead of five thousand
dollars use three steps instead of
three steps like use the number
that's what i'm trying to say
show your face in your thumbnails
okay thumbnails with faces
generally perform better because
people
connect with people and also over
time as you build like brand
equity like for me i'm like the
content
agency guy or the youtube guy
people see my face they know my
face so they're gonna click it but
if the
thumbnail had no face on it they
might not clock it that that's
actually my video so here's the
formula
that works four words or less the
more text you add the less like
people are to click just keep it
simple
high contrast text is needed to
use thick outlines thick text
thick drop shadows so you can
easily read it
even on small screens just always
remember to optimize for iphone
because that's going to be where
most of the traffic is
the thumbnails aren't huge on an
iphone they're pretty small so if
you have some little text no
one's going to see that right a
lot of the times when we're doing
revisions with our thumbnail
designer we're constantly telling
him like hey keep in mind that
like you know this is for iphone
and
then he quickly tweaks it right
show the transformation so if you
can obviously depend on the topic
of the
video use before and after images
or show the end result they'll get
also use familiar icons so if
you're talking about email
marketing include an envelope or
like a gmail icon or like a
klaviyo icon if
it's about youtube include the
youtube play button so on and so
forth now step four here's how all
your
videos work together as a client
acquisition system this is the
secret sauce okay your videos
shouldn't exist in isolation they
should work together as a complete
system that moves people
from stranger to paying client the
strategic content calendar
approach week one do an
action-based how-to
video this is gonna get new people
in week two do an educational why
video which builds your authority
and unique perspective week three
do a social proof content like a
client interview or a case study
and
then week four just like repeats
cycle consistently and then
eventually over time maybe week
five week six
you can drop that free course
video once the channel is warmed
up and then just keep cycling
through action-based educational
social proof this rotation ensures
you're constantly attracting new
people building authority and
providing proof that your method
actually works now here's how your
videos
pre-qualify prospects when someone
watches three to four of your
videos before booking a call they
already understand your
methodology trust your expertise
know your pricing philosophy align
with your
approach your sales calls become
less about convincing and more
about qualifying whether they're a
good fit now
on top of this obviously you want
to add like a type form and
different qualification metrics so
we can
reject the unqualified leads and
prevent them from slipping through
the cracks but naturally youtube
is
just such a high iq platform where
just smart people are using it and
if they consume so much of your
content they just get so pre-sold
but like if someone's just doom
scrolling on ig reels you can get
very low iq people on your
calendar which is what we don't
want so example right instead of
explaining
your entire process on a call you
can say like i mentioned in my
video about scaling 50k a month or
whatever the title is the first
thing we need to do is blah blah
blah if they told you before that
they came
from your youtube channel so we
want to create your content
ecosystem so think of each video
as serving
a specific purpose in your funnel
so you're going to have discovery
videos which is the how-to content
and then the authority videos
which is educational and then the
conversion videos which is social
proof
and then you also have the free
course in here as well so try and
link between your videos
strategically at the end at the
end of a how to get clients video
you can make a video that's
like how to fulfill for your
clients right they kind of lead
nicely into each other so
create a pathway that keeps people
in your ecosystem now on the
production side keep it simple
but professional here's the
equipment you actually need your
phone is completely good to record
with okay
seriously most people can't tell
the difference between iphone
footage and a 2k camera as long
as the lighting is good and then
for audio this matters a lot more
than video quality because you
can have bad video quality but if
like you're actually saying
something important and the audio
is
good people will still watch but
not vice versa you can get a good
microphone for like 100 to 300
bucks
on amazon i like the sure mv7 plus
for lighting try and sit facing a
window like i am right now
natural light is free and looks
great now for the background just
keep it clean and simple
a plain wall or a simple office
setup works perfectly now quick
recording tips that actually do
make a
difference record in segments so
don't try and nail a 15 minute
video in one take record each
section
separately and then edit them
together also it's okay to pause
and check your notes you can edit
out
the pauses don't try and memorize
everything by any means you can
also record multiple hook options
so
you can try two to three different
versions of your opening and then
have the editor or your team or
yourself pick the best one and
energy matters more than
perfection a passionate slightly
imperfect
delivery beats a perfect boring
one every time now here's your
implementation plan okay start
this
week okay stop pushing it off
because i know you have been for a
while pick your first video topic
okay choose the most common
problem your ideal clients have
that's your sweet spot write a
simple
outline hook three main points mid
video cta and a conclusion film it
don't overthink the setup good
enough is better than perfect
create a basic thumbnail in canva
or photoshop keep it simple
include your face
in clear text and then post and
move on don't obsess over the
first video plan your next one now
you
don't need to go viral to actually
get clients from youtube funny
enough we have clients who get
anywhere from 300 to
a thousand views per video
including my youtube channel and
we still get clients from the
videos
it's actually pretty crazy
compared to an ig real you have to
get like 5 000 10 000 views it's
like
pretty annoying youtube 300 to a
thousand views you're good and i'm
not talking about 300 to a
thousand
views on a day in the life video
i'm talking about on like my type
of video like this one you're
watching
right now just focus on solving
real problems for your ideal
clients and everything will change
most
people are trying to be the next
mr beast when really they should
be trying to be the obvious choice
for
their ideal clients so what's next
the difference between business
owners who struggle to book calls
and those who consistently get
those 5k clients isn't talent or
luck it's having a systematic
approach
to content that positions you as
the authority in your space so you
could spend the next six months
trying to figure this out through
trial and error watching my
youtube videos or you could have a
professional youtube system
running within nine days i can
have your first video live within
nine
days so if you want my help
implementing this exact system on
a done for you basis where we
handle ideation
scripting editing thumbnails seo
optimization and posting just
click the first link down in the
description but honestly again i
try and make my videos super
valuable so you can just rip what
i'm
saying and go try it yourself of
course you'll get results way
slower you might not even get
results
but with us at least results are
guaranteed so that's pretty much
it if you want a good video to
watch next watch the one where i
talk about how to come up with
youtube video ideas but that's
pretty much it i'll see you in the
next video