All right guys, so today we're
going to be going over the ICP and
also the lead generation method.
So ICP means your ideal client
profile.
So before you reach out to anyone,
you need to know
exactly who you want to sign as
clients.
And I'm going to walk through all
that today.
I've worked
with many, many different people
and I know exactly like who's
good, who's bad to work with,
et cetera.
There's many niches.
There's coaches, consultants,
agency owners, info product
sellers,
software companies.
There's like roofers, brick and
mortar, lawyers, financial
advisors.
There's
like so, so many niches.
So I'm going to break it all down
for you today.
The ICP is so important
and you need to like develop the
skill of being able to tell if
somebody is qualified or not,
because otherwise you're going to
be like wasting a lot of time on
your outreach.
So let's get right
into it.
So this should be your ICP.
Just listen to what I say.
Don't challenge me and it will
work.
This is the best ICP.
If you really want, you can throw
in software companies too, but
they tend to
take longer to make decisions.
And as a beginner, you're pretty
poor.
Like you need to like make money
quicker and software companies are
slow and we want to work with
people who are fast.
These people
make the decision maker.
If two at maximum, they don't have
to run the decision up to the
board of
investors and some stupid BS.
So make sure they're selling high
ticket.
So high ticket means a product
or service above $3,000 or like at
least the LTV lifetime value is
over 3,000.
Meaning over the
lifetime of working with a certain
customer, they would have made
3,000.
Who you don't want to work
with is somebody who's running a
school group for $27 a month
because their churn is 70% and
people leave
after two months and per customer,
they're making $60.
It's much, much easier for someone
to get an ROI
on your service or return on
investment.
If you know, they're paying you 3k
a month for their content
service and they just have to
close one person.
Okay.
They're break even close two
people.
Now they're
two X profitable.
So you need to approach this
business and every business with
the mindset of, Hey,
I need an ROI for my customers.
That's how I'm going to keep them
long-term.
Of course you need good
customer service and other things.
I'm sure Andre will cover that or
somebody else in a different
part of the course.
I'm also going to cover it later
on as well.
But going back to this,
if somebody is selling low ticket,
but they're ascending them into
high ticket, that's fine.
So what that means is, give me one
second.
So if somebody is selling a
product for like $20,
but then after they buy the $20
product, they're calling them and
selling them a $3,000 thing,
that's fine too.
No, no worries at all with that.
So coaches, consultants, people
selling coaching
programs, courses, et cetera,
agency owners, you guys are agency
owners, but you want to make sure
you're selling to people that make
above like 20 K months because
anybody below that, they're going
to be a pain in the ass client.
They can't afford your service
after expenses, taxes, food,
apartment,
giving money to people like
family, whatever they're poor.
So you don't really want to close
them.
But the unfortunate truth is when
you're a beginner agency owner,
naturally you're going to get more
bottom of the barrel clients.
And then as you progress, as you
get more social proof, you can
be more picky with who you work
with, et cetera.
So don't like turn down things,
but I'm just warning
you, like if you work with someone
who makes 5K months, it's going to
be the worst thing ever
because they're going to negotiate
your price.
They're going to like really need
your content
service to work.
And it's going to be brutal.
Make sure these people are selling
online because
if you're working with a like
cheeseburger spot in freaking
Atlanta, like it's not going to
work
because it's a food joint, but
also like their TAM, the total
adjustable market, it's only in
like
Atlanta.
I mean, it's actually like just
that little part of Atlanta where
like the cheeseburger
factory is.
So it's a funny example.
But if you work with people who
sell online, let's say you get
them a hundred K views on a
YouTube video or a million views
on a reel, they can sell to
freaking
Canada, Switzerland, Germany,
Dubai, like you name it.
Right.
And then this like, make sure they
value
attention.
I mean, pretty much everyone
values attention.
Make sure they can afford like two
to 5K
retainers.
So my personal general rule of
thumb is 10%.
So what that means is if someone
makes 20K a
month, you can charge them 2K a
month for marketing.
If they make 30, you can charge
340, you can charge
four, so on and so forth.
Your goal is to only target people
in this ICP, not random small
businesses that
can't pay or like passion projects
that don't care about ROI.
You can work with someone if they
don't
care about like a cash ROI and
they want just like views and
subscribers, just make sure to set
proper expectations.
Cool.
So that's the ICP now in terms of
the dream 100 outreach.
So this is the
number one free client acquisition
method for content use.
It's free meaning like you're not
really paying
for these customers with money.
You're paying for it with your
time.
So what you're doing is reaching
out manually to your top 100 dream
prospects with extremely
personalized outreach.
You're not spamming a
thousand copy paste DMs.
You're not blasting cold emails
with VAs.
Instead, you're giving upfront
free
value to five to 10 people every
single day.
So this strategy worked for me in
2022, worked for me in
2023, worked for me in 2024.
It still works in 2025.
Although transparently, I do less
this year because
I have other means of acquisition,
but we still sling them sometimes.
Like I literally did a loom like
three days ago.
I closed a client for 5K a month.
It'll work for years because it's
evergreen.
At the end of
the day, it's human psychology
where we're doing a piece of free
work for someone.
They feel
indebted to you.
They feel like they need to reply.
They need to check what you sent.
I scaled
zero to 15K in 82 days using dream
100 outreach.
So this works.
So first you need to build your
list.
Step one is finding your ICP.
Where do they hang out?
Is it going to be Twitter,
Instagram, YouTube,
TikTok?
I mean, to be honest with you, if
you want the answer, it's all of
them.
They're everywhere.
They're on Twitter.
They're on Instagram.
They're on YouTube.
They're on LinkedIn as well.
Those are the
main four sort of spots.
Of course, they're on TikTok too.
I don't really personally use that
to find
leads.
They're also in Discord groups,
Telegrams, Masterminds, paid
coaching programs.
I've used
this a lot where I joined programs
and I started signing people
inside of them, but obviously that
costs money.
What you want to do on these
platforms is you want to find one
person that's qualified,
which is pretty easy to do.
For example, you can just go on
YouTube, search how to drop ship,
and then you'll see someone named
Samir, for example.
And then you go to Samir's
Instagram and
then look at who he follows.
So he'll have like 100,000
followers, whatever, but he'll
follow
like 700 people.
You click that 700, rich people
will follow all the rich people.
So then now you
have a ton of leads in there that
you can reach out to.
Once you exhaust that list, you go
through
manually qualify everyone.
Then you're going to go on to the
next person.
So you're going to be like,
okay, inside of the 700 following,
there's one guy named Wiz of Ecom.
Cool.
Let me click Wiz of Ecom.
Now he follows 2000 people.
Now I'm going to go through that
whole list and then, okay, now I'm
going to
pick one person.
Boom.
And you kind of keep going, going
and going and going forever.
This is how
you're going to find leads.
Another way to find leads is you
just search things up, like how to
scale an agency, SMMA tips, or
maybe you want a drop shipping
client.
You're going to search how to
drop ship, how to find a product.
Maybe you want an AI agency
person.
You're going to search up like
how to use AI for XYZ.
Boom.
You're going to find AI clients.
And for Twitter, you're going to
use that
same method I said earlier.
So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to cut to a prerecorded
video I've
already made that just like shows
me like actually doing this live.
And then I'll cut back to this
video.
I'm going to do that in a second
though.
So yeah, I just want to finish
running through what I wrote
here.
And then I'll cut to that video
just so you guys get the actual
visual example.
So
ideally they have more than a
thousand followers.
Guys, this isn't like a rigid
rule.
There's people
with 200 followers who make like a
billion dollars a month, but like
it's usually like a decent
telltale
sign.
Ideally, they have an active
posting history and they're not
like dead on socials.
Ideally,
they have social proof as well.
Social proof is a great way to
tell if somebody makes more than
20k
months.
Also just kind of their lifestyle
or like where they're living, what
their camera setup looks like,
these types of things.
Like you need to just pick up like
little cues, right?
Because there's no way to
actually like look at someone's
Instagram and be like, oh, this
guy makes 73k a month and this guy
makes 82k a month.
It's like, no, you have to guess
based on what you can see, how
much social proof
they have, how many customers
they've worked with, what comes up
when you search them up and how
many
YouTube videos they have, et
cetera, how many views they're
getting.
Also, they need to have a clear
positioning.
Like if you ever see someone who's
like, oh, I help like people with
like life
coaching or they're just very
broad and it's like a stupid
offer, like they're probably not
making
money, right?
So like don't work with them.
You can kind of like tell how good
someone is at business
and then based on that, you can
guess how much money they're
making, factoring in how much
traffic
they're getting.
This might sound complicated.
The video I cut to will explain
it, but this is a skill
you're going to develop over time.
And then again, just make sure
they have social proof.
From there,
you're just going to build a
spreadsheet.
You're going to put everyone's
name on there and then
you're going to put their Twitter
link, Instagram, LinkedIn, email,
and their website.
You're not going
to find this for everybody.
Some people will only find Twitter
and IG.
Some people only LinkedIn and
email.
Everybody's like a little bit
different, but all the platforms
you can find, you put them here
because what's going to happen is
when we're actually doing the
outreach, you're going to be
reaching out
on all four platforms at the same
time.
So just copy pasting the same
message across all platforms.
In terms of finding their email,
you can use list kit.
But yeah, just fill this
spreadsheet with
a hundred people.
So I'm going to cut to that video
showing you how to find these
leads.
And
then I'm going to come back and
continue.
All right, guys.
So this is how you get high ticket
clients for your content agency.
And these are recurring high
ticket clients anywhere from 3k a
month to
8k a month.
I use the same method to scale my
content agency from zero to 93k a
month.
So let's get right
into it.
Basically search process.
So we use social media to find
these clients, specifically
Instagram and
Twitter and YouTube.
Those are my favorites.
There's also LinkedIn that works
as well.
And I'm going to do a
live walkthrough of how this
works.
So basically, number one is you
can use keywords, right?
So let's say you go to Twitter and
then you put in the search bar
like coach or helping or founder
or CEO or
stuff like that.
Helping is usually a good keyword.
And then you switch to the people
tab.
Then from there, you
can find people who have those
keywords in their bio.
Those keywords I gave, that's if
you're targeting like
coaches, like they typically have
that in their bio.
Maybe you're targeting like
someone who's like a fitness
guy.
You just want to think, okay, what
do all these guys have in their
bio or like in their name?
What do they have in common?
You put that in the search bar and
then you can find them.
And then once
you find one prospect, right?
Then what you do is you go into
that prospect's following.
So you see
who they follow.
So let's say like you want to
target health and like fitness
coaches like those guys.
So let me show you guys real
quick.
I searched up like health and
wellness on Instagram or just
health.
And then I found this guy and then
you want to go to his following,
right?
So in this case, he only
follows himself on like his
personal account.
So then if we go to his personal
account, this is what it
looks like.
He follows 800 people.
So now, you know, one health and
wellness guy, he probably
follows other health and wellness
dudes.
So now I'm going to go through his
following and I'm going to
find all the other people that
match my ICP.
So I'm going to one by one click
through every single
profile manually.
Yes, you heard that correctly.
And you're going to find the
profiles in here that you
like, or like the ones that are in
your ICP.
And then you're going to add them
to a spreadsheet or
whatever sort of tracker you use,
right?
So that's how you do it.
The reason why we're doing this
manually instead of automated or
something like that is because we
want to make sure that the
people we're collecting, like
these leads, they're actually
people we want to work with.
If you
automatically scrape a list,
you're going to get a ton of weird
people who would never get results
on content.
So that's one thing with a content
agency.
You want to be specific with the
type of
people you work with.
And you really just want to work
with people who you actually think
will get
results.
I mean, I think this goes without
saying for every type of agency,
but specifically content
agencies, some people just aren't
built for being on camera.
You're going to keep repeating
this to
build a list.
Eventually you're going to go
through someone's entire
following.
So in this case,
that dude's following was what,
like 800 people.
So then, you know, you're going to
go through 800
people pretty quick.
You know, maybe you'll get like a
hundred people, 200 people from
that.
So
you're going to want to go to the
next person and just build up a
list.
So typically I build up a list
of like a hundred people and I
just reach out to them because I
know for every hundred people I
reach
out to using the dream 100 method,
which is something I talk about a
lot, I'm going to close one to two
people.
All right.
I know what you're probably
wondering, like, what is the
evaluation process
for these leads?
Like, how do we even know that
they're, you know, qualified?
Like, obviously we
go through this guy's following,
you know, we find all these
people.
How do we know like which ones to
go through?
Like, okay, this dude whiz of
e-com.
How do I know like, okay, this guy
is a good fit or,
you know, what is the evaluation
process?
So basically like number one, you
just want to look at their
social media profile, right?
You want to see like, okay, do
they have a lot of followers?
Do they look like
a noob in business?
We're trying to assess if they can
afford our services, if they need
them
and like, if they're a good fit,
right?
So let's do a live analysis,
I just went through
Oscar's following and I also just
clicked around Instagram and I
found this person.
So Colin,
shout out Colin, great guy.
He's my friend's client.
So I'm not going to try and reach
out to him or
anything like that, but let's do a
live profile analysis on this guy.
So number one, we're going to
check and see, okay, how many
followers does this dude have?
Okay.
He has 700,000.
That's a lot of
followers.
Okay.
Next up.
Let's see.
Okay.
He's posting a Lambo.
He's out on like
yachts in Miami.
Okay.
He's like, he's traveling.
He's flexing the watches.
Okay.
This
guy clearly, you know, he has some
money, right?
Obviously some people are going to
be like flexing
on the internet and like they're
fake, but you can tell by like
looking at their profile or
digging
deeper into them.
You'll, you'll be able to tell,
but this guy, Colin, he's been
around for a while,
posting content, always posting ID
stories.
He's got multiple businesses.
Like he's probably legit.
By the way, guys, I know Colin is
legit.
I'm just like putting myself in
the shoes of like
I'm analyzing someone.
So basically I found the profile.
I analyze them.
So first thing I look
at the followers, I see, do we
have a ton of mutuals?
I'm looking at their lifestyle.
I'm just
trying to see, you know, if
they're a good fit other than
lifestyle and like how much money
they
have.
You want to see if they're already
creating content, right?
So like this guy, he's creating a
ton of content.
Okay.
He's probably a good fit to run up
YouTube, or maybe you want to sell
him short
for him.
Same thing.
He's making content.
So he probably makes money from
his content so we can help him
make more money from his content.
So next up, you'd also want to
just look at his YouTube channel
and
his other socials.
See if like his following is
universal, right?
Cause some people, maybe they
buy followers on one social media
account and they have nothing
anywhere else.
So Colin, he's got
followers on Twitter and he's like
known.
So I'm not going to do that, but
you just want to look at
someone's profiles because you can
buy Instagram followers.
So you always just want to be
careful.
So going through here, I looked at
this.
Okay.
He had a lot of followers.
He doesn't look like a
noob.
So we didn't disqualify him.
Right.
So now I'm going to show you a
profile who probably deserves
to be disqualified.
All right.
So let's say you just went
through, you know, that guy
Oscar's
following and you find this guy
Cyrus, right?
You're looking through it.
Okay.
He has only 800 followers.
Like he doesn't have like a
business in his bio or like
anything explaining what he does.
Like, okay.
It looks like, you know, he's
having fun.
He's like a, some sort of college
kid or something,
but there's no like business stuff
going on here, right?
It's just nothing like this
wouldn't be a good
fit.
We disqualify him right away.
And then like, you know, the
lifestyle doesn't check out,
doesn't have followers.
He looks like a noob.
And then also like we check his
funnel quality.
We'd look at this person's
website, right?
So obviously this guy, Cyrus, you
know, shout out
Cyrus, but he doesn't have any
like website or funnel or anything
in his bio.
So like, let's go back to
Oscar, for example, he's running
like a DME word funnel.
So we can't really like look at
his,
you know, his website and see case
studies and stuff, but he's saying
he has 300 plus client results,
which is very, very good.
Most people have zero also just
scrolling through here.
We can see he has a
good business because he's saying,
Hey, lifetime of digestion issues
fixed in weeks.
You know,
he he's saying, Oh, my hair is
thicker.
Okay.
Cool.
So this guy has a ton of
social proof, right?
So he's legit.
He has like another case study
right here, right here.
He's
also saying he has like a ton of
testosterone.
So this guy's legit.
That's what we're doing in this
funnel step is we're really just
checking like, okay, does this
person have a good business?
Right?
Cause the last thing you want to
do is take on a client who has a
bad business and they
don't get their clients results.
And they're maybe even just
scammers.
So this is one good
way to check because if someone
has social proof, they typically
make money as well.
So next up, we're going to look at
their content success level.
Even if someone has like bad
views on their content, we can
still sign them.
Right.
But this is just good to get a
pulse
on like, where are they at and
where could they want to be?
It just gives you ammo for your
pitch.
So like here, I know I said, Hey,
if it says no, like disqualify
them, but that's not actually
true.
So I'm going to delete that.
All right.
So everything looks good.
So now we're moving
on to the pitch.
So before we pitch, we want to
just add them all to a
spreadsheet,
keep it organized.
Like, Hey, here's all the leads.
You also want to have a tab that
says
like follow-up number one,
follow-up number two, or like
first message sent rejected sales
call book.
This is basically going to be a
CRM.
You want to keep it simple.
You could use a
spreadsheet.
You can use Trello notion to click
up all those types of softwares.
And we're
going to do custom high quality
outreach.
So let me repeat that custom high
quality outreach.
We are not going to do copy paste,
stupid, cool DMS, like those email
people who are like,
Hey, do you, are you doing
anything with email right now?
You know, we don't want to be a
short
form content, bro.
Who's like, Hey, do you need short
form content?
Like, no.
So we're going to do
custom high quality outreach.
So what this means is we're going
to send them free short form
videos
upfront.
We're going to send them content
strategy documents.
We're going to send them fricking
like
just stuff like looms, you know,
scripts, content ideas, a loom
analysis of their content.
Like
really just going to send them
free stuff upfront.
This is custom high quality
outreach.
And this works so
well, because if you invest like
30 minutes to an hour and a single
outreach, and the person sees
that, which they will after the
enormous amount of follow-ups,
they're going to almost feel bad
for
not answering you because you're
putting so much time into it,
right?
This is what we want to do.
When you just text someone, Hey,
do you need short form content?
Hey, do you need a YouTube?
Like it's
so easy to leave you on open.
Cause like, you're just like every
other person, number one.
And number
two, why should I respond to
someone if they're not putting
enough effort, right?
I already have
enough people reaching out to me.
So that's sort of how you want to
do your outreach in terms of
follow-ups.
You want to just keep following up
until they say yes, or they say
no.
So the follow-ups
like you typically want to do one,
two days later, one, like a week
later, one, like two weeks later,
and you just keep going and going
with the follow-ups like for
eternity.
At one point, you'll reduce
the frequency until it's like one
follow-up like per month.
So it'll be like super low effort
on your
end, but we're just going to
continuously touch base with this
person.
And eventually it will work.
Obviously there's going to be like
a couple people where like, they
just never open the DM,
but that's fine.
We also want to reach out to these
people in an omni-channel manner.
So that means
like hit them up on Instagram,
fricking Twitter, email, LinkedIn,
everywhere.
And then eventually
this is going to lead up to a
sales call.
So one thing I want to mention as
well is another way of
finding people like other than
Instagram and Twitter and
LinkedIn, which is the method I
was talking
about.
You can do YouTube, right?
So on YouTube, you could search up
like how to make money online
and you'll find like those gurus
or you'll search up how to get in
better shape.
You'll find like the
fitness coaches.
And then you can go to the about
section and you can grab their
email.
They also
usually have their social media
accounts listed there.
So that's a good way of finding
someone.
So yeah, guys, that's the whole
thing on how to find high paying
clients for your content agency.
Today, I just signed someone for
like 4.5K a month, also closed
like a one-off project and
things are going good with the
agency.
So I still use this method today.
Is this the only method I use?
No, this is half.
The other method I use is personal
branding and inbound,
but like I use this to go from 0
to 15K a month in four months.
And then I use this method
combined
with the inbound personal branding
method to go from 0 to 93K a month
in 15 months.
All right,
guys, that's everything for this
video, but I want you to watch
this video on screen because I
went
over how I scale from 0 to 93.5K a
month in 15 months as a content
agency.
So I'm not a freelancer,
I'm a content agency.
But if you're a freelancer right
now, you could easily transition
into a content
agency.
So that's it.
Hope you enjoyed that video.
And that's it.
Peace out.
All right,
guys, welcome back.
So once you have your spreadsheet,
you can like move them into
Trello,
which is like a free CRM.
So I'm going to cut into another
video now, just walking through
how to
keep your Trello board organized.
Hey, what's up, everybody?
So today I'm going to show you how
to
stay organized while you're
outreaching a hundred dream
prospects, because a hundred dream
prospects,
like that's a lot of people.
I don't think you guys understand.
You know, you could fill up like,
I don't know, three classrooms or
something, right?
So three high school classrooms.
So
basically real quick, I'm going to
show you how to stay organized
with a free CRM.
You know,
most CRMs cost money.
Trello.com is free.
Um, yeah, let's get right into it.
I was about to
mention an affiliate link, but I
don't even think Trello has any,
and it's free anyways.
So basically
you're going to go to Trello.com.
You're going to make a Trello
board, call it dream 100 lead
list,
and then you're going to make a
list.
So whenever I see the word list,
this is what I'm referring to,
like a column, right?
So you're going to make lists.
Each list is a cat is like a
status that
the person, the prospect is in.
And whenever I say card, you know,
like it's a prospect,
like this is a card.
So let me just delete this.
So basically lead in, this is
where we're going to
import those 100 leads.
Next up, we have first message
sent.
So whenever you send the first
message,
you take Johnny, put him in here.
All right.
Two days pass, you know, you set a
thing here so you
can go here and then you go dates.
You could set a due date for two
days from now.
So today's March
9th.
So two days from now by 9 30 PM,
you're going to do a followup.
So now here he's chilling in first
message sent.
And then March 11th, that's going
to say, Oh, this card is due
today.
You're going to know
that you have to send your first
followup.
So boom, you sent your first
And then next
up, you're changed the due date.
So you go here, change the due
date to like two days again, save.
Now, you know, okay, March 13th,
whenever that day comes up, it's
going to say, Oh, due today, then
boom,
you have to send the second
followup.
And then the best part is you have
a calendar here.
So right there,
it said March 13th.
So let me see.
Oh, I don't think I can see the
calendar because you need to
pay, but basically Trello premium,
super cheap, but you could just
see your whole calendar.
You're
going to see, Oh, I have to do
this many followups here, this
many followups on Tuesday, so on
and so
forth.
But I have the free version, so I
can't do it, but you don't need
it.
You just look at the dates
on the card.
So first message sent, first
followup sent, second followup
sent, and it just keeps
going and going and going.
And then after fifth followup, you
have the elder statuses.
So you have
meeting booked, deal lost, and
pipeline.
So meeting booked, this is
basically once you put them in for
a meeting, you put them here, deal
lost.
This is, you know, you had the
sales call with them and they
told you, Hey, I don't want to
work with you.
Boom, deal lost.
And pipeline is, you know, you had
the
meeting, but then you kind of
fumbled it a little bit.
You know, you didn't get a
decision on the call.
You know, they're still kind of
thinking about it.
Maybe you have a second meeting
booked.
Maybe you're
working on getting a second
meeting book, all those types of
things where it's kind of messy a
little
bit just goes in pipeline.
So that's how everything looks in
terms of importing the leads.
We got the
spreadsheet.
So what you're going to do is
you're going to click the first
person you're going to
hold shift, and then you're going
to hit the last 100th person.
And then you're going to do
command C
or control C.
If you're on windows, you're going
to hit add card and then do
command V hit add card
and then create five cards.
And that's going to create five
cards.
And then next, so you got to do
this
manually, you can get a VA for
this, but probably best to just do
it manually.
You could just go
here, click Andre, go to the
Google sheet, grab his Instagram,
you can go like boom.
Next, you're
going to type Instagram.
Boom.
You're going to grab the freaking
email, which you know, I didn't
want
to show his email just for
transparency purposes, because
he's a homie.
But next up, what did I just
grab Twitter?
So you're going to say you just
put his Twitter link.
And then next, we're going to grab
LinkedIn.
You can go like this.
Boom, boom, boom.
And then, you know, that's how you
do it.
You just
put all his social media links
there.
You hit save.
And then so we hit save.
Boom.
So now lead in, we see
all of his socials there.
Feel free to add any other
comments, anything else you want
to put in the
description.
You're just going to go and do
this for all 100 people manual
process.
But trust me, this is
how you make money.
And this is also where most people
quit.
They get lazy.
So don't quit.
Once you get all the leads in
here, you filled up all their
info, you know, you put all their
social
media pages.
By the way, feel free to skip the
spreadsheet.
I just like doing that for some
reason.
But basically, once you get
everybody in here, that's when you
start.
So you're going to
go through the process.
First message sent.
Boom.
First follow up sent.
Second follow up sent and
keeps going and going.
I know you guys are probably
wondering, bro, what message do I
send?
What's the
follow ups look like?
All that stuff that's going to be
in the next video.
I'm just showing you how to
organize everything.
So that's what you do.
And then once the person once the
prospect
reaches like meeting booked, and
then right after you do the
meeting, you want to add some
notes in
the you can add a comment right
here.
You're going to say, hey, you
know, I did the meeting with
Andre.
He was a G.
He was super nice, but he didn't
fuck with the pricing.
You know, you could just write
whatever you want here.
And then this is going to like
make sure that you know what
happened on the
meeting, because trust me, you're
going to forget you're going to
get so many meetings from
this.
You're just going to forget what
happened.
So you need all that info just in
one
place.
This is like your sales brain.
So after the meetings book, you
didn't close them.
He goes
pipeline.
There's also one more deal one,
which is the best one.
So once you close the deal, it
goes
here.
If you lose the deal, it goes
Pipeline, you want to make sure
you keep adding notes,
keep adding due dates for more
follow ups, so on and so forth.
You can even add more lists for
more
follow ups for this sort of stage.
You know, the post meeting follow
up stage.
You know,
the best part about Trello is it's
so flexible and it's so easy.
You could just edit this however
you
want.
So yeah, guys, that's how you set
up a free CRM and how you organize
everything.
And that's it.
I'll see you in the next video.
I'm going to break down the
message templates, first messages
and
follow ups.
Peace.
Okay.
Welcome back.
Next, we're going to talk about
what to send in your outreach to
the free work so that you can send
free video scripts, whether it's
short form or long form.
And next, you can send free short
form videos.
You have to look at their podcasts
and their YouTube
videos and like repurpose their
content into a reel and send them
the reel up front in the first
message.
Don't worry, the next part I'm
showing the outreach script.
Next is thumbnails.
You can like
make a new thumbnail from their
current content.
This is a YouTube video thumbnail.
You can also do
video ideas and like a content
strategy doc.
And you can also do a free audit.
I forgot to write this
one down.
But the video ideas and content
strategy one, this is like a
document that says like, hey,
here's like 12 video ideas.
Here's why I think these will work
for your channel.
Let me know if you
want to like turn these videos
into reality.
You CTA into booking a call.
Free audit is like a loom.
You're like, hey, this is
everything you're doing wrong on
your channel and what you should
be doing
instead.
Remember, guys, the main thing to
keep in mind in the content agency
space is like
everybody's like pitching editing,
but it's like no one cares about
editing.
We care.
The prospects care
about making more money and the
editing isn't going to do that.
Like I can make more
money off an unedited video than
an edited one.
Not to say that not editing videos
is better.
But
what I'm trying to say is editing
isn't actually what makes or
breaks the video.
What makes or breaks
the video is the idea, the title,
the script, the speaking skills,
the CTA, et cetera.
So you need
to always make sure you're not
positioning yourself as an editor
and you're making it super clear
that
you're not an editor.
So that's why I like sending
scripts.
I like sending content strategy
docs and doing
loom audits as well.
Free work is going to make you
guys stand out.
So just make sure you actually do
it.
And before anybody asks, you're
sending the free work up front.
Basically, we're going to write an
outreach script
live.
So you need to make sure it's
personalized.
Naturally, it's personalized
because we have the
free value in there.
And then you're going to give the
link to the value and then you're
going to kind of push
them into doing what's next.
So in terms of what this actually
looks like, instead of just a ton
of
yeah, I'm going to show you a
script, but like, it's actually in
your best benefit to tweak this
script
because there's going to be some
people in this course who are just
like, well, I'm just going to
copy this, but you should actually
try and learn how I'm doing it.
So you can craft your own slightly
different one.
Okay.
So first things first, you need to
like get your way in.
So you're going to be
like, Hey, first name, I made this
free value for you, depending on
what it is, it's going to tweak
the next part.
So let's say it's, Hey Johnny, I
made this free YouTube script for
you.
And then from
there, I like even pitching a free
video on top.
So I go like, if you're down to
record it, I'll do the
editing, thumbnail, SEO, and even
the posting for you.
Let me know if you're up for it,
or if you want
to jump on a call.
So you'd obviously like changes
for whatever free value.
But in this case, I'm talking
about scripts, free scripts for
you.
Hey Johnny, I made this free
script for you.
If you're down to
record, I'll do the editing,
thumbnail, SEO, and even the
posting for you, all for free for
the first
video, or you could say first
video on the house.
So what we're doing here is we're
saying, Hey, first
name, what have, like, what have
we done here?
I made this free script for you.
And then we say like,
what is kind of like the next step
that they have to take from there.
So the next step is they have
to record it.
And then we're kind of helping
them know what to say.
So we're also keeping the message
very concise.
I was reviewing some outreach
scripts the other day from content
agencies in my
program.
And they're just so long and
stuff.
This is like before we do our
onboarding call where I
like fixed it.
But it's like, sometimes they come
into working with me with like
these stupid long
outreach scripts.
And I'm just like, no, we need
like three lines.
This is roughly what it should
look like.
Of course, again, guys, please
make sure to tweak it.
Don't rip this word for word.
And I'm
saying this in your best interest,
because if everybody is sending
the same script, it's not really
going to work.
So keep it short, keep it concise,
say, always keep the prospect in
mind.
Don't be
like, I, I, I, I, I, I, I be like
you, you, you, you.
So it's like, obviously, here I
have to say I
sometimes, but I'm like, I made
this free script for you.
If you're down to record it, like,
sure, I said,
I, but it's like, I'll do this.
This is not for you.
You know, let me know if you're up
for it.
Or if
you want to jump on a call.
It's like, I'm focusing on them.
I'm not reaching out with like,
hey, I can make a YouTube video
for you.
I'm the best.
I've been working with Daniel
Fazio for two
years, which is a true fact.
No, instead, I'm like, boom.
You know what I mean?
So that's roughly how
you should think about your
outreach.
Now, in terms of the follow-up
strategy, the money is in the
follow-up.
So most deals don't close on the
first message.
Okay.
You need to bump people up.
You need
to send case studies.
If you have them, you need to send
GIFs.
You need to send emojis.
You need to
send quick looms as well.
So the follow-up cadence you want
to go with is like, okay, you send
the
first message.
And then let's say August 1st.
Then on August 3rd, you do
follow-up one.
August 6th,
follow-up two.
Let's take a three-day gap.
And then like a four-day gap.
Then like a five-day gap.
Then like a 10-day gap.
Then like 15.
Then like 20.
Then like once 30 days later.
And then quarterly
forever.
And you want to like constantly
reach out until somebody says yes
or they say no.
This is a
game of who can send the best
quality outreach and who can
follow up for the longest and post
the best
content.
Basically, that's the whole goal
here.
How you're scaling the agency is
posting content doing
outreach.
But you want to follow up until
they say yes or they say no.
You can just don't overthink it.
Don't be cringy with your
follow-ups.
You can also send GIFs as well.
Like if you go to the GIF tab and
you search up the word alone, you
can find GIFs of people just like
being sad and like alone.
You can
send those.
You can send a detective emoji.
Shout out Christian for that one.
I'll close some deals
from that.
So just never stop following up.
And you need to follow up on every
platform.
Just the same
follow-up across every platform.
In terms of KPIs.
So do five pieces of free work per
day.
And then anything you can do
extra, that's great.
But make sure you're also posting
content, right?
So leave some time for that.
I closed my first client in 24
days or 23 days for 6k paid in
full from this method.
So I'm not saying
it's going to take 23 days to work
for you, but you need to give it
at least three weeks of consistent
outreach and posting content.
And it can take a bit longer.
It can take one month.
It can take two
months.
It really just depends on you, how
well you're doing things, how good
is the leads you're
selecting and different other
variables.
Don't quit after like a week or
else you are just stupid.
But yeah, that's pretty much it
for this video.
And if you have any questions, let
me know.