Welcome everybody to the content
agency crash course
as part of Client Ascension.
So basically, just to give you a
rundown, who am I?
I started my content agency at 17
years old
on November 25th, 2022.
And 24 months later, we hit
$132,000 a month.
15 months after launching, we hit
93.5K a month.
And 82 days after launching, we
hit 15K a month.
And I'm gonna walk through exactly
how I did all of that.
And I joined Client Ascension on
December 26th, 2022.
And I'm still in there today,
coming up on three years at the
end of this year.
So great guys, great program.
Glad to have you guys on board.
But now I'm gonna talk about
the specific content agency sauce.
Because the thing with running an
agency
and content agencies, trust me,
I coach like 100 plus content
agencies myself.
It's a very specific model.
Okay, there's like little
intricacies
and stuff you need to learn,
which I'm gonna cover inside of
this course.
And yeah, I'm super excited to
help you guys scale up.
And yeah, I'm 20 years old now.
This freaking business model
granted me a life
I'm very, very grateful for.
And I'm super excited to share
that
and all the sauce with you guys
today.
So without further ado, this is
the outline
and we're gonna jump right into
it.