So in this video we'll talk about
long-form versus short-form
content.
What should you sell?
So personally I prefer selling
long-form but I still sell both
and that's what you guys should
do.
You should sell both but pick one
as your primary.
The other one is just like an
upsell
or just if people ask you for it
but you're not really actively
promoting it.
But the truth is
both models can work really well
and it's personal preference.
I'll tell you what I think and all
that though.
So basically for short-form a lot
of lower level people in the
market value short-form
content and think that that's
where the money is at.
So you can kind of sign clients
like decently
quick on short-form offers because
everyone everyone consumes
Instagram reels so people
understand the value of it
inherently.
But with YouTube sometimes you
have to sell them on YouTube
and why it works etc.
But with reels everyone just
freaking spam consumes reels so
they already know
it's important so they're kind of
easier to sell.
Honestly converting views from
short-form into
money is pretty difficult.
You also have to manage a lot of
content like you're doing like 20,
30, 60
shorts a month.
It's a lot of quality checking and
project management.
So many spelling mistakes on the
captions and margins can get
pretty squeezed especially as a
beginner because people will try
and get you to
negotiate down to like 50, 60
dollars per reel but your cost per
reel is like 20 to 30 bucks.
So like
your margin is like a little bit
cooked compared to YouTube.
It's like much much better.
YouTube I find
it much easier to get a direct
ROI.
It's also just a lot easier to
pitch where it's like hey we're
making
these 10 to 15 minute videos.
They watch so much of your content
so much value they get they want
to book
in.
With short-form you know someone's
watching a 30 second video they
barely even get the chance to
remember your name.
But with a YouTube video it's like
they're consuming so much of your
content like you can
freaking make bank off of them.
The fulfillment is infinitely
easier because you're just
managing like
four videos a month instead of 30
to 60.
Easier quality check because
there's less caption errors.
It's a
cleaner editing process.
There isn't editing every second
of the video and higher pricing
power too.
This is
debatable.
Technically you can like I've
closed people on 8k a month for 60
shorts a month editing only
right that's $136 per reel.
My cost per reel is 20.
But the thing is I find it easier
to sell people on like
YouTube for like higher price
packages.
But I know people who are closing
10k retainers on short-form so
this one is like debatable
basically.
I would say YouTube is like a bit
harder to sell at first if you
don't
have any like proof or case
studies.
And you have to put more effort
into like the strategy scripting
packaging.
Like with short-form you can kind
of just like throw up a ton of
reels and like see what works.
So you have a lot more bullets to
shoot with.
But YouTube you got four videos
you know you gotta like
make sure those cook.
But as long as you're doing free
work up front and you're posting
content online
you can still sell on the YouTube
offer.
But yeah it's long form is just
simple.
That's why I picked it.
The margins are better.
Like our cost per video varies but
like our margin right now is like
65%
across 100k a month.
And that's before taxes but after
everything else.
Well I'm in Dubai now so I don't
have to worry about that.
But I also personally just get
better results on YouTube for my
clients.
So
that's why I like it more.
I like getting my clients results.
And I actually enjoy the creative
process
with YouTube more.
And I'm sure with a lot of you
guys watching this you probably
want to be YouTube
YouTube big YouTube channels
owners or sorry content creators I
guess when you're a kid.
So it's kind of
like cool like doing it basically.
But I still sell short form.
Like last month we hit like a 10k
paid in
full for some reels for three
months.
So still sell it.
Like take the money.
But you need to pick one
thing to focus on basically.
So if you want me to like just
tell you what to do I prefer the
YouTube
offer.
That's what I think.
And then you can still sell the
short form on the back end.
So that's pretty
much it for this video.
And I'll see you in the next one.