All right, so in this video, I'm
going to walk through the service
delivery workflow.
It all starts from the contract
and the payment, and then it's
going to go down to what gets
triggered, the onboarding funnel,
the onboarding call, what gets
done on that call, the first
video cycle, like, okay, we've got
the ideas approved, now we're
going to do the script,
and then you've got to edit.
You're going to see that whole
flow and how it repeats itself.
So I'm going to cut into a
pre-recorded video showing exactly
this.
I'm about to walk through
exactly how you should be
onboarding your new content agency
clients step-by-step.
I've used
this for over 100 clients, so let
me break it down right now.
So first things first, once they
sign
the contract, this is what
triggers the onboarding.
I use Pandadoc as the software for
our contract,
and if you're using Stripe as a
payment processor, you can even
connect your Stripe to your
Pandadoc,
so as soon as they sign the
contract, then they pay the Stripe
right then and there.
It's much
better if you can do that, and
then that triggers the onboarding
within Zapier.
So you do have to do
the Slack channel invite manually.
Once they sign and pay, it
triggers the automation.
So the Slack
channel gets created, the Google
Drive folders get created, the
Frame.io folders get created,
a welcome email gets sent, and
then you just manually have to
send a Slack connect invite
because unfortunately you can't
automatically do it, or at least
there's no easy way to do so.
And then what the welcome email is
going to include is a link to this
onboarding funnel that I'm about
to show you right now.
So basically the first step of the
funnel, this is done within Go
High Level,
it says welcome onboard.
So this is a simple five minute
welcome video that kind of resets
expectations again, talks about
why YouTube is so amazing, and
also just walks through the next
step
and the timeline that they should
be expecting.
And then the next step is that
they fill out an
onboarding form.
And I also make sure to include a
video that talks about how to fill
out the onboarding
form properly, because if they
don't do so, it's going to make
our job a lot harder.
After they fill
up the onboarding form, they can
schedule their onboarding call
right here.
And then after they schedule the
onboarding call, I tell them, make
sure to check your email for the
Slack invitation.
And then this
step, I'm basically just telling
them what's going to happen next.
First things first, they have to
grant us access to their YouTube
channel.
And then next up, I show them how
to set up OBS.
So this is
the screen recording software that
most of our clients use.
And then next, I show them how to
take high
quality thumbnail pictures,
because we need HD thumbnail
pictures to make good thumbnails.
And then next up,
I show them how to upload into
Google Drive.
And then next, I show them how to
approve or disapprove videos
within frame.io.
And then finally, I just have one
last video here that just tells
them what they
should expect next and thanking
them for trusting us.
So once all of this gets done, we
can start our
side of the work, which is
prepping the first 12 YouTube
video ideas.
After that, we have our
onboarding call.
And what happens on the onboarding
call is we basically just present
these 12 content
ideas, get the green light on
them.
And then if we need any other
information, like maybe their
onboarding form is lacking a bit,
and we need more info, this is
where I would ask them a couple
more
questions to get to know them
better.
And then I also just make sure
they understand everything in
terms of the
timeline, what to expect guys
setting expectations is extremely
important.
And then that's pretty much
it.
So after the onboarding call,
that's where we start scripting
the first two videos, and we send
them to the client, and then they
record.
And then at this point, like the
onboarding is technically done,
like after the onboarding call,
but I'm going to keep walking you
guys through this up until the
point
that the first video goes live.
So once they record, they send us
the video.
And then after that,
we do the editing and the
thumbnail, and then we send them
the video via frame.io.
So there they can
leave their revisions, approve or
disapprove the video.
And then we schedule the video for
them.
And then the cycle just repeats
forever.
So we constantly give them
performance updates along
the way through Slack and updates
on the strategy.
So that's the entire onboarding
flow.
Very, very
simple.
Of course, there's like
automations on the backend, like,
you know, the Google drive folders
I was showing you guys and a
couple other things, but that's
what it looks like from the client
side.
And a little bit about what it
looks like internally as well.
As soon as the onboarding form is
done,
it zaps our copywriter and our
strategist right away to start
mapping out those first 12 video
ideas.
But other than that, I've pretty
much showed you everything.
Once you take clients through
this,
it just blows them away because
they're going to be like, wow,
this guy has such an in-depth
onboarding.
I've never seen this before.
And they're just very, very happy.
Usually right when people
pay you, they're still a bit
hesitant.
So just having such a clean and
nice onboarding helps out a lot
with LTV and trust.
So now that you've got some
clients onboarded, if you want to
know how to get
them results, just watch some of
the other videos on my channel.
Or if you need help getting more
clients and actually putting more
people through this onboarding, I
have videos for that as well.
And if you want to work with me
one-to-one to scale up your
content agency, just hit the first
link in the description, but
that's it.
I'll see you in the next one.