All right, so in this video, I'm
going to walk through all of the
tools and platforms that
you're going to be using, like
which software is a payment
processor, project management
tool,
which automation software, all
this stuff, everything we use to
run our 100k month plus
content agency.
So I've tried like every software.
So I'm just gonna like cut the
fluff and tell you
exactly what you need.
So yeah, I'm actually gonna cut to
another video I recorded that
covers this
exact topic already.
So I'll see you there.
I scaled my content agency to over
seven figures
per year using this exact tech
stack and you guys can steal it.
I've ran through a ton of
softwares
and I'm just gonna reveal
everything.
So let's get right into it.
First things first on the
marketing
side.
Very, very, very simple.
Hypefury.
This is a tweet scheduling tool.
I get a lot of clients
through Twitter.
So I schedule my tweets through
Hypefury.
I also do auto DMs on there.
So I give
away lead magnets.
I made another YouTube video all
about Twitter.
So if you guys want to watch that,
it's going to be somewhere on my
YouTube channel.
And then next I pay like I think
$11 a month or
something for a checkmark on
Twitter.
And I also pay around 20 bucks a
month or something for a
checkmark on Instagram.
Gives you added authority.
I think also on Twitter, if you
don't have a checkmark,
you can't outreach to a good
amount of people like qualified
leads on Twitter.
So it's important you
have it so you don't look like a
bot and it's very cheap.
And then next is card.
C-A-R-R-D.
This is what
we use for websites.
I'm currently on Webflow, but
before for the longest time up
until like,
what was it?
90 or 60K a month.
Actually, I was using card.
It's literally like $60 per year
or
something like that.
Very good, simple website builder
gets the job done.
Amazing.
Now on the sales side,
very, very simple.
So PandaDoc is what we use for
contracts.
So you need a contract with every
content agency client you guys
sign.
If you guys want my contract
template, just join the free
group.
And if enough people post in there
saying they want it, I'll put it
in there.
Next is Calendly.
So we use this for meeting
booking.
So people book in sales calls
through there.
And then next is
fanbases.
So I know a lot of you guys
probably have never seen fanbases
before.
It's a payment
processor.
So it's like the same thing as
Stripe.
If you guys want to use fanbases,
there's going to be
a link in the description.
So people who go through me get a
discounted rate.
And basically I don't use
Stripe anymore because I moved to
Dubai and Dubai Stripe is very,
very bad.
Another good alternative,
you know, WAP can work as well.
Stripe, if you're in Canada, USA,
UK, you know, Stripe typically
gets
the job done.
But fanbases is very, very good as
well.
No complaints at all.
Very simple UI as well,
like no funky business.
Next, I use Google Meets for my
meetings.
So like I don't use Zoom just
because
Google Meets gets the job done and
it's free.
And then next is the operations
section, which is the
biggest one.
So our tech stack for operations,
we use Zapier and Make.
So these, they do the same thing,
like it's an automation tool.
If you're not already familiar
with them, they just connect
different apps
and they set up automation.
So whenever a new video is ready,
it like, and we approve it on
frame and
automatically sends to the client,
like all that stuff is in Make.
But typically for like more
simpler
automations, we have a lot of them
running through Zapier.
So it's basically just the glue
between all of
our different softwares and the
whole agency.
And then next is our project
management system.
So we
currently use Airtable.
At about 50k a month or 60k, we
switched from Trello to Airtable.
Because what happened with Trello
is we just had too many clients
and we didn't want to just keep,
like the editors didn't want to
click through the individual
client boards to figure out what's
assigned to them, et cetera.
And I don't blame them at all.
So we switched to Airtable because
it's like
a master knowledge base.
And then the editors each have
their own interface.
It's super, super cool.
Let me know if you guys want a
dedicated video on our Airtable
setup.
But basically editors can log
into their interface.
They see what videos they have.
And then on the backend, like me,
the ops manager,
the team, we have like this really
big interface where we can assign
videos.
We can see all the
client information, so on and so
forth.
It's really good once you start
making more money.
But to be
honest, everybody below like 20,
10, 15k a month, keep it simple
and use Trello.
Next is Slack.
So we
use Slack for all of our
communication.
We don't use WhatsApp.
We don't use iMessage.
We don't use
Discord or anything.
We do all of our comms on Slack.
The reason why we use Slack is
because number one,
it's professional.
Number two, the people in our
space use it.
Since I'm using a tool that
everybody
uses, we just get quicker client
responses.
But let's say you're selling to
like roofers or something
for some reason.
They don't use Slack.
They use like iMessage if you're
selling to Americans.
So you need to adapt to sort of
what the market wants.
But the good thing with Slack is
it integrates
with all of the tools here pretty
much like Zapier, Make, like
Airtable works super well with it.
But if
we're using WhatsApp, we would
have some limitations.
And also I don't want to leak my
phone number to
everyone.
So Slack is the best.
Next.
So for AI tools, we use ChatGPT.
We also use Claude and we
have a custom built AI tool as
well.
But these are super good.
I usually use ChatGPT for like
more
basic tasks and stuff.
Claude is better for writing
things.
And then next is Envato.
Envato is a,
it has like no copyright music.
And then it also has transitions,
effects, kind of stuff like that,
text presets.
So our editors use Envato a lot.
We have a yearly plan with them.
And then Frame.io.
So this one is super, super key
because we used to not use Frame
and we were doing revisions on
Google Drive.
It was very annoying because
basically like the editor would
send something to Google
Drive and then we would send a
Slack message with the timestamp
saying, hey, at five seconds in,
change this word to that.
At two seconds in, change this to
that.
And it was, it was very stupid.
To be honest with us, we should
have switched to Frame a lot
sooner.
But on Frame, you can leave
notes directly on the video.
So it just works a lot better.
And then we use Frame for ready to
post
videos, meaning when they're going
to get sent to clients and also
after they're edited.
But for the
raw footage, we store that in
Google Drive just because I have a
ton of storage for super, super
cheap.
Yeah, it's just kind of more
organized a little bit.
So we put our raw footage in
Google
Drive.
That's where the clients upload
to.
It's also just easier for the
clients to upload into a Google
Drive rather than a Frame.
It starts to get a bit
complicated.
And as soon as something is
uploaded
into Google Drive, you know, the
Zapier notifies us and then it
gets assigned to a video editor by
our
project manager.
So everything is super well
connected.
Next, we use Google Docs just to
write our video
scripts on it and random notes.
And then we do use Discord.
We literally just implemented this
like
yesterday.
We're using Discord for editor
trials because we used to manage
them in Twitter DMs and then
we'd manage them on like Instagram
DMs and then we had Airtable.
Things were kind of messy.
So now the
flow is like someone applies on
our Airtable form.
And then if we like their
portfolio, we send them a
one-time invite link into our
Discord.
And then they submit a ticket to
pick which type of editor they
are.
And if they click the long form
editor button, then it creates a
channel.
It'll have like first
name, last name, dash LF for long
form.
And then it'll have the trial
information in there to say,
hey, do XYZ, you know, edit this
one minute trial.
Here's the footage.
Here's the script.
Here's all this
stuff.
Let us know if you have any
questions.
And then from there, we have a
direct line of
communication with them.
The thing with editors is they
like using Discord.
They're used to it.
You know, we found that kind of
putting them into Slack for the
trial process is kind of annoying.
And then we start to mix up like
trial editors and our real editors
and the Slack keeps pinging.
So we just wanted to keep it
completely separate.
I'll let you know how this goes,
but we literally
just implemented it like
yesterday.
And then finally, we use Loom as
well.
So we use Loom for a lot of
things.
So I'm using Loom right now to
record this video.
We use Loom for our internal SOPs.
We use Loom to request missing
assets from clients.
It's basically a screen sharing
software,
exactly as you're seeing right
now.
You can also connect to your
microphone and connect to your
camera.
So it's very good.
We also use this to minimize
meetings because at the agency,
like we run with very, very, very
minimal meetings, even prospects.
Like a lot of the times we just
close them in the DMs and just go
back and forth with them.
So yeah, that's everything
software-wise.
There might've been like one I
forgot, but I dig through my whole
thing, how we run all of our
operations, all our SOPs.
We pretty much only use these.
So that's everything for this
video.
If you want to know what my team
structure is like, or maybe you
want to learn about client
acquisition, I have a ton of other
videos on my channel that just
break down my seven figure
content agency.
I also have a free group linked in
the description with some free
resources for you
guys.
So that's it.
And I'll see you guys in the next
video.
Peace.
Thank you.