All right guys, so let's talk
about what makes a good YouTube
video.
So not all videos are created
equal.
Some get views, but no clients.
Others bring in qualified leads
that close at 30 to 50% on sales
calls.
One of my clients booked 250 sales
calls in the first 14 days of the
month.
So it's safe to say I know what
I'm talking about.
And in this video, I'm going to
run through all of it.
So first things first is the
script.
You need to make sure you have a
good video script.
I know I skipped over the ideation
part, but I'll get into that in a
sec.
But the script is very important,
right?
So there's three parts to a
script, hook, body, outro.
The hook, typically we script
these word for word for clients,
but you want to try to relate to
the viewer.
So when I started my agency, I had
no social proof, blah, blah, blah,
but I still managed to sign my
first client in 21 days for 6K up
front.
The person's going to relate to
the fact that I was a beginner, I
had no social proof, and they're
going to want the end result that
I just said.
I signed a client for 6K up front
in 23 days.
So then they're going to want to
tune in.
But now they're going to want to
know what they're tuning into.
So then I'm going to say, so in
this video, I'm going to walk
through exactly how you can sign
your first client by sending free
work up front in no less than four
weeks or no more than four weeks.
You want to show credibility and
social proof.
So as you can see from that hook
that I just came up with using my
brain on the fly that I didn't
script beforehand.
When you've been doing this for a
while, you're kind of just like,
you're kind of just automatic.
What was I going to say though?
Now I'm losing my train of
thought.
But yeah, the social proof, like I
said it there, subliminally or
like just nice and smooth.
That was like, oh yeah, I got my
first client for 6K up front.
Tease what they'll learn.
So like, hey, you'll learn this
outreach mechanism or whatever.
Keep it short.
Trim all the fluff, especially for
B2B clients, guys.
Like you really don't want to make
long, long, long hooks for a B2C
client.
They can be a bit longer.
You can do a bit more like mental
gymnastics with the viewer because
they're a bit more brain dead
goldfish memory.
But yeah, for the body guys, you
don't want to script word for
word.
The main thing with the bodies is
like just no fluff.
As long as it's no fluff and it's
super, super, super valuable,
that's awesome.
And that is a good YouTube video.
On top of that, if you have like
nice transitionary sentences
between points, that's great.
I also typically like splitting up
our bodies into like three main
sections or five just because like
the human brain likes sections and
chapters.
It just helps things easier to
digest.
Like, for example, if you look at
a phone number, it's like
604-604-6004.
It's like in three parts.
It's like easier to remember than
if it was just like 604-604-6004.
It's like, no, when it's broken up
into three parts, it's easier to
consume and easier to remember,
which is what you want with your
content.
So yeah, good analogy for you
guys.
Make sure you're adding like
stories as well, pre-answering any
objections.
And just overall, the whole time
you're creating a YouTube video,
whether it's for yourself or for a
client, you need to just put
yourself in the shoes of the
viewer.
Ask yourself, what do they want to
see?
So if I make a YouTube video
called how to script a YouTube
video, I can imagine somebody is
going to want to see an example of
a script.
Somebody is going to want to know
what's the sections of the video,
so on and so forth.
So just put yourself in the
viewer's shoes and make sure to
deliver.
And then for the outro, you're
going to transition smoothly into
it and then just do a clear,
simple CTA.
So I just want to show you guys an
example.
So this is one of our clients.
Don't try and steal him.
So title, how I use LinkedIn DMs
to book four plus sales calls per
day.
We like to add a little thing at
the top that just says like what
the length of this video is.
Also, I know in the program there
are going to be, I think Lucas
made some like AI script writing
tools and stuff like that.
So your scripts might look
slightly different, but roughly
it'll be like the same.
So the hook is up here.
I'll let you like pause and read.
And then the body, this is how we
structure it.
We do a mid-body CTA as well.
But overall, it's just bullet
points and we let the clients slip
in their own knowledge.
Whenever we're selling clients on
this, we tell them, hey, if I did
word for word, you'd be a puppet.
It wouldn't be a personal brand
and the video wouldn't perform.
So this is in your best interest
and they're always down for it.
Yeah, just think of the video like
a funnel.
You're hooking them in, delivering
value, then guide them to the next
step.
In terms of your delivery style,
don't read robotically.
In fact, it's better if you don't
read at all and you like kind of
memorize the script a little bit.
Obviously, guys, this same
feedback applies to your clients.
Make sure you use bullet points
and don't script word for word.
It's just if you script word for
word, naturally, you'll end up
reading.
Mistakes are fine.
Editors can cut out pauses and
errors.
And energy is more important than
perfection.
So like one thing to keep in mind
is the whole purpose of YouTube
and how YouTube works as a
platform
and what makes a YouTube video
good is like how good is the value
you're providing?
And also, are you boring or not?
And I don't mean you need to crack
jokes 24-7.
But what I mean is you don't want
to be like, hey, my name is Eamon.
I'm going to show you how to land
three clients.
So the first thing you want to do
is this.
And then you're going to do this
button.
And then you're going to send this
script.
It's so boring, ums and ahs, no
pauses cut out.
Like you're going to want to click
off.
So you need to make sure it's like
watchable and the value needs to
be really good.
That's our strategy.
Please do not create videos for
yourselves or your clients with no
value.
And what I mean by that is like
there's certain creators where you
click into their YouTube video
and they're just seriously
gatekeeping everything.
And it's actually the worst
experience ever from like a client
or potential client perspective
because they want to be like,
okay, let me see if this guy knows
his stuff.
And then they watch the video and
they just wasted 20 minutes of
their life.
They're never going to pay you 8k
for your program.
You know what I mean?
So just make sure you're pushing
value and not gatekeeping.
You can gatekeep little bits and
things.
So for example, my YouTube videos,
I don't talk about my outreach
script.
I don't show my air table or my
automation.
It's like there's just like little
things that you can gatekeep.
But for the most part, you want to
be kind of an open book.
Because at the end of the day,
people will pay you for your high
ticket programs and stuff
like that and services for you to
if it's done for you.
It's like the best selling
proposition of all time because
like, hey, it's literally done
for you for coaching.
You know, they'll want to just be
able to speak to you and stuff in
terms of editing.
I know I'm going to get asked, oh,
yeah, you know, can we just do raw
videos or something?
But the reality is, if you look at
practically every YouTube channel
ever that's scaled up
within the last decade or two
decades, if YouTube's been around
that long, like they
all scaled up through like edited
videos, basically, especially if
we look at like the
last decade, it's been edited
videos.
Sure, there's like the minority of
like more unedited stuff.
But like if you look at the 70,
80, 90 percent, it's edited.
So just edit your videos.
There's a difference between
editing a video nicely and editing
a video and doing like this
crazy ADHD editing crap.
So don't get caught up in the mix
of this whole raw content trend.
In terms of your thumbnails
overall, you want to make sure
that they have let's go here.
You want to make sure that they
have about like four words or less
in the thumbnail, ideally,
and like use like bright
thumbnails, like white background
like this, like this would perform
better if the whole thing was in
like dark mode.
And the reason why is most people
like myself are in dark mode.
So if you have a white thumbnail,
it sticks out more and then try
and use things that people
understand.
So for like my content agency
program, I know people will
recognize Zapier.
I know they're going to recognize
Stripe.
But let's say if my client was
selling to like how to create like
a how to do like Facebook
flipping business or something,
you know, I'd probably put like
cash app here because they're
not going to know what Stripe is.
So make sure you're actually like
keeping the viewer in mind and
putting things they're
familiar with.
So here I'm putting a YouTube logo
to try and catch people's
attention with that as
well.
Bright, big text, make it easily
readable.
You need to keep in mind that with
thumbnails, people are like 97% of
traffic is going to be
on mobile and mobile screens are
small.
So make sure that your text is
actually legible on a small
screen.
And always just put your face on
there because people over time,
you'll build like brand equity
and people recognize your face and
click your stuff.
But also it's just it's just
better that way.
So just do it.
And that's that's pretty much it
for the most part.
The best way to learn how to make
good thumbnails is just go and
look at other YouTube channels
and just see what they're actually
doing and what is working and
what's not working.
I know some of you guys may be
wondering, wow, Ayman only gets
this many views, but you don't
actually need that much money to
get views and make money from
YouTube.
Like we have clients with like 300
views per video and they're
signing clients for 5k a pop.
So don't think you need a million
views to get money.
Now, in terms of content types
that works, I mean, sorry, content
types that work.
There's two types talking head
videos and screen share videos.
Both are good.
Screen shares are pretty great for
B2B talking head is a bit more
B2C, but like you're still
going to want to do both, whether
you are B2B or B2C, just if you're
B2B, you'll probably
have more screen shares.
And if you're B2C, you'll have
more talking heads.
Now, in terms of actual content
types, like action based video or
sorry, like the ideation
categories, there's like action
based content, educational and
another type of content.
So what I'll do is I'll cut into
another video I recorded, which is
a tier list of like
the different content types,
client interviews, case study
breakdowns, action based videos,
et cetera.
So that will give you a good
understanding of that.
But let me just keep ripping
through this and finish up.
So YouTube rewards videos that
keep viewers watching and also
keeps viewers on the platform.
So that's what I was saying
earlier.
You need to edit the video because
like look at any freaking edited
video.
it'll almost always have better
retention than an unedited one.
If all other variables are the
same, speaking skills, et cetera.
There's one metric that's like not
even trackable on YouTube studio.
That's very important.
It's called like session duration.
Everybody has a different term for
an average view duration, session
duration, whatever.
Who cares?
It's basically just how long
somebody stays watching your
stuff.
So if somebody watches three of my
videos and they're 10 minutes long
each, their session duration
was 30 minutes and YouTube really,
really likes that statistic.
So try and CTA between videos and
make sure one video leads into the
next as well.
Next thing is in general, we're
optimizing for search when we come
up with video ideas,
because if we optimize for search,
usually it's optimized for the
home feed as well.
But if you optimize for the home
feed, it won't be for search.
So we just always go search first.
That's also where the highest
intent leads and traffic come
from.
So we want to optimize for that.
We want to make our clients money.
But yeah, also keep in mind, like
the more watch time you get on a
channel, the more money
it's going to make.
This is just a random thing, but
it could be one hour equals a
thousand.
It could be less, it could be a
bit more, but it's a direct
correlation.
Okay.
Make sure you're posting a ton of
social proof on your channel or
your client's channels
whenever you can.
This is where a lot of your
conversions will come from.
More on this in a second.
In terms of frequency, two videos
a week actually is the sweet spot.
Like one video a week is
completely fine and you can still
scale clients on that amount.
Our top performing accounts are on
two videos a week, but most of our
clients are on one video
per week.
So we usually try and get people
in on one video a week and then
upsell into two.
And over time, the videos stack
into like a library of like
digital real estate that just
generates leads daily.
And that's why it's important to
just keep making videos, making
videos, making videos.
Eventually you have so many
freaking videos that are just
working for you.
These like digital sales reps.
It's like pretty crazy.
Focus on being consistent, not
going viral.
So what I'm going to do now is I'm
going to cut into one video that
goes over the different
content types like action-based,
how-to videos, educational videos,
et cetera.
And then I'll also cut into
another video that talks about how
to come up with YouTube video
ideas too.
So that's it for this video and
I'll see you in the next one.
This is the YouTube content tier
list.
So in this video, I'm going to
break down what videos actually
make money.
I'm going to rank them for you
today.
So by the way, if you want to
download this document, it's going
to be the first link in
the description.
So here's how this tier list
works.
S tier is going to be your money
makers.
These content types get you high
paying clients like clockwork.
A tier is also super, super strong
and I wouldn't sleep on it at all.
It's just slightly worse than S
tier.
Great for building trust.
Great for getting clients.
B tier is decent for traffic, good
for building an audience, but it's
harder to make money
directly.
C tier is like vanity metrics and
get views, but it rarely makes
money.
And then D tier, I would just
avoid this at all costs.
It's not worth the time
investment.
So S tier, first things first,
client interviews.
The money potential here is super
high.
So here's an example.
This is one of our clients, Eddie,
who we helped go from 54k a month
to over 420k a month
in four months.
So here's why client interviews
work.
It shows real changes with real
numbers.
It builds trust.
And it also attracts prospects who
want to get the same result.
So for example, if I make a video
and then the starting position of
my client is 54k a month,
most likely a lot of the people
that watch this video are going to
be around that revenue
level or slightly below or
slightly above.
It's also very easy to make these
videos because you can just show
up to the call and ask the
client a set of predetermined
questions.
And you can run through these in
about 15, 20 minutes.
Very, very simple.
The other thing is client
interviews are very hard to fake.
And that's why they're so, so
powerful.
Anybody nowadays can Photoshop a
Slack screenshot or Photoshop a
Stripe screenshot, stuff like
that.
And then the other problem with
those iPhone testimonials, if any
of you have ever asked
your clients to make one, you know
exactly what I'm about to say.
Sometimes your client will just
hit record on their iPhone and
just completely ramble about
things that are completely
irrelevant or they're not saying
the exact right words.
But at the same time, you don't
want to ask them to record again
because already it's a big
ask for a testimonial.
And then you end up with this
garbage testimonial.
But when you do a client
interview, you can control the
interview, not in a way where
you're telling the client what to
say, but in a way where almost
like the client is AI and
you're prompting them with the
right questions.
Next up here, we got case study
breakdowns.
So this is kind of similar to a
client interview in a sense of
you're showing the before and
the after.
But in a case study breakdown,
it's not an interview.
So the client isn't in the video,
but rather you're either doing a
screen recording of a
document or it's just a talking
head.
And you're breaking down the
starting position that your client
was in and the after, and
you're breaking down the exact
steps that they took to reach the
new position.
So for example, in this video, I
went like, okay, first we have to
come up with the right
ideas.
Here's how we did that.
Next, we had to script the videos.
Here's how we formatted them.
Next, we had to edit the videos
and we had to do the thumbnails.
Here's what we did for the
thumbnails, so on and so forth.
I'm just breaking down exactly
what we did step by step.
And here's why they work.
You're doing a deep dive into how
you work.
It shows how complex what you do
really is, makes you look like an
expert, and it makes prospects
realize they need professional
help.
Going back into this first point
here, it's super, super important
because prospects, before
signing up for a done-for-you
service, they want to understand
how you work.
They want to know what it's like
to work with you, the behind the
scenes, what's your process,
so on and so forth.
This is almost like letting
clients try before they buy.
Similar to practically any
software nowadays, they always
have a free trial.
So with these YouTube videos,
you're essentially kind of letting
your client get a free trial,
but without actually doing any
work.
So the structure is very basic.
Hook, client background, and then
a step-by-step breakdown of the
process.
Talk about any tools you use,
systems, processes, tricks, et
cetera.
Go over the key lessons and
results, and then do a clear call
to action.
Well, this should be in like every
single video.
Next up, we have the free course
video.
So this is one we did for one of
our clients, and the money
potential is super, super high
on these.
Like these can literally rip.
We've done free course videos with
like over 100 or 200K views.
This one has 71K views at the time
of recording.
And these freaking print.
Like we've had a single free
course video drive over seven
figures in revenue.
And when I say revenue, I mean
cash collected, okay?
But here's the framework.
Basically, we're giving away
everything for free in a video
that's about one to two hours
long.
We found that videos crossing the
two-hour mark have diminishing
returns.
They take a lot of time to prep, a
lot of time to record, and it's
just really not worth
it, to be honest.
But that one to two-hour mark is
the sweet spot.
Now, in this video, you want to
give away your complete method.
And the reason why this works is
because you're building massive
trust.
You're letting people see how you
work.
But also, they're thinking to
themselves, damn, if this is what
I'm getting for free, imagine
what I'm going to get if I pay
him.
But also, when people pay you for
your coaching program, they're not
only paying you for the
information, but they're also
paying you just to be able to
communicate with you, ask you
questions, and also just get
permission to do certain things.
So maybe in the course video,
it'll literally say, pick a
cosmetic product.
But then a student in your program
is still going to want to pay you
just to join the program
and ask you, hey, should I do a
cosmetic product or should I do a
face mask?
It sounds very stupid, but people
pay you in order to just have you
hold their hand, ask
you for permission, et cetera.
But one thing that's super
important is you do want to
gatekeep certain things.
So for example, on my own YouTube
channel, I never give away our
outreach script.
I never give away our AI systems.
I never give away our project
management system, Airtable,
automations, all that stuff.
I like to gatekeep those things.
So we're essentially giving the
97%, but we're gatekeeping that 3%
that is very interesting
and appealing.
And this is also going to push
people into working with you.
Now, if you're selling a
done-for-you service, you can give
away even more stuff because the
number one value proposition of a
done-for-you service is that it's
done for you and that
people don't have to do it.
So even if you tell them exactly
how to do everything step-by-step,
you're still going to get
done-for-you clients through those
YouTube videos because people
don't want to do things
themselves.
Now, the thing with these is you
have to embrace the do-it-yourself
mentality.
A lot of business owners like
doing things themselves or
understanding things.
So they're searching things up on
YouTube, like how to run Facebook
ads, how to come up
with a YouTube video idea, how to
write scripts.
They're searching these things up.
So we want to have our videos up
there.
A free course video is going to
show a business owner exactly how
to do the thing themselves,
but they're still going to pay
you.
Usually for the template, you just
want to say like full dropshipping
course, a hundred
percent free, or there's actually
a couple other templates you can
use.
You can just search up free course
on YouTube, type in different
niches, and you're going to
see all the different ways of
doing your titles.
One thing that's super important
with these free course videos is
the CTA at the end.
So you want to give them an
ultimatum.
You want to say option one, you
can watch this video and treat it
like every other YouTube
video ever, where you just watch a
little bit or don't watch it at
all, throw it in the
watch later and never watch it
again.
Or B, you can try and implement
yourself.
You'll get decently far because
this is a great video, but
naturally you're going to hit
roadblocks and you're
to have nobody to ask for help or
option three, you work with us,
join my program or sign up for my
service, and then you get this
result.
So it's very important.
You have that type of CTA towards
the end.
And then you also want to have a
CTA around the two minute mark,
four minute mark, somewhere in
that
range, just because there's going
to be a lot of drop off after
eight minutes, 30 minutes, et
cetera.
Next category, A tier.
This is very strong for lead gen,
and this should be the majority of
the videos on your channel.
This is going to be content that
builds trust and gets good
prospects in through the door.
So with action-based videos, we're
basically just telling people
exactly how to do something,
step-by-step.
Similar to what I was saying
earlier, we want to embrace that
do-it-yourself mentality and show
people how to do things
themselves.
So this video is a smart lead AI
beginner tutorial.
If anybody searches up on Google
or ask ChatGPT, they say, hey, you
know, what's the best cold email
software or something?
They're going to find smart lead
as one of the options, if not the
number one option, since it's
the best one.
And they're going to want to watch
this video to understand how to do
the thing themselves.
But as they watch it, they're
going to learn that like, okay,
this dude, Matt Lucero, he's very
smart.
Maybe I should watch some of his
other videos, or maybe I should
just pay him to do the thing for
me.
So one example of an action-based
video is how to create a YouTube
sales funnel that books 20 plus
calls per month.
Usually action-based videos start
with the word how to most of the
time, not necessarily, but that's
just a very basic way to do it.
So again, this works because
you're showing your expertise in
action.
You're attracting people that are
actively looking for your
solution.
And you're also showing how
complex proper implementation is.
So a couple of templates here, how
to get specific result in
timeframe or the new way to do
thing in 2025.
The next category we have is
educational videos.
So the money potential again is
high.
So here's an example why YouTube
is the best way to get clients in
2025 or the three best
online businesses to make 1K a day
with online in 2025.
This is Nathan Nazareth.
So usually the format starts with
the word why.
This video, just to explain it a
little bit better, you're
essentially educating them on
something, but you're not telling
them exactly step-by-step how to
do it.
So if I made a video like this,
you know, one of the businesses
would be a content agency.
Then it would be like drop
shipping.
And then maybe it's like, I don't
know, clipping or something
random, even though clipping is
terrible,
even though clipping is far worse
than a content agency in this
video, I'm going to educate them
on what each business model is and
the pros and cons, but I'm not
going to tell them step-by-step
how to get their first client, how
to do this, how to launch the
store, whatever it is, because
then it would become an
action-based video, but this is
educational.
I'm just kind of staying a little
bit on top of the ice, not really
telling them exactly what to do,
but I'm still educating them and
it's still a valuable video.
Educational videos and
action-based are going to be your
top of funnel, just bringing more
and more
people into the channel with the
goal of getting them to watch the
S tier videos.
Next up, we have B tier.
So this is decent for traffic, but
it's harder to make money
directly.
First things first, we got
industry commentary, also known as
opinion videos.
So this is like medium, you know,
you're not really going to make
money from this video.
This is an example, is the content
agency space saturated in 2025?
Another one, why 89% of marketing
agencies fail, the brutal truth.
You're just telling them your
opinion.
There's not really any actionable
advice going on.
So overall, you're just making
less money from it.
It's good because it builds
thought leadership.
It shows industry knowledge.
It attracts prospects and it's
good for engagement, but it's hard
to directly convert people
into sales calls from a video like
this.
So I'm not saying you shouldn't
make these at all.
You know, these should just be
sprinkled in as I'm doing on my
own main channel.
Next up, you have tools and
software reviews.
So you could say, I tested 10
email marketing tools.
Here's the best one or every tool
you need to run a successful
content agency in 2025.
This would fall under the software
review category.
It's good because you're abusing
high search volume and you're also
showing practical expertise.
And there's going to be people
searching up like Airtable
tutorial.
Or if I go back up here to this,
like a smart lead tutorial.
Now, this one specifically is a
tutorial.
It's not a review.
So it's two different things.
But here we're captivating search
traffic from the keyword smart
lead.ai.
Same concept.
I find that the viewers of these
videos have too much of a
do-it-yourself mindset.
They really just want to know,
hey, is this software good and go
do it themselves.
It's hard to get done for you
buyers or even like coaching
program buyers.
Now, C tier, vanity metrics.
These get views, but they rarely
make money.
Reaction videos.
I really wouldn't waste my time
with this, to be honest.
It's purely entertainment value.
No authority building.
Gets the wrong audience.
And it's also like lazy content
creation.
A viewer's going to watch this and
know you kind of just want to make
a quick and easy,
lazy video.
Now, with behind the scenes and
day-in-the-life type of videos,
these are cool for building
a bit of an audience with your
prospects and audience.
But honestly, it's going to waste
your entire day because you have
to put so much mental bandwidth
into making sure the camera's
always recording, entertaining the
camera, so on and so forth.
But these just won't really make
you money.
They attract the wrong type of
person, which is typically people
who don't have money to buy
your done-for-you service or your
coaching program.
If you're targeting B2B, you
should completely avoid these
videos completely.
But if you have a B2C coaching
program, you know, you can
sprinkle some of these in,
you know, see how they do.
But it's really just for views.
You're not going to get direct
conversions from this.
It does build your personal brand,
show lifestyle outcomes.
It makes you feel more human as
well.
And it's good for engagement, but
it's more entertainment than
education.
Now, D tier.
You need to avoid these at all
costs.
These are time wasters that
typically hurt your business.
So first up, we have personal
vlogs.
So we have a vlog here on the
right side.
They went to go watch a Euro 2024.
Shout out Farouk.
We made this video on the left and
it performed super, super well.
We got 12K views and I know he
made a lot of money from that
video.
However, the video on the right
was only 1.3K views.
I know it attracted the wrong
audience.
They didn't get conversion, so on
and so forth.
Every single info seller I speak
to who's spamming these vlogs, the
vlogs don't get qualified
prospects in through the door.
These videos on the left are the
money makers.
Now, usually these are typically
flipped where the vlog has a lot
of views and then the educational
videos don't have that many views.
In this specific case, it's not
like that, but usually you need to
get 10 million views
on a vlog to get the same amount
of leads as you'd get from a video
with 2K views on an
action-based video.
Now, that's an exaggeration.
Those are random numbers, but I
think you understand the concept
that I'm trying to put you on.
Now, these were posted on the
exact same channel and you can see
how the audience really liked
this video on the left, but they
didn't really like this video on
the right.
So again, we only made this video
on the left.
The money potential is very low,
so just avoid these weekend trip
to Las Vegas or I just bought
this new XYZ, whatever it is.
There's no business value.
It confuses your positioning.
It also wastes your subscriber
quality.
This is also why you see a lot of
big channels.
They split their vlog channel from
their main channel, which I
actually really recommend
because if you do everything on
the same channel, you're really
going to make the audience dirty
in a sense where you're going to
have all these low-value people
mixed in with the high-value
people and then when you put out a
video, it's going to get
recommended to everyone and then
the low-value people aren't going
to watch it and it's just going to
ruin everything.
Now, you can sprinkle these in if
you're a B2C dude or if it's just
for personal reasons,
but if you're B2B, I would also
especially avoid these.
Random entertainment content
number 11, trying random food or
just doing random things, kind
of similar to vlogs, just avoid
these.
It's completely off-brand.
You're going to get entertainment
seekers and it destroys your
credibility, zero business
relevance.
It's just a waste of time.
So now here's some common mistakes
that kill conversions.
Mistake number one is chasing
views over value.
So instead of chasing that next
million-view YouTube video, you
should be chasing a video
that has anywhere from 300 views
to 10K views that actually gives
good value.
It needs to be specific content
tailored to your ICP.
Next up is weak call to action.
So you actually need to like tell
them what to do, like book a call,
first link in the
description.
Don't be like, oh, subscribe or
just magically think they'll find
the link.
That's not going to work.
Mistake number three is holding
back your best content and keeping
all the good stuff for
your paid clients.
You don't want to do that.
Of course, you want to get keep
some things from your YouTube and
only give that to your
paid people, but you can't just
make videos with no value in it.
You can't make a video titled how
to come up with YouTube video
ideas.
But then when you click on the
video, I'm just flexing social
proof and I don't tell
you how to come up with ideas.
And I tell you to book a call to
learn how to come up with ideas
because then that person
is going to feel click baited.
They're going to be like, man,
Eamon is terrible.
I don't want to sign up with him.
So on and so forth.
Finally, we have mistake number
four, which is trying to appeal to
everyone.
Generic content that doesn't
connect isn't going to make you
money.
Instead, like I was saying
earlier, you need to make super
specific content that attracts
your ideal client.
The long-term vision here is that
we're not building a YouTube
channel.
We're building a 24 seven sales
team that qualifies prospects
while you sleep a trust
building machine where every video
shows expertise, a competitive
moat through consistent value
delivery, a scalable lead source
that compounds over time and a
premium positioning tool where
high value content justifies high
ticket prices.
In terms of what to do next in
your 30 day action plan, try and
pump out a client interview
first, because these are super
easy to do.
You can also integrate these into
your funnel, send them out to your
email list, send them to
old prospects, so on and so forth.
Get some cash in through the door.
Next up, you want to create an
action based video about your
industry, how to come up
with YouTube video ideas, how to
make a dropshipping store, so on
and so forth.
Next, film a case study breakdown
of your methods.
So take one of your best students
or clients, show step-by-step how
they got the result that
they got to, and then week four,
just do another action based
video.
Continuously loop this and then
around month two or three, if
you're ready, try and pump
out that free course video.
Make sure you're optimizing based
on results, so double down on
content types that generate
calls, stop making content that
only gets you views, and focus on
S tier and A tier
content 99% of the time.
Now, if you want us to handle all
of this done for you and you're
making over 50K a month,
we'll do strategy, scripting,
editing, thumbnails, SEO, and
posting for you.
You just have to record for two
hours per month.
Just apply here.
Either click this document if
you're on the doc or if you're in
the YouTube video, it's
going to be linked in the
description.
But that's all for this video.
Thank you so much for watching,
and I'll see you in the next one.