All right, guys.
So in this video, we're going to
talk about what is a content
agency.
If you
already know what this is, feel
free to skip it.
But I mean, this video is going to
be like six
minutes long.
I actually already have a video
recorded that goes exactly over
this.
I recorded
it in a podcast studio.
It's super, super nice.
So I'm actually just going to cut
to that instead
of just repeating myself, it's
going to be a lot more efficient.
I made sure to go super in-depth.
So here it is.
A content agency can generate
$30,000 to $40,000 per month with
just a handful
of clients.
In fact, I went from zero to 93.5K
a month in 15 months with my own
content agency.
But here's the thing.
Most people have no idea what a
content agency actually is or how
it works.
So in this video, I'm going to
break down exactly what a content
agency does, how it makes money,
and why it's the perfect online
business model for beginners in
2025.
So to start a content agency,
most people think this is just a
video editing business, but that
couldn't be further from
the truth.
I know many content agency owners
who don't know how to edit at all
themselves,
but what they do know how to do is
hire video editors to handle that
segment of the workload.
But you never want to only offer
video editing.
You always want to add other
things on top
so you can promise an ROI to your
clients.
ROI stands for return on
investment.
Because if
you're only doing the video
editing, you can't go up to your
client and say, I'm going to get
you 30 sales calls a month.
You're going to close five clients
every single month.
You can't do that.
So what you need to add on top of
the editing is strategy.
Now this applies if you're selling
Instagram reels, YouTube videos,
but you need to be the one who
comes up with the ideas and the
strategy for your clients.
And you need to write the scripts.
On top of that, you should be
doing
the thumbnail, the SEO, and the
posting.
So this way you control all of the
variables.
So you'll be
able to promise an ROI for your
clients.
So just to recap, you're not only
video editing, you're
basically a content strategist.
In a nutshell, what you'll be
doing is selling videos to other
businesses.
You'll be able to get them on a
monthly retainer, meaning they'll
pay you anywhere from
2000 to $6,000 every single month.
And in return, you'll make them
four videos a month.
You'll make
them four YouTube videos, 30
reels, whatever you structure the
deal as.
The way that I run my content
agency TickScale is that I've
never ever done an in-person shoot
for a client.
Whenever I sign a
client, I send them a video that
tells them exactly how to record
from the comfort of their own home
using just their iPhone and a
laptop.
I know a couple guys that run
content agencies where they're
shooting in person.
Every other week on their
Instagram story, they're flying to
this place,
flying to that place.
And that's not the type of life I
want to have.
Not that I don't like travel,
but I don't want to be forced to
go somewhere.
I want to go there by choice.
It's also just going to
ruin your schedule.
So just to make it super clear,
you don't need expensive
equipment.
In fact,
your clients will be covering any
equipment costs.
Now with a content agency, there's
many
directions you can go in.
You can sell YouTube videos.
You can sell Instagram reels.
You can
sell video sales letters.
You can sell ad creatives.
The list goes on and on.
A lot of beginners get
hung up on which type of video
they should be offering.
But instead of having analysis
paralysis,
what you should understand is that
people aren't paying you for an
Instagram reel or a YouTube video
or an ad creative.
They're paying you for a result
and they don't actually care what
type of video
gets them that result as long as
they get it.
Now that you guys understand what
a content agency is,
I'm going to go into how you can
get your first or next client.
So there's two tiers of
clients you can work with.
The first tier is composed of
business owners who pretty much
have
no content online.
They're coming to you starting
from scratch and they need help
building from the
ground up.
We'll call that section of the
market tier one.
They're easier to sign, but they
typically
pay less and stick around for less
time.
On the other hand, we have tier
two.
This is composed of
business owners who already have a
personal brand.
They're already posting and they
don't
necessarily have to be famous, but
they already have that momentum.
And then when they start
working with you, it's like
pouring oil on the fire.
Tier two clients will pay you more
and they'll
stick around for longer because
you'll be able to get them results
quicker.
So if you're more of a
beginner, you want to start
pushing towards those tier one
people and then work your way up
towards
tier two.
But if you're watching this and
you're already experienced, you
should try and focus as
much of your attention towards
those tier two clients.
Now, in terms of how much you
should be
charging, when you're starting
out, you want to go on the lower
end of the spectrum, which is
usually
1.5K a month, 2K a month, 2.5,
somewhere in that range.
And then over time, as you get
more
experience, you can add more and
more money to your retainer.
What I did is for every two
clients
I closed, I added an extra 250
bucks to 500 bucks a month to my
retainer.
Now, on average,
our clients pay us $3,500 every
single month.
We've had clients pay us up to
$8,000, $9,000 a month,
but those are just a couple of
needles in the haystack.
For the most part, we make 3,500 a
month per
client.
So basically, since we're charging
such a high ticket price point,
all you need is three or four
clients and you'll be making 10K a
month.
In terms of the profit margin,
you're typically looking at
anywhere from 75% to 80% when
you're at those revenue levels,
but as you scale, it'll start to
dip
towards 75%, 70%, and 65%.
The good thing with this business
model is that similarly to your
clients,
you don't actually need that much
equipment yourself.
All you need is your phone, your
laptop,
and a Wi-Fi connection.
You can run this business from
anywhere in the world.
In fact, I just moved to
Dubai at 19 years old and clients
were paying me while I was on my
business class flight.
The one thing
that most people don't know about
this business model is that you
can use AI to do most of the work.
It can help you with client
acquisition and it'll help you
with fulfillment.
I developed a custom AI
tool that we use to come up with
video ideas, content strategies,
and write video scripts for
our clients.
We've been using it for over four
months now and client results have
never been better.
On
top of that, it just gives us more
bandwidth to bring on more clients
without having to hire more people
and bring down our profit margin.
I don't know about you guys, but I
don't want to run a business
that has 50 employees, 30% profit
margin.
I want to run a lean machine.
The next thing I want to talk
about is how far you can scale
this because there's two types of
people, right?
Some people
only want to make 5k a month, 10k
a month, replace their income,
maybe 3k a month.
But then there's
other people like me who just push
this to the max.
So I scaled to 93.5k a month in 15
months,
and I did this as a complete
beginner.
In fact, as I'm recording this,
there's still eight more days
to go for this month, and we're
already at 86k cash collected.
Inshallah, this will be our first
six-figure month from the agency
alone.
As you scale up to my level,
you're going to need to get an
operations manager, a copywriter,
and a video quality checker.
On top of that, you're going
to need systems and automations to
keep track of everything, or else
you're going to get lost
because there's so many videos.
But I have it so dialed in to the
point where I don't even have to
be there and my business is still
going to run.
It's always good to keep your eyes
peeled and still
stay involved.
So that's what I do.
But it's a good feeling knowing
that you could disappear for two
weeks and your business is still
running and still making money and
your clients are happy.
Now let's
backtrack a little bit.
Let's talk about what type of
clients you should be working
with.
So in theory,
you could actually work with any
type of business, but I personally
prefer working with online
businesses.
This is because no matter what
country my video ends up reaching,
they can sell to people in that
country.
However, if my client was a car
dealership, if I make them a video
and it gets 2 million views,
maybe only 20,000 of those views
were in their local area.
So really this is maxing out the
potential
result that our clients can get,
meaning they'll stick around for
longer.
And in terms of how we
actually land these clients, we
use the golden bullet method.
This is basically where you send
out
five messages a day.
You heard that right, just five
messages a day.
And in each message,
you send a piece of free work and
you only reach out to businesses
that you actually want to work
with.
Like these need to be your dream
clients.
For the piece of free work, you
can use AI to help
you out.
So it's not that time consuming.
The reason why this works so well,
and it allowed me to scale
up to 90 grand a month at just 19
years old in 15 months is because
you're going to stand out from
the crowd.
Everybody's just copy pasting DMS
using crazy mass cold email
sending software and
overall nothing's personalized.
But with the golden bullet method,
you want to think of yourself as a
sniper.
You're picking your dream client
and sniping them and signing them.
Sounds a bit cringe, but you get
what I mean.
Typically you can sign one to two
clients for every 100 messages you
send.
Of course,
this is going to vary depending on
your industry.
And if you actually know what
you're doing.
Now,
one thing with me is that I'm not
a one hit wonder.
I've also helped dozens of people
scale up.
Take
Yaroslav and David, for example,
who scaled to 14k a month in four
months.
And actually I have to
update the interview I did with
them.
That's on my channel because after
nine months of being in my
program, they hit 30k a month.
Next up, we have Chris and Amrit
who hit 35k a month within four
months
program.
And eight months later, they're at
50k a month.
This is Steven Batarina.
And within a four
month period, he scaled to 30k a
month.
This is recurring income.
But I got to update that one as
well, because after nine months of
being in the program, he's hit 50k
a month as well.
I have more
interviews on my channel, so I'm
not going to list them out, but
you get what I mean.
So there you have
it.
That's exactly what a content
agency is and why it's such a
powerful business model in 2025.
You've heard this before, but we
live in an attention economy and
pretty much everybody needs to be
on
social media or else their
business is going to dry up.
Now you might be thinking, okay,
this sounds
great, but what exactly should I
do first?
Well, I actually made a 100% free
training.
That's going
to be the first link in the
description.
You should definitely check that
out.
On top of that, make sure
you subscribe so you never miss
another video.
All right, that's it.
Catch you guys in the next one.