Hey guys, what's going on?
Hope you're doing well.
Update for you on your VSL review
process
inside of Klein Ascension.
So one of the things that we've
realized is the most difficult
thing
for me is to give feedback to
people when they just send me the
VSL.
When you send it to me
over Slack and I have to go back
and forth with you over it, it can
end up taking anywhere from
like 15 to 20 minutes in terms of
the total time elapsed.
But really it's like days because
I got
to get back to you.
You got to get back to me.
I got to get back to you.
I'm busy.
You're busy.
You know what's a lot easier?
Just showing up to the call.
So we've made it a
requirement now that if you want
feedback on a VSL, whether it be
your current one, one that you're
writing right now, whether it be
an improvement you made to it,
whatever it is, you need to show
up to
the calls because we found that
that is the easiest way for you to
be able to get feedback on your
VSL.
Okay.
So you type in a submission form.
You then show up to the call and
then I give you
feedback on your VSL.
We are not doing it anymore where
there's messages back and forth
on, can you
check out this VSL or, you know,
don't show up to the call and just
submit it and then watch the
recording on it.
It is very difficult for me to
give any level of effective
feedback if I can't have
a two-way dialogue with you.
And it ends up with me taking a
lot more time.
And I am very limited
because there's a 500 of you and
one of me.
Okay.
So if you need feedback, you show
up to
the call.
Now, some of you may be saying,
oh, but Nick, it's like 2 AM where
I'm at because
the time zone difference totally
understand.
You're going to show up to the
call and just
let us know ahead of time.
Hey man, I'm in Serbia or wherever
the fuck you're at.
I'm in
Serbia.
It's 2 AM here.
Do you mind if I go first and
we'll move you to the front so you
can get yours done first.
And then we'll move on to the
other people who are maybe on a
more
standard time zone with us.
Now, some people, oh, but it's 2
AM.
Grow up.
Time to grow up a
little bit.
You can stay up a couple times to
be able to get this reviewed.
We can't have
everyone, you know, we can't get
to everyone with every single time
zone.
Otherwise we'd be having
80 calls a week.
We already have a lot of calls,
but for me personally, I'm on
Pacific, so I can't
compensate for everyone out there
and all the other time zones.
So all you need to do if you want
to get
feedback is submitted through the
VSL form, show up to the calls,
which are normally on Wednesday.
We've been switching them around a
little bit because I've been
traveling a lot lately,
but normally on Wednesdays and you
can get feedback then.
So that's everything.
I'll see you on the next call.
Bye now.