All right so these are examples of
vsls that worked on cold traffic
plus the templates that
you can actually sit and use so
we're going to go through each of
these real quick and and and
kind of just give you like a base
structure and just like show you
what this could visually look
like um so cold you must set up
offer v3 here's over here so i've
got the actual video as well
posted at the top so you can watch
that as well um so again headline
um i put a table of contents
here for them to see um expected
roi and results section this is
the sales argument system section
this is the section where it shows
how it works um this is just i i
decided to put in here in this
particular vsl on some typical
kpis because we were getting like
a bunch of questions about that so
this this was like an iteration i
made up at after getting sales
calls and like as as as a
secondary
note like you don't make one vsl
and like that's the vsl you do
forever you're gonna do like
fucking
100 of these in your life like
you're always gonna be making
changes to stuff this is just how
life is
i understand like it's a pain in
the ass to re-record things but
what you have to ask yourself
is like would you rather have the
comfort of not needing to
re-record something but having all
fucked up sales process that make
that means you need to explain
shit constantly over and over and
over and over again on the call
which ultimately leads to you
having more work or would you
rather
just refilm the fucking thing and
solve the problem you get what i'm
saying like it's it's like one of
those things where it's like yeah
it's a pain in the ass but it's
like a leveraged decision right
so this is the section in this
particular vsl that walks through
the actual deliverables um and
then i
just walked through like kind of
like onboarding timelines and
whatnot and like but this was this
was a contextual to this offer
right like you don't you don't
have to have this you can have it
like
but you don't have to right so now
this is a different iteration of
this this is this is a version of
the
same offer but it's targeting a
different person so this is like
an enterprise one it's kind of
going at an angle of what you send
100 000 250 000 co-deals per month
so um again same thing as the
headline um expected results um
more expected results i walked
through the roi calculator um
again i show how the system works
um and then this is the part where
i explain what they get
um i do another uh onboarding
timeline and then i have a pricing
section um and it's i have a
comparison against the alternative
now i've seen somebody take this
vsl and then they also made a
like a comparison sheet themselves
where it's like doing it yourself
right now let's say like
but this is like a kind of like a
like a software thing where it's
kind of like let's just providing
the software uh it's like a setup
of of the software and it's like
we just give them all the
necessary
components cheaper right so it
makes sense to do an alternative
right now i had some guy who was
selling um he was selling like a i
think it was e-com email marketing
or some funnel build i don't
fucking know but like he also made
a comparison sheet comparing doing
it yourself versus doing
it through him and i'm like bro
that's not the alternative these
people are thinking of they're
not thinking about doing it
themselves they don't even know
you get what i'm saying like and
for that
specific offer like because what
we find on sales calls is that
when people ask us like when we
explain
all these deliverables to them
they're what they're asking is
like well what would it cost if i
did it
myself they're saying that they're
actually saying that on sales
calls now if your market isn't
saying
that then don't make a fucking
comparison sheet comparing doing
it yourself because that's not
what they're thinking you get what
i'm saying so so what that would
render this as is like if you had
a comparison sheet of like
explaining doing it themselves
versus doing it through you but
that's
not like what they were thinking
in the first place now this is
like a drop-off point in the vsl
and
they're like well that's not
relevant to me now you're just
like babbling fucking nonsense you
get what i'm saying like it needs
to be contextual and like you you
you'll the the thing is that
you'll you'll learn what your
market is like and what they say
and what they think over time it
just
takes time this first vsl you make
is not gonna be the final vsl you
make like you're gonna learn
hundreds and just fucking
thousands of different little
micro nuances about everything as
time goes on
it's just completely impossible to
convey everything every single
thing about every single
market for every single offer to
you because there's just fucking
millions of different things
that could you get what i'm saying
like you just have to go you just
have to do it and just have
like a base level vsl right so
this is another example one of our
offer olympia um so olympia has
different kinds of versions
there's like done for you
components of olympia there's done
with you
components of olympia but the
general is that it's like it's
like our mastermind offer but like
you see here i positioned it to be
like done for you so this this vsl
was actually like a case study
funnel so like i started this off
as a case study where i'm kind of
just walking through it but then
i'm kind of like presenting it as
a direct offer right so again
here's the 30 000 foot overview
and the
sales argument um this is me
showing like the graphical
representation of what this looks
like uh this is me
going through the campaign results
um this is me talking about ltv to
cac to make people understand
like how that works um it's just
me going into how the system works
again and like again showing this
um and then this is where i talk
about the deliverables of of of of
uh
of olympia so like now this has
two different packages generally
you shouldn't have two different
packages you should sell you
should sell one package like and
that's it it's just one package
right
um so but you got to understand
like what just happened here where
i'm saying like at this point
where it's like going back again
to the premise inside of the how
to sell high ticket packages
video like me presenting all the
deliverables and like explaining
like like this whole thing i've
walked through this whole thing
and i've explained how much
logistical intensity is here and
now i'm
gonna re again reiterate like how
much logistical intensity is
involved in this there's offer
creation
funnel setup ad scripts vsl gamma
doc video editing and vsl on the
first 10 ads um the campaign
launch
email sequences and text sequences
automations build outs center and
sdr recruitment closer
recruitment fulfillment and
recruitment campaign scaling daily
ads management right that's like
hella fucking logistical intensity
that is involved in deploying this
system and i'm basically saying
yeah we do all of that for you and
then i say and here's some like
other shit that's that's
involved there's one-on-one calls
in-person events course videos
one-on-one review materials
unlimited texting you get what i'm
saying like that's the premise i'm
trying to get at so the link
to all three of these will be
below for you to see and you can
watch them as well so like the
actual
video is embedded at the top so
you can watch how i say it right
and again it's like it's literally
just
me screen sharing the doc like
it's like super simple um so i'll
leave those in the description and
over time i will add additional
examples of vsls as time
progresses so all right peace