All right, so let's talk about how
to structure VSL
and the elements of everything
and like just an actual full
walkthrough
of everything that's going on.
So as you saw inside of the offer
section,
inside the video about how to sell
high ticket offers,
which is an extremely important
video to understand,
you have to understand this video,
right?
So we established that in order to
get people to buy,
we must present an opportunity to
them,
then convince them with evidence
the opportunity is a good idea for
them
and then make them an offer slash
proposition.
So we do this via using ROI
calculators,
using client case studies,
or case studies about the
opportunity itself,
irregardless of your personal
results,
and then explaining the logistical
intensity involved
in getting the results
and that you will do exactly that
for them.
So logically thinking,
this is how you generally want to
structure VSL.
So attention grabbing headlines,
so either a direct claim of the
result,
you can get them or a strong value
proposition
or something genuinely intriguing
needs to be immediately clear what
exactly does he do,
the expected results your
prospects can possibly achieve.
So either do case studies or ROI
calculators.
So this is just an example of an
ROI calculator.
So like, you'll learn more about
these in a little bit,
but this is just basically like,
so this is one made for Olympia,
our product Olympia.
So it's talking about like ad
spend, right?
So how much can you make from,
how much money can you make by
doing ads?
So like, okay, so let's simulate
this out.
You spend $30,000,
say it's $300 cost per call.
The close rate on the calls is
20%.
The average monthly amount you
charge a client is $4,000.
Your gross profit per customer is
80%.
Your average customer stays for
six months.
That would mean your CAC is
$1,500.
You close a,
you get a hundred calls booked,
$24,000 lifetime value.
So you get a 12 to one, eight.
12 to one LTGP to CAC ratio.
And that's just explaining.
So like what happens is you spend
$30,000,
you would realize $354,000 in
profit over six months, right?
So this is just a calculator
visualizing this.
And it's like,
we're just on a call fucking
showing this to people.
You get what I'm saying?
So next is a depiction or
graphical representation
of how your system works.
So the actual system slash process
you're building for them
represented graphically or with a
flow chart.
Number four is what deliverables
your offer includes.
And sometimes pricing,
but not always generally.
It's safe to just say a range of
pricing
so you don't have to make this in
the entire VSL.
But as far as you're concerned
right now,
don't reveal pricing in your VSL.
Then a call to action
and then frequently asked
questions.
So let's dive a bit more deep
into like some like each element
and get a little bit more advanced
with this.
So like attention grabbing
headlines.
So directly stating your offer.
Here's just some examples.
We help coach the consultants
that have $50,000 revenue in 60
days.
Using a VSL funnel guaranteed or
you don't pay.
I'll be able to launch a VSL
funnel
for your coaching business
and guarantee you sign 20 clients
in the next three months.
I'll be able to launch a VSL
funnel
for your coaching business.
Run all your ads.
Run all your ads
and guarantee you $50,000 in
profit.
Now you could also like fuck with
this
and be like,
I'll be able to launch a VSL
funnel
for your coaching business.
Build all the emails,
run all the ads and run it all for
you.
So like this doesn't have a direct
claim inside of it.
Now you might be asking,
well, Daniel, should I do this
or should I do this?
And the answer is that most of the
time
you as beginner without any kind
of authority
or any case studies whatsoever,
you really can't get away without
doing this.
And then as you start to get
results from clients,
then you can shift to doing
something like this.
Generally, that's generally how it
works.
What I'm just saying is that
if you're sitting here doing this
and you're not using like a
fucking revenue claim
or a guarantee
and you're a complete beginner
with no authority
and no case studies,
there's an extremely low
probability
this will work for you
and you need to stop being a
fucking pussy about it.
Like I'm just saying that to like,
so you understand how this works,
right?
So like my first agency
I worked for free.
Now you could say some shit
where it's like as well,
where it's like,
I'll be able to launch a VSF 100
for your coaching business,
I'll be able to build all the
emails,
all the ads and run it all for you
on a performance only basis,
right?
You can do that.
And then you get in a call with
the person
and you could just say,
like you can just also pitch them
a setup fee.
You get what I'm saying?
They're not going to like
throw a fucking giant shit fit
about the fact that like,
you get what I'm saying?
Like you can say there's a setup
fee,
but what you have to understand
in this VSL is that
you can only,
and as I said also
in the selling high ticket
packages video,
the price you are able to command
is a product of showing,
showing all of the deliverables
that are associated.
like if you sit here
and like you get to the
deliverables section
of what you're selling
and you list out like
a completely fucking profuse
amount of shit
that you do for them,
like what's that going to do?
It's going to show them
that wow,
this guy does a lot of fucking
shit
and even though you said
performance only basis
in the headline,
they're going to understand like,
wow,
this is a completely absurd amount
of work
that this guy is going to do for
me.
Yeah,
I think this fucking does warrant
a setup fee
or a small like
base retainer
on top of the performance.
You get what I'm saying?
Like this is what we're trying to
do
in the VSL.
This is the purpose of the VSL.
The VSL is a direct application
of what I talked about
in the How to Sell High Ticket
Packages video.
If you haven't watched the video,
go watch the shit again
because it's completely
a thousand percent integral
for you to understand selling at
all.
You have to know
what the fuck I'm talking about in
there.
So number two,
second section of the VSL
is a quick sales argument.
So like a 30,000 foot overview.
So this is where you just give
a quick sales argument
as to why your thing is so good
and why it makes logical sense,
right?
So for instance,
you're going to see examples
of this as well,
but I got this over here.
So this is the one from Olympia.
Most people are trying to scale
to seven figures
with cold outreach and content.
This is fundamentally impossible,
right?
So basically I just walk through
and saying like,
hey, you're trying to scale
because Olympia is like
helping them scale with ads,
right?
So what I'm saying here
is like most people
are trying to scale
by only doing cold outreach and
content.
I'm like, hey,
that's fundamentally impossible.
So I give it like a 30,000 foot
overview
of like a sales argument.
Now here's an example
of a list kit one.
We're selling the cold email setup
offer.
So I just have a section
that says why cold email
is so effective, right?
Here's all the reasons, right?
Just a sales argument here.
So let's define
what a sales argument actually is.
It's the structured,
persuasive reasoning
you put in front of a prospect
in order to lead them
to the conclusion
that buying is the only logical
move.
We're going to walk through
what Dan Kennedy says
about sales arguments here.
So this is like a,
this is like a,
it's just a point-by-point
depiction
of how like Dan Kennedy
defines a sales argument, right?
I won't go,
I won't go like super deep into
this,
but it's basically like
pick the jury,
define who the verdict,
who the verdict is
that you must persuade.
Name the niche,
situation, budget,
desired outcome.
If you cannot describe the jury,
you cannot win the case.
You've got to state the charge.
So name the painful problem
and the real cost
of letting it continue.
Put a dollar figure
and a time figure on the loss.
Present the big idea
of what's the unique mechanism.
one clear idea
that explains why this works
and the specific mechanism
that makes your approach
different.
Name it.
Establish authority fast.
Prove you are qualified
to argue the case.
Credentials, results, media,
clients, years, and market.
Use hard numbers.
Raise the stakes.
Spell out the consequences
of doing nothing.
Future pays the pain.
Stack proof.
So just show more proof.
Chain the logic.
So create an if-then sequence
that boxes the jury in.
If you want X
and X requires Y,
the only method
reliably delivers Y,
then this offers
the logical decision.
Use a damaging emission.
Confess a real limitation
or past mistake.
Then show how the mechanism
fixes it.
Detailed offer.
Solicit the deliverables.
Timeline.
Access and support.
Make it tangible.
Value stack and price
from anchor against alternatives.
Remove the risk.
That's like a guarantee.
Add urgency.
Preempt objections.
Call to action.
Micro steps in the future.
Future pays ownership.
Right?
So just as like a side tangent
on this,
you could take all of this
and feed this
to ChatGPT
or Manus
or Claude
or whatever the fuck
and then also say like,
hey,
I want your help
making a VSL script
or an ad
and I want you to follow
this logic
of a sales argument
with Dan Kennedy
or you could just say like,
I want you to help me
to develop a sales argument
following this framework
by Dan Kennedy.
Here's my offer.
And you can fuck with this
and like just use AI
to your advantage
to further your understanding.
You get what I'm saying?
Like,
you need to become
more AI brain,
like more AI like default.
Like that's what you do.
You get what I'm saying?
So you could take all of this
and copy this
and just like start fucking
with your offer
and like talking with Manus
or Claude
or ChatGPT
back and forth
to understand this, right?
So like for instance,
let's just walk through
some examples here.
This is an example
of a webinar offer.
So you build webinars
for clients.
So I'm just putting
a ChatGPT prompt here.
Condense the sales argument
down using the logic
of Dan Kennedy
to eight sentences for me
and then create a sales argument
for me for this offer.
We help clients build
an advertised webinar funnel
for the business
so that they can acquire
more high ticket coaching clients.
We build the funnel
via sell all the copy,
all the ads,
the webinar itself,
attacking all the back-end
selling systems
to maximize the return
to the webinar.
Okay.
So this is what
ChatGPT spit out.
Most coaching businesses
are stuck chasing
low quality leads,
wasting money on ads
or posting endlessly
on social media
without ever creating
a predictable client flow.
The root problem is simple.
They don't have a proven system
that turns strangers
into educated,
pre-sold high ticket buyers
at scale.
That's exactly what
a webinar funnel does.
It positions you
as an expert,
builds trust and leverage
and gets prospects
ready to buy
before you ever speak to them.
We don't just give you
advice on how to build one.
We build the entire thing
for you.
The funnel,
the webinar,
the VSL,
the ads,
the copy,
the tech,
the back-end selling systems
to maximize conversion.
It's the same model
top coaches use
to book dozens of sales
costs in a week
without relying on referrals
or organic grind.
You compare the cost
to figure this out yourself
versus plugging it
into a done-for-you system.
The numbers make
the decision obvious.
Waiting just delays
the revenue moving
to the table.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So like personally,
like I changed this up
a little bit.
This is what I would
personally say
having read this output.
If you run a high ticket
coaching business
with a low quality,
leads,
not enough sales calls
and no predictable system
of getting high ticket buyers
on the phone,
then the only reasonable way
to fix your problem
right now is with a webinar.
A webinar is the only funnel
that positions you
as an expert
and gives sufficient time
together with you
and a prospect
to actually get them
into buying mode.
That's why we're able
to see 5 to 6x returns
of cold traffic
with a webinar funnel
and we do all this for you.
The funnel,
webinar slides,
automations,
the ads,
the copy,
the tech,
the SMS,
the email,
the back-end selling system,
everything.
All you do is show up
to the webinar
and say exactly
what we tell you
and we can have this
up and running for you
in the next 10 days
and guarantee you
see a profit
or you pay us nothing.
Right?
So that's just an example.
So you can do the same thing
with a content offer.
I'm not going to spend
too much time on it.
The link to this Gamma Doc
is in the description.
You can open it up yourself
and read through this.
But the premise of saying,
like another side note
to say is that
like what I said in here,
what I said
is that
this is the only reasonable way
to fix your problem.
Right?
And then also in here,
like I'm going to,
also in this content agency thing,
I'm also going to say
content is the best,
now fuck ads.
Right?
And then in this one
I'm going to say
LinkedIn content is the best.
And what I'm going to say
in this LinkedIn one
is LinkedIn is the best,
fuck cold email.
You get what I'm saying?
So you got to understand
what's happening here
and become immune
to propaganda.
Right?
So
if someone is selling
a webinar funnel build out,
a fucking course
you should say
that a webinar
is the only way
to fix their problem.
Like,
you don't fucking sit here
and say like,
like you and I both know
that,
well,
a VSL funnel
also could work.
A low ticket product funnel
Right?
Doing cold outbound
also could work.
And that's like the reasonable
way to go about this.
But if you're like,
if you're offering
all of the available
contingencies to somebody,
you're basically saying
you don't have to buy my stuff.
You can go buy something else,
which is a completely
fucking retarded way
to go about selling.
Like,
you gotta,
like,
when I say some shit in here,
LinkedIn is the single best
platform
to book sales calls
with buyers
who actually have budget.
Now,
if I just said that to you,
like,
you would think
that my actual ingrained belief
is that LinkedIn
is the single best.
And that's not what I'm saying.
I'm saying that in the context
of if I was fucking selling
a LinkedIn offer,
that's what I have to say.
You get what I'm saying?
Like,
like,
it's propaganda.
I'm exuding propaganda.
You get what I'm saying?
Like,
so,
you need to learn,
like,
as a marketer,
not everything you see
is fucking true.
It's,
you get what I'm saying?
Like,
you need to learn
how to maneuver
this fuckery yourself
and understand
what the fuck is being said.
You get what I'm saying?
This is like,
this is like super important
for you to understand.
So,
that was just like
a side tangent.
So,
all right,
so let's talk about
the expected results
your prospects
can possibly achieve,
right?
So,
case studies
slash studies of a case.
So,
if you have case studies,
this is where you'd put them.
So,
case studies being
screenshots of results
or interviews with clients
revealing quantifiable results,
ideally revenue generated,
right?
So,
if you don't have case studies,
this is,
okay,
so,
you understand,
like,
what a case study
is effectively doing
is,
it's showing them
two things.
One is that
the thing you're selling works
and two is that
you're a person
who can execute
the thing correctly
to actually generate
the result,
right?
So,
there's two components here.
It's that the thing works
and that you work,
right?
So,
if you lack a case study
which shows that
the thing works
and you work,
you've got to try to do
a reasonable effort
of at least getting
some evidence
that the thing works
irregardless of you doing it,
right?
So,
you have to sell somebody
the concept
that the thing works
at all.
You get what I'm saying?
So,
you've got to understand
like why I said this,
studies of a case.
So,
like a case study
like could be defined
as like
it's the
it's the study
of a case
that occurred.
It doesn't necessarily
have to be a case
that you were in charge of
but it's a study
of a case.
Now,
that doesn't mean
you're going to sit here
and fucking lie
that a case study
is yours.
Do not do that.
Don't fucking lie,
right?
But I'm just saying
is that
if you were to present
a study of a case
that is not yours,
you need to explicitly state
it's not your case study.
So,
like for instance,
let me show you
what's possible
with a VSL funnel
and to do that
I'm going to walk you
through an example.
Here we have Daniel Fazio
with his company ListKit.
Here are all his ads
on Facebook Ad Library
and here are the landing pages
he's sending these ads to.
You can see that these ads
are leading to an opt-in page.
Once the people opt-in
his ads,
they can automate
text messages and emails
after they opt-in
they're taking to a VSL page.
This page has an application
that qualifies his prospects
to make sure
he's talking to people
that can afford his offer
from their sales calls
or booking
he's selling packages
in the range of $600
to $6,000 a month.
ListKit is doing
over a million a month
with his funnel.
Now,
first off,
you can't use me
as an example
because if you were to do that
every fucking one of you
would just use me
as an example
and then like
don't do that.
You need to go find
your own example.
But if you were doing this
for instance
you would just show
some screenshots
of the shit, right?
So,
what you're effectively doing here
all you're doing here
is just selling
the concept of the thing.
So,
this is like an example
of just selling a VSL
an opt-in VSL funnel
as a concept.
You know what I'm saying?
So,
all the while
you're not saying
these are your case studies.
You're not lying.
What you're doing
is simply selling
the opportunity itself.
If your thing
is making low ticket
product ascension funnels
then you find examples
of people doing that instead.
If your thing
is cloud view email marketing
you find brands
doing an amazing job
and use them as a result.
If your thing is content
then you find people
doing content right.
The premise is that
you're selling them
on the opportunity itself.
You need to do your best
to find out
how much money
the examples
you're using are making.
It's typically easy
to find out
if you ask around.
People like to brag
about how much money
they make on the internet
so it's normally
easy to find.
So,
it is in fact
possible to get a
okay,
just side note.
It is in fact
possible to get away
without doing this
case or study
of a case results section
but only if you've done
a really good job
of conveying
your 30,000 foot
overview sales argument
and have a great
value proposition.
So,
for instance,
if you have a value
proposition in your headline
like I'll launch
and scale your paid
traffic funnel
and generate you
leads using my own money
you only pay on results
then that would be good.
Right?
This offer would
technically be structured
in such a fashion
that they still have to
pay a set of fee
plus cost per call book
and you are effectively
making money based
on the arbitrage
of what you can
get calls book
versus how much
you charge the client
for each call.
So,
there's always some
wordplay trickery
maneuvering going on.
You just need to like
learn how to do that
yourself.
Right?
So,
second,
next,
ROI calculator.
So,
immediately after showing
the results that are
possible to be achieved
this is where you want
to make the numbers
more tangible for them
and use an ROI calculator.
The easiest way
to make an ROI calculator
is do Claude or Bolt
or there's some other ways
there's going to be
some more training
on ROI calculators
specifically but
Bolt makes it look
prettier.
So,
this is like an actual
thing that
Claude made
right here.
So,
I made this
in Claude,
right?
So,
this is what's called
a Claude artifact.
There's going to be
more training on
our ROI calculator
so I'm not going
to go deep into it.
Now,
a question you might
have here is
when should you
reveal price,
exact price in your VSL?
As far as you should
be concerned right now,
you should not be
revealing your price
in your VSL.
It generally becomes
okay to reveal price
once you have tons
of case studies
and you have tons
of inbound
because your authority
level is high
but for now,
don't do that.
Next is a depiction
or graphical representation
of how your system works.
So,
this is kind of like
it's just a visual show
of what exactly
is the system
you're selling.
You understand like
if you want to charge
a lot of money
like you're selling
a system
like a full
a full system
of accomplishing something
right?
You got to understand
that like
you need to sell
a car
not tires
right?
You're selling
a full fucking car
right?
And then
if you get on a phone
with a client
and they don't want
the full car
because they already
have a car
then you could sell
them tires
to their current car.
You get what I'm saying?
But you're not going
to get people
on the phone
unless you're selling
the car
first.
You see what I mean?
So,
so this is the point
where you say something like
so now that
you know what kind
of results are possible
with this
let me show you
how the system
is even constructed
in the first place
and how the whole thing works
and you then lead them
into some graphical depiction
of what your things
looks like.
So sometimes
this system
is fairly simple
you can get away
with just like
some gamma
native diagrams
so like
for instance
you go over here
gamma has like
these native diagrams
where you could like
just visually show
what the fuck
you're doing
you get what I'm saying?
Or you could like
you do this thing
with gamma
over here
where it's like
you do this
and you can do
visualize this text
or edit
with AI
expand the text
or convert
to a specific
type of thing
you get what I'm saying?
You can fuck
with it yourself
or again
you can use Claude
to create an artifact
from a description
of your system
so here's an example
so I said this
in Claude
so can you
can you create
a graphical depiction
that visually shows
and explains the following
a video sales order funnel
that uses Facebook ads
to send to an opt-in page
the opt-in page
collects name
email phone number
immediately after opting in
the user is taken
to a page with a VSL
embedded in a button
to submit an application
obviously not everybody
will submit the application
so we use their phone
over to text
and call them
we also use their email
to send them
promotional emails
these promotional
email flows
contain a 10 sequence
series of automated emails
and then
you get the point
I'm just like
fully explaining
the offer
right
and then this is the output
of what Claude made
this is what it looks like
this is called
a Claude artifact
it like publishes it
on a URL
right
and you can share
this URL
or you can take
screenshots of the URL
now
you can either
tell Claude
or redesign it
if you want
a different design
you can expand
on more sections
or simply use
what it outputs
in order to manually
create your own
something
so like
you can take
what is here
and use something
like Miro
or Funalytics
or Lucidchart
just to like
manually redesign it
so it's not like
so
you get what I'm saying
like you can just
fuck with it
right
but you need
some kind of
graphical representation
that shows people
like the flow
of what is occurring
right
so
next
is
the next section
that you do
in the VSL
is what deliverables
your offer includes
so this is the part
where you basically say
so what exactly
is including this offer
keep in mind
what you've done
at this point
is fine
you've made
first is that
a big fat claim
there's all they can get
or lay your dick
on the table
headline
or you've made
a clear direct headline
just stating
what you can do
for them
two is that
you explained
how either you have
or other people
have gotten results
doing this thing
three
you use raw math
to visually show them
what kind of metrics
are possible to get
you graphically
or visually show them
everything that's evolved
in the offer
and ideally made it
as complicated sounding
as possible
and really really really
explained how many
moving pieces there are
and that you're going
to handle
so
now for the final act
you will tell them this
all those pieces
I just explained
all of that
is part of this offer
you get this
this this this this
this this this
this all done for you
all you do is this
I do everything else
you get what I'm saying
exactly like I talk about
in the
how to sell
high ticket packages video
so CTA
this is where you ask them
to get on the phone
it only really needs
to be as simple
as if you're interested
in getting started
click the button
below this video
schedule and call
with me directly
not a salesperson
we'll go
and I'm saying
not a salesperson
if that's you doing it
but if it is
if they are going
to talk to a salesperson
don't fucking say that
right
we'll go through
what the metrics
and deliverables
will look like
for your specific business
how much I charge you
and what
what results
I think
are reasonable
for you to get
FAQ
now this is where
you'd simply answer
the common question
objections people have
the proper way
to source these
is by using
recordings of call transcripts
but you probably
don't have those
so you can use
Claude, GPT
or Manus
and take everything
you've already written
inside your GammaDoc VSL
then use a prompt
like this
I'm making a section
VSL for the FAQ
I need to figure out
what the common
objections and questions
are going to be
the target market
for this
are coaching consultants
selling high ticket
coaching packages
so this is where
you put what
your niche is
below and pasting
all the information
I have written
for the VSL already
please read all
the information
then through logic
determine what you believe
is the most probable
to be the most integral
and highly asked questions
that I will get
on the call's pace
and then you get
your output from there
and then you have
a giant list
of frequently asked questions
right
and yeah
that's it
that's all the elements
so what I'm going to do next
is just show you
actual examples
of VSL