All right, let's talk about video
sales letter.
So video sales letter, it's just a
video on your page.
It's pretty much a requirement.
You gotta imagine, like if you're
talking to cold traffic,
like no one's buying from a
faceless,
like just random company.
Like you have to show your face
here, right?
Because what you have to
understand is that
you are default an internet
scammer
until proven otherwise.
And the first step to building any
form of trust
with anybody is obviously showing
your face to them.
Like you can't be doing this thing
where it's like, I'm never gonna
show my face.
It's just a completely
unreasonable expectation
to believe that anything is gonna
work out
for you hiding your face.
Like this whole idea of like a
faceless brand,
like it's not happening, bro.
It just isn't.
So let's go over this real quick.
So I'm gonna make this wildly
simple for you to do.
So what you're gonna do for your
first VSL
is what's called a GammaDoc VSL.
This is what I do for like 90% of
the VSLs I make.
So this is generally a B2B tactic.
Sometimes it can work for a B2C,
but the software I'm using right
now
in this presentation is called
Gamma.
So like you probably see like most
of the videos
I make inside this course are on
Gamma.
It's just Gamma.app, right?
It's just a Google Doc,
basically Google Doc software,
but you can like,
there's all sorts of like
formatting and whatnot.
There's some AI tools inside of
Gamma.
So it's really good.
It's free to start.
There's a free version of it,
but there's also a paid version of
it.
I have the paid version.
So then all you're gonna be doing
is putting all of the relevant
information
about your offer onto a Gamma Doc
and then screen record yourself
going over the document with Loom
or OBS.
So OBS is,
like I'm filming with OBS right
now.
It allows you to like customize
like how it looks right now.
Like I can,
there's like different scenes and
whatnot,
but Loom is just a video screen
sharing platform.
It's like super cheap.
I think it's like $10 a month
or something like that.
You'll probably use it
a substantial amount in your life
anyway.
So then all you do
is embed this video directly
onto your landing page.
Like literally that's it.
The reason why this makes sense to
do
like a Gamma Doc VSL
is that you don't have to memorize
the script.
All you do is effectively
just read off the document
and convey the idea and arguments
and whatever the fuck is said
on the document
just like directly.
You get what I'm saying?
Like you would need
like crazy camera equipment
or a mic.
Like I'm using a mic right now,
but I don't even have to have the
mic.
I'm using the camera on my Mac
right now, the webcam, right?
It's super easy to do this.
So if you can do it at one take
without messing up,
you won't even have to do any
editing.
And even if you did mess up a
little bit,
if you have a Loom subscription
with one of the AI features
enabled,
it can clean up your video
by removing like blank spaces
and ums and ahs and shit.
So why do I structure my VSLs like
this?
Because it means
that they can also serve
as the sales deck
you use on the calls with clients.
So what do you got to understand?
Like what our base instruction
here
for you to do is
in the beginning at least
is that your VSL,
this gamma doc you're making
as your VSL
is also your sales deck.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, so Dan Crowley
will be teaching a significant
amount of sales
inside of the sales section
of this course.
Him and I both agreed that
generally it is very difficult
for a beginner to sell
without a sales script
or doc to go over.
Like you'll kind of like
get onto a call
and it's like all sorts of just
like,
you might fucking spiral
and like not know what to say
and whatnot.
This is like a structured way
to go about it
and to convey a sales argument.
So this is why I've chosen
to instruct you as a beginner
to make a VSL in this fashion
so that it can also double
as your sales deck.
And what I mean by that
is that you will quite literally
screen share the VSL
with clients on sales calls.
So I was actually talking
to someone the other day
and they were talking about
how what they were saying
is they were using ads, right?
Now typically what you'd find
like with cold email for instance
is like it seems that people
you book calls with on cold email
and ads tend to show up
more aware of your offer.
Like they tend to actually watch
the video on your page
and stalk your social profiles
and like they'll go to your
landing page
and actually watch it.
Like a substantial amount of
people
from cold email
and cold outreach of any kind
actually conduct research on you
before they respond.
Like the vast majority of them do
this.
So what that means is that
they tend to show up
relatively aware.
Now, if you're using ads
in exchange for being able
to fucking hyperscale ads
with like barely doing any
just putting budget up.
What happens is people tend
to show up
not being more aware
of what's going on.
Like they tend to have watched
your VSL less on your page
and like conducted
any kind of research on you
or stalking of you
less than they otherwise
do normally
having come from cold email
or cold outreach.
So what I was talking about
with this dude is
he was saying this to me
and I was like,
yes, well,
that's the purpose of like
closers for instance.
So like he has a sales team
and I was like,
well, if the people
were showing up unaware,
what would be the purpose
of your sales team?
Like your sales team
is there to reconvey
the sales argument
and whole message
you're trying to convey
in the VSL.
So you gotta understand
like this is why
Dan and I are making it
so that you want to start
with the VSL
is your sales deck
because what you say
on the sales call,
like the pitch,
the argument
that you're putting forth
just is the argument
that's on the VSL.
Now I want to exemplify
this premise to you
a little bit better.
So what I'm going to give you
like the outline of the VSL
that you're going to be given
inside this section
is using like base element
components,
right?
However,
at the most advanced end of this,
the best way,
the single best way
to construct a VSL
would be to go take like 50
or you could even do it with 10.
You could do it with 5,
like 5, 10, 20, 50,
100 recordings of sales calls.
Upload them to an AI
that can handle that much data
such as Manus
and then tell it,
hey, analyze every single
question,
objection, and concern
that every prospect
has conveyed on here
and then list them out
in descending order.
and then you would have
in descending order
of the frequency
with which they're asked.
And what you would find
is it would list out
maybe like 10, 20 questions
in descending order
of the frequency
with which they asked
and this would,
by mathematical nature,
uncover
what people are concerned with
most probably,
right?
using like big data
from like actual fucking prospects
that you had like spoken to.
So, but in the absence of that,
because if you're just starting
out,
you don't have a fuck ton
of sales call recordings.
That's why I'm just giving you
base elements.
But I'm just,
I'm just saying this
to exemplify the parody
of that.
What you say,
you got to imagine
what a video sales letter is,
is the sales conversation.
They're just not on the phone.
Like they just can't talk back.
Get what I'm saying?
And the sales call
just is the VSL,
but they can talk back.
You get what I'm saying?
Like the parody between the two,
it's the same thing.
It's the same exact thing.
You're trying to say
and convey the same thing to them
on both the VSL
and the sales call.
You get what I'm saying?
So, further down
in this VSL section of this
course,
you'll see another VSL training
from Nick Verge.
Nick Verge is a professional
copywriter.
Nick Verge is hyper intelligent,
right?
So, like a very extremely good
copywriter.
So, Nick Verge teaches VSLs
in a little bit of a different
way.
And you'll see it.
I won't go into a deep explanation
of it,
but my way is easier
to get started with.
Nick's way is more advantageous
for you to take the time
and learn if you plan
on getting good at copy
or direct response copywriting
in any capacity.
I'd recommend you do go through
it,
but you could proceed forward
with this course and everything
without having gone through that
yet, right?
So, for instance,
if you ever foresee yourself
writing VSLs for clients,
it's a really good idea
for you to go watch Nick Verge's
version
of writing VSL
and seeing what he has to say
about creative briefs
in particular, right?
In the future,
various amounts of Nick's content
will be posted inside that section
as well.
So, I would recommend you go watch
it.
I'm going to label it
as Video Sales Lenders Advanced,
right?
But this is like a basic,
what I'm going to show you here
is a basic structure of VSL.
So, TableCon,
we're going to talk about
how to structure VSL
and VSL elements
and then examples of VSLs
that worked on call traffic
and templates for you to use.
So, let's move on
to the next video.