So I wanted to briefly go over
deliverability metrics and kind of
where you want to be in stand as
far as like all the metrics.
I don't look too, too, too much
into these besides open rates,
which we'll talk about in a
second.
A lot of them, it's really hard to
gauge metrics because every brand
is different, every audience is
different.
It's really hard to say like this
is the number you want to be at.
That's just not how it works.
So it's very fluid.
But like these are like general
numbers of where you want to be
open rates.
We want to make sure we're above
45 percent across our flows and
our campaigns.
If you're lower than 45 percent,
all you can do is for the emails
that you're sending in campaigns,
if they're lower than 45 percent,
just create a segment of people
who have opened an email in the
past 30 days and only send to
those people.
You pump your open rates just by
only sending to people who open
your emails.
That helps a ton.
If you send campaigns to those
people, you'll slowly start
increasing your reputation and
then your flow open rates will
start to rise as well.
So greater than 45 percent is
where we want to be at with our
open rates.
Don't want to be lower than that.
If you're lower, do that or
there's going to be a six-week
delivery recovery protocol in
another module.
So make sure you're doing that.
Click rates.
So what's the rate at which
somebody clicks your email?
We want to be greater than 1
percent here ideally.
Now, this is less of a
deliverability thing and more of
an email design and content thing,
but I get asked about click rates
a lot.
So ideally, we want to be at 1
percent.
Big brands, sometimes you can have
less.
I have one brand whose average
click rates are 0.6 percent, and
they're eight figures.
We're sending to like a
million-person list every time
we're sending.
And you know what?
That's okay to be a little bit
lower.
That'll happen.
But we have perfect
deliverability.
Our inbox placement rate is
super-duper high.
And so it's like not as much of a
concern.
It's more of a design issue.
If you're a smaller brand, you're
sending to less than 5,000 to
10,000 people, and you're under 1
percent, it's going to be a design
thing.
So refer to the design modules.
Bounce rate, less than 1 percent.
Ideally, way less than that, 0.5
percent.
But bounce rate is essentially
emails like that didn't get
delivered for whatever reason.
Either it's like a blocked email
or it's a fake email that doesn't
exist.
Those are all bounces.
We want to make sure we have less
than 1 percent on all of our
emails.
So you can just create an
exclusion segment in your email
sending, which is just like if
somebody's bounced an email at
least once over all time, then
we're just going to remove them.
So that's bounce rate.
Make sure you're less than 1
percent.
Spam complaint rate.
So this is tough to track because
sometimes people will do it
directly with Gmail and not in
Klaviyo.
But we want to be less than 0.01
percent.
0.05 percent is really where we
want to be at.
The spam complaint rate.
This can harm your inbox
placement.
So you want to make sure your spam
is low.
But it's tough to track.
Really, you're going to be raising
red flags if you're over like 0.1
to 2 percent.
But ideally, we want to be lower
than 0.01 percent.
Unsubscribe rate.
This actually doesn't affect
deliverability because
unsubscribes are natural.
You want people to unsubscribe who
don't want to receive your emails.
Like that's totally fine.
We want to be less than 0.5
percent though so that we can keep
people on our list.
Unsubscribe rate.
If you're lower, if you're higher
than 0.5 percent, like 1 percent,
then you probably have some issues
going on with your content.
You're not sending good enough
emails to these people to keep
them engaged in wanting to
continue to be subscribed to you.
So these are the base metrics.
Main one is open rates that we
really want to pay attention to
because that's going to have the
biggest impact.