So you can't send emails without
an ESP, which is an email service
provider, unless you just want
to send manually through your
Gmail to your list, but that's not
very efficient and that's just not
reasonable for any brand that's
over five customers.
So these ESP softwares allow you
to
design your emails, send out your
emails, and store your list data.
Do not overcomplicate this.
Use Klaviyo.
I've used all of them.
MailChimp, ActiveCampaign,
HubSpot, Omicent, Drip, all of
that.
Klaviyo is the only true option,
especially as you scale.
Just do it now.
Just be on Klaviyo.
If you're on another platform,
just switch to Klaviyo now so you
don't have to worry about it.
Klaviyo is the best and if you
want to save like $50 a month,
then I don't know.
Maybe you can do
that with other platforms, but
that's, you really just, it
doesn't really matter.
So Klaviyo integrates
with Shopify very, very smoothly.
All you have to do is create a
Klaviyo account.
So if you have a
store, just get set up just right
here.
Literally, this is all you fill
out and then
you'll, they'll walk you through
the whole entire process.
And you'll be able to follow
their easy to follow instructions,
integrate with Shopify or any
other e-com provider that
you are using with their platform.
They also have an excellent
support team and they'll
be able to help you with any
integration questions that you may
have.
So once you integrate,
so just follow their instructions.
Literally does not take long,
should not take you more than
a day.
You just kind of have to install
the embed on Klaviyo.
And so once you are inside
of Klaviyo, this is how your
integration pages should look.
So if you go here, this is inside
Klaviyo.
When you're inside your dashboard,
you will see this, but if you go
down to settings,
which is down here, and then go to
integrations, this is how it
should look.
You should see Shopify
here and you should see status is
enabled.
Um, that should be how it looks.
And then if you click
onto Shopify, if you click onto
Shopify, this is what you want to
see.
This is exactly how you want
to see.
You want to see that onsite
tracking is enabled here.
We want to check this box, add
viewed
product to my site.
This is going to be helpful later.
This is for helping us set up
flows and track
customer data.
Like if somebody views a product
and leave, somebody goes to
checkout and then leaves.
And then you're going to want to
sync your Shopify email
subscribers to Klaviyo.
Just put them on the
basic list newsletter.
And yeah.
So we will talk about this more
later on.
Um, and just a warning sign
here.
So again, this is more talking to
right here.
If you have this integration,
you're not done
because you need to have the full
integration to make sure that
you're tracking all the different
triggers.
And so make sure you have enabled
onsite tracking, which is this
button here.
The instructions
are right in here.
I've also attached them here.
Um, you want to be able to monitor
customers as they
view products, start, check out
all the stuff and create
automations.
Here's an article on how to
enable,
um, onsite tracking.
It's just right here.
Um, it walks you through the whole
entire process.
It's onsite
tracking is super easy.
You just check mark something in,
um, Klaviyo.
You just go, once
you're in Klaviyo, if you don't
have onsite tracking, it'll bring
you this link and you can
literally just click this link
here.
It's going to take you directly to
Shopify in the, in the Klaviyo
app embed.
All you have to do is switch a
toggle, save the theme, and then
it will be, it'll be
complete, super easy.
Um, and then also, so that's not
all of it.
So what this is going to give you
is viewed product, active onsite
and, uh, check out started
triggers.
But we also want to have an
added to cart trigger.
Added to cart is different than
check out started.
Um, and Shopify doesn't
automatically do that.
So you have to do that manually.
There's a little bit more
advanced, but
you, you need to have added cart
because if you're only tracking
check out started, you're missing
out
on anybody who just adds to their
cart.
So, um, these are different, have
different triggers.
Again,
abandoned checkout and abandoned
cart.
Follow this blog here.
I'll go over here just so you can
see how
it looks like, how to create an
added to cart event for Shopify.
You have to physically go into
your theme and add a snippet.
You add this snippet to your site.
Um, and in most cases, you're
going
to want to follow these
instructions.
If your store has custom liquid
blocks, if your store doesn't have
custom liquid blocks, you're going
to have to actually manually go
into the code.
This is super easy to do
if you have, um, custom liquid
blocks.
If not, you're going to have to
follow these instructions.
And in both
cases, you're going to have to
copy and paste this snippet and
then test it by using a UTM of
email
testing.
And then you'll be able to see if
your trigger fired.
Now we're not quite done with
getting set up.
We need to get the deliverability
technicalities.
There are new center requirements
for Google and Yahoo as of 2024.
And also there's just some best
practices that you need for
deliverability.
So first thing is you need a
dedicated sending domain.
And so if you follow
these exact steps here, go to this
article so you can see it, how to
set up branding, branded sending
domain.
So with email, you're sending from
a certain address and you don't
want to have the
clavio email.com.
This is actually a requirement
from Google and Yahoo.
So if you follow these
instructions, you're essentially
just like getting DNS records from
Klavio and adding that to your
domain and creating your sending
domain.
Um, this can be a little bit more
technical.
So you can shoot
me an email if you have any
questions, but it is a necessary
thing that you do need to have.
Um, and then you need to set up
DMARC on your domain.
Um, DMARC is essentially just
going to
help you with deliverability and
it is a requirement where else
you're pretty much just going to
be
guaranteed to go to spam.
So here's another article.
We're getting that set up,
understanding email
authentication.
And then if you go down to DMARC,
you can understand this.
And then it's also going to
tell you how to install it.
I've also put the instructions
here, set up DMARC.
Um, this is
all you need to do.
Log into your domains, DNS
settings.
Um, and once logged in, create a
new
record with this information.
This is literally all you need to
do.
It's super easy.
It seems all
technical and all this stuff, but
literally just go to your DNS
settings and create these, um,
create these, um, records.
And then that's all you need to
do.
Then you can just look up DMARC
authenticator on Google and then
plug in your domain.
And, um, that site will tell you
if you
have DMARC successfully installed.
And then, so those are the two
main ones.
And then you need to
ensure that your reply to
addresses on all your emails have
the same root domain.
So for example,
you can not have a sending domain
send@getnike.com.
And then your reply to address is
support@nike.com
because get Nike right here is
different from nike.com.
That's going to send you to spam
as well.
So you can just set that in
Klaviyo settings, just have your
automatic reply to be the same.
Um,
I know some brands have different
domains, but you have to make sure
that that is set up.