So now we're going to get into
some of the nitty-gritty, and then
I'm going to show you
inside Klaviyo, inside an actual
e-commerce brand's account, and
just kind of like walk
you around so you can get familiar
with it.
So right off the bat, here's just
a diagram of the Klaviyo home
dashboard.
And so just a quick walk through
here, we have this section here.
This is just going to be your
total store revenue, and they're
just going to track that
for you.
And so there's a total store
revenue from Shopify, and this is
going to be your Klaviyo
attributed revenue.
So how much money actually came
from email and SMS marketing if
it's inside of Klaviyo?
That's what this tells you.
And something to note, you can't
take the attributed revenue
straight to heart.
Like $28,000 here is directly
attributed to email.
Attributions, it can never be
perfect because imagine you open
an email, you click onto the
site, and then you don't purchase,
and then a day later, you're like,
oh yeah, that email.
That reminds me, I forgot to
purchase.
And then you go back and purchase,
it's like, how is that being
attributed?
So Klaviyo, typically they say,
somebody clicks an email and they
purchase.
Within three to five days, they
count it as email revenue.
So usually it's a little bit
inflated, but there's no perfect
way to track it.
Some to note there with Klaviyo
attributed revenue.
And then right here, you can see
the percentage of your total
revenue that comes from email
and SMS marketing.
So typically you want to be
anywhere from 30 to 50%.
If you're over that, say you're at
like 60%, that tells you, okay,
let's funnel some of
our profits back into paid ads.
If you're anywhere under 30%, 40%,
then that tells you, okay, our
email systems can be improved.
And then right here, there's
another important part, campaigns
versus flows revenue.
Here, this is just the percentage
of revenue coming from campaigns,
the one-time emails sent
to your list.
And this is the percentage that's
coming from flows, which are the
automated emails.
Typically you want to be around
50-50 or 40-60, 60-40, anywhere in
that range.
Depends on the business setup, but
in most cases, that's what you
want to shoot for.
So if you look at a brand like
this and you see 14% from flows,
that tells you like, okay,
the flows could use a lot of
improvement.
And then up here, if you want to
change the dashboard analytics,
you can just click on time period.
And so right now we can see this
is doing January 27th, 2024 to
February 26th, 2024.
So a 30-day period.
And it's comparing these numbers.
If you see over previous period,
the comparison period is just the
prior 30-day period.
So that's the main dashboard.
And then you have top performing
flows down here.
So you have the name of the flows
and then like how much revenue
they did and then percent change.
Then over here, this is the main
nav bar.
I'll show you around here.
Your brand name will be here.
And then you have just the
different sections of Klaviyo.
So let's go over to this live
Klaviyo account.
This is a completely new brand,
fresh brand, just started.
And let's just walk around Klaviyo
here.
We have the homepage just like I
showed you, only $590 in the last
30 days, only $47 from email.
And yeah, let's just go through.
So we have the homepage here.
And then we have campaigns, flows,
reviews, sign-up forms, audience,
which is a drop-down, content,
which is a drop-down here, and
then analytics as well.
So let's look at campaigns.
So campaigns, this is where you
send the campaigns to your huge
email list or certain segments of
your email list.
The campaigns are the emails where
you click a button and they send
right away or schedule.
And so if you click create a
campaign up here, you can name
something, test campaign, test
campaign, select the date.
Maybe we want to send it for March
5th.
Save and continue.
We want to do an email.
And then we get taken to
recipients page, which is, okay,
who do we want to send to?
You can pick who you want to send
to newsletter.
Who you don't want to send to,
make sure they're filtered out.
Let's not send to news
subscriptions.
Skip recently emailed profiles.
Typically, you want to send that
off.
Continue to content.
And then this is going to be your
actual email builder.
So this is your subject line.
So I'm sure you know what a
subject line is.
And then preview text, preview.
And that's essentially just like
completely, that's how you do
everything.
And so then we have here drag and
drop is what, how you can, that's
how I recommend creating your
emails.
So you can see inside Klaviyo,
they have a ton of templates that
you can use.
If you just want to use this
template or you can create a blank
email.
For this sake, let's just use a
template and we can move things
around.
So let's do something like this.
Let's use template.
And then we'll be taken into the
Klaviyo editor.
More will, I'll show you more
about this later on.
But this is the Klaviyo editor.
You have different blocks that you
can drag, like a text block.
You have image blocks.
Everything that you need is right
here.
But super simple.
You just edit the text however you
want to.
And you can view on desktop and
then how it will look on mobile as
well.
So super simple.
Super easy.
And yeah, that's kind of how that
works.
And then say it's complete.
Click save.
And then you can continue to
review.
And then this is where you would
send it out.
You're just ready to send it.
Schedule or send.
And boom.
That's how you do it.
Now let's go to the flows tab.
Their flow is set up for this
brand.
And so you have all the different
triggers for these are the
automated flows.
So browse abandoned, cart
abandoned, checkout abandoned,
post-purchase, site abandoned,
sunset, welcome, win back.
These are the recommended flows
when just starting out.
So you'll be able to see the
revenue, oops, revenue, revenue
per recipient.
Everything of that matter will be
recorded here.
So if we like went to, I mean,
let's go to like the checkout
abandoned flow.
Then you'll be able to see like
the flow journey.
So what's happening in the flow?
We're sending where the trigger's
happening.
We're sending a time delay.
And then we're sending an email,
another time delay, another email.
And then we're splitting by the
different products.
What did they leave behind in
their order?
And then more emails.
And this is like the editor.
You drag in emails that you want
to do for the customer journey.
Time delay is here.
And then just like with campaigns,
if you just click on to here and
click edit, then you'll actually
be able to edit the emails that
are inside.
And so, and then it's just going
to look just like campaigns in
designing a campaign.
So this is just like seeing how
the flows are mapped.
So let me zoom out here.
Exit, and that's flows.
And then we have, if you do
reviews inside of Klaviyo, you can
do it here.
Or if you use a different
platform, then that's fine.
But if you want to add reviews,
you can add review emails here.
And then, important, we have
sign-up forms.
So sign-up forms are essentially
the, like, pop-ups and embed forms
and everything like that.
So, yeah, and again, these numbers
are really bad.
And because typically you want to
shoot for 6% to 12% of your total
email revenue.
Or 6% to 12% of your total site
traffic.
And so you can see here with this
form, this mobile form is
converting 0.7% of people who view
the site.
So if 1,000 people view the site,
what is that?
Seven people are purchasing?
That's, or seven people are
signing up.
That's not what you want.
You want to be at least 6% to 12%.
Excuse me.
So if you have 1,000 people
viewing your site, you want to
have at least 60 to 120 people.
As for mobile, same as desktop.
You have these different forms.
And then creating sign-up forms.
We'll go over this later.
But you essentially just create a
template and then put it on your
site and you're good to go.
Now let's talk about the audience
section.
Audience, you have exactly as you
want.
Exactly how it sounds.
Growth tools.
If you just want to have, like, an
overview of, like, what growth
tools you use.
I really, like, I'm inside a lot
of Klaviyo accounts and I never
visit this page.
I never really view profiles
either because if you're looking
for somebody specific, you can
search for someone.
But really, all that really
matters is you want the lists and
segments.
And so lists and segments is where
you can create different segments
of your email list based on
conditions.
So you can see here, like, in
gauge 60 days, we can look at this
list and we can see this person,
in order for these 258 members,
these people have to be in the
newsletter.
They have to have opened email at
least once in the last 60 days or
clicked an email in the last 60
days or they've been recently
added to the newsletter in the
last 30 days.
And so that's how these segments
work.
You can segment by all these
different things.
Let's walk through one here.
Create segment.
Let's do test.
And then we can say we can say
abandoners, people who have
abandoned something.
So you go to definition here and
then just fill out whatever you
want.
Let's do what somebody has done.
I'm going to say they checkout
started.
So they started checkout at least
once in the last 30 days.
We'll do that.
And then let's just do that.
And they've placed order zero
times in the last 30 days.
So what this is going to tell us
is people who have abandoned
checkout in the last 30 days.
And then we can create the
segment.
And then we'll be able to see how
many people actually did that.
Quick water break.
And so that's the segments.
Let's wait for this one to load.
All right.
The segment loaded.
And you can see that there are
eight members who did that.
They met these conditions of
checkout started.
But placed order.
They did place.
Okay.
So I messed up the definition.
So this is great.
Great example of being able to
update.
So you just go to update
definition if you want to change
it.
And then we'll do placed order
zero times.
So they've checkout started.
But they've actually placed order
zero times.
And then we're going to have, it
looks like, two are going to meet
this requirement.
But let's check it out.
And, yep, so this loaded up.
And there have been two people in
the last 30 days who meet these
requirements of checkout
started at least once and placed
order zero times in the last 30
days.
So segments are very useful to get
different levels of engagement of
your list
and just get a better
understanding of where they're at
in the customer journey.
So next we can go to content.
This is where if you want to
create templates for your brand,
you can create templates.
You can look at past templates.
And then say you have a template
that you like,
you can save it in the saved
templates section.
And that's where you can do that.
So if you want to create a
template, you can just create a
blank email up here.
It's going to take you to just the
regular email builder.
And you can go from there, put in
all your logos, put in all your
colors, all that stuff.
Then if you want to go to
products, again, I don't really
use this, but that's there.
Images and branding.
So this will get put into like
unsubscribed pages.
So you can upload images there and
name them.
Then you have coupons.
If you want to create coupons
inside of Klaviyo, which we will
talk about later,
then you can do that here.
And then you have what's very
useful as well.
So kind of the main things that
you use on Klaviyo is the homepage
for an overall look.
You have campaigns for actually
sending.
You spend most of your time here,
campaigns and flows.
And then you have the audience,
lists and segments, pop-up forms,
and then you have the analytics.
So typically, I just look at the
dashboards.
You also have metrics and you have
all this other fun stuff.
So you can go to dashboards and
you can look at your analytics
over whatever period you want.
And it will give you all the
information you need.
If you want to look at a specific
thing, you can add a card.
You can create an analytic from
scratch or use some of their
pre-made ones.
Super cool, super easy.
And yeah, you can create new
dashboards as well if you want to
do something like specific to just
campaigns dashboard
and only show campaign stats,
flows dashboard.
Super easy.
I use dashboards a lot.
You have experiments, which is
just A to B tests.
You can see your A to B tests that
you're running.
And then you have metrics.
You can see what's actually
firing.
So like, for example, added to
cart, we had to add manually.
Let's see if it's firing
correctly.
Yes, people are actually
abandoning or adding to their cart
and it's being tracked.
That's perfect.
And then you have all these
different metrics where you can
actually track how often they're
being triggered.
We have benchmarks.
This is helpful if you don't
really know what you're doing in
terms of like email marketing.
So you can collect your, you can
put your industry and access
benchmarks for that industry.
Looks like there was an error
there, but you'll be able to see
like what open rates should I
shoot for, what click rates, and
all that jazz.
You have deliverability here.
And then you have custom reports
here.
If you want custom reports to be
sent to your email.
And then conversations.
So essentially just SMS.
What are people responding back
with?
And so, yeah, that's essentially
the full Klaviyo walkthrough of
just like on a base level.
What do all these sections take
you to and what is their purpose?