Hello, hello, and welcome.
In this module, we're talking
about the profitable e-commerce
funnel.
And you have my cool Airbnb
kitchen situation behind me.
You can just ignore that.
But today we're talking about the
funnel.
So you can see the funnel here,
why exactly we are doing
this.
And at the end of the day, we want
to be profitable.
That's the only thing that really
matters with e-commerce.
And we're talking about how that
funnel has changed.
And so today we're
talking about one, the evolution
of the e-commerce market, just so
we can understand the context of
where we are at.
We're talking about the top three
e-commerce problems in 2024, 2025.
And then we're
talking about the old e-com
funnel, used to work 2020, 21, 22,
versus the new one, the only way
to
survive in today's market.
And then we're talking about how
to convert and retain customers
with
email, because that's the point of
this whole thing is with email for
maximum profitability.
So that is
what we will be covering in this
video.
So sit back, pay attention, take
notes.
This is very, very
important, very important to
understand the context of where we
are at.
So evolution of the e-commerce
market.
Let's talk about it.
Okay.
So 2020 to 2023, which is 2024
plus.
Okay.
2020, we were in the
pandemic.
We had some crazy stuff going on.
Government was just printing money
out of their butt cheeks
and there were stimulus checks
everywhere, just getting sent.
You were just, money was coming
out
of thin air and people had a lot
of money.
They had stimulus checks and they
also were probably
getting paid from their job.
Still, a lot of people were still
getting paid.
And so consumers just
had a ton of money.
And so they were buying anything
and they had nothing better to do
all day, but to
buy anything.
They were just scrolling,
scrolling, scrolling and buying.
That's at least what I was
doing.
Literally nothing but scrolling.
And so e-com brands just felt
rich.
E-com exploded.
And so what
happened, people saw this
opportunity.
New e-com brands started
absolutely multiplying.
And thanks to
Shopify for making it super easy
for people to set up e-com stores,
just made it so easy for
new e-com brands to come up.
And so now we're kind of in this
situation, in this transition,
2024,
we're feeling the repercussions of
kind of like the mass printing and
where we were at in market with
2020, kind of in a bear market,
fear of inflation, recession, all
that stuff.
And the consumer just has
less cash.
They're getting less money.
Costs of living are rising.
And so people just have less money
than they did in like 2020, 2021,
when they were getting just money
thrown at them.
And then on top
of that, consumers are just more
skeptical and they're buying less.
The rate at which they're
buying is less than in prior
years.
One, because they have less money
and two, because they're
skeptical.
People have been scammed online
before and they're more protective
on their money.
And so
there's a little bit more
skeptical.
And so what happens, we have so
many more e-com brands on the
scene, but less people buying that
obviously makes e-com brands make
less money.
And so we can have two
options here.
E-com brands continue as usual
with the old funnel, which we'll
go over and they're just going to
fizzle out.
And then we have e-com brands who
are actually focusing on profit.
Those are the ones who are going
to
thrive, not just the revenue, we
want profit.
And so those are the ones who will
survive for the coming years.
So let's talk about the top three
e-commerce problems and how that
relates to everything.
I've talked, I talked to hundreds
of e-commerce brands and these are
the ones that come up
consistently.
The only thing, the only things
that really matter and they're all
kind of related to each other.
So number one, cost per
acquisition, how much you spend on
average to acquire one customer.
And so essentially
you have to pay on marketing.
What good is like a website where
you're selling products if nobody
knows
of it.
And so you have to spend on
marketing to get people in.
So how much are you spending to
get people in?
For example, if you're running
Facebook ads, you pay $6 in total
Facebook ads to get one purchase
for
like your bakery or something.
Then your cost per acquisition is
$6.
The problem which we'll talk
about and I'll go, I go more in
depth in a second.
But let's talk about retention.
So after cost per
acquisition, cost per acquisition
implies that you made that first
sale.
Retention is now what's the rate
at
which your customers come back and
buy again.
So how many times do your
customers come back on average?
One time, is it two times, three
times?
And so that's the rate and that
contributes to your lifetime
value.
And then we have profitability,
which is your take home cash,
revenue minus expenses.
Profitability is
directly related to cost per
acquisition and retention.
Literally the formula for
profitability is your cost per
acquisition
and your expenses and everything.
Profitability relies on
everything.
I kind of butchered that.
But revenue minus expenses, it's
all that really matters.
So problem number one, let's talk
about cost of acquisition.
So this is the ideal scenario.
We are absolutely blessed today
with easy ways to get site
traffic.
It is so simple.
You can just put some creatives
together in Canva or Figma,
whatever you want.
Toss Mr.
Zuckerberg some cash and you're
pretty much guaranteed to get site
traffic.
You are guaranteed if you give
enough money.
And so what we have, this is the
goal.
You have some money, spend it on
paid ads.
You throw some cash at Zuck.
He will bring you site traffic and
hopefully you can make some money.
And then you can just refund it
here.
Now you have more money.
You spend more on paid ads.
You get more site traffic and
hopefully you can make more money.
But this all revolves around site
traffic and making some money from
your site traffic.
The problem is on your site
traffic, people aren't buying.
They're not buying like they used
to.
You're paying for these cold
traffic ads, but so little people
are actually purchasing at a much,
they're purchasing at a much lower
rate than before.
The modern customer just doesn't
want to buy from you because there
are a few reasons.
For one, they have options.
Thanks to Shopify, so many e-com
brands popping up every single
day.
And the average customer sees over
70 e-commerce ads per day, which
is ridiculous.
If you think it's about every two
or three posts on Instagram,
you'll see an ad, some of them
being e-com, some not.
But if somebody scrolls for like
an hour a day, it's way more than
70 e-com ads.
And so they're seeing a lot of
brands that are getting exposed to
a lot of new brands.
And so they know what's out there.
They know when they see your
brand, they know there are
probably hundreds of other brands,
thousands of other brands in your
niche that they could choose.
And two, they have the options and
they just like to shop around.
It's fun to shop around.
It's fun to see what other brands
are out there.
It's fun to see what kind of
branding is there, what
influencers are promoting.
It's fun.
People like shopping around.
That's why people go to the mall.
You like to check out your
options.
And so that's the other thing.
It's just they like to.
And then three, they're wary about
buying online right away.
If they see your brand one time
off an ad, it's really difficult.
They don't know who you are and
they don't know if they can trust
you.
They're not just buying from you
right away.
I've been scammed online before
buying stuff or I haven't just
received my order.
And so a lot of people have too.
And so that just like scars you.
And so you always like to do your
due diligence now.
And so those are kind of like the
reasons why people are buying at a
much lower rate on the website.
So kind of what we have to do is
we have to cross the trust
threshold, which is just like a
concept that I've made up.
But it relies on the fact, like
the concept is what I made, but
the fact that the modern customer
needs to see your brand five plus
times to trust you enough to
purchase is fact.
People need to see your brand
multiple times.
Maybe it's not times.
Maybe it's time exposure.
Like if somebody watches like a
one hour podcast with the founder,
that could be enough to get
somebody to trust you enough to
purchase.
But we're talking like ads, little
bits of content has to be at least
like five plus.
If you ever heard of the rule of
seven, the rule of seven is
essentially somebody needs to see
you seven times enough to
purchase.
Someone needs to see you seven
times to purchase from you, to
trust you enough.
And also if you just, if they only
see you like one or two times,
they don't know enough about you
to purchase.
And so you just need to be able to
give that information.
So choose like the theoretical
trust threshold, say it's right
here, number of times exposed to
the brand, first brand
introduction, not ready to
purchase.
And then once they cross that
trust threshold, they're ready to
purchase in every exposure.
After that, it doesn't mean
necessarily that they're going to
buy right at this point.
It just means they're ready and
they trust you enough to where if
you, if they have a strong enough
need for the product, if your
marketing is strong enough, they
trust you enough to buy.
So that's what that is.
But where it gets expensive is the
customer doesn't buy from your ad.
They get the first brand
introduction and they don't buy
from you this time, this time,
this time, this time, this time.
The thing is each time costs
money.
If you are using ads, you're just
constantly buying more ads to get
more visibility.
And so what happens, your expenses
go up and the cost of acquisition.
Every single time you're having to
pay for a Facebook ad, you're
paying for these clicks, the cost
of acquisition inevitably just is
going up to the point where
potentially you're just breaking
even on your first purchase.
That's what a lot of econ brands
are doing, especially with
margins.
Even if you have a 2X, 3X ROAS,
depends on your margins, you might
be breaking even on that first
purchase and you're hoping to make
it back in the back end.
And so that's where it really gets
expensive, where cost of
acquisition is a real problem.
Now let's talk about customer
retention.
So kind of related to cost of
acquisition, once you have your
cost of acquisition price,
somebody buys from you, what
happens after they buy from you?
Are they not buying again or are
they going to continue to come
back because your cost of
acquisition isn't going to change.
And so no matter what, if you have
a set $5 cost per acquisition,
somebody buys from you once, you
have a set cost per acquisition,
somebody buys from you twice, you
have more profit with that
customer because you don't have to
pay for cost of acquisition twice.
So we're talking about customer
retention.
Your product just isn't enough.
Just relying on the quality of
your product for retention used to
work.
It used to be just if you have
something really good, people
would come back.
Like in 1900s, if you had good
pantaloons, people didn't have
options.
You had good enough pantaloons,
this dude would, you just have
your customer for life.
That's all you had.
But today the modern customer is
spoiled because thanks to Shopify,
there are just millions and
millions and millions of brands
out there with new ones popping up
every day.
People just like new.
Even if your product is awesome,
you have the best pantaloons in
the world.
People are curious what else are
out there.
What other pantaloons are there?
What other styles are there?
And they can find them because
it's so easy.
They just pull out their phone,
but the pantaloons galore.
Whereas like in the past, you
didn't quite have that.
So we kind of just have the
situation where it's like, hmm, I
like this brand.
I just saw this cool new young
brand on TikTok.
Maybe I'll try them.
And so customer retention has been
going down with the increased
competition.
It's increasingly harder.
So what you need to do is you need
to maintain their attention.
You have their attention.
You got their purchase once.
You need to have a good product.
You need a good product.
But it's not game over from there.
It's not you're locked in.
You need to maintain their
attention and keep their loyalty
for them to keep coming back.
You need to keep building upon the
attention you gathered or else
they're going to try someone else.
Many will just rely on continued
paid ads, which definitely will
work in keeping attention.
Just continue to expose people.
That's very expensive.
It's kind of the basis of
everything that we're talking
about.
Paid ads are very expensive.
You need ads.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm not saying do not use ads.
You absolutely need them.
But what about your budget for
acquiring new customers if you're
spending so much on these past
customers?
Better ways to go about it because
you constantly want to be
increasing your budget to acquire
new customers.
So that's the main problem.
So we've talked about cost per
acquisition.
Facebook ads going up.
People need to see your brand
multiple times to purchase.
That's not cheap.
And so cost of acquisition goes
up.
And then with customer retention,
the problem with that is retention
is low because there's so many
brands out there.
People want to try out new things.
People want to try these new
things.
They're seeing so many new things.
And so that leads to lower
profitability, which is problem
number three.
Revenue is awesome, but it means
absolutely nothing without profit.
You can't reinvest and grow
without it.
I talked to a brand the other day.
They're doing a million dollars a
month.
And then they just went out of
business.
You think they're doing a million
dollars a month.
Holy cow.
They weren't profiting anything.
They were unprofitable.
They were taking, they were
spending more money than they were
making.
And so they failed.
And so revenue doesn't mean
anything, even if you're at a
million a month plus.
It's very tough to overcome.
Profitability issues are a result
of one of the, both of the prior
problems of cost of acquisition
and customer retention.
In a perfect world, you would
acquire customers for cheap.
So you acquire a customer for $1
and you retain them for cheap.
They come back 10 plus times and
you don't really have to spend
anything.
That would be ideal.
That leads to the most profit.
However, you need to get new
attention to get your brand, to
your brand, to get new customers
in.
That's, that's not a problem.
You need ads.
And so that's the problem.
Ad prices are higher than ever.
So it's very hard to acquire
customers for quote unquote cheap.
Cost of acquisition, we need to
accept.
Yes, we want to minimize the cost,
but we need to accept that it's
going to go up.
Cost of acquisition is going to go
up.
It's going to keep going up and
it's going to keep being pricey.
Mr.
Zuck just has us in a chokehold.
We need him and so he can charge
whatever he wants and then we just
have to deal with it.
So this is how we maintain profit.
We need to pay for our site
traffic.
We need to pay to get the
attention with paid ads or
whatever.
Paying for influencers, paying for
SEO, organic search, whatever you
need to do.
UGC content.
We need, we need site traffic.
We need to bring it.
We need to get people in.
So the only way to maintain
profitability is in the back end.
You're able to retain rather than
spending more money on ads,
influencers, all that stuff.
In the back end, you can retain
more profit by using cheaper
methods of retention, which
is email.
And so you'd be okay paying top
dollar and you'd be comfortable
with your cost of acquisition
being high to acquire a customer
if you knew that they would make
10 plus purchases over
a lifetime.
So that's kind of like the concept
on a wide level.
And we also want to talk about the
top of mind effect.
So this is really how to solve all
three problems at scale.
If you're always in the face of
your customer, you're going to, no
matter what, hold mental
real estate.
If you just, if you see a brand
every day, like Coke, a lot, if
somebody says soda, it's
just the first brand that comes to
my mind.
They have top of mind.
Any given moment, they think about
industry or product, you want to
be the first brand
that comes to mind.
Because if Coke, somebody asks me,
do you want a soda?
And Coke is the first one that
comes to mind.
They don't have to pay cost of
acquisition on me.
They don't have literally any
costs directly with that.
So that's where that's super
valuable.
And email is the cheapest way to
do this.
This way you and all your
customers will get the random
sales when the customer is going
about their day and think of a
need for you that your product
fulfills.
So sometimes you're just going
about your day and you're like, oh
shoot, I need laundry
detergent.
What's the first brand that comes
to mind?
Whatever the first brand that
comes to mind is, that's what I'm
going to pull out my phone
and order on like Amazon or on the
website.
I just thought of Tide.
And so I'd go like on Amazon,
search Tide, and then Tide just
got that sale because they
hold top of mind for me.
And so that's kind of the way to
do it.
And email is the cheapest, costs
pennies to send emails.
And it's just content, just like
any other platform.
And everybody checks email.
That's the thing.
Everybody checks their email.
If you're in their email, they
will see you.
They will see your brand.
And so that's why email is the
best for that.
So let's talk about the old versus
the new e-commerce funnel.
So this was the old funnel.
What used to work fine.
Top of funnel is essentially
attention acquisition.
So you have paid ads, referrals,
word of mouth, SEO, organic social
media, et cetera.
But most stuff is coming from paid
ads.
So you're paying money.
You get site traffic and people
who don't buy like 99, 97.
Usually conversion rates are
between 1 and 3% for e-com stores.
And so they all leave and then
they go back to the top.
And then you pay more on paid ads.
You get whatever to bring you site
traffic.
And then eventually you'll get
conversions.
That used to be fine when cost of
acquisition was low.
Paid ads were easy when you could
get a 6X ROAS easily.
That's not what we get now.
So this used to work okay.
And you could just keep, even if
people buy, you could pay more on
this stuff.
Paid ads, pay for social media
teams to run your profiles.
That used to be okay, but now we
really can't.
This is what's profitable now.
We need to have stuff in the back
end to retain profit.
We need to send as much content
cheaply as we can rather than
spending more.
So this is why we have in-depth
and very strong ways to grow our
email list.
So that we can be able to actually
contact these people for cheap.
And then they become an email
member.
And then we have strong systems
set up in the back end and systems
and emails that repeat and send.
We have automation set up that are
going to automate the customer
journey.
Give them a customized experience
and convert them at key parts.
Just like when they abandon
checkout or abandon your site.
This is what we need.
And this is what's profitable
right now.
So to summarize, increased
competition has made it very, very
difficult to scale your e-com
brand profitably.
There are just a lot more e-com
brands and that's also why ad
prices are so high.
And cost of acquisition is going
up and retention is going down.
But email is the cheapest way to
nurture your customers into a
purchase.
Which can help with lowering your
cost of acquisition.
Rather than showing somebody an ad
10 times to get them a purchase.
Show them an ad once or twice.
Get them on the email list.
Send eight emails.
Much cheaper to lower your cost of
acquisition.
And then once you have them to
buy, you can retain them for
cheap.
Get them into multi-time buyers
with email and keeping them
nurtured and holding top of mind.
So that when they think of your
brand, when they think of your
product or industry, you're the
one that comes to mind.
So that is the profitable
e-commerce funnel.
This is essentially the basis that
we will be talking about in this
course.
So hopefully that all made sense.
Let me know if you have any
questions and we'll get to the
next one.
Hello.