Okay, today we are talking about
the 3.5 pillars
of email marketing.
Sounds kind of weird to have 3.5,
but we're gonna get into that.
These are literally the only
things that matter
with email marketing, everything
else is just noise.
If you just double down on these,
these are the 20,
these carry 80% of the results.
The 80/20 rule, the 20%, if you
just dial in these,
this is all you need.
So we're talking about these 3.5
pillars.
They're really only 3.5 things
that actually matter.
When you're under a million
dollars a month,
you should just be putting all of
your time
into these three and a half
pillars
until you reach that point.
Then when you're at a million a
month,
like the little
micro-optimizations
and the fancy stuff, those can
definitely help.
But that's only when you should
start getting fancy.
Let's just focus on dialing in the
basics
and do them really well.
It's quite overwhelming as well.
If you're seeing all these
different noise with AI,
all these advanced automations,
yada, yada, yada,
it just makes you stop doing these
things.
So I'm telling you, just focus on
these three, three and a half
things
and everything else, ignore it
until you're at a mil a month.
Just, it's gonna make your life a
lot easier.
So these are the 3.5 pillars.
List growth, flows, send
campaigns,
and then the 0.5 is
deliverability.
Very important, but it's quite
easy.
That's why it's a 0.5, so I'm
gonna show you how it's easy.
But list growth, flows, and
campaigns, that's all you should
be focusing on.
How do we get more people on the
list?
What are the main ways we do it?
What are the base flows?
Flows are the automations, so
automated emails that are gonna
fire for you,
based on a customer's action.
And then three, campaigns.
So campaigns are the emails that
are sent to the whole list.
How often are you sending?
What emails do you send and
keeping the list engaged?
So these are the 3.5 pillars that
we are going to be touching on
briefly in this video,
and then we're going to be going
in more depth throughout this
whole course.
So 2024 Email Marketing Funnel, I
talked about this in the
Profitable Ecom Funnel video,
but essentially what we have here,
we can see the different pillars.
So these are all list growth here,
how you get people on list growth.
So of course we have like
attention capture, website
traffic, organic traffic, paid
traffic,
bring you to site traffic,
somebody could leave, or they can
purchase and go here,
or you can convert your site
traffic into email subscribers
here with these different ways.
So we're talking about all of
these.
This is gonna be the list growth
pillar.
This right here is going to be
your flows pillar, so your
automated emails.
And then this right here is going
to be your campaigns pillar.
So that is what we will briefly
touch on.
So let's talk about list growth.
That's this part of the funnel.
There are four main methods of
list growth that we need to
understand, kind of ordered by
importance here.
One, pop-up forms, so important.
We will talk a lot about pop-up
forms, the most overlooked, not
paid enough attention to part of
the e-com funnel.
Every single customer who goes to
your website is pretty much seeing
your pop-up form and it is the top
of funnel.
It's how you're getting people.
You double the conversions of your
pop-up form.
You double the amount of revenue
that you get from email over time.
So that's pop-up forms.
Then we have post-purchase
opt-ins.
So after somebody purchases, you
get their email and they're in the
email list.
Sign-up pages, so just parts of
your website where it's, hey, sign
up to our email list, which you
can link like on your social
media.
You can have links to these
sign-up pages.
Then sign-up embeds.
So embedded parts of your website,
embedded parts of wherever, where
it's, put your email in and we'll
get you into the email list.
So first, let's talk about pop-up
forms, the best, easiest, scaling
way to grow your list and getting
a profitable e-com funnel.
It doesn't matter what you think
about pop-up forms.
It's like, oh, I don't like them.
It doesn't matter.
Your opinion does not matter.
Marketing doesn't care.
Money doesn't care.
What your opinion is doesn't
matter.
You can, yes, they can be a little
bit intrusive at times, but a good
pop-up form isn't.
People like deals.
People like discounts.
People like good offers.
People like, if you're a brand
they like, people will want these
pop-ups to have the opportunity to
get discounts and everything like
that.
So I could rant on this forever.
You need pop-up forms.
You can make them well.
You can make them good so they're
not intrusive, but like here are
the examples, right?
When you open a website, a pop-up
comes up.
So those are the pop-up forms.
This is kind of the post-purchase
part where it's essentially
checkout page, email sign-ups,
which is just like, for example,
when you're on the checkout page
here, you have the contact
information and then kind of like
this check box where it's keep me
updated on up-to-date
on news and offers.
That's that.
That's what we mean.
That's a super easy way to get
people who already know, like, and
trust you onto your
email list.
They bought from you.
Now let's get them on the email
list.
So there's that.
And then we also have sign-up
pages.
So for example, this is like
Gymsharks.
These are like optimizations that
I would do.
We'll talk about all these
individually in later modules, so
I'm just quickly going
through them.
But this is like what a sign-up
page is.
And so this is like what they link
on their social media, sign up to
our newsletter.
The only thing is people really
only give a crap about the
discount.
They know when they sign up for a
newsletter, they're getting
exclusive content, events, product
drops, all that.
People know that.
That's implied on a newsletter.
All they really care about is the
discount.
And all this information is extra,
not needed.
And it's just going to increase
your churn.
The amount of ROI you get back
from somebody's date of birth to
send them one email a year,
the ROI isn't there for the 3%
less people who are going to opt
in because this scares them
and it's too much work to fill
this in.
And then these are like sign-up
embeds.
So if you have, it's always a good
idea to have an email sign-up in
your footer.
Just remind people of the offer.
Get this discount.
And then also like halfway down
your page, you can have embeds
like this where it's, "Hey,
get 15% off your first order."
So those are the different methods
of list growth.
That is this part of the funnel.
Now we're talking about the email
campaigns, which are this part of
the funnel.
So why do we want to send
campaigns?
So campaigns are the one-time
emails that you send to the list.
campaigns are essentially just
consistent, cheap traffic from
customers who already know,
like, and trust you.
Email is cheap, cheap, cheap, 40
times cheaper than paid ads and so
it's cheap traffic.
And then it's also people who
opted into your email list or have
bought from you before.
These people already know, like,
and trust you, unlike paid ads,
which are more expensive
into people you don't know, and so
it's very harder to get them to
purchase.
So that's why we need to be
sending campaigns.
It's just, in principle, it's so
much better to be sending to them.
So you can get a consistent
cadence of like three to four
email campaigns per week.
It may sound like a lot to some
people would talk about that later
on, but trust me, I've
tested everything.
Three to four campaigns a week.
It helps with engagement.
It helps people get in a
consistent cadence of
understanding you, getting used to
seeing
you in their inbox, and then also
if you're sending good content,
people won't care.
So that'll establish a
relationship with the customer
where they get in the habit of
opening
your emails.
So you kinda have like a couple
different banks of content that
you can send with your
campaigns.
You have discounts and promotional
emails.
Then you have education and
nurture emails.
So you kinda want like a five-one
ratio, at least, of educational
and nurture emails versus
discounts and promos.
So education and nurture, these
are emails like social proof, like
testimonials, media publications,
things like that.
Those types of emails.
Benefits, so choosing, picking out
different benefits of your product
and making emails around
those.
News, whether that's like product
drops, news in the company,
whatever it may be.
And then trending/popular to go
over just like products that have
been performing well.
And then you have like discounts
and promotional emails where it
could be just like you promoting
a product like heavily or it could
be like percent or dollar off
deals, free X with X order, free
shipping, those types of deals.
And so usually we want to have a
lot more educational and nurture
emails to keep people liking our
emails
and staying signed up.
So now with campaigns, we need to
send consistently.
Send consistently.
I've talked about the top of mind
effect and this is the goal.
And that's what we want because
then you don't have to pay to
acquire customers really.
It's just like you send these
emails for cheap and you just have
the top of mind.
You're in top of mind.
So this is a very, very, very
profitable byproduct of just
sending consistent campaigns.
No, you're not going to annoy your
list.
If you're sending good content
people enjoy such as tips, you're
educating them.
And people will look forward to
your emails.
You have good copy, fun copy.
You have clean design.
People are going to like that.
It triggers dopamine.
So the below example is like a
brand.
They were sending one email
campaign a week.
We went to three to four per week
of sending good content.
And this was the result.
This is proof that more content is
good.
Open rates up 14%, 60% average
open rate for the whole month.
Click rate up 1.77%.
It was down at 1.02% when we came
in.
2.79% average click rate.
Placed order rate up 0.07% and
revenue per recipient up.
You could see quite a big
difference from just sending more.
And they were wary about sending
more as well.
It's just how it goes.
So highly recommend.
Not even recommend.
Like you need to do that.
Okay, so we went through this part
and we went through this part.
Now let's talk about the automated
flow emails.
Which usually is the part that
trips people up.
So what are flows?
Flows are the automated emails
that get sent to a customer after
they complete a specified action.
Things like joining the email
list.
That could trigger a flow.
Abandoning an item they left in
their cart.
That'll trigger a flow.
Or like making a purchase.
And essentially each customer, if
a specific customer is doing an
action, they individually will get
a set of emails.
Rather than like a campaign, I'm
sending it out to everybody.
But a flow is turned active and if
somebody completes that action,
then they go through and they
receive one email, wait a couple
days, another email, another
email.
So flows allow us to automate the
customer journey and send high
converting reminders, such as
abandoned carts, which are very
profitable.
Send cross-sells.
So somebody bought this, you'd
like this.
And then like relevant information
for the customer that's convenient
for them in the customer journey.
So they should make up around 50%
of your total revenue and 50%
coming from campaigns.
It's going to vary brand to brand
in terms of what's healthy.
Like for this brand, 43, 57.
You kind of, as long as you're
within 40, 60, 70, 30, 30, 70 is
stretching it.
If your flows were at 30% and
campaigns were at 70%, then it's
like, okay, your flows need some
work.
Usually we want to be around 50,
50, 60, 40, 40, 60.
So again, why should we use flows?
A lot of brands I talk to just
don't have them, but that's
completely idiotic.
You get automated revenue.
You take pressure off your
campaign.
So you're not just relying every
week on, oh, we didn't send
enough, we didn't send a campaign
this week.
And now our revenue is down 70%.
Take pressure off that because you
get consistent revenue.
You're converting high intent
traffic, like abandoned carts,
abandoned checkouts, people who
had an item in their cart, but
they forgot.
You get to recover lost sales with
your abandonments, kind of as I
said, and you get to personalize
the customer experience by giving
them content that's custom to them
based on what you're sending.
That's why you use flows.
And then the last 0.5, so the 0.5
pillar, deliverability.
And so what is deliverability?
It's essentially your domain and
your eyepiece, like you're sending
credit score is how I look at it.
If you have a good credit score,
you'll land in the primary tab,
which is this part, which is what
everybody checks.
If you have a bad credit score,
you're going to land in spam.
And if you're somewhat in the
middle, you're going to land in
the promotions tab here, which is
also very hard to get people to
check as well.
But really, we want to be in the
primary tab and good
deliverability, but you're in the
primary tab.
And so what affects
deliverability?
What affects your credit score?
A few things.
One is technical setup.
So having things like DMARC, DKIM,
essentially just like validations
on your domain, which we'll go
over.
If that sounds overwhelming, it's
not.
Just like having these validators
on your domain, it's just like a
checklist.
Do you have this?
And so super easy.
That's one thing that affects it.
If you're missing one, you'll just
land in spam.
And then open rates.
How often are people opening your
email?
If you're getting 10% opens on
your emails, so one out of 10
people are actually opening your
emails,
what do you think that tells
Google and Yahoo?
Do you think they want to send
their customers who they want to
have a good experience?
Do you think they're going to send
emails from a brand that's getting
one out of 10 people to open?
No.
Same thing as click rates.
If nobody's clicking or engaging
with the email, and that proves
that they don't really,
like the emails, and so they're
more likely to send you to spam.
Spam complaint rates.
If you have more spam complaint
rates, obviously that tells Google
and Yahoo, let's send these
people out.
And then sending volume over time.
So if all of a sudden, say there's
a new domain, if right out of the
gate, I start a brand, I start a
domain, and I send a million
emails in one day, they're all
going to land in spam.
So it's sending volume over time.
If you ever go through a hiatus,
you stop sending, and then you
send a ton of emails, you're going
to have some deliverability
problems.
You need to be consistent.
That's also why we need consistent
campaigns.
So why is it only a 0.5 pillar?
Because it's so easy.
As long as you only send to
engaged profiles and send good
content, you'll be fine.
I'll go over this later.
But if you send good content that
people want, and then you're only
sending to people who want your
emails, who open your emails, then
you don't have to worry about it.
Because you'll get high
engagement, and you won't get
spam, you won't get unsubscribes,
you just, well, you will get
unsubscribes, that's natural.
But you won't get spamming, so
it's super easy, trust me.
We'll talk about that in a bit.
Quick summary, only 3.5 things you
need to pay attention to in your
email account.
List growth, consistent campaigns,
have your base flows, and
deliverability.
All the other stuff is noise,
aren't worth the time unless
you're at one mil a month.
Just focus on these.