Alright, what up, lads and ladies?
Let's talk about agency marketing.
So marketing and sales
are two different things.
Marketing is how you get the calls
booked.
This is how you
get people interested in you, and
then they book the calls.
Sales is, okay, after they
book a call, how do we get them to
hand over their wallet?
So agency marketing, marketing
is going to be the most important
part, and that's something that
I've been able to do
pretty, pretty well, I would say.
I'd say it's my strongest, easily
by far, it's my strongest
suit, it's agency marketing.
It's how we've grown from nothing
to over $300k a month in
the past couple years.
So let's talk into agency
marketing.
How the fuck do we get clients?
How do you get people to find out
who the fuck you are to book a
call?
So there are four ways
to get clients.
Now, agencies love to
overcomplicate this.
It's really easy to overcomplicate
this,
but there are really only four
ways that you can get clients.
Everything else is just some
sort of remix of these.
So you have ads, so it's going to
be meta, YouTube, Google ads,
etc.
This is all scalable once you have
money in proof.
I haven't really seen too many
people
have success in the agency space
with YouTube ads and Google ads.
Particularly, it's going
to be meta.
Everybody just has Instagram.
Everybody's scrolling reels.
That's where e-com owners are.
So typically, it's going to be
meta ads, and I know a lot of
people who do really well on meta,
but if you want to book calls and
shit, you've got to put money
down, and then also you've
got to invest a lot of money to
learn how to do it.
So there's ads.
You have content.
So organic
content, posting on Twitter,
LinkedIn, Instagram, YouTube, all
that shit, builds trust and
authority,
and it's a multiplier for all
other forms of outreach, meaning
that if you run ads and you
have organic content build up,
your ads are going to perform
better because somebody will look
at your
ad, go see your content, be like,
oh, this guy kind of knows what
he's talking about, yada, yada.
Job boards.
When they look at you and they see
all your content, they're like,
oh, okay, this guy's
legit.
He's not just like some random
fucking dude who's going to scam
me.
Outreach as well.
If they
know who you are, they've seen you
before, and then you reach out to
them, it's going to work a lot
better.
But anyways, content, and that's
how I've always gotten my clients
is content.
So that's
majority of my expertise and what
I'm going to be talking about.
But also job boards.
This is what got
me off the ground.
A quick way to land first clients
as a freelancer, and I'll be
talking about
that.
I know a lot of people who do
really, really well on Upwork.
Job boards.
Upwork is the
main one of them.
And then outreach.
So manual and automated outreach
both work and have their pros
and cons.
So I've done all of these.
I've done all of these.
What I've tripled down on is
content
because that's just my strong
suit.
I'm good at making content.
I'm good at giving value to people
in good ways that also convert
them into interested clients.
So that's just what I doubled down
on.
There are other people who aren't
good at that.
They don't like having their face
everywhere.
They don't like creating content
because every Twitter post you
might only get like a couple
hundred views or whatever.
Some people like ads because you
guarantee that people are going to
see it.
They're a little bit more numbers
oriented.
Some people like the job boards
because they know
exactly what people are looking
for.
And then some people like to do
the outreach just because it's
scalable.
And there are different ways of
doing it.
It's just whatever your strong
suit is,
I tried all of them.
What ended up sticking was
content.
So that's what I do.
And then I'm about
to relaunch ads here shortly.
So let's talk about all these.
So ads are the best and most
scalable
method for getting clients.
Sorry for the typo here.
And most scalable way of getting
clients.
The problem is you're usually not
the best starting point as you
need upfront capital for it.
I don't
know about you, but when I was
starting, I was dead broke.
I wasn't just going to fucking
start
launching ads when I don't know
shit about them.
It'll take you at minimum $10,000
plus to get a
hang of ads.
And then also you have to pay a
large cost per acquisition.
So you might run ads for three
months before you kind of start
getting booked calls.
And that's three months of
spending 4K, 3K a month.
And so it's really difficult off
the bat.
But if you have like a mentor who
can walk you through it,
who's done it particularly for
agencies and booking calls with
agencies, then you can make it
work.
I know people who have done that
directly from the get go and
they're, they work just fine.
And then also the thing with ads
as well, you're going to pay a
large cost per acquisition.
So say you have a $3,000 service,
um, you might have to pay $3,000
on ads to sign a client.
Um, and so it's going to be like,
you make no money on like the
first month or the first couple
months.
Um, I wouldn't recommend starting
with ads unless you really have
somebody holding your hand and
like
building this all for you.
Um, but I just have never really
done them.
Cause I've never really needed to.
Um, but the pros are, it's
predictable.
And then also it's scalable.
If like you ever, um, like it's
just, once you have cracked ads,
then it's just like, do I want
more clients?
Okay.
Let's up our ad spend.
Do I, do we need to chill and
focus on operations?
Let's decrease our ad spend.
And then you can just like control
how many calls you're booking.
That's what makes it scalable.
And then great.
Once you have case studies that
exist because case studies are
what's going to get people to
actually like believe you.
Um, cons, very expensive to test
and beginners usually waste money.
I've wasted over $20,000 on ads
when I probably shouldn't have
spent $20,000 experimenting on
ads.
Uh, but I learned a lot.
Um, and that's shit that they
don't teach you in college.
And so it was super valuable and
it's going to help me as I
relaunch ads here shortly.
Um, the best time to use, once you
have an offer, two to three great
case studies and you have cash
coming in.
If you want to do ads and you
haven't like really doubled down
on any of the other acquisition
sources,
then maybe you can look into ads,
but that's really not my
expertise.
And so I'm not going to talk about
it too much, but it could
literally just be as simple as
fucking, um, book a, like, here's
a video of me talking about a case
study, book a call on my website.
There are all sorts of different
things you can do.
You can go to meta ad library and
look up people and literally look
at what their funnels are like.
Um, so I can go, sorry, Angus, I'm
going to expose you, but you can
look up like Angus.
He's an email marketer.
He runs ads and he does great on
ads.
And you can literally go and look
at all of his ads that he's
running right now.
You can see exactly what it looks
like.
Um, maybe we can go to use
Klaviyo.
So if you're running an e-commerce
brand doing over 3 million per
year and using Klaviyo,
then this is worth two minutes of
your time.
Q4.
And so just talks about Black
Friday, Cyber Monday, and then
take them to a landing page, get a
free audit,
and then it's just a form and book
a call.
Super simple.
That's all you really need to do.
There are all sorts of different
ways you could run ads, but
there's that.
If you find somebody who you know
is running ads for an agency, um,
and you want to use that,
then you absolutely can.
It looks like I'm on the wrong
page.
All right, here we are.
We're back.
Um, so yeah, that's pretty much
what you need to know about ads.
If you want to learn more about
ads, hit up an ads expert.
This is what I do, content.
That's what I do.
It's how you build authority and
prove what you know what you are
talking about.
It is a compounding game.
It's very slow at first.
So the first year you do content,
you're probably not going to get
any clients.
And you're going to be doing it
every fucking day.
And you're not going to get
clients.
Um, it's very slow at first, but
then it really picks up.
This is my sole method right now
for getting clients.
And it has taken us from 30k a
month to 300k a month in about a
year and a half now.
Um, so it allowed us to 10x.
Um, and now I'm kind of like the
guy for email marketing, which is
pretty crazy, crazy to say
because I looked up to other
people.
Um, and now like it, just if you
go off like impressions and, um,
and getting clients, um,
I am the guy in the space, which
is pretty, pretty crazy.
So it, it'll come up faster than
you think.
Um, so this is essentially
LinkedIn, YouTube, X, and
Instagram, X, Twitter, whatever.
Um, I have gone through different
periods where each one of these
performed better than others.
Um, but in every case, like
YouTube and Instagram have been my
most, uh, my best ones, um,
because I was kind of early to
both of them, um, compared to like
other people in my niche.
Um, now it's a little bit more
saturated on YouTube and
Instagram.
Um, but that doesn't mean that
like you can't get clients or
anything.
Um, and I still get over a hundred
calls a month from these.
Um, so, but essentially it's just
sharing case studies, wins,
insights, behind the scenes stuff,
uh, build trust with silent
lurkers who will then reach out
later.
It's a long-term play, the earlier
it starts, the more it stacks,
start now.
You will not, there's no, there
like, there's no negative of, of
building your content and your
network because it gives you your
network as well.
All my friends that I have in this
space right now, the client
ascension guys, um,
the people giving you this course
now, how did I become friends with
them?
My content.
Um, and so it's just like, it just
compounds and it becomes just like
your asset.
Um, and it becomes you and it's
how you get your name known.
It's how you get referrals from
other people.
It's how you get clients.
And then also even better, it's
how you learn your service.
I learned, I, there is this, this
doc that I made.
Um, everything you need to know
about e-commerce email marketing.
I believe that is what it's
called.
This was one of the first things
where I really, really, um, where
I really, really doubled that.
Like I started to like really
focus on content.
My knowledge about email marketing
just 10 times, because when you
create content,
you're forced to think about your
thing.
You're supposed to create
philosophies.
You're looking at your past work.
Just creating content makes you so
much better and so much more
knowledgeable.
It helps you like put your ideas
into thoughts.
And so it's, it's just, it's, here
it is.
Okay.
Magnum Opus.
I'm actually, yeah.
So this was like the first one
that I did like a year over,
almost two years ago, um, where I
kind of just like compiled all my
email marketing knowledge.
And then I just created this
massive document of 71 pages of me
essentially giving everything
that I know about email marketing.
So, um, you can look at this.
Um, this is like what, what it was
just a sales letter for brands.
And I was just like, fuck it.
I'm just going to write everything
that I need to know.
If I wanted to write a massive
document towards e-commerce
owners, what would I write?
Um, and so I pulled up like a
couple of different examples of
like other people and other niches
who had something like this.
And then I just wrote, what is
email marketing?
Why is it important?
What is all this stuff?
And all of this shit, I low key
didn't know before.
I was just forced to kind of like
figure it out.
And it was like, okay, why does
email work?
Why do these, why do I have these
philosophies?
And then I justify it.
A lot of this is just completely
made up, um, with justifications
that I kind of like figured
out as I'm writing this.
Mind you, this was before ChatGPT
as well.
Now you have ChatGPT to help you
compile your thoughts and
everything.
Um, so then I had these winning
philosophies and base principles
and everything, everything
that you need right here.
And this is what started it all
because then I have this massive
document.
Now I can turn this into fucking
so many different tweets.
I can turn this into everything
that I need, um, and for content.
And then this lasted me a while.
And then this was one of my first
YouTube videos as well, which
really popped.
Ignore my YouTube, um, the
recommended here, but it was one
of my first videos that really
popped.
Where are you?
Right here.
$25,000.
Me just reading this doc.
In both time and in this video
training, I'm going to be breaking
down exactly how I've managed
to generate.
It's me just reading this doc
right here.
Um, and this has gotten me a lot
of clients.
It got me a lot of clients at the
beginning.
I was pretty early on the email
marketing wave and this video has
printed me so many
fucking clients.
It's kind of crazy.
Um, and then I just started
ranking and this is what I've done
for YouTube.
Uh, but just start posting, just
do it.
Don't overthink it.
Just start posting out on all
these platforms.
Just post what you're doing, your
email examples, things you're
learning along the way.
Um, shit like that.
That's really all you need.
This is my Twitter.
You could go back to my beginning
days on Twitter, scroll down if
you want.
When I was an absolute nobody,
December, 2021, um, when I didn't
know shit and I'm still,
I don't have any clients and I'm
tweeting and doing this, reaching
out to other people my size,
just like building, building a
network.
This is just what you want to do.
So you can look at my content,
kind of how it works.
I do three tweets every day,
minimum, and then a couple of
threads per week as well.
Um, and then my Instagram, I do a
short form video and then I do a
swipe every single day.
Now I have like people who help me
write my content in my team.
Um, but this is like, for example,
what I'm posting and how it all
works.
And then LinkedIn, I'm just
repurposing some of my Twitter
content.
So a lot of this was literally
just like a tweet and then just
copy and pasting it.
A lot of this shit, I'm just
posting the same shit on every
platform.
And then YouTube, I post one video
per week.
Um, and that's how I do it all.
And then they all funnel into a
newsletter.
So I tell people, Hey, go sign up
for my newsletter.
Um, inbox newsletter.com
Right here.
This is just my newsletter.
It's also like a fucking, um, this
is like, I, I, I do newsletter
Monday, Wednesday, Friday.
I have 16,000 people on it.
If I ever need to do a push, I'll
just send a list, send an email to
my list being like,
Hey, if I can book a call, stupid
e-com owner, and that works.
And so everything funnels into the
newsletter, all my content.
I'm like, Hey, go sign up to my
newsletter.
I give you a 75 page guide on
email marketing.
And it's, it used to be this doc
that I'd give away to people when
they sign up to my newsletter.
Um, but then I adapted it.
And now it's a little bit more
modern to what I have now.
Um, so that's how my content
funnel works top of funnel post on
all these different platforms,
create tons of value, give free
guides, and then give free guides
hidden behind a newsletter.
So give me your email and I'll
give you this massive guide on
email marketing.
And then my newsletter I'm
sending, I have a sequence of when
somebody signs up to my email
list, I send them a daily email,
just giving them a stupid amount
of sauce.
And then also just like teaching
them email marketing and then
pushing the e-com brands to,
uh, book a call with me.
Um, and then, yeah, and then they
eventually book a call and that's
how it all works.
And that's how my content funnel
works.
Uh, now we have job boards.
This is what got me off the
ground.
This is what got me to 10 K a
month where my job boards, it's
where a lot of beginners
get their first dollar.
It's what I would tell everybody.
If you don't have experience, go
to the job boards, go to Upwork.
This is where I had my first 10 K
months, my buddy who I just got on
email marketing,
he had his first 20 K month purely
Upwork.
I know a guy who does nearly a
hundred K a month just on Upwork.
Um, job boards are great because
these are brands who are actively
looking for help from
someone.
So you don't need to convince them
that they need email marketing.
You just need to convince them to
pick you.
Upwork is my favorite.
Um, essentially it's just a job
platform where anybody can post,
hey, I need help with this
thing.
And then what you, what you're
able to do is then with these
posts that people are like,
Hey, fucking, I need help with
this.
Then you can be like, I can do
that.
And so if we go here, let me
switch to the freelancer side.
Um, buh, buh, buh, buh, buh.
So this is what it looks like.
And all you need to do all
throughout the day is look up
email marketing.
And then you can look at all the
job posts that brands right now
are asking for email
marketers.
Um, so graphic designer for meta
Google ads and email marketing,
mailer light email campaign,
uh, go high level expert for email
templates, email marketing
designer for Mailchimp.
So just a designer.
And then you can see all this.
So maybe I'd need entry level
email specialist needed.
Perfect.
I'd click onto this.
This is the job post.
This is the brand.
You can look into it and then it's
like, Hey, we need, uh, this is
the job post.
And then you can apply now.
It's perfect.
Um, you can see all of this email
marketing three to five emails per
week.
Boom.
And then it can talk, it'll talk
about like the brand or whatever.
And so you have people who are
actively looking for help.
And so that's, what's great, uh,
easy access people who are
actively looking.
So you don't need to convince them
that they need email marketing.
They already know it.
They're asking for email
marketing.
You just have to convince them to
pick you.
Um, cons is a lot of these have
smaller budgets.
A lot of these brands have smaller
budgets.
Um, they're looking for
freelancers, beginner people,
which is great.
Uh, but it's going to be very
difficult for you to get like
super big deals.
We have got, I've gotten big deals
and you can get big deals 100%.
It's just a little bit harder.
Um, and so there's that.
And then it's high competition.
It's a bunch of people just like
reaching out and be like, Hey,
pick me.
Um, so you can use these right off
the bat for case studies,
portfolio building and getting
early momentum.
Again, I was purely up work for
like six months, not like, yeah,
like six to nine months.
Um, and it got me to my first 10
K, um, 10 K a month.
Um, and so it's great.
It's just all throughout the day.
You're refreshing, trying to find
these different, uh, these
different posts.
And so, um, you can figure it out
on your own, but literally it's
just convince them to work
with you, give them value when
they ask for something.
And so always be looking for jobs.
Then you have outreach.
So outreach is also a great path
to book meetings early on.
Uh, but it's pure brute force in
persistence.
Same as job boards, but outreach
is just like fucking hitting
people up.
Like, yo, let me do your shit.
Uh, so you have, you have two
things.
You have manual outreach and cold
outreach.
So, uh, or automated outreach.
I don't know why I said cold
automated outreach, um, automated
outreach, manual outreach would
entail you reaching out to brands
that you want to work with
manually into having them
or emailing them manually.
Um, and then you have, uh,
automated outreach.
So you can do the same sort of
thing, but make it automated.
So things like cold email
automatically send emails.
And I, I did that.
That's what took me from 10 K a
month to 30 K a month, um, 30, 40
K a month.
That's what cold email took me to
that.
I stopped doing job boards and
switched to cold email, got me to
like 40 K a month.
And then my content started
ripping.
My cold email started to not do
good anymore because I was putting
less time into it.
So then I just doubled down on
content.
Um, but that's what I, that's what
I did.
I did the automated.
So you can do cold email.
Um, you can just look it up.
The client ascension guys, um,
Fazio and Andre and Christian and
Dan, that's what they do.
Cold email.
They can help you with it.
Watch their content on it.
You can send thousands of emails
every day to brands.
Um, and so you can do that.
Um, the only thing is like, it's
not going to be super targeted
because you're sending
the same thing to everybody.
Whereas like if you do manual
outreach where you're just
reaching out to less brands,
but it's super personal and you're
reaching out personally.
Um, and being like, Hey, work with
me.
So this is what I would do if I
was starting out and I wanted to
get clients.
Uh, I would do a manual outreach
method of hyper targeted and
giving free work.
You have to give free work.
It's good experience for you when
you're starting out and it's going
to build your portfolio
by having all these email examples
that you create.
Um, and it's just the best.
So find a list of brands that you
want to work with.
Go on Instagram, just search this
fucking brute force.
Find a ton of brands that you
think you could work with.
Uh, for me, I was looking at
brands who were like a thousand to
a hundred thousand followers
on Instagram.
They sold physical products.
They were at least doing like one
post per week.
I'd find one of them, um, that I
like, and then I would, uh, like
go to their following
and then see if they're following
similar brands.
Cause a lot of these brands are
following similar brands.
I would find all these brands.
I would screenshot their profile
so I could find them later, make a
list.
Um, and then opt into all their
email lists to see what their
emails are like.
So that's what we would do.
We'd opt into the email list and
then what we want to do is look at
their welcome email
and then recreate it and make a
better one than what they
currently have.
That's all we want to do.
Um, so I literally have even
YouTube video on this.
Um, if you go to Max Sturdivant
right here, I literally have
welcome email.
Um, I have a YouTube video just on
how to create great welcome email
number ones right
here.
It's a welcome flow right here.
You have that.
And then I'm pretty sure I have
another video from way back on.
Do, do, do, do, do, do on
reviewing welcome emails.
Um, I do have a lot of stuff so
you can go through these.
I know there's one of me roasting.
There we go.
Welcome flow emails, grading
welcome flow emails right here.
There's a great one right here of
me going through what welcome
emails suck and what good ones
look like.
Um, so you have that and that's
what I would do.
I would take the time to write a
new email and design that email.
And then what I would do, I have
the upgraded email and then I have
their before email.
I'll show a before and after.
Maybe I'll shoot a loom video
showing it.
And then what I would do is I
would send that upgraded email to
the brand, send it to the
owner and every single employee
that I can find on every single
platform.
I'm going to find their Instagram.
I'm going to find their LinkedIn.
I'm going to find their email.
I'm going to find absolutely
fucking everything that I can and
just blast them with it.
Hey, I made this.
Let me know what you think.
Um, can I do the whole welcome
flow for free for you guys?
I think I'll be able to make you
money.
And that's what I would do.
And just follow up like a mad man.
Just consistently every other day,
shoot them custom messages, shoot
them voice notes, everything.
We want to do email, Instagram,
DMs, LinkedIn messages.
This is free.
It's immediate, unlimited scale.
The cause is that it takes
persistence.
You're going to get a lot of
rejection.
You're going to get, most of the
people are not even going to
respond to you.
You got to get used to that.
But the, the pro of this is you
get a fuck ton of experience
creating emails and you have a
fuck ton of emails now that you
can show in your portfolio and you
have templates that'll make
your process easier.
Um, the goal here is just to get
conversations and not close deals
in the first message.
Just be like, Hey, I made this for
you.
Let me know what you think.
And if I'd love to create the rest
of the welcome flow,
if I had some of your assets, um,
something like that, that's what
we'd want to do.
So what's one should you focus on?
Depends on where you're at and
what you're good at, good at all
of them work,
but don't try to do everything at
once.
Just try to focus on one platform.
One thing that your gut says you
think you'd be the best at and
then do that.
Try them all.
Maybe like briefly get a sense of
what you like, find what you like
best and triple down on that.
Here's a baseline need clients.
Now I would recommend job boards
and targeted manual outreach.
So like what I said earlier of
upgrading the emails, I'd do that.
And I'd be a madman on the job
boards.
Um, and, um, just like do that.
And you can also do a combo of
both.
If somebody makes a job posting on
Upwork and you can find their
name,
also send them emails, find their
Instagram, find their LinkedIn and
reach out to them there.
Um, that's something that's super
good.
You just gotta be, you gotta be a
madman on this and down to play
the long game content.
Just start doing that now.
And if you have case studies in a
budget, then you can get going on
ads, uh, stack them over time.
The outreach will pay the bills,
but content is what build the
brands and then ads will scale
the business.
And so that's just like a good
little phrase, um, that I heard
once and it absolutely is true.
So that is how we do the marketing
for the company.
I wish I could give you a roadmap
for absolutely everything.
But a lot of this is just like,
figure it the fuck out.
These are the keys.
Just start going and figure it the
fuck out.
Hope that was helpful and I'll see
you in the next video.