What is up, my beautiful email
marketing people?
Today we are going over email
marketing agency operations and
fulfillment.
So hopefully you have watched my
other video or videos, whatever,
on what the fuck an e-commerce
email marketing agency is.
Now let's go over a little bit
more in depth on operations and
fulfillment
because, you know, it sounds great
in theory.
Let's send email for brands.
It's a little bit more complicated
than that,
and so we need to go over that in
this video.
We're going to go over the
different levels of fulfillment,
how to do this, what offers you
can run, and everything here.
So first let's go over the core
offers of what the fuck are you
doing for these brands?
Like when it's like, okay, I can
do your email marketing.
Okay, well, what exactly are you
doing?
These are the two offers.
These are the core offers that we
run and the core offers that I've
always done since I started.
So offer number one is you have a
flow rebuild or a flow setup
project
where we talked about those
automated emails.
That's exactly what we're doing.
So we do a one-time setup of all
of a brand's emails because a lot
of brands,
when they're started with email
marketing, you need all these
automations.
You need these, you just need all
these automations.
And so this is going to be a
one-time setup of 30 to 40 emails
within the flows.
Sometimes it can be more.
Maybe you can do less.
But things like your welcome flow,
your abandonment flows, your
post-purchase flows,
your win-back flows, how do you
get somebody who bought six months
ago to come back and buy again,
all that stuff.
This is usually lower barrier to
entry for brands.
They kind of want to start with a
project rather than before working
like long-term with somebody.
But it all depends on what a
brand's looking for and what they
want.
And so these are great for quick
wins and case studies.
So this is a quick little project
that you can do, 30 to 60 days,
lower barrier to entry to close.
You have to be like, yeah, we're
going to be working ongoing
together.
It's like, I'll just do this
one-time project and it'll make
you money because you set it up
once for brands
and they can run these flows for
years if they want.
And it'll continue to make the
money every single month.
And so that's just like the flow
rebuild where you just set up
these automations and then you say
adios.
And then number two is we have the
full email management where it's
we own your email channel
and we're sending everything for
you.
So we're doing this flow rebuild.
We're doing this setup, but we're
also doing campaigns.
And so we're doing the ongoing
campaigns, the 3x or so email
campaigns per week,
and then the ongoing testing, the
reporting, all that good stuff.
This is going to be a higher
retainer, so a monthly retainer.
This is recurring revenue.
So it's $3,000 a month and we're
your email team and this is what
we do.
Whereas like a flow rebuild, maybe
you charge like $5,000 for this
flow rebuild.
And then this, you get stronger
client relationships because
you're working with them over
time.
So these are the two offers.
There's like some smaller offers.
Like you could just do campaigns
if a brand's happy with their
flows.
You could do that as well.
I've never done that personally.
I've always been like, hey, we're
your full email team.
We don't work with brands where we
can't own the whole email channel.
And that's just what we do.
I know a lot of people who do
campaigns only.
I've just always chosen to do the
full management because I want to
be able to be like,
we own this channel, we've set up
everything, and these results are
purely ours.
And so it helps prove that.
And then we have the flow
rebuilds.
So for example, context right now,
I very much prefer the full email
management because
it's recurring revenue.
And so typically if we sign 10
brands in a month, we'll have like
eight brands on the full email
management and then like two on a
flow rebuild.
So that's like typically how it
will split up for us.
But we have some months where it's
like five and five.
It just depends on the month.
We have some where it's 10 ongoing
and zero flow rebuilds.
But these are like the typical
core offers that we want to do.
And so the first thing that I
really wanted to hit on, like yes,
we agree on this and we
do this project, we're doing this
fulfillment, but the most
important part of your agency
and your performance as an agency
is the client communication is the
most important part of
your service delivery.
You could have mediocre results.
You could be a beginner who
doesn't know shit about email.
But if you have excellent
communication and you're letting
the client know of every little
thing that you're doing, your
clients will stay with you because
they just like to be
updated.
They like to know that somebody is
proactive in managing the email
account, constantly reviewing
things and they give a shit about
the account.
That's all they want.
They just want somebody who gives
a shit and is looking at it so
that the client, they don't
need to look at the email.
So we use Slack.
I don't recommend any other
platform.
Just use Slack.
That's what most businesses
already communicate in.
And so we just use Slack.
We go to their platform and that's
where we communicate.
And if we just simply respond fast
and we're proactive with updates,
the client's going to be happy.
That's all that we want.
So this is like our communication
cadence.
So daily, all client emails and
Slack messages are answered within
one hour during working
hours.
We work 9 a.m.
to 5 p.m.
Eastern.
But everybody on our team, you're
expected to respond ASAP or at the
latest within one
hour for anything client has a
question or they share anything
with us, whatever it is.
So daily response times.
We just need to be communicating
daily on email revisions,
whatever.
We need to be communicating all
throughout the day.
It's not like, hey, we'll pop in
once a month or once a week with
an update.
No, all throughout the day, we
need to be available.
And then on a weekly level, we
want to have some structure with
our communication and our
reporting.
So we always do, for us, we do
weekly updates on Mondays.
And so every single account that
we're working with, we are going
to show you some numbers.
What did we do last week?
How much revenue did we make you
to reinforce, like, keep working
with us.
We're making you money.
So we're going to break down what,
how much money did we generate?
What did we learn?
Did we, one campaign, absolutely
crush it?
Did one, did not, didn't perform
as well as we thought that we
learned something from.
So we want to break down the
numbers, give a, give kind of like
a synopsis of the week.
What do we do?
We want to give a status.
What did we complete last week?
Show them that, like, yeah, we've
been fucking doing shit.
Hey, we just finished this draft
for the Browse Abandoned Flow.
Last week, we set live two flows.
And so it just shows to them that
we're moving forward.
And then also, like, campaigns,
like, how many campaigns did we
send?
And then, super important, since
the Monday, we need to outline the
upcoming week.
So now we tell them, this is what
we did last week.
This is what happened last week.
Now here's what we're doing going
forward.
Here's what we're doing this week.
This is our plan.
This is our action item.
We have these three campaigns that
we're going to be launching for
you.
And we're finishing up this
post-purchase flow.
You can expect that to be
delivered to you around middle of
the week.
Boom.
Now they have something to look
forward to.
They know that we're working on
shit.
And they don't got to worry about,
are these people just taking my
money and they're not doing
anything?
No, this is exactly what we're
doing.
So that's the weekly updates.
And then, every month as well, we
want to do a broader overview of
the stats.
Do a performance deep dive of the
revenue attribution, your
deliverability, your list growth,
your A-B tests, everything.
We want to put together a set
little slide deck of just broader
overview numbers.
How is the channel progressing?
What have we learned?
Are things trending downwards or
upwards?
What suggestions do we have?
Anything like that.
And also, you want to have at
least monthly check-in meetings.
Some people will meet every single
week.
Some do bi-weekly.
We've typically found that monthly
is kind of a good place to go.
You can do like bi-weekly for the
first couple weeks, first couple
months with a client, maybe like
the first two months, and then go
to monthly.
But I definitely recommend forcing
clients to meet with you monthly.
There are some clients who won't
want to talk to you, but it's good
for relationships to be meeting
with them face-to-face so that
you're not just another profile on
a screen.
It's like, this is a real person
working on my account, and it
makes it harder for them to want
to drop you.
Especially if you have fun with
the client and you have a good
relationship, they don't want to
drop people that they're friends
with, and so make sure that we
have these.
But this is really all you need
for communication.
Now, let's actually go into the
fulfillment for these different
offers that I showed you, and
like, what do the timelines look
like?
What do we do?
So this is an example of when we
were a little bit smaller, this is
like what our fulfillment would
look like.
So again, we have the flows, so we
need to map out the strategy.
We need to write the emails,
design the emails.
We need to build the emails in
Klaviyo, test them, get them
reviewed by clients, everything.
We have the campaigns, we have
pop-ups, and then reporting and
communication.
So those are really the only parts
of the email strategy.
And so this is like a flow rebuild
right here, and then this is what
an ongoing project where we're
doing absolutely everything would
look like.
And so this is just what we do.
Take it if you want or do
something different.
So this is like where we start
with the client.
Really, we're bigger, and so we
move a little bit slower because
we have a lot more moving parts.
But if you're a small team, you're
definitely going to want to
condense this.
When you're small, you have to
move with speed.
You have to move with speed.
That's what you can leverage
against the bigger agencies like
myself.
So we have a kickoff call, and
then we're going to build out the
core segments, so the list,
analyzing the list.
And then on the fourth, we're
going to have a flow map diagram.
So we're going to be mapping every
single automated email.
What email, what do we do for
email three on the card abandoned
flow?
Oh, we're doing, we're going to
remind you the card.
So we want to map this out and
show them the strategy.
And we like to have a call to go
over to this strategy with brands
to get them to see it and let us
know if they want to change
anything with the emails and the
strategy that we're doing.
Then we'll send a campaign
planning form being like, hey,
we're about to build our campaign
calendar.
Do you have any events?
Do you have any sales coming up?
Do you have any new product
release?
And so we'll send like a form
being like, hey, what are the
dates that we need to know?
And then right here, the 10th, we
have pop-up forms ready to launch.
And then we have an unsubscribe
preferences page, which is a
little bit advanced.
You probably don't need to do
this, but it's just like if
somebody clicks to unsubscribe
from an email, we have a page
where it's like, hey, would you
like to stay subscribed and get,
but only receive emails like once
a month, something like that.
And then on this date, we'll do
the campaign calendar.
But all throughout this, we are
doing the copy and the design on
all the flows.
And then on the 13th, we'll
deliver the campaign calendar.
This is every single email that we
want to send.
This is the topic of this email
and this email and this campaign.
We send the topics and our
strategy of what we want to do for
review and then see if the client
has anything they want to change.
And then by day 15, the 15th here
is when we have the welcome flow
and we send that over to the
client to review.
And then card abandon, checkout
abandon, kind of just like two to
three email flows per week.
And then all the flows are kind of
built out by the middle of month
two.
We're just working on making sure
they're all approved and whatnot
and getting them uploaded inside
of Klaviyo and turned on.
And then we can just focus on
campaigns.
So that's like what a kickoff
schedule would look like there.
And for flow rebuild, this is what
it would look like with just doing
the flows.
Same sort of thing, but no
campaigns.
And so this is like what a
calendar would look like.
So that is how that timeline would
look.
Let me take a drink of my water.
Now we need to build our
fulfillment machine.
And I'm going to go over, I'm
actually going to skip to the
scaling fulfillment and how to
handle more clients just to show
you like the different phases of
growing your company to be able to
then operate without you.
So stage one is the solo operator.
This is going to be you from kind
of like one to four-ish clients.
For some people, it might be
higher.
lower.
It just depends on the brands
you're working on and your
fulfillment, whatever.
Typically one to four-ish clients,
and this is what I was doing,
where it was kind of like at four
clients, I was kind of maxed out
on time, four to five clients, and
I needed to start hiring some
people to help.
So this is where you're wearing
every single hat.
You're doing all the strategy.
You're doing all the copy.
You're doing the design.
You're doing the Klaviyo uploading
and building the emails and
sending them live and scheduling
them, and you're doing all the
client communication yourself.
This is great for learning the
entire process end-to-end.
You need to have this phase to
where you learn it because as the
owner of a company, you need to
know how everything works.
But there is a limit.
You'll cap out around maybe three
to five clients before quality,
your response times, and your
sanity will start to suffer.
And so there's that, where you're
doing everything.
And so this is just what you want
to focus on.
Don't fucking worry about your
team until you've maxed out your
own time.
A lot of people just think way too
far ahead before.
It's like, brother, get your own
clients until you're maxed out on
time.
Then you can figure out how to
hire and everything there.
So that's where we go to the stage
two, where you're working with
freelancers and contractors, where
you're at five.
This will take you from five to
10-ish, 15-ish clients.
And this is where you get some
help from some part-time people.
You don't quite have enough cash
flow to hire full-time people, but
you can hire part-time and sort of
like contractors.
And so first hires are typically
designers to design emails,
copywriters to write emails, and
Klaviyo VAs.
So people who will actually build
the emails inside of Klaviyo and
schedule the emails for you a
little bit more of the busy work.
These are typically the easiest
work to – this is the easiest work
to offload, and it's just like
whatever you prefer.
Whatever takes you the most time,
I'd recommend doing that.
You should still hold control of
most of the strategy communication
in the execution, the management,
and the strategy, building out the
calendars and building out the
flow maps and the strategies and
then client communication.
But whatever's taking up the most
time for you or you just don't
like, do that.
And so the first thing that I
hired was a designer.
Fucking hate design.
Suck at design.
I hired a part-time designer to
design the emails, and I was
writing the emails, and then I
would upload into Klaviyo as well.
And then we got more clients, and
then I, again, got way too busy.
So then I hired a Klaviyo VA,
somebody who would actually take
those designs and build them
inside of Klaviyo, add the links,
quality check the emails, and
schedule them to be sent inside of
Klaviyo.
And then once I maxed out on that,
then I brought in a copywriter,
and then I had somebody writing
the copy.
This gives you breathing room
unless you take on five to ten
clients.
You can scale this even.
I see people who scale this to 20,
30 clients just doing this sort of
thing.
But that's typically what I would
recommend before you really want
to start bringing some people as
full-time employees because the
challenge is freelancers aren't
always reliable.
They're not as bought in to you
because they're doing their own
thing.
They have their own clients.
They're not as bought in.
It's just a different frame when
it's like, hey, they have other
shit, and they are usually
entrepreneurial, and it's
different when you hire somebody
off of a job platform versus
somebody that you got off of a
LinkedIn job post.
It's just a different vibe.
So they're not always reliable, so
what you'll need is clear briefs,
QC, and training systems.
And so that's that stage two.
And then once you have enough cash
flow, then you can start really
building out pods and teams within
your company.
So then we can build structured
pods of each pod.
It's just a clump of people that
can manage, like, six to ten
clients in each pod.
So there's going to be an account
manager.
So this is somebody who does the
strategy in the client
communication, and they manage the
team.
And then you'll have a designer, a
copywriter, and a Klaviyo
technician to upload into Klaviyo
and all that.
And that's going to be one pod,
and these can manage six to ten
clients.
And so that's what we will build
out.
And then you can build out
multiple, multiple pods, and so
then with each one having six to
ten clients.
Account manager is kind of like
the new position where this is
what I would recommend as your
first full-time hire is get an
account manager,
and then they'll manage, like, the
other freelancers, the designers,
copywriters, and Klaviyo VAs.
And they are dealing with the
clients.
And so this allows you to scale to
20 to 30, 40, 50 clients, and your
role kind of shifts to training,
hiring, and overseeing the pod
performance at this level.
So I ran this all the way to
around 30-ish clients until I
needed to get a director of
operations.
Because then my whole day was
just, like, reviewing everybody's
work and being like, is shit
getting done, checking in on the
client channels, making sure
people are actually active.
And that's when I was just maxed
out on time because I was also
doing sales and marketing, getting
us clients.
So that's when you need to bring
in the management layer, which is
when we're above 30 clients where
you can potentially add senior
account managers to oversee
account managers or directors to
oversee multiple pods.
So, like, a director of operations
to make sure that shit is running
smoothly, to ensure consistency
across the accounts, handle
escalations, and maintain client
relationships so that you can
focus on whatever you're good at,
which, for me, was marketing and
sales.
And then you're just stepped into
the CEO role.
You're focused on growth, sales,
and vision instead of the
day-to-day client work.
This is where you get out of the
day-to-day operations, and you can
focus on growing the business.
This will get you to 50-plus
clients in stable systems, and
this is still what we operate at,
around, like, 100 clients.
So this is, like, for example,
what our team structure kind of
looks like.
It's a little bit different than
this, and we have a couple more
divisions, but this is what it
looks like.
Like, for me, I'm the CEO, and
then sales closer, so I have
somebody now who takes my sales
calls.
And then we have a director of
operations, and so he's the one
who is kind of managing everything
on the internal, training
everybody, and double-checking
that shit is getting done, and
just being the support for
everybody.
And so you can see here we have
this division, so where we have a
senior account manager, and then
we have four different pods.
And so you can see one pod,
account manager, designer,
copywriter, Klaviyo technician,
and then each pod will handle six
to eight clients.
So we have that pod, we have this
pod, we have this pod, then this
pod, then we have a senior account
manager to kind of, like, oversee,
help with the strategy, help deal
with clients and everything there.
And then we have that division
multiple times.
So, like, at its full scale, this
is what it looks like.
At first, maybe it's literally
just you managing everything right
here for clients, and then you
turn into the account manager, and
you have a hired designer,
copywriter, Klaviyo technician,
and you're doing that for, like,
two pods.
But then eventually you have to
hire an account manager, and then
they help, and yada, yada, yada.
And that's typically how it all
goes.
It never happens that smooth or
cleanly.
You kind of just got to, like, go
over time and adapt, and you're
going to have some weird setups.
That's okay.
And ours is definitely not as
clean as this.
We have some shits that's, like,
over here.
We have some Klaviyo technicians
working in multiple pods.
We have an account manager over
here who also manages a client
over here.
It's never this perfect, but,
like, in general, this is what it
looks like.
So common pitfalls that beginners
make when they're building their
operations and planning things and
growing.
First thing is going to be
overpromising deliverables and
then can't fulfill, saying yes to
absolutely everything.
Daily campaigns, dozens of flows,
24-7 communication just to close a
client.
But then you can't actually do
that.
That's not going to be good
because then the client's just
going to leave, and it's going to
be super stressful for you and the
team.
It's going to lead to missed
deadlines, rush to working on
happy clients.
The solution, just make sure you
set realistic expectations up
front and surprise your clients
with overdelivery.
It's okay to push back a little
bit on some clients as you grow.
At the beginning, fucking take
what you can get.
Do what you've got to do to close
these clients.
Get a case study out of them.
Get a positive testimonial.
And then figure it out later.
But really, we need to be sure
that as we're growing, we need to
make sure we're super clear and we
have these boundaries.
Underestimating setup time.
So beginners think a full flow
rebuild can take just, like, one
week to create, like, 30, 40
emails.
But we have copy design.
We have client revisions that
they're going to leave comments
like, hey, change this, change
this.
You've got to make those
revisions.
And then uploading it and testing
it can take a minimum three to
four weeks.
And so try not to rush too much.
It'll lead to sloppy execution,
broken automations, and
everything.
So build in buffer time and use
SOPs to keep your projects on
track.
So just make sure you're tracking
everything and make sure you're
not trying to do way too much
right off the bat.
And use that kind of, like,
calendar that I gave you as
something to go off.
Poor client communication is the
most important thing.
You can't go quiet while working
hard behind the scenes.
It just makes them feel ignored.
And the client literally only sees
Slack.
You could be fucking working 24
hours a day in a fucking sweatshop
and bending over backwards,
calling Klaviyo, and doing all
this, like, crazy shit for them.
But if you don't tell them that,
they just see an empty Slack.
They just see an empty Slack chat.
So you need to be telling them
about this stuff that, like,
you're working on your stuff.
So that'll often lead to churn as
if you're not giving these clients
updates.
Because the clients assume nothing
is happening, and they'll start
looking for other agencies.
Make sure you do daily response
times under one hour, weekly
communication, and proactive
communication, even if the
progress is slow.
Make sure you're doing this.
No clear scope.
So lead to scope creep kind of
ties into the first one.
But without a defined scope of,
hey, we're just doing email
marketing.
We're just going to do your email
campaigns and your email flows.
This is how many we're going to be
doing roughly every month.
Then they're going to start asking
you for other stuff, and you end
up working double for the same
pay.
So make sure that your contracts
and your deliverables outline
clearly, like, hey, this goes up
to 12 email campaigns a month.
They're up to four flows a month.
And then enforce them politely but
firmly.
Often what I'll do is if a client
requests something, I'll be like,
yes, for sure, we can get this
taken care of this time.
But please note that, again, we
just do this service, or this is
just what we do.
And so that's something to do.
Then neglecting reporting and
results.
Some beginners just think that,
hey, we're sending these emails.
We're all good, without showing
the value in how much money that
you're making the client.
If they don't see the ROI, they
don't know how much money that
you're making them, they're going
to leave.
So provide clear monthly reports
and your weekly reports to tie
your actual work into revenue so
that they can justify the price.
And I want to end this by saying
just do not overthink it.
Most beginners stress about
systems, processes, and problems
that don't even exist.
They don't even exist for you yet.
They will, but don't worry about
them now.
Your number one priority is to
sign clients.
Nothing matters until revenue is
coming in.
Worry about the operation second.
You will naturally figure out
operations over time.
Sales is one thing that you don't
naturally figure out over time
because you have to put in so much
work to get these clients in the
door.
I started with absolutely no
knowledge on email marketing, and
I was advertising to everybody.
I'm an email marketing expert.
Come work with me.
I generate amazing results.
I'm an email marketing expert.
And then I just figure it the fuck
out later.
I sign, like, five clients.
Then it's like, fuck, what do I do
now?
It's so over.
How am I doing this?
And then you always figure it out.
And the operations just naturally,
you're forced to figure it the
fuck out.
And that's how everything that
I've shared with you just come
from me figuring it the fuck out.
Just focus on sales, and then
you'll figure it out later.
A simple-based system is good
enough to get started, and your
growth will just naturally expose
the weaknesses in your operations,
and then you can just pivot and
adjust.
When something breaks, just fix
it, update the system, and then
keep moving.
It's going to be a system of you
grow, grow, grow, grow, grow, and
then your operations kind of break
a little bit.
And then you kind of go down, and
then you kind of figure it out,
and then you grow, grow, grow,
grow, grow,
and then you meet another point
where you go down a little bit.
And you've got to figure it out
because some stuff breaks and
yada, yada, yada.
You need to make a new hire,
everything like that.
That's typically how it goes.
So just repeat this cycle.
It's an ongoing cycle.
I'm still going through this.
It's an ongoing cycle all
throughout business.
Find your system that works.
Scale it until it breaks.
Figure something new out.
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom,
boom.
And then your operations will
evolve alongside your client base.
So that's it for the operations
and everything, mindset,
everything, some base knowledge.
Let me know if you have any
questions.
And, yeah, let's get to the next
one.