The sales process.
Let's get some fucking money, huh?
Let's get some goddamn money.
All right, so you get somebody to
book a call with you.
Finally, you get these bastards
on the phone with you.
How do you get them to hand them
their credit card so that you
can swipe it and drain their whole
wallet?
No, I'm kidding.
Of course, we're not doing
that.
But how do we actually get people
to buy from us once we get them on
the phone?
The sales process.
This is so not complex, so
straightforward.
Do not get caught up in
all the sales tactics and all this
shit.
It is so simple.
And really, as long as you're
not mentally disabled, this should
be easy for you.
Sales, after you have your first
few
calls, you're going to be fine.
It's literally just a
conversation, just like, hey, what
do
you need?
What are you struggling with?
Oh, okay, you're struggling with
this?
Cool, I do
this.
I think I'll be able to help with
that.
Here's how I do it.
And then they're
like, okay, well, what about this?
And then you say, oh, yeah, yeah,
I can do that.
I'd
probably do this, this, this.
And then if they like what you
say, they'll be like, all right,
cool, what's the price?
And you drop the price.
That's it.
So let's get into
it.
Sales mindset.
Sales is not about tricking people
or doing crazy sales tactics.
It's not
the Jordan Belfort fucking, what
does he say?
That sound fair enough?
It's not that
shit.
No.
Sales is just made to be so
complicated when reality, you're
literally just having a
conversation with this person,
seeing if you get along together
and if they want to buy
from you.
Sales is literally just, does the
person like you?
Does the person think that
you will do a good job for them?
If someone likes you and they're
like, he'll do a good job
for me.
Then duh, they're going to go with
you.
That's literally all that sales
is.
So those are
the two things that you just need
to understand.
So how to get the person to like
you on a call.
Hopefully I do not need to teach
you this.
Just be personable, be funny, be
kind, transparent,
be honest, everything that you'd
expect.
How do you get people to like you
should be pretty
straightforward.
For me, I've always been like,
this is just my style.
Like if you see me, I'm very
like no bullshit.
I'm a little bit, I'm extroverted
on calls and people like feel
comfortable and I'm
also very transparent and honest.
I'll tell people exactly what it
is, exactly how the situation is
and I'll just get along with them
and match their energy and that's
just what works for me.
And I think I'm not a good, I
don't think I'm a good salesman at
all, but I've closed over 200
deals because I think people just
kind of like me and they like my
vibes and they can feel my passion
and my hunger.
And so a lot of them, especially
when starting out, like I still
have the same energy
when I'm coming in with no
experience and jumping on a phone
with somebody.
I'm like, fuck yeah,
no, that's sick.
I think we should do this.
I think we should do this
coming up with great ideas and
that's how you get people to like
you.
Just be personable,
be funny, make jokes, be kind, be
transparent, be honest.
Your vibes should be what gets
them
to like you.
And then you have to actually get
a person to believe that you will
do a good job
for them.
If I'm just a funny guy and I'm a
nice guy, but I don't have any
good ideas about email
marketing and this guy's like,
well, what the fuck can you do for
me?
Then I'm just going to walk away
with a friend and not a client.
Um, so how to get them to believe
that you can do a good job for
them.
One, give them good advice on the
call.
They're like, Hey, I'm struggling
with this.
Then you can say, what if you
tried this?
Give them a good idea.
And then if they're like, Oh yeah,
that's a good idea.
Then boom, they're going to
believe that you do a good job for
them.
So give
them good advice on a call.
What I like to do is have a really
well put together document on your
process and philosophies.
This document is going to do the
selling for you.
That literal document that I
showed you in the, in the
marketing video can literally just
do that.
And when somebody books a call
with
you'd be like, read this document,
read this document, read this
document, make the document
full of life, make it fun.
And then people will come to the
call being like, Oh, this guy's,
this guy knows his shit.
Um, and also he has some life to
them.
I like his style.
I literally have
had that document just sell people
like on the service just already.
They're like, damn, I like
this style.
This is funny.
This is, this is good.
It seems like he knows what he's
doing.
He he's,
he's getting the fuck after it.
And that will do a lot of the
selling for you.
I literally
have had multiple closes where
people almost every single call.
When I was using that document,
people were like, love that
document.
That that was great.
I read it.
I read all of it.
I was like,
hell yeah.
Um, and so put something really
good together like that.
Um, and then also respond fast
to these people over email and
messages to prove you're on top of
your shit.
Uh, this is an indicator
of you moving fast.
People want results fast.
They want shit to be done fast.
A lot of agencies and
freelancers out there, they take
forever to do stuff.
So if you are responding instantly
to all
their emails and text messages,
they're gonna be like, Oh, then
that's a sign to them that
subconsciously, like this guy
moves fast.
He's going to get our shit done
fast.
So that's what we want.
And then also clearly outline
exactly what you will do for them
and on what timeline.
That is how a person will believe
that you will actually get the
shit done in a certain amount
of time.
You need to show exactly what
you're doing on what timeline on
this day.
I'm going to do
this on this day.
I'm going to do this on this day.
I'm going to do this.
You need to lay
this out so clearly for the
prospect that they don't have any
questions about what you're going
to do for them.
One of the biggest problems I see
miss beginners make on sales is
they're like,
yeah, I'll do your email
marketing.
Yeah, we'll, we'll do this.
Uh, it'll take a, take a couple
months.
Um, no, you need to literally tell
them, okay, day one, I'm going to
do this day two.
I'm
going to do this day three.
I'm going to do this day four.
I'm going to do this.
Tell them literally
fucking everything.
Show them a calendar of like, once
you understand their situation,
you know what you want to do for
them.
Show them a calendar of the due
dates of every single thing
that you were going to do.
And that's how you approve to them
and get them to believe that,
oh, this guy's actually going to
get this stuff done for them, for
me.
Um, and then as long as
your philosophies are good, you
give them good advice, they like
your ideas, then they're going to
be
like, okay, well, I like his
ideas.
I trust that he's going to do good
work.
And then this is the work
he's doing.
I don't have any uncertainty and I
like this guy.
Let's do it.
That's exactly everything
that we need.
So now let's get into like the
actual process of the sales
process in terms of what's the
flow of somebody going from
interested in you to then booking
a call in or interested in you to
then
they paid and you have money in
your account and you can go buy
your first fucking Rolex or
something.
Um, so here's the flow.
The lead books a call with you.
You warm them up ahead of the
calls.
You have two calls, they get
closed and then onboarded.
This is how it looks.
Call booked via
Calendly.
Get a Calendly account.
It's just a way for you to have
people book in.
Um, it allows you to
send automated emails of
reminders.
It allows you to set up workflows.
Um, so ours right here is just
like
this.
If you can see it, boom, just like
this discovery call.
This call will be discussing
where you're at with your brand,
where you want to be.
And if you're right, if we're
right fit to get
you there, I have a quick doc
answering some FAQs.
And then this is just the
calendar.
And we asked
some questions just about the
brand and everything right here.
So somebody is going to book a
call
right here.
Oh my God.
Where the fuck did the document
go?
Why do I keep losing it?
There we go.
Um, that's so call book via
Calendly.
They get the call booked.
You want to have an automated
email
and send a document like I'd
showed you before of this.
I'm going to pull it up again.
Some sort of
document that goes over your
process.
Something like this, where I just
did a Google doc, just walking
through all of my philosophies,
exactly what I do.
Some of my case studies, how I
think about email
marketing, how it's supposed to
run, everything like that.
You want a document like this to,
to show some life and to prove
that you know what you're doing
and to warm this person up.
So it's
not like this dude's just like a
nobody.
And ideally have it be a video as
well.
Give them a document
and then give them the video as
well to show your face, show that
you're a real person and
everything
like that and outline your
process.
And then case studies, if you have
them say it is required to read
ahead of the call to make the best
use of the time on the call.
So in a follow-up email, um, after
somebody
books, make sure an automated
email gets sent to them and say
like, you need to check out this
video,
watch it, yada, yada, yada.
If somebody, if you book somebody
in manually, send them the
document in
the video and say, please watch
this ahead of time.
So you have an understanding of
our process and we
can make the best use of time on
the call.
We can just talk about you and
your situation.
So I can
build you a tailored plan, uh, for
how I might be able to help you.
So we have that super important.
Once I implemented this into my
process, my close rates
skyrocketed, super important.
Um, and then what we have here is
then
you have call one discovery.
I like to do two call close.
It's going to be very difficult to
close people
in one call.
Um, so just expect that it's
probably going to be two calls.
Um, and yeah, call one is
just discovery, um, 30 minute
meeting.
Some people do 15 minutes.
Some people do an hour, whatever
you
want.
I've set it at 30 minutes.
You just want to figure out their
pain.
I don't really like that idea
because I really don't think you
need to dig in like too deep to
pain.
Like everybody talks about that,
but figure out their pain.
What are they struggling with?
What are they looking for?
Lightly introduce your process and
get a second call booked to talk
through the strategy you would
employ for them.
Ideally get access to their email
platform to run
an audit if they have an account.
And so that's typically what we
do.
We'll have a call one,
figure out, okay, what's going on.
Can we actually help you?
If we can help you,
let's actually run an audit of
your account.
So we can tell you exactly what we
think we would do for
you.
And then we get a, we get the
access to their account in between
calls, run an audit of their
account.
You're fucking up with this.
I would
fix this by doing this, fix this
by doing this.
This is how much money I can make
you.
Then you
present that on the second call
and you really go over like the
set in stone pricing in the plan
and
what it looks like.
So call one should literally just
flow like, Hey, nice to meet you,
but have some
small talk.
And it's like, all right, why
don't you just tell me a little
bit about your
situation.
Um, and kind of, we'll take it
from there and then they'll start
talking like, okay,
we've had a brand since dah, dah,
dah, dah.
We've been doing this.
Um, and we're having a hard time
with this, uh, dah, dah, dah.
And then you're like, Oh, okay.
Um, so just on, so you're doing
this
and you're struggling with this.
Could you go a little bit, tell me
a little bit more about how
you're struggling with like your
email marketing flows?
Like, um, have you worked, are you
currently
working with someone?
What's that like?
And then they're going to be like,
Oh, well, we worked with
somebody, uh, like a year ago,
they set up our flows and you
know, they're just not performing
as well, um, as we want.
So that's why we're looking and
why I like book this call.
And they're
like, okay, perfect.
So like the main, main thing that
you're struggling with is like the
flows.
Um,
and you just kind of want the flow
set up.
Got it.
Um, so like what, so like, I'd be
curious to see
like exactly what you're looking
for in the flows, uh, compared to
what, like you don't have just so
I
can like be sure that like, you
know, and then you're just like
understanding like, okay, what is
this
person?
What, what don't they like and
what do they want?
That's all you're trying to find
out.
What do they want?
And once you kind of figure out
what they want and you have a full
understanding of
their process and the business and
kind of where they want to go,
then you're, then you just go
into, okay, got it.
Like, I think I understand kind of
everything that you're looking
for.
Um, and so
yeah, is there like anything else
you want to add or anything else
that like you feel would be
helpful for me to, to know and
then have them, have them tell
you.
Um, and then, and then if not,
then you'd be like, okay, perfect.
Well, based on everything you
said, like I definitely can help
as far as like flows and whatnot.
That's our bread and butter.
I'll send you a couple of case
studies
after this on like us, uh,
rebuilding flows for brands, but
kind of our best case studies are
with
brands in your situation right
here.
So we can definitely help you out
with the flows and do like a flow
rebuild or something like that.
Um, something that I think would
be super helpful if you're open to
it.
So I can create like a custom
tailored plan for you.
So if you're open to it, I'd love
to run a
review of your current flow
system.
Um, and kind of like give you then
like a tailored roadmap in
strategy of what I'd like to do
for you.
And then we could go over that on
a call, say like middle
of next week, if that's something
that you're open to.
And then they'll be like, yeah,
that'd be great.
And you're like, okay, perfect.
Awesome.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
So just add me to your
Klaviyo, add me to your email
marketing account, yada, yada,
yada, do this.
I'll review everything in
between calls.
And then they'll be like, okay,
great.
Um, what I like to do is also
briefly run
through the process as well on
this call, just so they're not
surprised on the follow-up call.
And then you can gauge like their,
um, gauge like how interested
there are, they are right now.
So
I'd be something like, yeah, so
for a flow rebuild, just to walk
you through like a little bit of
what,
what it is.
Um, so usually it's a 60 day
process.
And so in the first seven days,
what we're doing is
we're mapping out the strategy for
you and like figuring out exactly
what emails do we want to send?
Um,
what are the topics of each emails
and mapping them out across the
welcome flow, all the abandonments
post-purchase.
And then we're going to go over
that and share that strategy with
you.
That's usually the
first seven days.
That's what we call analyze.
We then move to the next phase
where it's actually
creating all these emails.
So we got to write these emails.
We got to design them.
Um, we got to send
them over to you for review.
Um, and then we got to upload them
into Klaviyo and get them, uh, get
them all set live and quality
checked.
And so that's usually the bulk of
this.
It's going to be
every single email we're sending
it to you.
Um, and usually this process is
going to take around
like 45 days for everything to be
all set up.
We're going to start with the
welcome flow,
the most important flow.
And we'll send that over to you by
day 14.
You'll receive a new flow every
couple of days.
Um, and then we'll make revisions
as you have them usually by day
45, day 50, we're all
set up and we're just finishing
getting emails uploaded into
Klaviyo.
And we kind of have an extra two
weeks there, uh, just in case some
flows are taking a little bit
longer.
And then also we can use this
time to set up some AB tests for
you.
And that's usually what the last
little push in this product
project is, is reviewing some of
the initial numbers and getting
some of those AB tests.
So that's typically like what the
process and timeline looks like.
As far as like that is,
are you clear on that?
Do you have any questions with
that?
And then they'd, if they have
questions,
simply answer the questions.
And then they're probably going to
ask, yeah, like what's the pricing
like?
Some people will be like, I'll
give, some people will tell you
like, Hey, don't, don't give the
price.
But dude, if someone asks a
question, like give them, give
them an answer.
I usually give them a range
though.
Uh, so if somebody is like, like,
yeah, like how much is this?
And then you'll say something
like, yeah, so for a two month, 60
day flow rebuild project, I'll be
able to give you an exact number
after I run a review on the
account.
Um, and like the exact strategy
that I want to use once I have a
sense of the workload, but
typically for a flow rebuild, it's
going to be anywhere from five to
$7,000.
And we can split that up into two
time payments as well.
Um, if, uh, if you prefer that
and then just, and then just drop
that.
And then they might be like, most
of the time they'll be
like, okay, sounds good.
Looking forward to what you have
to say.
And then boom, then after that
first call, follow up email, send
them a follow up email, just
recap, just same day as fast as
you
can after that call, just to prove
you're on top of your shit, send a
recap and confirm the second
call for a tailored proposal.
Make sure you get that on the
calendar.
On that first call,
be like, okay, does Wednesday 9am
work?
Get that call scheduled while
you're on that first call
so that they don't ghost you.
Um, and ideally get the access to
their Klaviyo account.
If they
don't have an account, that's
fine.
You can create a process or
strategy just based on like what
you
know.
Um, so send a follow up email, um,
and then call two, all it is, is
just you presenting the
strategy and then going, walking
through again, what the process
looks like.
So simply, Hey John,
great to see you again.
How are we doing?
Um, do anything over the weekend?
It's bullshit.
And
then, okay, perfect.
Well, thank you so much for
jumping back on.
Um, just want to, you know,
go over the strategy that I had
for you, but I just want to
confirm a couple of things just to
make
sure, um, that I understand
everything correctly.
Recap what you guys had talked
about last week,
be like that all kind of like,
everything's still the same for
you.
Was there anything else that came
up that you want to share?
They say no.
And then share your screen and go
over the strategy that
you put together and then go over
what the next 90 days look like
and be like, so the official
price is $6,000.
And then, and then just wait.
And then maybe they'll be like,
Oh, that's too
much.
Um, then you can be like, what
about it is too much.
Um, and then just talk through it
with
them.
It's just that simple.
Um, and then at the end of it,
just be like, okay, like, do you
want to
move forward?
Is this something you want to move
forward with?
And then they might say yes,
or I need to think about it,
whatever.
That's completely fine.
People are very rare to get
them to close directly on the
call.
I never push.
I'm just like, okay, no problem.
I'll shoot you a
follow-up email, um, with
everything that you need to know,
summarizing everything that we
talked
about with this Taylor proposal.
Um, just so you have it.
Um, as, as far as like making a
decision,
like when do you think that you'll
have a decision by?
And then they'll tell you when
they have a
decision.
Um, and then you can just follow
up on those days.
That's literally it.
That's the
process.
So as far as like call booking and
warmup, uh, you're going to be as
far as like the first
part of the process.
So booking the call, um, and
warming them up, you will be
judged on the
professionalism and smoothness,
smoothness of your call booking
process.
Um, so what we want to do is
just make it simple, have a
Calendly link, and then an auto
confirmation email.
You can set this up in
Calendly.
Just, just look it up.
Super easy.
Um, and then automated, like what
to expect doc,
which we had went over, uh, just
go over like who you are, case
studies, client wins, and then
your
process, what do we do?
So the goal is that when they show
up, they already believe you're
credible
and you run a legit business.
Um, so that's what we want to do.
And call one discovery.
I literally
already went over this.
I forgot I had these slides, but
this first call again, it's not
about closing.
You should want them to get the,
get to know where they're at and
where they want to go and then how
you could fit in.
Um, so figure out exactly what
they want.
And if you're fit, key questions,
what's got you interested in
upgrading email marketing?
What have you tried in the past
for email?
What's your goal in three to six
months?
Um, so this is what we do.
This is the process.
I already kind of went over this
and by booking the follow-up call,
do not leave it open-ended.
Always book that follow-up call on
that call.
Or if you pitch on that first
call,
ask, when are you making a
decision by?
Always try to get a second call
booked in the calendar.
Now between calls, this is where
you prep for your close, send a
short recap email right off the
bat
to prove that you give a shit
about them.
Run that Klaviyo audit, just a
simple slide deck,
um, on pain points they told you,
the audit highlights, like what
did you notice in their account
that you'd like to do better, your
strategy to fix it, and then a
roadmap.
What do you,
what do the 60, 90 day, what, what
do those 60, 90 days look like?
What are the things you're going
to do?
And in what order?
And in that confirm, present and
close.
Start by confirming.
Last time
you mentioned X, Y, Z are the big
problems, right?
Anything else you think is
relevant to share?
Perfect.
Maybe they talk a little bit about
stuff and then you ask a couple of
questions,
but then you just share your
screen, walk through your audit,
present your 90 day plan,
transition.
Does this sound like something
that you're looking for?
Like, is this exactly what
you're looking for?
And then they might say, I'm also
looking for this.
And then you can be like,
okay, cool.
Let's talk about it.
Or maybe they're like, most often
they're like, yeah, no, this is
perfect.
Thank you for putting this
together.
You just want to clear yes or no.
And then just drop the
price.
Okay, got it.
And so the investment for this is
$6,000.
Don't overthink it.
Just the investment is
$6,000.
Don't cower in the corner.
Just like, no, no, these people
have money.
You can always come
down on price if you need to.
But after that, just like drop the
price, $6,000.
And then just wait,
wait for them to respond.
And then they might be like, oh,
okay, got it.
Thank you for, thank you
for sharing.
It'll probably take me, I'll need
to think it over, talk to my
business partner.
And then
you can be like, yeah, yeah, no
problem.
Like overall, like, what are you
thinking?
Like, is
like, as far as like the process
price and everything, like kind of
where are you at?
And
then maybe they'll be like, and
then they'll tell you what their
objections are.
And then
you always want to ask, when do
you expect to make a decision?
When should I expect this?
Instead of follow up email
outlining the offer and follow up
every day until they close, which
means you, they sign the contract.
That means that they close.
After the close, they say,
let's do it.
So maybe on that call, they'll be
like, let's do it.
Let's work together.
And
then you will, then that is send
the invoice and contract
immediately.
And so that's what
officially does the close.
They might close over email.
They're like, sounds good.
Send
me the, send me the contract.
We decide we want to move forward.
And that's what you want
to do.
We want to send the invoice, the
contract.
I use PandaDoc.
You can have ChatGPT to make
you a contract.
Don't overcomplicate it.
You can ask some other people what
their contracts
are like.
And then once somebody does that,
they sign the contract, pay the
invoice, which
I use Stripe for.
Have a simple onboarding form.
Ask for brand info, assets, brand
story,
everything like that.
And then book a kickoff call to go
over that form and then start the
process.
And the goal is to make the
transition frictionless so that
they feel confident immediately.
Just like that.
Contract, then onboarding form to
get them going.
And common sales mistakes.
Here's what kills beginners in
sales.
Calls right off the bat.
Talking more than you listen.
Just like yapping.
Don't yap.
If you find yourself on a long
monologue,
shut the hell up.
Just listen and ask questions.
You just want to ask questions.
And then if they
have questions for you, then you
answer them.
But listen more than you talk.
Pitching before
you understand their problems.
You don't want to pitch too early.
You need to understand fully
what exactly their problems are
and summarize their problems in
one sentence before you go
to the pitch or anything.
It's like, okay, got it.
So like overall, you're working
with an agency,
but you're kind of not confident
that they're bringing you the best
results
because they're not sending quite
enough emails and the flows are
just not being optimized.
And
they're kind of just like set and
forget.
And then boom.
And then they're like, yeah,
that's it.
And they're like, okay, perfect.
So this is what we do.
Being vague on deliverables and
pricing.
Don't be vague on what you're
doing.
Tell them exactly what
the fuck they're getting.
Not asking for the close.
Not being like, once you drop the
price,
just letting them go.
Be like, so what do you think?
Do you want to move forward?
Get them to
answer that.
And then letting momentum die
between calls.
Do not go rogue in between calls.
Do not go
silent.
Send them a follow-up email and
send them even like a call, an
email, personal email leading
up to the next call as well, just
to prove that you give a shit and
carry that momentum and give them
value.
Sales mindset reminder, sales is
literally just solving problems.
If you do that better than
anyone else, you will win your
clients for life.
If you come up with the best
solutions to their
problems, you will get a sale.
Everybody has problems and they're
just looking at who has the
best solution for my problem.
If you come up with the best
solutions, you get the sale.
Confidence,
if you just have confidence in
yourself and you're clever, that's
way better than clever sales
tricks.
Just like you need to have that
dog in you to just like be like,
I'm that fucking guy.
Like you
have to genuinely think that you
will do better than anyone.
Cause like, that's one thing that
allowed me to succeed at the
beginning is I genuinely thought I
could do this better than
anyone.
I don't have as much experience,
but I'm going to figure it the
fuck out.
I'm going to be
in YouTube, in the YouTube
trenches, figuring this out.
I'm going to go balls to the wall
for this
client.
And so that, that confidence goes
and objections are opportunities
to clarify and push
the client closer to trusting you.
If the client asks you questions
or objections, it's not a bad
thing.
Your job is to lead them, not to
beg them and be like, please work
with me.
Just like,
this is our process is what we do.
I think you qualify for it.
Confident that we can help.
This is something that you want to
do.
If it's not like, let's talk
through it.
That's it.
You just got to have that dog in
you.
Just got to have that dog.
Shout out Connor for having this
when he was the sales coach for
client Ascension.
When I was in there, he showed
this graphic a lot
and you just got to have that dog
in you because clients will sense
it and they want dogs on their
team.
That is it.
Thank you so much for watching.
Hopefully that was helpful.
And don't overthink
sales.
Just have a conversation and bring
good solutions to the table.
Peace.