So what the fuck is e-commerce
email marketing?
That is what we are going over
today.
Apologies,
I don't have a fancy setup right
now.
I'm traveling.
I've been traveling Europe for the
past three months and I don't have
my regular setup so we are
recording on Loom here.
But that
doesn't matter because this
information is going to be
amazing.
So let's get into it.
So we're
assuming that you are a beginner
in terms of an email marketing
agency.
Maybe you've gotten
some stuff set up.
Maybe you've gotten a couple
clients or maybe you know
absolutely nothing.
But
I'm going to go over what
e-commerce email marketing is
because Fazio and the guys have
asked me to share
what I've done because I went
through client ascension, their
program, and I learned a lot
from them.
And I came in to them at around
10k-ish a month a couple years
ago.
And now I'll talk about
on the next slide, but we do
$300,000 a month now at my agency.
So my name is Max.
I am 22 years old.
I started all of this not knowing
anything as a freshman, 19 years
old in college.
Now I'm 22.
So it was about three years ago
today where I really started
taking this serious.
I went to the
University of San Diego and I
graduated two, three months ago,
May 28th or something.
And I'm making
this in late August.
And so I graduated, stayed through
school.
I graduated at around 250k a month
in revenue in my company.
And now I'm just traveling Europe
and trying to figure out what the
hell I want
to do now and where I want to go.
So there's that.
So we do email and SMS, $300,000 a
month in revenue.
So that was just under two years
ago.
So we've grown a lot.
And so here's like me, like for
example, I was doing this all
through college.
So here's like here, here's me
with some of my boys and then me
traveling.
I studied abroad as well.
So I did this all while studying
abroad too in Prague.
And then this was July $309,000 in
revenue on Stripe.
So let's get into it.
Obviously like this is something
that can work because I've done
it.
And now let's get into what this
all is.
And so why do brands need email
marketing?
Sounds stupid.
I don't know if you have ever
bought from an email, but I don't
think I ever have.
But people do buy from emails.
And it is a main traffic channel.
Why do brands need email
marketing?
It's cheap as hell.
And it costs dollars to get a paid
ad lead, but it costs pennies to
send emails.
Brands pay literally tens of
thousands of dollars, hundreds of
thousands, millions of dollars,
depending on the brand every
single month to drive traffic to
their website just for these
website viewers to leave.
They're spending all this money on
ads.
They're spending a shit ton.
A brand is doing like $100,000 a
month.
They might be spending like
$30,000 a month on ads.
That's a fuck ton.
But just for these site viewers to
leave.
Because if somebody clicks on an
ad, they go to your website, and
then they don't buy, then you're
fucked.
You don't have anything.
But what an email allows you to do
is capture this expensive paid ad
traffic.
Somebody clicks on your ad.
Now, instead of somebody just like
leaving, and it's just like,
adios, we can at least get their
email address by having a really
good pop-up form.
And then we can send them emails
to make that first sale without
having to spend more on that paid
ad traffic, because email
literally costs pennies.
Because there's the rule of seven
in marketing.
People need to see your brand
seven times before they actually
trust you enough to buy.
You could pay a shit ton on ads to
get somebody to see you seven
times, or what if you have
somebody see an ad once, and then
they see your email six times, and
then they know you enough to
trust.
And then maybe they buy from an
ad, but the email is what built up
the trust.
And as a retention tool, email is
the best method.
Everybody checks their email.
Even just a brand being in the
inbox, they're reminded.
And if you're in the face of
someone three to four times a week
on email, specifically in their
inbox, which 90% of U.S.
users check regularly, you're just
guaranteed to stay top of mind.
And you will not be forgotten.
You get sales on autopilot.
Cheap traffic, you stay top of
mind.
And top brands are pulling 40% to
60% of their total revenue from
email and SMS.
So here are just like a couple
quick examples here.
It's like a brand, for example,
41% of their 15 million came from
email.
And you can see here how much
revenue we do every month.
You can see the blue is attributed
email revenue.
And this is in Klaviyo, the email
sending platform that we use.
And so attributed revenue, like
for this month, 815K.
This was last month.
And unattributed revenue, 1.12.
So they did about 2 mil, and 815K
of that was from email.
Then here's another example.
This was one of my first case
studies, where a few months into
them,
we were doing 47% of their total
revenue coming from the email and
SMS, just from the email channel.
Just email.
Boom.
Right here.
So it's possible.
And so obviously if you can
generate $326,000 a month for a
brand, they'd be down to pay you
$3,000 a month.
And so that's why this model works
so well.
And so we have an e-commerce email
marketing agency.
That is our model.
We run emails for brands.
Because every brand needs email if
they want to be profitable in
today's day and age.
You could get away with not having
email in the past, where ads were
a lot cheaper, but today ads are
just so expensive.
We need an email to make us to be
able to recoup some of that
profit.
And you can check Mild.com for
examples.
It's just like a huge platform of
all the emails that a brand may
send.
Maybe you've seen like Dr.
Squatch.
They are a very fast-growing
brand.
You can see these are all the
emails that they send.
August 24th, 23rd, 22nd, 19th,
14th, 13th, 12th.
Like they send a lot of emails.
And this is the sort of stuff that
they're sending.
we will be making for brands.
So you have all these brands.
You can look up any brand you
want.
Like Patagonia right here.
You can look at all of Patagonia's
emails and how often they're
sending.
They're sending a daily, pretty
much a daily email.
And so you can see everything that
they're featuring here.
So that can give you a sense of
what we're doing.
This is why we run email marketing
for brands.
So pricing structure, like
typically what we do is you do
$2,000 to $5,000 a month
retainers.
And typically you're going to be
sending or creating 10 to 20
emails per month.
Early on, ideally the more you can
do the better because that's how
you can leverage yourself
against the big agencies or the
bigger teams like myself.
I have to set these limits on like
we're going to do 16 emails a
month for you
and we can't go over just because
I need to be predictable.
But when I was starting, we're
doing 30, 40 emails a month if we
have to
to keep these clients and have
them and just leveraging that.
And as far as team structure, so
we have like how a typical email
marketing agency will operate
is you have an account managers
and strategists.
These are the people who are
building the calendars, the
strategy,
and they're directing the team
behind the scenes.
You have a copywriter, somebody
who writes your emails, all the
text on the emails,
and then you have the designer
who's putting the pretty designs,
putting in the brand assets and
everything there.
So that's typically what we're
looking at right here for how it's
used.
So that's like a very broad
overview of the email of what an
email agency is.
Now email sending platforms.
So these are platforms that
e-commerce brands have set up that
are connected to their store.
And on these platforms, you're
able to create sign-up forms, hold
your list,
create automations, and send
emails for brands.
It'll house everything for you.
And so the main platforms are
going to be Klaviyo, which is best
option,
and then OmniSend is coming up
right now.
Good option for brands on a
budget, but most often you are
going to be using Klaviyo.
Again, it's just going to hold.
It's where you can set up pop-up
forms, set up automations where,
like,
if somebody abandons a cart,
Klaviyo will recognize that,
and then you can set up an email
that'll send to those people who
abandon a cart
and then, like, hey, finish your
order, that sort of stuff.
And then it allows you to track
how much revenue your emails are
making.
You could send emails from Gmail,
but you're not going to be able to
send to that many people,
and you're not going to be able to
track your sales.
So that's why we use these
platforms.
And so every brand is going to
have one of these platforms that
they use,
and Klaviyo is the most used one.
So that's the email-sending
platforms.
Now the last thing I want to touch
on is just the different aspects
of email marketing
because there are three different
parts of email marketing.
We have your list growth, your
pop-up forms.
So pretty self-explanatory,
growing your list.
If you want to see a ton of
examples, here's just, like, Alia.
These are, like, the sort of
pop-ups that brands can set up.
You can do this inside of Klaviyo
or in a platform like Alia where
it's, like,
hey, here's a discount.
Give us your email, something like
that.
And you can get fancy by asking a
question and then asking for their
email address.
But this is what we are doing, and
this is super important to nail
your pop-up form
because this is how you grow the
list.
And then you have your campaigns.
So I like to think of this as
casting a wide net.
It's an email blast just sent to
people that you have their email.
And so that's what a campaign is.
Typically, we're sending two to
four of these campaigns per week.
You can see these big brands
sending these campaigns, like,
almost every day.
But really, until you're doing
over a mil a month, until a brand
is doing over a mil a month,
you really don't need to be
sending every day.
We want to be sending usually,
like, three times per week is a
good sweet spot.
And this is where you're sending
things like back in stock, sale
emails, new product releases.
And then you have, like, the
educational emails, which is
mostly what you want to be doing.
Just, like, reminding of your
brand and things like that, like
this example.
What to bring, Camp Kitchen
Edition.
We made it easy to get out the
door with our packing checklist.
And so stuff like this, where you
don't always need to – you don't
need to be sending only discounts
to make sales.
You can do stuff like this and
just remind of your product.
So those are the campaigns.
And then we have our flows, which
are, for me, I think of, like,
campaigns casting a wide net.
And then flows is, like, super
targeted.
You're targeting specific people
at a certain point in their
journey.
So automated emails will fire when
a customer does a specific action.
So we're going to be going over
all these core flows and whatnot
and what these core flows are.
But an example is, like, the
welcome flow.
So we're going to send somebody a
sequence of emails when they give
us their email address right here.
So we're going to send them an
email being, like, hey, here's
your discount code.
Here's a little bit of information
about our brand.
Here's our best sellers.
So we'll set up a couple emails
being, like, hey, your discount's
about to expire, things like that.
That's a welcome flow.
And you have, like, our
abandonment flows.
So there are different abandonment
flows.
So if somebody abandons a cart,
they add an item to their cart,
but then they leave.
We want a couple of emails in
place being, like, hey, get your
cart back.
Or overcoming objections, anything
like that.
You've abandoned checkout.
Somebody goes a step further, they
go to checkout, and then they
leave.
We have browse abandoned.
Somebody views a product.
They don't add it to cart or
anything.
They just click on the product
page, and then they leave.
We have a couple emails in place
being, like, hey, did you like
this?
What can we do to help?
Things like that.
Then you have, like,
post-purchase.
So right after somebody purchases,
what emails do we send them?
To try to get them to come back.
So those are the different flows,
and that's what we're setting up.
So this is literally all that
we're doing for email marketing.
We're setting up these pop-up
forms, and then ideally
optimizing, testing these.
We're sending consistent
campaigns, which when you're
working with brands, it's going to
be
the bulk of it.
It's sending these consistent
email campaigns over time, like
three times per week.
And then you're setting up these
automated flows, which you set up
once, and then they're
going to continue to fire.
And then obviously, ideally,
you're optimizing these flows over
time.
So that is what email marketing
is, and that is kind of just like
a brief overview of what
an email marketing agency is, why
you need it, and everything there.
So hopefully that was helpful.
Let's get into the next video.