All right, for this video series,
I'm going to talk about RY
calculators.
So, over the next few videos, I'm
going to show you a comprehensive
guide on how to build
them from scratch with a live
Watho example.
So, in this GammaDoc, you're going
to see four main components.
The first one is what is an RY
calculator and why you need it on
your VSL.
And the second thing is you have
to understand the logic of an RY
calculator, first using
Google Sheets.
And then, once you understand the
logic, you're going to use Claude
to build certain prompts.
I'm going to show you the basics
of prompt engineering using a
method that I use every day.
And then, only then, are we going
to deploy this as a tool, as a
"marketing tool"
that you can use on your VSL.
So, without further ado, or any
other French words, I'll get
straight into the first part of
it.
All right, section one, what is an
RY calculator?
Why do you need it on your VSL?
RY calculators are just tools that
shows the prospect exactly how
much money they'll make,
or save by working with you.
It's not just a calculator.
It is actually a sales weapon that
does the convincing part for you.
People buy when they see clear
financial benefit and not just the
impressive features that your
service offers.
And the next logical question is,
do traditional sales methods fall
short?
The answer is yes or no.
Let me explain.
Your prospects simply cannot
visualize the value.
Okay?
And the common mistakes that
usually occur are, you end up
being vague on these sales calls.
Talk about,
"Oh, we'll increase your
efficiency instead of actually
quantifying it."
And you'll say, "Hey, we'll save
you time."
It's not measurable in your
prospect's head.
And leading with testimonials.
Sure, this is good.
But then it is not personalized
enough for the prospects to give a
crap about you just yet.
So this is where
this is when the prospects usually
tell you, "Hey, honestly, let me
think about it or some variation
of it."
And then they'll go shoot, right?
Then the next thing is going to be
the VSL framework that Daniel's
teaching you right now.
According to that framework, the
third component is the ROI
calculator.
This creates that mate desire
within your prospect to work with
you and also puts a sense of
urgency in them.
So in this series, you're going to
learn how to build these
calculators even if you've never
used AI before.
Okay, spoiler alert.
We're going to use AI to build
this.
And the next thing is we're going
to go over three proven calculator
templates for different business
models.
And then you're going to learn how
to embed them anywhere.
You know, it could be a website.
It could be a presentation.
It could be emails anywhere.
And then the last thing is I'm
going to teach you advanced
prompting techniques using a
method
that I will explain in a later
video to build exactly what you
need.
And by the end of this video
series, you'll have your own ROI
calculator that does the heavy
lifting
in your sales process.
There's no more hoping that the
prospects just get it magically.
They'll actually see the potential
ROI in quantifiable numbers.
That is very important.
Okay.