All right.
Section two.
So in this section, I'm going to
help you understand the logic
of an ROI calculator first with
Google Sheets.
You know, see, all calculators are
just numbers
plugged into a formula.
If you don't even understand the
math, then the tool is useless.
I'm not going to share my screen,
but that Google Sheet, so you can
clearly understand the math
behind this process.
Also, don't ask me to share editor
access with you.
Just make a copy of it
and see for yourself.
Do not ask me editor access.
All right.
Now that you can see my Google
Sheet,
the first thing that we're going
to look at is if you're running
paid ads as a service and
specifically the VSL, the book
call fund.
Let me explain all the inputs and
all the calculated
outputs that we are showing that
we are going to show on this ROI
calculator.
So the first one
is you've input the following.
You ask the user to input ad
spend, the CPM and the CTR.
Based off of
this, you're going to get the
total impressions, which is ad
spend by CPM times thousand.
You're going to
get the unique clicks, which is
CTR, this one times the total
impressions and the cost work
click, which is
ad spend by this value.
Once we get all that, we're going
to input as the user to input the
unique
page visits, the total
applications and the total cost.
Based off that, we can calculate
these four
variables.
The application rate, which is the
total number of applications
divided by the unique page
visits.
The cost per application, which is
the total ad spend, this one by
the total number of applications.
And the booked call rate is the
number of calls booked divided by
the unique page visits.
And then you get your
cost per booked call, which is the
total ad spend by the total calls
booked.
After that, you now get total live
calls.
How many people are actually
showing up?
How many
deals did you close?
What is the average sale price?
Based off this, we get show rate.
We get the cost per live call.
We get the close rate, the total
revenue and the ROAS.
The formula for all of them are
explicitly mentioned here.
So only once you do this for your
own business model, would you even
get an understanding as to what
prompt to even give Claude.
Now let's look at cold email lead
generation.
So for cold email lead generation,
let's say you are running a $500
per month tech fee plus $300,
which is the cost per call.
That is the $300 that you're
charging the client when the call
actually happens.
So to select the tech fee package,
let's say you have 50,000 emails
per month, which is at $500,000,
100,000 emails a month, which is
at $1,000, and 200,000 emails a
month, which is at $2,000.
So you have to have the cost per
month, which is at $500,000.
So you have to make that a drop
down.
You have to get the logic of this
right.
And input the number of emails
that you send per contact.
And then you're going to ask the
user to input the cost per call.
And then you would be inputting
this here because you set the cost
per call before half another sales
call.
Then we're creating reply rate
sliders and pasta reply rate
sliders.
For the sake of this example, I've
used these inputs.
Based off of this, the total
people contacted per month is
$25,000.
How do we come up with this?
This is equal to the total emails
per month divided by the emails
sent per contact.
So $50,000 divided by T, which is
$25,000.
The second thing is the total
number of people that have
replied.
This is 2% times this, which is
500.
And the total number of pasta
replies, you would actually get
this as 12.5% of 500, which is
$62.5, but you need to round it
down.
So you need to use the floor
function here on Google Sheets.
And then the next step is the
conversion part of it.
How many calls were booked from
the pasta replies?
25% of them.
So out of these 62 pasta replies,
you book a fourth of them.
So you end up getting 15 booked
calls.
This is the rounded down number of
the total pasta replies times the
call booking rate.
And then what is the close rate?
The close rate is 25%.
So this is the rounded down number
of the total calls booked times
the close rate.
And what is the average sale
price?
Based on the average sale price,
you can then generate net new
monthly revenue generated, which
is going to be $30,000,
which is equal to the total number
of clients closed times the
average sale price.
And based off of this, Zoom
calculate, what you pay the
agency, what they pay you with
that month,
which is equal to the tech fee
cost, plus the number of calls
booked times the cost per call.
So that is going to be $500,000
plus 15 times $300,000, which is
$4,500.
Add that $500,000, you get $5,000.
And then you're going to show them
the customer acquisition costs.
So they just paid you $5,000.
You got them three clients.
Their CAC, customer acquisition
cost is $1,667, US.
And the return on their investment
is they just put in $5,000 and
they're getting $30,000 out of it.
$6,000 right there.
That is how you explain the math
to them.
So let's go to the next one, which
is going to be the LinkedIn
outbound.
Let's say you're running lead gen,
but purely through LinkedIn.
So this is where you would talk
about how many market qualified
leads that are going to be
contacted.
800.
What is the connection acceptance
rate?
60%.
So based off this, you're going to
get total connections accepted.
And then what is the reply rate?
So once these people accept a
connection, automatically you send
them a message.
So 40% of those people reply to
you.
So you get 192 total replies.
F7 times C&I.
And the positive reply rate,
usually for LinkedIn campaigns, is
high because you are reaching out
to a personalized set of very few
people.
So I'd like cold email.
So your positive reply rate would
end up being 40%.
If it ends up being 40%, the
number of total positive replies
you get is 40% of this number,
which is 76 right there.
And out of these positive replies,
76 of them, you are now booking
40% of them on the calls.
So you've now successfully booked
30 calls.
This is total positive reply,
stats call booking rate.
Great.
And now based on the close rate,
20%, you've closed this person six
new deals.
And here you can now show this
person what is the customer
acquisition cost.
And here we're making an
assumption that you charge these
people a flat retainer of $2,500 a
month.
So if they pay you $2,500 a month
and you get them six clients, the
customer acquisition cost is
$2,500 by six.
The net no monthly revenue that's
added is $30,000.
And what is the ROI?
How would you calculate with the
ROI?
That is the $30,000 divided by the
money that they pay you, which is
12X right here.
So this is how you understand the
logic, understand the math behind
the whole thing.
I'll see you on the next one.