All right section three prompt
engineering 101 with claude all
right so now that we have the
logic down the next step is to
actually build the roi calculators
but before jumping straight
onto the tool you need to
understand how to give high
quality inputs your outputs
directly correlate
on how good your inputs are if
your inputs are shit then your
outputs will be dog shit
i'll say it again if your inputs
are shit your outputs will be dog
shit say that four times
this is going to build your
foundational understanding of what
inputs to give the system
and why are we using claude a
because claude is superior to chat
gpt yes i said it and claude is
an ai assistant designed to answer
questions generating text write
code analyze documents
and help with business tasks it's
a large language model built by
anthropic this is the link for it
why are we using claude the tool
we're going to use to build the
roi calculator is inside a large
language model itself so what's
the best way to give a prompt to
an ai make another ai right right
and to build a killer prompt for a
large language model you need five
components to it and we're
going to use claude to generate
those five components properly for
us and i'm going to show you all
of
them absolutely i call it the
escape method okay refer to this
claude artifact for more details
so the
escape method is s-c-a-p-e you
provide situation and context as
your first few lines and the
second few
lines you're going to give it the
components and the structure and
then the third one is going to be
through
actionable requirements and then p
is going to be the prevention and
edge cases edge cases literally
mean it's a it's a very
very extreme scenario something
that may happen and you want to
make sure that your calculator
is built to handle that and then
experience and polish i'm now
going to explain using the
artifact
link above on how to build a
really good prompt all right this
is the ultimate guide to ki prompt
engineering for the code
generation this is going to build
you exactly what you want and i'm
going to show
you the escape method because the
rest of the stuff you can read it
on your own time all right so
first
thing you have to understand is ai
is literal it is sequential and is
pattern matching you have to
understand these three components
core principles and then instead
of just saying build a calculator
for my
business we are going to explain
the why using the five-step
framework called s-ne-a-p escape
situation
and context is first set the scene
explain the context so this is the
context that we are giving for the
vsl the book call phone next thing
is components structure what is it
break down the complex request
into logical components why you
prevent the ai from making
assumptions on how things should
be organized
this is very important for the
cold email the one where we have
500 tech fee free and a cost per
call
you're saying create a clean
professional two-step calculator
with a modern card-based layout
include
a prominent header titled this
with the subtitle that design the
interface to work seamlessly on
both
desktop and mobile devices so that
it can be seen phone it can be
seen anywhere actual requirements
you give specific and measurable
requirements that leave no room
for interpretation because the ai
loves to
interpret if it has missing gaps
so what we're going to do here is
we're going to say hey use react
hooks
including blah blah blah and this
is something we asked claude to
generate for us and now let's look
at the prevention and edge cases
like i said before this is the
extreme scenario remember in the
cold email
ry calculator that has a 500 tech
fee and a 300 cost per call in
that specific example i told you
to create
drop downs the drop down
specifically states that and i
also said for the reply percentage
use 0.05
0.5 to five percent because no one
ideally speaking would have more
than a five percent reply rate
five percent is massive by the way
and
that is exactly why you know you
can't have percentages over a
hundred or unrealistic values make
sure that
none of the inputs you know you
prevent putting a negative number
in there you can't contact
negative 36 000 people in a month
right that just just simply
doesn't make sense and now this is
the
experience in polish now you're
going to provide details that
transform the function of code
into a
professional application so
something like add a smooth hover
and focus states on all
interactive elements
and through the summary dashboard
at the bottom showing key metrics
total investment total revenue
generated net profit all that
stuff
so the few techniques that we use
here the first one was like an
assumption elimination method
instead of saying make it look
professional we say apply a modern
aesthetic using blah blah blah
and the second technique is we're
clearly giving the formulas if you
take a look at the google sheet
on the right side i put the
formula for everything the
transparency of the formula leaves
zero room for
the ai to interpret anything else
and the third thing is the
realistic default strategy so
empty calculators
simply don't demonstrate any value
so so you need to have
pre-populate all the fields with
realistic
default values that demonstrate a
successful ad campaign successful
linkedin outbound campaign
successful
cold email campaign allowing users
to immediately understand the
calculator's functionality
and then the next one is just edge
case prevention you have to
understand the technical uh edge
cases ux
edge cases business logic edge
cases this is the only thing i
would ask you to focus on what
conversion rates are
actually realistic you know
someone can't have a cpm of two
dollars or someone can't have a
reply rate of 99
percent right it's not realistic
and the next thing the fifth
technique is the incremental
specificity pattern
overall application you you know
you have to start broad and then
start getting increasingly
specific
exactly like how a funnel works so
now let's look at the technique we
used for each calculator
so for the ad performance we're
saying this is the input and then
we're saying all right this step
should
immediately calculate and display
the total impressions i've given
the actual input elements and the
actual
outputs that i need for that step
now let's look at for the cold
email i'm not saying all right
create a
drop down menu select the tech fee
package like i said 500 per month
is for 50 000 emails
a thousand per month is for 100
000 emails to for 200 000 emails
per month you pay 2 000 a month
you see what i mean now let's move
to the linkedin calculator over
here i say for the reply rate
between 20 to 60 percent and
defaulted at 40 percent and the
positive reply rate same 20 to 60
percent
defaulted at 40 percent
representing genuinely interested
responses versus polite rejections
etc
and once all of this is done you
now have a really good prompt and
in the next video i'm actually
going
to show you the exact prompt as a
pasted text that i got from claude
that i inputted to versell
i'll see you guys in the next
video thank you