All right, fourth and final video
of this series.
So in this video, I'm going to
show you how I went and built the
exact prompts using Claude.
I'm just going to run you through
the outputs.
And then I'm going to explain why
Vercel is the superior model to
build these ROI calculators.
And then I'm going to throw in a
little bonus at the end.
All right, let's get into it.
All right, the way that you build
these prompts is you actually tell
Claude,
hey, this is exactly how I
inputted it onto the Google Sheet.
And attach a screenshot of the
Google Sheet to Claude so it can
come up with the logic
and understand it visually as
well, apart from just throwing a
bunch of formula at it, right?
So now we're going to take a look
at the VSL to book a call funnel.
I'm going to highlight it with my
cursor so that you guys see it
because this is not visible.
I don't know why it's doing this.
So first one, let's take a look at
this.
Build a comprehensive VSL to book
a call funnel.
And it's giving the overall layout
requirements.
Create a clean professional
interface.
Three distinct sections
representing the three steps of
the funnel.
And then step one.
And this should automatically
calculate that.
Now step two.
This step should automatically
calculate this.
If you look at this, it's exactly
the same thing that we did from
the Google Sheet.
I'm just doing the exact same
thing here.
Step three is the revenue
analysis.
We put this information and then
we should and it should say, all
right, calculate this immediately.
And then we provide the technical
requirements so that AI does not
make its own assumptions.
We don't want the AI to make those
assumptions.
And then step four is the visual
design requirement.
Use a modern card-based design
with subtle shadows, all that.
And then the last one is
additional features.
If you take a look at this second
prompt as well, it starts with S,
situation and context.
Comprehensive ROI calculator as a
React component using modern
tailwind CSS styling.
This tool helps businesses
evaluate the economics of
partnering with a B-generation
agency for B2B cold email
marketing campaigns.
Great.
Overall application and structure.
And then provide step one.
Give the input elements.
And then provide the calculated
display fields.
Do you see that given that we
explicitly said on that Google
Sheet, it has to be the floor
function.
Now it's saying rounded down using
math.floor.
This is very important.
And now step two.
These are your inputs.
And then this should immediately
calculate the following outputs.
And now we're going to talk about
the advanced interactive features.
Now we're going to go down to the
technical implementation
requirements.
And then you see the visual
specifications, UX, enhancements,
et cetera.
And finally, we're going to talk
about the formula transparency
because in this case, we want to
make sure that the formula is
transparent and the AI does not
make assumptions.
Because the AI is literal and it
will try to interpret it in a
certain way.
You don't want that happening.
You want to be the one in control.
So that's why your input has to be
really, really, really good.
And what did I say?
If your inputs are shit, your
outputs are dog shit.
And I'll say that again.
Prop three.
LinkedIn lead generation ROI
tabulator.
Boom.
Situation and context.
Right there.
In our application and structure,
it talks about the input section
that talks about this.
And then we have the calculated
output section, which talks about
this.
And then we have the advanced
interactive elements and features,
implementation specifications.
After that, we have the visual
requirements, UX requirements, and
then the mobile responsiveness
just to make sure that it is, you
know, good to be used on a cell
phone as well.
And then formula transparency and
education, and you are giving it
error handling, et cetera, because
you want to explicitly specify
those things.
So just copy the entire prompt for
the calculator you want to build.
Face it directly onto v0.apps
input field, submit, and let the
AI generate your calculator.
It's literally that simple.
And I'm going to show you exactly
that in the second part of this
video.
All right, what is Vercel?
It's a cloud platform that makes
it really easy to deploy and host
web applications.
It's Vercel, V-E-R-C-E-L.com.
And the tool that we'll be using
to build this is called v0.app.
And there's the link to that right
there.
V0.app is an LLM that helps you
build interactive websites,
landing pages, sales assets, et
cetera.
And in our case, we're going to
use v0.app to build actual ROI
calculators.
There are like a couple of other
tools in the market that you can
use to build this ROI calculator.
So one's called Lovable.
You guys are probably familiar
with it.
Probably not, but that's fine.
And the other one is called Bolt.
Lovable and Bolt are both
AI-assisted coding environments
that help you make this web
application.
But the process of hosting them
and deploying them is like a
little bit more complex than that
of Vercel.
So due to the simplicity, we're
going to use that to build the
calculators.
Now we're going to take a look at
the chat window on v0.app to
fundamentally understand this
building process.
To build these calculators, you
simply have to take the prompt
that Claude built for you and
pastes it on Vercel.
Let's look at it.
All right.
Now we are on v0.app.
All I said, now build me this ROI
calculator from the pasted text
and just pasted the text.
This is the calculator that I got.
Boom.
Email marketing, ROI calculator.
Step one, not read setup, response
rates.
You see that?
The drop down.
You can choose your options.
For the sake of this example, let
me choose these many.
And let's do 350 for call.
And also, let's do a 2.1% reply
rate and a 12.4% or a 12% pasted
reply rate.
So these are the total number of
people that replied.
And it's explaining how you got
that number and the total number
of positive replies right here.
Round it down.
And this talks about the sales,
conversion, and the ROI part of
it.
Let's say your call booking rate
is 29%.
And your close rate is only 21%.
So for 36 calls booked, you are
closing seven clients.
That is $70,000 in net new monthly
revenue generated.
And what we pay the agency that
month is a $1,000 tech fee plus 36
calls times 350.
And your customer acquisition
costs is right there.
And now we have an ROI summary,
which is monthly investment is
$13,600.
Your revenue is $70,000.
Your ROI percentage is this much,
which is excellent.
So it's about five, right?
Which is great.
All I did, now build me this ROI
calculator from the pasted text,
and I literally pasted the text.
If I show you the pasted text,
it's the exact same thing.
All 76 lines of it.
Great.
And that's exactly how you use
v0.app to complete your own ROI
calculator notes.
Now, I want you to take a look at
the VSL, the book a call fund.
Do you see this right here?
I just pasted the text right here.
Build a comprehensive, this thing.
And it's got 76 lines.
Again, boom.
And now what it did, it built it.
And it says, step one, add
performance and tracking.
Now, let's just drop the CPM to
110.
And let's increase the CTR to 1.6.
And now let's up the page visits
to like 1,900.
And the total applications to like
550.
You know, you mess around with the
numbers.
All these things are going to
change.
But let's say the calls dropped to
120.
So now it talks about what are
your total repressions?
What are the unique clicks?
What's the cost per click?
What is your application rate?
In percentage, what is your cost
per application?
What is your book call rate?
And what is your cost per book
call?
And now you have 100 live calls,
25 closed deals, and ASP of 5,000.
Say your show rate is now this.
Your cost per live call is now
this.
Your close rate is now this.
With this, you've generated total
revenue of $125,000.
And your return on ad spend, which
it's showing here, is total
revenue by ad spend, which is 125K
divided by 20K.
And this is the profit that you
make.
This is how you visualize the
funnel.
So many impressions, so many
clicks, so many applications,
calls booked, live calls, phone
CS.
And these are the key metric
summary that it's added to the
bottom.
Total ad spend, total revenue,
ROAS, profit margin.
Well, now we have it.
And the last thing I'm going to
show you is the LinkedIn ROI
calculator.
All right, for the LinkedIn lead
generation calculator, all I said
was, I have now pasted some text.
And based on this text, you're
going to follow the instructions
and build an ROI calculator for
LinkedIn regeneration.
Thank you.
And it went ahead and built this
entire thing for me.
And now you can see step one,
which is the input.
And step two, which is the sales
and conversions.
So, based on the M2Ls contacted
and the agency fee, with the
connection acceptance rate, reply
rate, all of that, it's
calculating this.
480 connections accepted, 192
people replied.
Out of that, 77 were positive
advice.
And based on a call booking rate
of 40% and a close rate of 20%,
you now have 31 calls booked, six
clients closed, 30K in new monthly
revenue generated.
And now your customer acquisition
cost is this much.
Now you have an ROI summary right
here.
It says your investment, your
revenue, your net profit, and your
ROI percentage.
It's literally that simple.
Best of luck.
Okay.