Okay, so this is a simplified way
of doing an ROI calculator,
just using Claude without any kind
of like super complex stuff.
This is like a quick and dirty,
like make one real quick
and all the prompts and everything
in here.
I'm just going to throw in the
description so you can read it.
But basically just said, I want to
make an interactive ROI calculator
for my prospects
and be sharing the calculator on
my video sales letter and sales
calls
purpose of it to show what results
in terms of money are possible to
achieve working with me.
This is my service.
I do a VSL call funnel for these
people.
Here's the things I want to
consider.
Normal coaching pricing is
between, you can read it in the
description.
But then it came back and said, it
needed some clarifying questions
because I said, if there's
anything else you're unsure about
before you make the ROI calculator
in order to make it correctly,
please ask me how.
So it asked me a bunch of
questions, yada, yada.
And then what I did is I just
answered the questions.
So just one by one, I answered the
questions.
And then it created an ROI
calculator.
Okay, cool.
So now I started going through
this and like this was defaulted
to 10,000.
And this was defaulted to 5,000.
And what I'm going through here is
you've seen a month one, it's net
profit negative $500.
So I'm like, okay, well, if you
fucking presented that to a
client, like that's not going to
fly.
You know what I mean?
And then you go to month three and
they fucking have lost money.
You get what I'm saying?
So I'm like, okay, well, like, I'm
like, well, fucking that can't be
the case.
So what I'm doing as well is I'll
walk you through some of my logic
in the next prompt I'm going to
give it.
So under campaign settings, I want
you to remove the cost per lead
and lead to call booking rate.
And instead, just show cost per
book call.
Why?
Because even when I'm personally
doing media buying, I don't give a
fuck what the cost per lead is.
I'm only concerned.
What is the cost per call?
Right?
So it doesn't even matter what the
cost per lead.
It doesn't matter.
Like, what's the cost per call?
Right?
Then under call show up rates,
make a non-adjustable field that
just says call is booked.
Right?
So I just want to see how many
calls were booked right here.
Right?
Under sales and pricing, put a
field under package price that
says clients closed.
And another one says revenue
generated.
And they're calculated based on
the provided input fields.
Right?
And then again, going back to
this, like these numbers are not
big enough.
So now what else I'm going to do
in addition to this, make the
monthly ad spend
default to $30,000 and also make
the package price default to
$10,000.
Okay.
So, and all you do to make these
adjustments to the calculator is
you just explain in natural
English what you want to change.
So I'm going to do that.
And now it's just going to redo
the whole thing.
And like a lot of what you'll do
playing with AI tools is like,
it's like kind of just
like sitting here, like going back
and forth with it.
Like, ah, I want, I want to change
this.
Ah, I want to change this.
Like what you kind of are is like,
you're kind of like a fucking
developer, but you just
use natural language.
Like you don't know code.
You're just a developer, but you
use like the English language.
You get what I'm saying?
Okay.
Thank you.
Also, when you do this, you always
want to make sure you're using the
highest model.
So, like, right now, it's Opus
4.1.
Okay, cool.
Yeah, so this looks fucking much
better.
All right, so what?
Here's how you do this.
Here's how you publish this.
All you do, you go to Publish.
Publish and Copy Link.
Copy Link.
Go into a browser.
Here's your ROI calculator.
It's just on a published link,
right?
So you can just play with this
now.
So, like, you're talking to a
client.
It's like, okay, so what would the
three-month results be?
If you were spending $30,000 per
month, you had a $300 cost per
call, you'd net profit, after my
fees, $222,000.
So, and then you can adjust it.
Well, I assume, like, over time,
like, it's starting to work
better.
Like, you want to increase the ad
spend from $1,000 a day to $2,000
a day.
So then we go to $60,000, and
you'd be profiting $456,000.
You know what I'm saying?
And, like, your service fee on
that would have been, you would
have clicked $84,000 on that over
fucking three months.
You know what I'm saying?
You know, you can sit here and
adjust it with them.
Like, well, what if the cost per
call is higher?
Like, okay, well, then that.
You see what I mean?
Well, I actually charge $8,000.
Okay, that.
Well, what if you close less?
And you can, like, give, like,
conservative estimates and shit.
And it's like, yeah, even if you
had a $350 cost per call, and you
were only closing 18%, and you
were only charging $8,000, you're
still profiting $196,000.
But in reality, it's like, as we
optimize the sales process, it'll
just go to $23,000.
That could stay at $8,000.
Like, we constantly make new ads.
So this would be, like, $280,000.
You know what I'm saying?
You know, we have some cool stuff
that we do to increase show up
rates.
So this would go to $70,000.
So it's $540,000.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, oh, 12 months, $2.1 million.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, you just kind of fuck with
it like that.
And if you just want to make
changes to this calculator, you
just explain to Claude in natural
language.
Like, what do I want to change?
You get what I'm saying?
So I'm going to put all the
prompts in the description below.
I'll put a link to this artifact
as well.
But you can just, like, replicate
the whole thing just like that.
It's super easy.