Thank you.
Hey, Brady.
What's going on?
Jam, jam, jam.
Love it.
How are you doing, guys?
This is super weird for me because
I'm used to being on Zoom calls
where I can see everyone's faces
and we can talk.
And so I'm going to need you guys
to help out as much as possible
just by being super active in the
chat.
Say what's up.
Let me know where you're from,
where you're calling in from.
How's the challenge been up to
this point?
Let's talk in the chat because it
feels weird just being up here
without seeing any of you guys.
Where is everyone calling from?
You can probably tell that I'm
calling from Christian's office.
Christian hosted the call on
Tuesday.
And I'm staying with him down here
in Tampa.
We have an event this weekend.
And so I'm in his office, which
probably looks familiar if you
guys were on Tuesday's call.
So calling from Tampa.
Wow.
We got people from Paraguay,
Finland, Michigan, Fort
Lauderdale, Chicago, Moldova,
Sweden.
Wow.
Seattle.
This is awesome.
We got people joining from all
over India, Orlando.
Charlie, what up, boy?
My dude, Charlie.
Good to see you, bro.
Keelan, good to have you on here,
bro.
Load up that chat.
If you guys are just joining in,
just let me know where you're
calling in from.
It's pretty cool to see we have
people literally calling in from
all over the world.
And I'm even seeing some people
from the same places.
I see a couple of guys from
Orlando, a couple of guys from
Seattle.
And so maybe you guys will find
some new friends and connections
in the area where you're from.
That'd be pretty cool.
But we'll get started here in the
next minute or so.
I just want to give some people
more time to join.
What I would love to see in the
chat is what has been the number
one learning, the number one key
takeaway, the number one action
item from the first three days
with Daniel on Monday, Christian
on Tuesday, and Dan yesterday.
Post in the chat, number one key
takeaway from Monday through
Wednesday.
Go.
And yes, for everyone asking, I'm
in Christian's office right now.
So I'm borrowing Christian's
office for today's call.
Awesome.
So we got a sales scripting
process, specific product offering
with a guarantee, adding a
performance guarantee, nailing the
offer.
My offer sucks.
Okay.
That's okay.
Have a no-brainer offer.
Dan's sales call was goaded.
Authentically selling.
Follow up with interested leaves
until doomsday.
Your offer needs to have a
guarantee and a claim if you don't
have social proof.
Having very detailed terms on the
guarantee is super, super
important.
How to properly do outreach.
It's harder to get someone on the
phone than it is to sell them
something.
Need a better offer with a
guarantee.
Contract stipulations.
Detailed sales process.
The top offer will win every
client in the market.
Super easy objection handling.
This is awesome, guys.
So if you're just now joining in,
what we're putting in the chat is
like the number one key takeaway,
the number one learning from the
sessions on Monday with Daniel,
Tuesday with Christian, and
yesterday with Dan.
And then we'll get started here in
a minute.
And we'll go for about an hour to
an hour and a half is I think what
we have scheduled here.
So I'll present for around an hour
on something that I think is super
important and relevant
based on the information that you
guys learned over the past three
days.
And then we'll get into Q&A.
So before we get started, three
things.
One, tomorrow's session with
Daniel is going to be the most
important session of the entire
challenge.
And so if you've shown up today
and if you've shown up on the
previous days,
make sure you show up to Daniel's
call tomorrow.
Myself, Daniel, Dan, and
Christian, we're all going to be
on that call.
And I'm telling you guys, that
call alone makes the entire
challenge worth your investment
10x.
So make sure to show up to the
call tomorrow.
I believe that's also at 1 p.m.
Number two, because I cannot see
your faces and because I cannot
hear from you guys in a more
interactive way
because of this format on Zoom, I
need you guys to be super active
in the chat because I need that
validation to see that people are
still here, you're listening,
you're getting value.
Okay.
And then number three, if you have
questions, I'm going to do my best
to answer as many questions as
possible at the very end of this
call.
And for me to make sure I hit your
questions, please use the Q&A
feature in Zoom because I'm not
going to be scrolling through the
chat to find out, you know, which
one of the chat messages are
actual questions.
So please use the Q&A box on the
bottom of the Zoom meeting.
You should see it in your screen.
It says Q&A.
And if you have questions, make
sure you put your questions in
there.
And at the end of the
presentation, I'll spend however
much time we have left doing some
Q&A with you guys.
All right.
So three things again, tomorrow's
call with Daniel.
It's an absolute must attend.
Number two, be super active in the
chat throughout this entire
session.
So I know that you're still with
me and you're getting value and
you're not falling asleep.
And number three, if you have
questions, put them specifically
in the Q&A box.
Okay.
All right.
So I'm going to get started.
As you guys probably know, what
I'm going to be sharing with you
guys today, it's operations
focused.
All right.
So it's client fulfillment,
operations, and systems.
And the reason this is so
important is because we need to be
able to capture the sales velocity
that was created from the
conversations you had with Daniel
on Monday, Christian on Tuesday,
and Dan yesterday.
You need to be able to capture the
value of your sales velocity.
If you only do a good job getting
leads and closing deals and you
don't have client fulfillment
operations and systems dialed in,
you're only going to go so far
before it crashes and burns to the
ground.
And so you can't just get really
good at marketing and sales.
You also have to do the follow
through.
And that's the simplicity of
business.
It's really just those three
things.
It's marketing, and then sales,
and then fulfillment.
But so often people underestimate
the importance of the fulfillment
piece because it's a later on type
thing.
You have to do marketing and sales
first, which I completely
understand.
But once you get marketing and
sales going, you need to make your
fulfillment operations and systems
as dialed as possible so that you
can capture the value of your
sales velocity.
So I'm going to get straight into
it, and this is going to be a bit
of a marathon presentation.
And then, again, we'll make as
much time at the end for Q&A.
So sales velocity, what is sales
velocity?
So sales velocity is the lifeblood
of your agency, okay?
So the definition, at least in my
mind, is consistently signing new
clients for your agency by never
turning off marketing and sales,
okay?
The critical importance of this is
without a continuous stream of new
clients, your agency simply won't
survive.
So you can sign a bunch of clients
until you can't.
Not because marketing and sales
isn't working, but because you
can't fulfill for more clients.
You're, quote, unquote, at
capacity.
And if that's where you're stuck
at for too long, your agency just
simply will not survive.
And so the key insight here is
it's not just about getting
clients.
It's about getting them
consistently.
And in business, what you'll learn
is that momentum is everything,
okay?
And so here's the hard reality of
agency churn.
The standard for agencies from the
ones I've run and who we've worked
with is anywhere from a 10% to 20%
monthly churn rate.
And so let's just take the best of
those numbers and look at 10%
monthly churn rates.
If you have 10 clients every
month, you're going to lose one
client with a 10% churn.
If you have 20 clients, you're
going to lose two clients this
month with a 10% churn.
If you have 50 clients, you're
going to lose five clients with a
10% monthly churn.
So what does this mean?
Well, you need to at least replace
churn clients with new clients
just to stay flatline,
a.k.a.
you're not even growing at that
point.
You're literally just staying at
even growth, right?
You're stuck at 10K a month or 30K
a month or 50K a month or 300K a
month
because you're churning 10% and
you're replacing only that same
amount of churn customers.
So if you have 50 clients and your
churn's 10%,
you need to sign at least six
clients to continue growing,
right?
And for a lot of you guys, signing
six clients is like a pipe dream
because you haven't even signed
one yet.
But what does that look like for
some of the more advanced guys in
here that have 100 clients?
Well, if you turn at 10%, you got
to sign at least 11 clients to see
positive growth.
And so as you start to grow, sales
velocity has to continue to
increase.
It has to pick up.
You have to sign more clients
every single month as you grow
because churn will always weigh
that back down.
And so you always, always, always
have to be able to outsell churn.
And that is the hard reality of
agency churn.
So this is the flywheel that will
make you go rogue.
And this is the number one reason
why people who start and have
success later on fizzle out of
their agency.
And it just doesn't work out for
them long term.
And it's also why Client
Ascension, our agency, our
software business list kit,
and all the businesses we're
involved in have been going on for
years.
And every single year they've
grown in revenue.
It's because we understand the
concept of sales velocity and we
understand this flywheel.
And we've also lived it.
It's also why our previous
agencies didn't work out, right?
So at some point in your career,
you're going to have to learn it.
You might as well learn it from me
rather than having to go and
experience this yourself because
it's painful.
So number one, sign several
clients.
You have initial success.
Great.
Then after you sign a bunch of
clients, you feel overwhelmed with
fulfillment issues, right?
You have a lot of clients that you
have to deliver on.
So that puts strain on your
operations.
And so what do you do?
Well, you pause sales so that you
can, quote unquote, catch up.
And when you do this, growth
stops.
You lose momentum.
The sales pipeline dries up.
You struggle to restart the sales
engine because momentum is the
most important force that drives
the sales engine.
And you just completely cut the
lights out.
And then your business fizzles
out.
And so this stop-start approach
will kill your growth potential
and keep you broke.
But luckily, we're going to show
you today how operations can
enable and help you to capitalize
on your sales velocity.
Before I continue, I see some
stuff happening in the chat, all
right?
I need to know that you guys are
listening.
even interested in what I'm
talking about so far.
So if you are, just please put W
in the chat, W in the chat, like
blow it up, crash the Zoom
servers, W in the chat all day
long.
I'll even start putting W in the
chat.
Any letter at this point, just
blow up the chat.
I want to see as many messages as
Zoom can handle just to get the
validation that I should keep
going.
Okay, great.
All right, we're good.
All right, guys, chill out, chill
out.
I think we might get charged for
additional comments in the
comments section.
I don't know if we can afford it.
Awesome, awesome, awesome.
Okay, thank you guys.
I appreciate that because, you
know, I've sat through
presentations and lectures that
for whatever reason, they're just
not hitting.
And I just need that reinforcement
from you guys to keep this same
energy and keep pushing through
and show you how, at the different
businesses we've built, operations
has enabled sales philosophy.
So what this should look like is
you can continue signing clients
without pausing.
So you have an uninterrupted
growth trajectory.
You can convert sales momentum
into client success.
So meaning you can turn new
business into long-term
relationships that actually grow.
And I'll show you what that looks
like later on.
Because the real math of agency
churn is if you can upsell to
cancel out churn, you actually
don't have to worry about it as
much.
But we'll get to that later
because you have to at least not
churn them before you can even
start to focus on upselling them.
And then you can maintain quality
as you scale.
So consistent delivery regardless
of the client volume.
If I have 100 clients or 1,000
clients, how can I make sure that
the quality of my deliverables is
consistent?
It's super important, but it's
also really hard to do.
And so the bottom line here, guys,
is you should never slow down
sales and marketing because of
fulfillment bottles, bottlenecks,
right?
You should simply be able to
figure it out.
And that's, you know, something
that Daniel has coined as a term
is like the figure the fuck out
ability.
That's like a real thing.
That is like one of the key traits
of an entrepreneur and a business
owner is what is your ability to
just simply figure it out?
And what I always lean on from my
own business experience is if
someone else has been able to
figure it out, then why not me?
They're no better than I, right?
And that's kind of the ego thing.
But that's how you can start to
leverage your ego in a really
healthy, really productive way.
And so here's what we're going to
cover.
Efficient client onboarding
systems and management systems
that'll create smooth client
experiences from day one.
Scalable fulfillment processes
that don't depend on you.
So building systems that work
without your constant involvement.
Team structures that grow with
your business.
And that's just basically
developing organizational
frameworks that support expansion,
not just retention.
And so you may be asking, how do
we deliver consistent results
while continuously adding new
clients?
That's really what we're talking
about today.
I'm going to show you how you can
capitalize on the marketing and
sales trainings that you went
through Monday through Wednesday
so that you can continue adding
fuel to the fire and signing more
clients than you ever have.
Ready?
Let's do it.
So part one is we have to
understand the client journey.
Like what should this even look
like?
When someone pays us money for a
service, we close them on a sales
call.
What should the journey look like
from there?
And if we look at it in like the
simplest form, it's onboarding,
which is first impressions and
getting them set up.
It's implementation, which is just
executing on the strategy or the
service they sign up for.
It's optimization, refining for
even better results.
And then growth, finding new ways
to help, essentially expanding
success.
And so that's like at the highest
level what the client journey
should look like.
And if we dive into specifically
onboarding, I like to use a
framework called the 24 activation
framework.
And there's three steps to it.
So one, the critical time frame is
that the first 24 hours determine
the entire client relationship.
And I couldn't stress the
importance of this.
Like quite literally, you win or
lose a client for life within the
first 24 hours.
You can do everything right, you
know, a week into the client
relationship.
But if that first 24 hours, you
know, didn't knock out their
buyer's remorse, you already lost
them.
It's really hard to recover, to
build trust back after
expectations didn't meet reality
immediately after they paid us
money.
And then there's a psychological
factor to this as well, right?
Buyer's remorse kicks in quickly.
We've all experienced this on
purchasing decisions that we've
made, right?
And so you must counter it with
immediate engagement.
So when someone pays you money for
a service, those first 24 hours
are of utmost importance.
And ultimately, what we want to do
in those first 24 hours is
obviously get them onboarded and
started into the fulfillment
cycle.
But at the same time, be super
careful by avoiding what customers
hate more than anything else,
which is unknowns, surprises, and
repeating themselves.
Okay, this is something I've
learned from one of my mentors,
Lincoln Murphy, on the customer
success side of things.
And he's identified these are
three things that customers hate
the most.
Unknowns, surprises, and repeating
themselves, right?
So if they pay you money and
they're surprised that they
haven't heard from anyone on our
team about what the next steps are
for two days, customers hate that
more than anything else.
Or the unknown of what happens
after I pay them money.
What do I need to do?
What are they doing?
When is this all going to start?
When am I going to see results?
They hate that.
Or if onboarding kind of overlaps
with the sales process and you ask
them the same questions, and you
already have this information from
the sales call, and you're just
making them repeat themselves.
And they hate those things more
than anything else.
So when you're looking at your
entire onboarding process, ask
yourself, do I have anything in
this process that creates
unknowns?
Do I have anything in this process
that makes them surprised in a
negative way?
And do I have anything in the
process that makes them repeat
themselves?
And if I do, how can I weed those
out and get rid of them, right?
So again, the first 24 hours, so,
so, so important to any client
relationship.
And so here's the action plan in a
little bit more detail.
So immediately upon them signing
up, I'll send them a welcome
email, right?
This is like immediately after
payment.
And this should ideally be an
intro from the salesperson to the
fulfillment person.
And so the handoff is super
important.
In an agency or a B2B sales
process, like a phone call sales
process, typically the person that
closes them is different from the
person that'll do the service
delivery.
And so you want to bridge that
gap.
You want that to be a really
smooth handoff and a really smooth
transition because it's all about
relationships when it comes to
agencies, you know, services and
fulfillment.
And if you abruptly swap out the
person who they're used to having
that relationship with in the
sales process, with someone in the
fulfillment process that they just
don't know anything about, that
can really fall off the rails
quickly.
The second thing they need is
clear direction, right?
So including specific next steps,
not just we'll be in touch.
Like the first thing you send them
should have a very clear
step-by-step, you know, set of
instructions.
For us, it's really as simple as
fill out the onboarding form,
number one, and then book an
onboarding call, number two,
right?
So you don't want to give them a
bunch of steps, but at least give
them one or two things to work on
immediately.
So as soon as they pay, they fill
out the onboarding form and book
an onboarding call.
And then on the onboarding call,
we can continue making progress on
the client journey that we looked
at at the very beginning.
Then you want to get some, you
know, really simple things set up,
like communication and project
management.
So like I would set up a Slack
workspace and potentially like a
Trello or a ClickUp or a Notion
board for them to track progress.
Then you want to gather
information.
So again, like the onboarding form
is where we're gathering
information.
But we should also see, again,
knowing that customers hate
repeating themselves, we should
see what information we could get
from the sales call so we can take
out questions that we'd otherwise
ask in the onboarding form.
Because we don't want to make them
do more work than they need to.
Okay.
But information gathering is super
important.
And then get to that first meeting
as soon as possible.
That first meeting is the
onboarding call.
And ideally, the onboarding form
and the onboarding call get
completed while they're still on
the sales call.
So if you have like a one-call
close or if your sales process
collects payments on the actual
sales call, you should stay on
them for another five minutes and
just have them fill out the
onboarding form with your guidance
and book an onboarding call before
hopping off.
Like you already have them there.
You already have their undivided
attention.
Why wait for them to get an
automated email from us with the
next steps?
Why not just get the process
started right then and there?
And then resource access.
You want to provide them access to
resources and trainings.
And you want these to be tailored
towards best practices that the
clients need to implement to see
results.
So for example, we ran a cold
email agency.
And we knew that even though we
would book calls for our clients,
they needed a really good offer.
And they needed a really good
sales process.
So while setting everything else
up, we gave them access to free
training for offer creation and
free training for sales call
training from Dan so that when our
service actually started, we knew
we're promoting a good offer
through cold email.
And we knew if we got a call
booked, they'd have an increased
likelihood of actually closing it.
And so overarching, the three
pillars of an effective onboarding
process is removing friction.
So making everything as simple and
clear as possible.
One of the best ways to do that is
by doing it right then and there
on the sales call after you've
collected payment.
If you can't do it, then make it,
you know, an automated follow-up
email after payments collected
with just really clear next steps.
It's like two simple things like
an onboarding form and a kickoff
call.
Focus on time to value.
Like how can you get results
quickly?
And it doesn't have to be like the
North Star results.
Like if you're doing cold email,
the result doesn't necessarily
need to be you have to get them a
client from cold email, you know,
during onboarding.
No, but like if we can show them
progress, progress is more
important than results.
If we can show them that the first
email was sent out, then that's
time to value.
So you want to map out like what
are the different activation or
value points along the way.
So for cold email agency offering,
it could literally be we wrote
scripts that they're happy with.
We built them a leads list that
they're happy with.
We sent the first email.
We got the first reply.
We booked the first meeting and we
closed the first deal.
Those are like six different steps
along the way.
And we can celebrate each and
every single one of them as a
valuable step and a valuable
progress milestone.
And then we want to reward desired
behavior.
So again, if we know that if our
customers go through our sales
training, it increases the
likelihood that they get an ROI
from our cold email services.
We want to reward the behavior of
going through our sales training.
So we might say something along
the lines of like if you go
through Dan's sales call training
before we launch our cold email
campaigns, you know, we'll give
you some additional leads for
free.
Or we'll give you $100 off your
next subscription payment or we'll
give you some free bonus or reward
of some sort.
We'll unlock another training
resource for you, right?
It doesn't even have to be
monetary.
But you want to reward desired
behaviors and remind them that
doing these things will ultimately
help them get the results that
they want.
So let's get even deeper into
these, right?
So remove friction.
So step-by-step instructions with
visuals, like clear guidance
that's easy to follow, similar to
this presentation.
Assume they know nothing about
your process.
So like explain as much as you can
without jargon.
Like you don't want to try to
sound smart.
You just want them to understand
what you're actually saying,
right?
So a lot of us like to use, you
know, big words like sales
qualified leads because we think
it sounds cool, but like you have
to understand they're not
registering what that means a lot
of the times.
So dumb it down and just make sure
they understand everything that
you're explaining about the
process.
Use tools they're already familiar
with to minimize learning curves,
right?
Break complex tasks into smaller
steps.
Again, like make progress
manageable.
This is key for lowering turn.
Always give them something to look
forward to so that they're feeling
like they're making progress.
So if there's one big step, like
launch a cold email campaign,
break that down into build a leads
list, right?
By identifying your ICP, write a
cold email script, refine your
offer, set up email accounts, do
warmup, like break complex stacks
into smaller steps.
And then always end communication.
This is like the number one line
that you guys should be using in
your client communications is the
next step is you need to provide
clear direction forward and
specify who's responsible.
You are the client and have due
dates like operation systems
fulfillment.
It's all about clarity.
At the end of the day, there's no
room for obscurity.
Obscurity only leads to chaos and
chaos leads to churn and churn
leads to you not having a business
anymore.
Okay.
And so always end communications,
whether it's an email or call with
here's the next step because
there's always a next step.
But you also need to clearly
identify who's responsible for
that step and when are the due
dates.
And remember, bottom line, confuse
clients, don't become long-term
clients.
All right.
I see some questions, hands being
raised.
I'm not going to stop for
questions.
So please, if you have a question,
write it in the Q&A box.
There's a Q&A feature in Zoom.
I already see one question from
Fabrico or Fabricio.
Apologies if I'm getting that name
pronunciation wrong, but I only
see one question in Q&A.
I'll do Q&A after the presentation
is done.
And so please use the Q&A feature
in Zoom and I'll go through those
questions at the very end for
whatever time we have left.
But we're going to continue.
So pillar number two, deliver
immediate value, right?
So create quick win deliverables
in the first week, tangible
results that build confidence,
like sending that first email out
or getting that first reply or
giving them access to super
valuable, world-changing training,
right?
On how to build no-brainer offers,
like something that Daniel offers
to our cold email clients that
they love because his offers
training is world-changing, right?
Like it changes up everything they
thought about business and their
offer.
And you guys have experienced that
on Monday.
You also want to identify, you
want to show progress before their
subscription renewals or just
validating their investment
because not only did like the
salesperson close them on the
call, but you have to close them
every month, right?
Because they're making a decision
typically on a month-to-month
basis whether or not this is
worthwhile.
And so, yeah, just because you
close them on a sales call doesn't
mean it's over.
You're always selling them on
staying.
And a lot of times you're selling
them on paying you more money for
expanded services.
And so, keep in mind when those
subscriptions renew because that's
essentially a deadline for you to
make sure that their investment is
proven as a good investment.
You want to identify what clients
value most up front.
So, this is a great question in
your onboarding forms and on your
kickoff calls is focusing on what
they care about and prioritize.
And like I said, ask them, what
are their most important goals and
what would they consider?
What would they need to see happen
to consider this a win?
You want to demonstrate competence
through early action.
So, prove your expertise quickly
even when results are not there
because results are not always
there.
And if the only way someone stays
on versus churns is whether or not
you're getting results, your churn
is going to be through the roof.
You have to get them focused on
progress over results.
Results will ultimately be there
and you need to generate results,
but you need to buy yourself some
time to do it because it's not
realistic to get results right
away.
So, there's got to be some element
of patience, but there has to be
progress milestones along the way.
And that's really that last one.
Just set realistic expectations
about bigger milestones.
Balance quick wins with long-term
goals.
It's all about making progress.
So, early wins, build trust for
the longer journey, especially
when proper expectations are set.
Pillar three, rewarding desired
behavior.
So, acknowledge when clients
follow your process.
Again, positive reinforcement for
cooperation.
Celebrate their engagement and
participation.
Highlight how their actions
accelerate results.
This is one of the best lines in
the entire presentation is you
want to connect their behavior to
outcomes.
Right?
This is the best way to train not
just your clients, but also, like
I say here, remember these steps
when hiring.
The best way to get your team to
do the things you know they should
be doing to get the desired
outcome is show them how certain
behaviors track to certain
outcomes.
Right?
Rather than saying, hey, you
should go through this offers
training just because I want you
to go through this offers
training.
You need to show them how going
through the offers training makes
them more money because that's
really what they care about.
They don't care about the offers
training.
They care about making more money
and they'll do anything you tell
them to do that increases the
likelihood of them making more
money.
Right?
So this is like psychological and
it's super important.
And then you want to create
incentives for completing
onboarding steps because you
cannot start the service or the
engagement if you don't get them
through onboarding.
So stuff like small discounts on
their next renewal or access to
bonus trainings, these are, you
know, really nice things you can
do to just unlock, like we call
them unlockables, right?
If you complete these steps,
you'll unlock free content or
you'll unlock free credits for
ListKit.
And again, what gets rewarded gets
repeated.
If they do something and they get
something for it, they're going to
do that thing more often.
And again, this becomes especially
relevant when you're hiring and
managing teams, right?
Not just client relationships.
Okay?
I'm going to stop for water.
If you're still with me, let's do
that thing we did about blowing up
the Zoom chat.
W is in the chat while I take a
sip of water.
Thank you.
All right, man.
Way more people here than I
originally thought would be.
And it's great to see some
familiar names out there.
So thank you all for the support
and for the attention that you're
giving.
Because this is super important
stuff, guys.
I know marketing and sales is way
more sexy than onboarding systems
and fulfillment.
But you can't have marketing and
sales without fulfillment.
You just can't.
Okay?
You need all of them.
And so you can't drop the ball
after going through Daniel,
Christian, and Dan's training.
You won't have a business for very
long if you do.
So even if this stuff is boring or
if this stuff is hard, it's what's
required.
And so let's get into part two,
the weekly engagement system.
So weekly engagement is just like
how are you communicating with
your clients?
Number one, you need proactive
communication, like regular touch
points.
You need, and the key word here is
proactive, not reactive,
proactive.
You need progress tracking.
Again, not results tracking.
Progress tracking.
Measuring results and important
KPIs.
Expectations management.
Aligning their perceptions with
reality or what's realistic.
And then relationship building.
How can you strengthen trust?
Because when results aren't there
or progress is not there, what you
do to build the relationship
is what will keep them hanging
around longer than they really
should.
Longer than what's smart for their
business.
And so remember that.
The number one mistake that kills
client retention that I see, even
if you get onboarding correct,
is silence, right?
Your silence, your communication
gaps, or your unwillingness to
communicate with your clients
creates uncertainty.
It also leaves room for them to
have a dialogue with themselves
where negative assumptions could
be formed, right?
They assume nothing's happening.
They question if their investment
was smart.
They start looking elsewhere and
they get FOMO.
Like, man, I should have went with
that agency instead because I keep
seeing their case studies
and they lose confidence in the
results.
And so by the time they actually
express this concern, it's too
late.
Because usually this concern
festers for a long period of time
before they will share it with
you because it's hard for them.
They don't want to have conflict
with a service provider.
So they'll keep it to themselves
until they just can't anymore.
You never want to get to that
point.
And the way you don't get to that
point is you become proactive in
your communication,
not reactive.
And one of the easiest ways to do
this is weekly updates.
And weekly updates doesn't have to
be anything crazy.
It can just be wins and progress,
right?
Like KPIs and metrics that matter.
Work status.
Like, what work did you complete?
What are you currently working on?
And then future planning.
What are some upcoming progress
milestones?
And what are some upcoming action
items?
So what's important here is the
consistency of your communication
with clients is more important
than the format and how you're
communicating with them.
And novelty is important as well
to keep things exciting.
You don't want to communicate in a
way that's super robotic, right?
Like you want your personality to
shine through.
The way to deliver this, it's
really just figuring out, like,
where are they most responsive?
That's going to be their preferred
method.
Whether it's email, whether it's
Slack, whether it's text, whether
it's on a live call or a phone
call.
But that's kind of my guide.
It's like emails for formal, more
old school clients.
Slack is quick.
It's conversational.
It's fun.
It's more modern.
Loom videos are great, especially
when there's, like, more in-depth
updates or visual things that you
want to show them.
And then live calls are great for,
like, talking through hurdles and
bottlenecks.
And just, again, like, getting
their input and feedback on things
as well.
And just overall building
relationships, right?
Other things for client
communication best practices.
Over-communicate rather than
under-communicate.
Hold clients accountable for their
responsibilities.
Because, again, like, success is a
joint accountability effort.
You cannot get someone meaningful
business results with cold email
if they don't have a good offer
and if they don't have a good
sales process.
So, like, even though you crush it
with cold email, it's not going to
lead to actual business results
like new clients sign without them
doing their part.
And so that's super important.
Celebrate wins, even the small
ones.
Again, like, you need to highlight
progress and achievements, not
just results.
If all you celebrate is when you
get a client signed, it's not
going to be enough, right?
They're going to feel like they're
just not getting enough results.
So you need to, like, switch this
wording in your brain of, like,
results is king.
It's like progress is king,
actually.
And progress leads to results in
due time.
But you can't lead to results if
you don't have enough time to make
progress, which is why you need to
highlight progress, not results,
to keep them around.
Frame everything in a way that
benefits the client, focusing on
their outcomes and goals.
And then be the first to address
problems with solutions attached.
So, like, proactive communication
looks like, hey, like, if you're,
you know, doing cold email, hey,
look, like, we've ran a campaign
for you guys.
And based on what we've seen from
our most successful clients, this
one's just on track to be a flop.
Like, quite honestly, like, this
one's just going to completely
flop.
And I want to let you know now so
that we can work on your offer and
work on your targeting.
Because those are the two things
that can really turn the
performance around.
But that needs to be worked on.
But if you wait for them to tell
you that the results are shit and
that, you know, their campaigns
are flopping, you're in a position
of defense instead of offense.
And most of the times at that
point, you already lost them.
So, this is one of my favorite
signs.
When you're performing well, let
the client know.
And I'm pretty sure all of you
guys are good about this.
But when you're not performing
well, let the client know.
Still, a lot of you guys are
probably more shy to do that.
When doing that is actually going
to be the best thing you can do to
keep people around long term.
So, part three, I'm zooming
through.
There's just a lot of content and
a lot of things that I got to get
through to make sure you guys are
fully equipped to capitalize on
what you learned from Daniel, Dan,
and Christian.
And so, we're going to get through
this as fast as possible and then
go through as many questions as
possible.
Part three, building scalable
fulfillment systems.
So, it's all about documenting
your process, making sure everyone
on the team is following those
processes and systems,
implementing different forms of
automation, and then ensuring that
there's quality control as things
start to scale.
Making sure that as things scale,
you're not doing things at a lower
standard than what was previously
expected or accepted.
And what that really goes back to
is like, you should have the same
quality or even better quality
with 1,000 clients as you do with
10.
And this is, you know, the
presentation is trying in a way to
show you how to exactly do that.
But okay, the optimization
framework for operations, the
72-hour task audit, the removing
the unnecessary steps is one of my
favorite quotes.
It's not a direct quote, but Elon
Musk essentially says, most people
try to optimize things that
shouldn't exist in the first
place.
So, remove unnecessary steps,
create systems for repeatable
work, like just having an SOP that
you can then delegate to other
team members and then automate
things that are more predictable
and use AI tools to do that.
Because the world we live in now,
like, man, like when I was running
an agency with over 100 clients
before ChatGPT existed, man, like
it was so different than what it's
like today.
Like today, there's just no excuse
not to be able to handle a high
volume of clients because the
tools available are just so
advanced.
So, 72-hour task audit is where I
would start.
You need to document all the
things that you do for 72 hours
and show how much time is spent on
each activity.
Categorize them, each activity by
what gives you energy versus what
drains your energy.
High-value task, low-value task,
and then client-facing task,
internal task.
And what this audit is going to
do, it's going to give you a lot
of insights and clarity as to,
like, how your time is being
spent.
And if you have a team, you should
have your team do this as well
because that's going to show you,
like, where you need to systemize,
right?
Time tracking.
It's not something you need to do
forever, but you should do it for,
you know, a 72-hour time period
and see what insights come of
that.
And then create systems for
repeatable work.
So, you want to identify patterns
like tasks you perform
repetitively.
And you might think you know right
now, but I promise you, if you do
a 72-hour task audit, you're going
to be blown away.
You're going to be like, wow, I
had no idea I was spending all
that time doing this.
I need to get rid of that.
Or processes that have really
predictable steps or work that
follows similar patterns or
activities that could be
templated, right?
Just made easier instead of
starting from scratch each time.
And so, document those processes
with start and end points, clear
start and end points, step-by-step
procedures, triggers, like, what
triggers that step or process to
start?
And what are the different
decision points along the way?
And then the expected outcomes and
the standards of the work.
That's how you create a system for
repeatable work.
And then automating the
predictable parts, things that you
can automate are, like, repetitive
data entry, notification systems.
Like, when a client signs on, you
can send an onboarding email.
And if they don't fill out the
onboarding form and book an
onboarding call, you can automate
a follow-up reminder.
Or if they don't show up to the
call, you can have a no-show
sequence.
Or, you know, after they've
successfully onboarded, you can
trigger, like, an education-based
flow to give them drip-fed value
as, you know, they continue to
become a paying customer.
Or document generation, like,
creating SOPs.
One of the best processes for
using AI and automation tools is
creating SOPs.
Follow-up sequences, like I talked
about, email, text, those sorts of
things.
And then status updates.
There's ways to automate, you
know, weekly reporting using
automation tools like ChatGPT,
Zapier, project management, like
Intrello, email sequence tools
like ConvertKit, and just
templates in general.
And just Google Doc templates, one
of the best things you can, you
know, spend your time on putting
in place.
I get this question all the time.
It's like, send me your SOPs.
And it's like, SOPs, I'm not big
on SOPs.
Because not, most things don't
have step-by-step instructions.
They're not, you know, do this, do
that.
They're more creative.
They're more free-flowing.
And they're more often changing.
And so I lean into training more
than SOPs.
Training is teaching your team how
to think.
It's giving them mental frameworks
for decision-making,
problem-solving approaches, when
to escalate versus when to handle
yourself.
And then developing judgment, like
decision-making, intuition, right?
And so I find trainings to be more
valuable than straight-up SOPs.
Obviously, SOPs are valuable,
right?
Like, you should use SOPs when the
process is repeatable, when
consistency is critical, when the
steps don't change, when you need
to scale quickly.
But training is when the work
requires a decision to be made,
best judgment, decision-making.
Situations vary significantly.
It's different than what you've
seen before.
And then creativity is valued,
right?
And then you want to develop your
team's ability to handle things
without you always being there or
without, you know, step-by-step
instructions needed to be given.
So the more you SOP and tell them
exactly what to do, the more you
create robotic humans as team
members, not problem solvers.
And problem solvers are the types
of people in your organization
that are going to help you to
scale.
And so how do you have quality
control without micromanagement?
So we're getting more into, like,
the team aspect of operations,
systems, and fulfillment.
Like, okay, it's not just you at
this point.
There's people involved.
Real quick, just for, like, a
litmus test, can you guys just put
in the chat, if you have a team,
just put the number one.
If you have any team members, just
put the number one.
It could be a VA.
It could be, like, a co-founder.
If you're not the only one running
the business and doing things in
your business, please, in the Zoom
chat, put one, because this part
of the presentation is going to be
absolutely critical for you.
Okay, so some of you guys.
Again, if you're listening in, put
the number one in the Zoom chat,
if you currently have a team, even
if it's just one other person that
works on your business other than
yourself.
Because, again, this part of the
presentation is going to be worth
all of the money that you invested
into this challenge.
Okay, so quality control without
micromanagement.
You need to establish clear
quality standards.
Like, what does excellence
actually look like?
With examples, you need to have
review processes in place.
So, like, call reviews are one of
the best review processes.
So, like, when we hire salespeople
and they're not, like, hitting
KPIs, we need to review their
sales calls.
So, like, Dan, he probably talked
about this on his call yesterday.
And if you didn't, it's a critical
piece.
It's reviewing sales calls to see,
like, how can I coach and train
this person to be better at sales
calls?
And you can do that on onboarding
calls by reviewing them and even,
like, checking calls with clients
as well.
You want to create feedback loops
for improvement, right?
So, like, a feedback loop can be
through a call review.
And then you want to set specific
check-in points for complex
projects.
And that could be through the form
of, like, weekly team meetings or
huddles at the start of every
single day.
Or end-of-day type forms.
And an end-of-day type form, you
can ask, like, what are you
currently struggling with or what
do you need help with?
And that way you have, you know,
consistent communication without
having to micromanage and check
in, you know, by your own memory
with every team member.
If quality across the board
decreases, and it's not like
you've never had a high quality,
it's just you started at a really
high quality and it decreases over
time, it's probably a case where
you're at capacity and you need to
hire more people to manage more
clients.
That's really it.
So, if you start to see quality
drop and it's been, you know,
where you wanted it before, it's
probably because the existing team
members are spread too thin.
So, that's something, that's
something, that's like a signal to
keep out an eye on.
So, how do you protect your energy
while managing clients?
We're going to get into, like,
your day-to-day and then your
team's day-to-day.
So, time management, structuring
your day for a balance of
productivity and fulfillment.
Go back to the 72-hour task audit.
What gives you energy?
And by identifying what gives you
energy, you can add those into
your day-to-day and you can weed
out the things that drain your
energy.
And as long as you have the
self-awareness and know these
things, you can operate at a
really high level.
Setting boundaries, right?
So, like, creating clear
expectations with clients and
things like expected response
times.
I know a lot of us are, like, just
confused about this where we think
clients really value, like,
immediate responses.
Like, if I have a question and I
send it, I expect immediate
response.
Like, it's not true.
And it's not fair to you if those
boundaries are not properly set.
So, give them an expected response
time.
Like, hey, if you message me on
Slack within these hours, I'll get
back to you within an hour to two
hours.
If it's outside of business hours,
it'll be, you know, the next day.
Some of you guys are on Slack, you
know, up until midnight, and I'm
guilty of this as well, getting
back to clients when you really,
you really just need to set
boundaries so that you can protect
your time and protect your energy.
So, anyways, and then strategic
delegation, knowing what you
should handle personally versus
what to delegate.
And this is, like, a limiting
belief, but, like, by implementing
boundaries, the client
relationship is actually much
better off.
It's strengthened, not weakened.
So, super, super important.
And then this is the daily
structure for operational
excellence, at least for me.
So, if you're more of an
operations-minded person, I'll
usually do a meetings block from
when I wake up to when I have
lunch.
And so, I have, like, a specific
morning routine.
But then from 9 a.m.
to 1 p.m., pretty much for four
hours, it's a meeting time block
on my calendar.
So, all my team and client
meetings are during that time.
And then afternoons are for deep
work.
So, I have, you know, my mind is
clear and I can just fully focus
on deep work rather than going
into a meeting and then having 30
minutes and then a meeting and 30
minutes.
So, that whole stop and start
pattern of your day structure will
kill all momentum.
You're just not going to be able
to get anything done.
And then, like, post lunch or
during lunch for catching up on
Slack and email, that's usually
super effective.
So, like, for me, like, I clear
Slack and email before my meeting
block.
I clear Slack and email at the end
of my meeting block.
And then after, like, my deep work
at the end of the day, I'll clear
Slack and email.
So, pretty much three times.
And if you do that, like, the
response times are not, like,
going to be 24 hours.
It's still going to be a couple of
hours.
It's just set specific times and
check Slack.
Morning, afternoon, end of day,
rather than just always being on
Slack and email.
Otherwise, again, it's the stop
and start thing.
You're never going to get anything
done.
And then reserve late afternoon
for strategic work because that's
when you're going to get the least
emails, the least last Slack
messages, the least text messages.
So, you can actually focus on,
like, more high-level strategic
things.
And then weekly planning.
Here's how I plan my weeks.
On Monday, usually actually Sunday
night, I'll set my objectives.
Like, here's what I want to do
this week.
And then on Friday, I'll review my
progress.
What did I get done?
What's still in progress?
What did I learn?
And I'll just simply keep, like, a
running to-do list throughout the
week.
And then I'll adjust, you know, as
needed.
Like, maybe some things that I
thought I wanted to get done this
week just need to be pushed back.
Or, you know, this is something
that just no longer needs to get
done.
So, okay.
So, when to push back
professionally.
This is, I've also, I also realize
just going through this again,
that this is kind of out of order.
But stay with me.
And if you're extra focused,
you'll still get value.
But anyways, this is talking about
pushing back on clients.
And this is, like, when, again,
like, they're crossing boundaries,
right?
You set boundaries and then they
break them.
So, like, scope creep.
They request something that falls
outside of the scope of work.
Unrealistic expectations, like
timelines and expected results are
unrealistic.
Quality compromises, like work
that they're asking you to do
would compromise on the overall
quality.
And then strategy buy-in.
Like, the demands are inherently
bad for their business, right?
So, like, a client might ask you
to do something.
But it might be, like, something
that you shouldn't do even if they
wanted you to do it.
Because it would set them further
back, right?
So, you want to make sure that,
like, what they're demanding are
also in their best interest.
And you always want to, again, go
back to framing what you're
pushing back on as, like, I'm
doing this to protect you and to
deliver the quality you deserve.
So, here's, like, there's a couple
of, you know, snippets in this
presentation that you can
literally take.
Like, the next best step is, like,
use that in your emails.
Or to deliver the quality you
deserve, we need to, and then you
tell them what you need to do.
Like, these are actual blurbs that
you can include when writing, you
know, emails or Slack messages or
even on a live call with your
customer.
Super helpful.
So, this actually now gets into
building your dream team, right?
So, like, here's the structure
from the top down.
So, you have, like, leadership,
which is you, your, like,
strategic direction.
Actually, you guys are probably,
like, one to four all at the same
time.
And I get that.
And that's okay.
But you want to be strategic
direction.
You're going to want to have
managers in place to coordinate,
you know, what the team is doing.
Then you have specialists.
They are the ones that actually,
like, execute on the ideas.
And then you have support to,
like, help the specialists
execute.
Like, operational foundations.
Those are more, like, executive
assistants, chief of staff, those
sorts of roles, VA roles.
But those are, like, the four
levels of your team.
This is a really important slide
because I get this question all
the time.
Like, when should I start hiring?
So, here's a couple of signs that
it's time for you to start hiring.
One, quality issues start
appearing that weren't there
before, right?
Standards slip due to overload to
the point where you're actively
losing clients because of this.
Tasks take longer than they
should.
Efficiency decreases with volume
to a point where it diminishes
your value.
You're turning down sales
opportunities.
So, growth is limited by capacity.
This is actually number one,
right?
I just didn't want to change it to
number one because I was trying to
rip through this as fast as
possible last night when I was
making some edits.
But, like, man, like, if you have
to turn down sales opportunities
because you don't have the
capacity, like, that's business
critical.
That's as big of an issue, as
important as an issue, or a red
flag, as anything I've ever come
across before.
Also, this one, super relatable.
You're working harder but
accomplishing the same amount or
less.
So, you have diminishing returns
on your effort.
And then if you're just stuck
doing low-value work, right?
And that, you know, prevents you
from focusing on strategic
priorities and higher-level
projects.
So, if you need to hire because
any of those things resonate,
here's what you should hire first.
At least from my experience, these
are the roles that you should
focus on.
The first one is client-facing
roles, like customer success
managers.
Now, free up your time on a
day-to-day doing client
management, talking to the
clients, having consistent
communication with the clients on
calls, on Slack, on email,
so that you can just flow doing
other work and not have to worry
about getting back to your
customers because someone else is
doing that.
Admin support, like handling
back-end projects, like project
management, meeting coordination,
KPIs, results reporting, et
cetera.
Systems and documentation for what
everyone else is doing, right?
So, like SOPs and just creating
structure, similar to what we
talked about in previous slides.
And then, eventually, delivery
specialists for your core service.
So, like if you offer SEO, like
bringing in an actual like SEO
expert that can help, you know,
deliver services for your clients
and get them results and scale
your capacity to get results, you
know, for more clients.
So, in that order, CSMs, admin
support, and then eventually
delivery specialists because, at
least for right now, like you're
pretty much the expert and that's
okay.
You can continue being the expert,
especially if you free up time
communicating to your customers
and free up your time doing, you
know, admin level work.
Then you can spend all your time
doing delivery, and that's, you
know, much more worth your time
than client-facing and admin
stuff.
So, focus on these first and then
move over into delivery
specialists.
The way I like to hire is
performance-based compensation
that aligns them with your
incentives, right?
Like your incentives as the
business.
So, like, for example, the CSMs,
you can pay them a specific
percentage of revenue for each
client that they manage or for a
setter, right?
We do this with salespeople, and
it's like the standard for hiring
salespeople, but we don't do it
for any other role, which to me
makes no sense, right?
Like, for a salesperson, you pay
them when they collect cash, and
you pay them a percentage of cash
collected.
Simple.
So, like, for a CSM, what is the
goal of a CSM?
To keep clients.
And so, if they keep clients, they
should get paid every month that
that client pays us because
they're keeping them and managing
them actively, right?
Setter compensation.
Maybe you throw in a base.
Maybe you throw in money for
completing certain activities, but
really what you're paying a setter
for is booked calls, right?
So, you should pay them per book
call.
It's also like an inbox manager
role that you would hire at your
lead gen agency.
You should pay an inbox manager
for every call that they book,
right?
Or if you have someone doing
revenue recovery, right?
You have clients that keep failing
payments.
This is super relevant for us at
our SaaS company.
We pay our revenue recovery
specialist 5% of the revenue that
they recover, and we're happy to
do it because that's revenue that
we lost.
If they get it back, we're happy
to give them 5%, right?
The benefits of performance-based
comp is you hire when you need to,
not when you can afford to,
because the biggest hesitation to
hire is like, I can't afford to
hire.
Well, yeah, you can.
You can hire a salesperson because
you don't have to pay them unless
they bring you money, and that
should be the same for every other
role in your business.
It's a natural alignment with your
business goals.
So, if your business goal is to
close more deals and to decrease
churn, then align the comp
structures to that.
It scales automatically with
growth.
So, as you grow, the
performance-based compensation
grows, and if you dip and have a
bad month, you don't go out of
business because you overcommitted
to hiring, and your payroll will
put you out because it scales up
and down.
It rewards performance, not just
time, which is really like, we
don't care if someone's working 80
hours a week or someone that's
working 40, as long as the output
is there, the performance, right?
And then it also creates healthy
competition, like, even amongst
themselves.
So, okay, I got to zip through
this because I'm already at the
one-hour mark, and I still, I want
to have time for Q&A, but there's
a decent amount left to still go
through.
Hopefully, at least, this is
valuable.
Hopefully, it's valuable.
Okay, I didn't even have to tell
you guys to put W's in the chat,
and you already are, so that tells
me enough.
So, thank you, guys.
But the five-step hiring system
for A-players, so define the role,
source the right candidates,
screen them properly, test that
they can actually do the job, and
then set them up for success with
proper onboarding.
Funny enough, the way you hire an
A-player is the same way you
market and sell a client.
And then the way you onboard an
A-player team member is the same
way you onboard a client.
So, it's actually the same.
It's the same foundational skill
sets and concepts, which is pretty
cool.
So, the first step is to define
the role scorecard, right?
So, the core responsibilities,
what are the required skills, what
are the performance metrics and
KPIs, what defines your culture,
and what is the reporting
structure and autonomy level?
Who are they reporting to?
Who's making the decisions, right?
And the main takeaway here is you
don't want to just create a
generic job description.
You want to define what excellence
looks like in the specific role.
And here's the big thing.
If you're not abundantly clear on
what you're hiring for, the
candidates or whoever you hire
will not be abundantly clear on
what they're supposed to be doing.
And that is what results in low
performance, no matter how
talented the person you hire is.
We've probably all, including
myself, have hired A-players, but
because the scorecard and the role
is not clearly defined, they look
like C or D or F-players, but it's
not their fault.
It's your fault, and you need to
realize when that's the case.
Finding A-players, like you need
to source and find them, it's
similar to cold email outreach.
It's a volume game, right?
And you should also, again, it
parallels marketing, sales, and
client fulfillment.
You should never stop sourcing
talent the same way you should
never stop marketing, because what
this will allow you to do is build
a bench of talent before you need
it.
So, as you continue to grow,
you're going to start to hire a
lot more often, and going through
the five-step hiring process
might take you a long time.
And maybe you need, you know,
someone in that CSM role as of
yesterday.
So, if you build a bench and just
continue to source candidates that
you can just tap in, and like in
sports, right?
It's like a bench.
Like, if I need to swap someone
out, like I have a guy on the
bench warmed up and ready to go.
I don't have to go find, you know,
someone to bring to the team.
They're already there.
Screening them properly.
This is my framework.
It's attitude, competency, and
experience.
And then I'll go through, and I
won't hire anyone that scores less
than a six in any of these
categories.
And the key is, if you have a
co-founder or other team members
that you really trust, have them
do an interview as well and score
attitude, competency, and
experience.
And then see how they compare to
yours.
And this is a good sanity check
because maybe you really like this
candidate and you're biased or,
you know, their, you know,
referral from a friend.
And you just say their attitude,
competency, and experience is good
enough, but maybe someone else in
your organization sees something,
you know, that's flawed with their
attitude or flawed with their
competency that you should know
about before hiring.
If they're a fit, then you test
their skills with a practical
evaluation.
So the evaluation components are
role-specific assignments,
realistic scenarios, clear
evaluation criteria, and then
appropriate time constraints.
So example, test for different
roles, like a CSM, I'll give them
like a client scenario to handle,
like a client requesting a refund.
How would you respond to this
client that's clearly aggravated
and clearly, you know, won't go
away unless we give them a refund.
Or if you're hiring a designer,
make a design of this as like a
sample.
Or if you're hiring copywriters,
write cold email scripts for this
offer.
Or a developer, do a coding
challenge.
Or sales, do a mock call with me.
So you can see how they perform on
a sales call.
And if you like what you see from
the first four steps, you then
make the decision to hire them and
then set them up for success.
So you need a structured
onboarding plan, comprehensive
integration roadmaps, such as
introducing them to other team
members, clear documentation of
resources, access to necessary
information and tools, regular
check-ins, daily at first, super
important, consistent support and
guidance via one-on-one calls.
Like, this you have to take to an
extreme level.
Like, I just hired a really big
role at ListKit.
And I literally flew down to Tampa
two days early before our event,
that's this weekend.
And I flew in the guy I hired from
Texas so that we could spend two
days in person working close
together.
Because I know how important
onboarding and setting him up for
success is and how much, you know,
more valuable that is if we can do
it in person.
Early wins in confidence builders,
specific actionable feedback, and
then a gradual increase in their
responsibilities.
And that's when, essentially, the
training wheels come off.
But, again, I could put a
blindfold on so you can't see what
the screen is saying.
Or, like, yeah, you can't actually
see the words.
And you might believe that I'm
talking about setting up new
clients for success.
It's the same thing.
And the same way you set up new
clients for success is the same
way you set up new hires for
success.
And that's what's so cool about
hiring and fulfillment processes.
It's the same concepts.
And then I also use this process
for PIPs.
A PIP is a performance improvement
plan.
Because you're going to hire
people that are not performing to
the level that they need to be
performing.
So when that happens, you can
identify specific performance
gaps, create measurable
improvement objectives, establish
a 30-day timeline, provide
necessary resources and support,
schedule weekly check-ins, and
then make a firm decision after 30
days.
The bottom line, important
takeaway here is we need to fire
fast to protect culture.
But at the same time, we need to
give them a fair chance to
improve.
We need to give everyone we hire a
fair chance to improve while still
maintaining that mindset of we
need to fire fast.
So that's it, guys.
So this is the roadmap to
operational excellence.
Look at your current systems.
And if they don't exist, you know,
that's also a sign of where to
start.
Create improved, design improved
new processes.
Implement, like deploy new
operations.
And then optimize, refine for
maximum efficiency.
So like at a high level, how do
you take everything that we just
talked to and implement it?
It's these four steps, right?
And what does this actually look
like on a more granular scale?
Like in the next seven days, map
out your entire client onboarding
process.
Implement a weekly update template
and get feedback from the clients
on it.
And then begin a 72-hour task
audit.
Like literally complete a 72-hour
task audit in the next seven days.
It'll be the best thing you ever
did.
And then in the next 30 days,
design a first role scorecard once
you've identified who your next
hire should be.
Automate three repetitive
processes.
Create client health scoring
system to see like where each of
your clients at.
Who needs proactive outreach?
Who do I need to hop on a
one-on-one call with?
Who do I need to provide more
value to?
Who's, you know, potentially an
upsell or an expansion that's just
waiting to be had?
And then in the next 90 days, you
can make your first strategic
hire.
You can implement that hiring
decision with a performance-based
comp structure.
And then you want to establish
meeting rhythms for your
organization with proper review
processes
to ensure quality standards are
met across the board.
So that's just how I would
approach a lot of this.
Obviously, it's also dependent on
where you're currently at.
Some of you might already have
teams and, you know, some of these
different things in place.
But at least, you know, check the
box on these things and see where
that leaves you.
But there's a lot to implement.
And maybe you guys have, you know,
even more things that you wrote
down
that you're going to go out and
implement immediately after this.
And I'd love to hear those.
So next actions, document your
client journey from sign-up to
success.
Create templates for client
updates and communication.
Identify your highest value and
energy draining task.
Define the next role to hire for.
And then develop performance
metrics for your fulfillment team.
Like, what does success look like?
And some of the major themes from
this entire talk is it comes down
to clarity.
And for anyone, including your
clients and your team to have
clarity, you need to have clarity.
Number one.
And number two, progress is more
important than results.
And so lean into making your
clients feel like they're making
progress, not just results.
So important.
Much more scalable, much more
sustainable.
Your turn rate will thank you if
you switch your mindset on that.
My final thoughts before we go
into Q&A.
One, operations is the foundation
that makes growth possible.
Again, even if it's the least sexy
of, you know, the marketing sales
and, like, the Christian Dan and
Daniel calls earlier this week.
It's what makes what they do
possible.
Like, you can't market and sell a
client into nothing.
Like, you have to be able to
deliver something.
Otherwise, you're a scammer.
And that's going to be revealed,
you know, really soon.
And you're going to, you know,
have a rude awakening.
So operations is what makes growth
possible.
Systems create freedom, not
restrictions.
So get out of the thinking that,
like, systems are too strict and,
you know, they trap creativity.
That's just not true.
You should never slow down sales
and marketing because of your
fulfillment bottlenecks.
Again, you need to have that
figure-the-fuck-out ability that
Daniel talks about.
The journey from you being the
operator you currently are doing
the day-to-day task of the
business to becoming a leader,
like a true leader,
like we saw in that pyramid of
hierarchy, it requires you letting
go and trusting other people.
And the best way to trust other
people is to go through a really,
you know, well-defined hiring
process that I mapped out.
And then number five, I love this
one, is you should always be
striving to hire people better
than you.
Doing this will make number four
really easy.
You'll want to let go because
you're like, man, like, I'd so
much rather this person do it than
me because they're better at it.
And they have more time and they
can fully focus on just this and
nothing else.
And once you get there, you have a
business that you can truly scale
in a very enjoyable way.
And you can capitalize on what
Daniel, Christian, and Dan already
spent three days teaching you
guys.
So thank you so much.
I also made a workbook for you
guys where you can just go through
different action items that relate
to the presentation.
And I would highly encourage you
guys to do this.
I spent a lot of time on this
stuff and I used, you know, AI
tools to help organize it and
format it in a way that is super
interactive and easy for you guys
to follow.
But the underlying content, it's
all fully based on what was in the
presentation here today.
So if you've got value and you
have, you know, some different
notes on things you want to do or
things that you had as a key
takeaway,
like that workbook is going to be,
you know, one of the best things
for you guys because it's got a
lot of, you know, really clear
action items and things that you
guys can do in there.
So before I get into Q&A, I don't
want to forget to share this with
you all.
And the nice thing is this Google
Doc also links back to the actual
gamma presentation.
So instead of just using the
presentation link, I'll send you
the workbook link and that has
both.
And so enjoy.
But that's it.
Thank you guys.
I'm going to take a minute to take
a sip of water and then I'll get
into doing Q&A.
All right.
And in the chat, I posted the
Google Doc link.
So everyone chill out in the chat
for a minute so that everyone can,
everyone can grab that.
Okay.
I'll send it one more time just
so, just so each of you guys can
grab that.
But okay, Q&A.
So there's 20 questions in here.
I got about 20 minutes to rip
through them.
So I'm going to go through as many
of them as I can in the time that
we have left.
And that'll be that.
But for a minute here, I got to
take a sip of water.
Okay.
All right.
This is the last time I'm going to
ask you guys to use the chat.
But if that was valuable, and if
you're still here, and if you're
still wide awake, send whatever
you want in the chat.
Just let me know.
It doesn't have to be anything
specific.
Just blow up the chat.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Thank you guys.
Appreciate it.
Man, that was fun.
That was good stuff.
All right.
So Fabricio, what software do you
use to send automated emails when
onboarding?
ConvertKit is what I would
recommend.
But there's all different kinds of
softwares that you can use for
that.
But ConvertKit is what I would use
there.
Can you talk through your whole
process for hiring and managing
sales reps?
So Kareem asked that earlier on in
the call, and I answered it with
the later part of the
presentation.
So check out literally like the
last 15 minutes.
I went through the entire process
for hiring.
Managing sales reps is different.
That's more of what Dan does
because Dan manages the sales
team.
But a lot of the same concepts
apply.
Yeah.
Better for the partner who did the
call yesterday for the sales
specific hires.
How much do you know?
How much?
How much you should pay the people
you hire?
Oh, it's performance based.
And so, okay, so some of these
questions are already answered
later on in the presentation
when you put the question in here.
But if you have a follow-up
question or need more clarity on
that, let me know.
But the way we determine how much
to pay someone is performance
based.
Would you say having a full
website with an intro video is a
good way to onboard?
Yeah, you could do a website.
But like, I think that's a little
overkill.
I think it's a nice way to stand
out and make it a great onboarding
experience for new hires.
But like, that's not what's
required.
Like, if you don't spin up an
entire website with an intro
video, you're going to be okay.
Focus on the elements that I...
Oh, actually, this would be for a
client.
But same thing, right?
Because it applies to both.
But yeah, like, you don't need a
full website.
Like, you could do it in a Loom
video and an email.
But again, you can make a really
good first impression if you have
something that goes a little bit
above and beyond.
But don't take too much of the
focus away from doing the actual
fulfillment.
Communication, like I said, it's
not about the quality necessarily.
It's more about the consistency of
it.
So like, clients value consistency
of communication more than like,
oh, like, that's really cool that
you put together an impressive
website just to make an intro
video for them.
Someone asked, what are the five
most important SOPs?
Again, I focus more on training,
not SOPs.
And I couldn't tell you because
your agency, I don't know what
your agency is.
I don't know what the bottlenecks
are and where you're currently,
you know, needing help.
So do the 72-hour task audit and
go through the process that I
outlined to identify, you know,
what you need to systemize first.
What if you do sales?
Marketing will also handle most of
the comms, most of my employees
overseas, and usually a
communications gap.
Great question.
You have to hire someone to do
communications with your clients.
And if the overseas people are not
capable of doing it because they
don't have great communication
skills, then you have to find
someone who's capable.
And we have overseas talent that
does customer communications from
Lebanon.
And we run a business, I run a
business called RemotelyX.com.
It's a hiring business,
recruiting.
And you can hire people from
Lebanon for cheap, and they're
really good in customer-facing
roles.
So check that out if that's, you
know, something of interest.
Do you share wins as soon as they
happen?
Yeah, literally share wins as soon
as they happen.
No reason to wait.
What happens during the onboarding
call if I have a YouTube content
agency?
That's for you to decide.
That's the service you're selling.
So map that out.
What do you, what is your
onboarding and fulfillment process
look like?
That's, that's homework for you.
Can you give an example of how you
reward a desired action?
When do you bring it up?
And how do you phrase it?
Do you offer ongoing incentives?
Yeah, so again, like, if I know
that going through our sales
training will get them better
results,
I'll tell them if they go through
the training, they'll get a
discount, or they'll get, you
know, a $100 gift card,
or they'll get free bonuses that
they would otherwise not get if
they don't do it.
So that's all you really do to
reward desired behavior.
What's the best way to phrase a
client that you need them to do X,
Y, and Z?
Grant access, pay invoice, signed
contracts, sent assets, or else
you'll need to delay the current
timeframe.
It's, yeah, like, it's literally
like, hey, I want to make sure
that we get this launched for you
as soon as possible.
And we, we help you achieve your
desired goals and outcomes as fast
as possible.
And for, in order for that to
happen, I need X, Y, and Z.
Can you, you know, please get that
done, or can you please commit to
doing that?
So it's joint accountability.
It's always tying the things that
you need them to do back to their
desired outcome.
Okay.
Insight into tech recommendations
for 15 to 25K company.
Task management, I would do
Trello, knowledge base, Google
Docs, communication, Slack.
Those are the three.
My current business, I handle
sales and marketing.
He's, he handles fulfillment and
hiring.
Perfect.
Yes.
That's, that's the exact way you
should structure a business
partnership is someone should be
sales and marketing and someone
should be hiring and fulfillment.
I do hiring and fulfillment.
Dan does sales and Christian and
Daniel do marketing.
So we have even more co-founders.
But yeah, that's a good way to go.
What percentage of project revenue
do you suggest for CSM?
I mentioned that in one of the
slides.
Seven and a half to 12 and a half
percent.
It's going to vary depending on
the type of business and how
involved they are in the delivery
of the project.
But anywhere from seven and a half
to 12 and a half percent is
usually good.
But don't take those numbers, you
know, and run with them without
doing your own thought experiment
and calculating ROI and margins
and profit and all this sort of
stuff.
But at least that's a range that's
worked for me.
I run an email marketing agency
for e-com brands and have two team
members, tons of action items out
of this.
What would you say are the biggest
needle movers trying to figure out
what to prioritize?
Start with a 72-hour task audit
and even have your two team
members go through the 72-hour
task audit.
That'll give you a lot of clarity
on where you should spend your
time or where you're currently
spending your time and how that
needs to change.
Okay.
72-hour task audit is usually
where I would recommend anyone
start.
If you're confused, I'm like, I
don't know, based on this
presentation, what to do first
because it all sounds important.
Otherwise, like, if you're pretty
set on what your day-to-day looks
like right now and you're signing
clients but the onboarding is not
good,
like, onboarding is a great place
to start.
Or if you have a bunch of clients
and you're scared that they're
going to churn,
focus on, like, the weekly update
system and improving your
proactive communication, right?
How do you balance progress is
better than results and operations
with client and the results
promised in your offers that sales
and marketing put out there to
your clients?
Actually, the best way, the best
part about what Daniel teaches is
an offer with stipulations.
Stipulations are progress
milestones.
You can't get the guarantee
without doing the stipulations,
right?
You can't get results without
first seeing progress.
It's not just start, result.
It's start, progress, progress,
progress, progress, progress,
result.
And the offer is, it's guarantee.
It's not just you sign up,
guarantee.
It's you sign up and then
stipulation, stipulation,
stipulation, guarantee.
So it's the same thing.
It's just we call it performance
or, sorry, progress, milestones,
and results instead of
stipulations and a guarantee.
For context, you want to call the
email agency.
I want to know if the focus should
now be on AI or actual people, for
example.
Some low leverage activities.
I'm a big proponent of AI is best
to assist existing team.
It's to get more out of your
current headcount.
So the answer is, most of the
time, you should hire someone to
then manage the AI.
So AI is going to allow you to get
more out of your human team
members.
I'm a new agency owner, so I'm a
first client.
About two weeks ago, I've been
focusing on and been making a lot
of mistakes on fulfillment.
What should I focus on?
Focus on onboarding to start and
then focus on ongoing engagement,
which happens through that
communications framework that I
spent like the first half of the
presentation on.
I'm currently stuck on how to
properly onboard clients into my
content agency.
Do you have experience on that?
On what answers to ask in order to
give them the best scripting that
is tailored to them?
That's tough because I don't run a
content agency.
But like, how to properly onboard?
Do you have experience on what
answers to ask in order to give
them the best scripting that's
tailored to them?
Yeah, I mean, I guess reverse
engineer success.
If you have content that's doing
well or if you have clients that
are doing really well, what from
those clients enables you to
create really good content for
them?
Like, what do you know about those
clients that if you knew for the
rest of the clients would help you
write better scripts or create
better content for them?
It's usually like the obvious
things that like, what do you
create content about?
Like personal anecdotes and
stories, previous failures and how
you were able to overcome them,
success and accomplishments.
Just pure tactics and training.
What's your offer?
You know, what do you help people
with?
These sorts of things.
Getting clarity on that is usually
a good starting point.
At what point should you take the
initiative to offer a client?
How do you offer a client?
Smoothly.
When they become a problem child,
essentially, just like they
complain, they're too demanding
and it's worth getting your time
back more than it is getting paid
from them.
You have to have somewhat of a
tolerance, though, to put up with
pain in the ass clients because
there will be a decent amount of
pain in the ass clients.
And that's the reality of running
a business.
And that's okay.
That's why we have frameworks like
setting proper boundaries that I
taught you on this call so that
even if you have pain in the ass
clients, at least they're not, you
know, wrecking the way you go
about living your life.
How do you offer a client
smoothly?
You just let them know, like,
look, like you do it through email
or on a call and you just let them
know that, like, respectfully.
What you want from us is not
something that we can deliver on.
And I don't think it's fair for
you to continue paying us money.
And I just don't think we're the
best service providers for what
you're looking for.
So best of luck with what you're,
you know, going to do next.
But that's it from us.
Can hire internationally or can I
only hire locally?
You can hire international.
Like I said, we have team members
from Lebanon, from remotelyx.com.
And I have team members in other
areas in the Middle East.
I have team members in Portugal,
some team members in the U.S.,
some in Canada, some in the U.K.
We have team members all over the
place.
So, yeah, you can do that.
No problem.
Is hiring for sales, delivery, or
admin of first priority?
Well, if you can't deliver work,
then why hire for a salesperson?
Because you're just going to sell
more people into a system that's
broken or actually just doesn't
have capacity.
So delivery is usually top
priority.
Unless, you know, you can handle
10 more clients, but you're just
not getting those 10 clients, then
hire for sales.
You just got to hire where you
actually have the need.
We don't have time for a screen
share right now.
I got a couple more questions in
here.
How has your experience been with
overseas talent and what should
cost expectations be roughly?
My experience with overseas talent
is they're as good as any other
talent I've worked with.
I have some of the guys that I
work with from Lebanon on this
call right now, and they're some
of the smartest people I've ever
worked with.
So, yeah, like, I would 100%
recommend working with people from
Lebanon, at least, as a starting
point.
I have experience working with
people from Canada, from the UK,
from Portugal.
The people I work with, it doesn't
really matter where they're from.
They're all really good.
In terms of cost, it's going to
vary based on location, but you
can hire people for as low as
$1,000 a month, part-time, most
likely, from somewhere like
Lebanon.
I provide video editing services.
Should I hire for someone to do
outreach for me or someone to do
the editing for me?
I mean, it's like a chicken before
the egg, right?
What came first?
You need clients to do designs
for.
So, if you don't have clients,
then do outreach.
And then if you have too many
clients to do editing for, hire
people on the delivery side.
Could you share the original doc
so we can make a copy of it?
What is the original doc?
Yeah, we'll send everything in a
follow-up email.
Whatever's in the chat is what we
have right now, but we'll send
everything.
The Gamma doc and the Google doc
in a follow-up email for you guys.
Okay, the Gamma doc.
I'm pretty sure the Gamma doc is
in the Google doc that I sent.
It's hyperlinked.
Yep.
It's hyperlinked in the Google
doc, like I pointed out.
A couple more.
Do you hire employees or are they
contractors?
Everyone that I hire is an
independent contractor,
technically.
So, independent contractor.
How do you track A players if you
only pay on performance?
Well, you make the performance
incentives really rewarding so
that they end up making more money
if they perform than they would if
they were in a consistent base
salary role.
And A players love to be rewarded
for their performance.
A players are actually attracted
to performance-based pay because
they know that their performance
is what will make them the most
money.
They're entrepreneurial is the
best way to describe it.
The doc is shared.
How do you do performance for VA
manual work that's needed to fill
the, like, how do you determine
the value of that?
It just depends.
What is the work?
What is the work that you're
hiring for?
There's not like a, oh, just pay
them this much or hire them this
way.
Like, there's not a, if this, then
that answer to that question.
You have to think smarter about
it.
What tools do you use to manage
tasks, work, and clients?
Really, again, like Google
Workspace, Trello, Slack.
That's it.
Are you hiring people full-time?
I almost never hire people
part-time.
Pretty much everyone that works at
any of our businesses is full-time
because they're fully invested
into their work at our business.
If you don't have capacity or you
just don't need someone full-time,
then you can start someone off
part-time.
Like, for a graphic designer, for
your email, like, yeah, they only
need to do, you know, 10 hours of
graphic design work every single
week.
Just pay them per email design.
And if they do 10, they make X
amount of money.
If they do 100, they make, you
know, 100 or 10 times that amount.
So, do you think that a contract's
always required?
Yes.
Test?
Okay.
Have you integrated AI into your
ops yet?
Yes.
Again, AI is a tool.
It's a sidekick to make your
existing team members more
productive.
So, that's how you should always
be thinking about it.
Most people think about AI as,
like, how can I outsource all of
my work using AI?
It's just not realistic.
How can I enable my team to
deliver higher quality work, more
volume of work, more consistently
on time, without changing anything
about the amount of time that they
spend working on the business?
Well, using AI, right?
That's how you should think about
it.
Do you think a performance offer
can scale at the same time as a
retainer offer?
If you're performing and if you've
found, you know, a system in which
you can consistently perform, but
in terms of, like, long-term
scalability, you'll find that most
agencies are retainer-based.
For the most part, maybe they're
retainer-based performance, but
you have, for the most part as
well, you have to start
performance-based.
Otherwise, no one's going to pay
you a retainer if you don't have
proper experience and expertise.
When hiring for CSM, are you
vetting for client success or
project management?
Do you have a job ad example?
When hiring for CSM, you're
looking for people skills, really,
because they're just doing
communication, right?
Like, they're not really doing
project management.
They're streamlining
communications between whoever's
doing the actual service delivery
and the client, right?
So, like, they're that bridge.
They're a connector.
They're a really effective
communicator.
How do you set up contracts for
clients and independent
contractors?
Do you make them one page max?
Most of them are much longer than
one page, and we have business
attorneys.
I'm not a lawyer or an attorney,
so I don't do that.
I outsource that to an actual
lawyer so that everything that
needs to be in the contract for an
independent contractor
or for a client relationship is
covered fully.
But, all right, that's it, guys.
We're at time.
That was a marathon, an hour and a
half of systems, operations, and
fulfillment sauce.
Hopefully, you guys got some
value.
And, again, last reminder for,
like, the 50 people who are still
on here.
Tomorrow is going to be the most
valuable day out of this entire
challenge by far.
Like, if you thought today was
good, if you thought yesterday
with Dan was good, if you thought
Tuesday with Christian was good,
if you thought Monday with Daniel
was good, tomorrow is going to be
even better, if that's even
possible.
And it's going to be Daniel to
start, but me, Dan, Christian, and
Daniel, all four of us will be on
there.
So it's going to be a lot of fun.
Like, that call, I so look forward
to it, and I hope to see every
single one of you on there from
start to finish.
It is quite literally, like, the
most valuable call that we host,
like, ever.
So, yeah, tomorrow can't come soon
enough.
And I hope to see all of you guys
there, and I hope that today's
session was valuable.
Thanks so much.
God bless.
See you all tomorrow.
Peace.