All right.
So what is a contract?
We're going to talk about client
contracts and just kind
of like how all this works.
So it's a formalized agreement
between two parties outlining deal
terms, right?
So like payments, if there's a
guarantee, what's being done, like
bullshit
like that.
So the contract examples I'm
giving you are example contracts.
Your use of them
does not constitute me giving you
legal advice.
This is not legal advice.
Use them at your
own risk.
Consult the lawyer of your own for
legal advice.
My providing of these example
contracts is merely to illustrate
how a contract works and provide
an example.
If you were
to use them, it would require
editing to adjust to your specific
situation and specific offer
being sold.
Have I taken example contracts
from the internet or chat GPT and
use them myself
personally in the past?
Yes.
I now personally do not do that
since I can afford an actual
lawyer to write mine.
Proceed with that information as
you will.
All right, cool.
So proceeding
forward.
So this is just an example of a
marketing funnel build out
contract between, it's going
to be using a retainer with no
refunds, right?
And then I'll show you another
example as well.
So just staying in disagreement is
entered into as of date.
So what you'd want to do here
is, and the links to these would
be below as well.
So what you would want to do,
you'd want
to take these, copy everything, or
just go to file, make a copy.
It's entered into as of here by in
between client and agency.
This would be a name field.
This would be a name field here
for yourself.
So the way this works is you
probably want to use DocuSign.
I think DocuSign is cheap.
We use
PandaDoc.
PandaDoc is more expensive.
But generally people tend to use
DocuSign because of how cheap it
is.
So what you do, the way contracts
work is that you upload, you would
literally like go to file,
you'd go to download, and then you
would, you would download it as a
PDF.
And what you would do inside
of a contract software is you'd
upload the PDF.
And now it will take you through
what's called field
mapping.
So what you would do right here is
you put a field, it's a field
mapping and like person
mapping.
So like for instance, you'd upload
it.
You'd be like, okay, two people
are signing this
contract.
Client is signing the contract and
I'm signing the contract.
So right here, you'd put
date.
And then you, I would assign the
date field to yourself.
Then you would put a name field
here,
right here.
You would assign the name field to
the client.
And then you'd have a name field
here
that's assigned to you.
So let's, let's go through scope
of work.
Agency agrees to deliver the
following.
So this is just where you list
your deliverables.
Here's what I'm actually doing for
you.
So this has like an example of an
appendix where it shows like
project specific,
specifications.
I personally never used this to be
honest with you.
It's, it's there just,
just to be there.
You can remove it.
You can leave it, but you got to
understand that you would,
you would need to use the
appendix.
So this is, this is like a, for
instance, where you'd want to use
this if you specifically wanted to
use a certain software.
So like if you were building a
funnel for
someone and you wanted to use
click funnels, like this is saying
that we got to use, we got to use
click funnels, right?
Cause you don't want the client
coming in and say, Hey, I actually
want
to do this.
But when you only know click
funnels or some shit, you get what
I'm saying?
So timeline
project will begin upon receipt of
the initial payment and the client
submission of all required
information assets, estimated
completion.
And you'd have, um, you'd have a,
uh, uh, a thing right
here.
Um, you, you just assign another
field for weeks to yourself.
Now you could just not have
that.
You can, you, you, you could
theoretically just remove that.
And it's just like vague about
the completion time.
So, um, client responsibilities.
Um, this is what you're requiring
the client to do.
They need to, they need to do all
of this.
Payment terms, ongoing fee, X per
month.
There are no
refunds for any reason.
Um, revisions.
They can revise things two times.
Additional revisions are about
a 200 hour.
Upon final payment for each month,
all those become the property to
client.
Um, you can see
what deliver the assets outline,
but does not guarantee specific
results, such as lead volume,
cost per, uh, lead sales or
revenue, unless explicitly stated
in separate written agreement.
So again, this is a non, this is a
non-refund, uh, contract
confidentiality.
Um, you can't share
the shit termination.
Who, when can the thing be
terminated?
Limitation of liability.
You're not
responsible for shit.
Um, governing law.
Um, I live in Florida.
I put Florida, put your state
there,
um, or country that, that, that
works, that works too.
So this agreement, um,
um, so this is just saying the,
the, the entire agreement applies.
So now this, this is where
you would set, like, I would make
this, I want to make this a little
bigger.
So again,
this is where you'd set a
signature field for the client and
you'd assign the signature field
to the client.
Then you'd have a date field here.
You'd assign that date field to
the client.
And then
you have yours down here, which is
a signature field you'd assign to
yourself.
And then a date
field you'd assign to yourself.
And then what happens is you
upload this and you send the
contract.
And then what will happen is like
you assigned you yourself as the
agency.
So you put
your email address there, bam, you
sign the contract and then they
sign the contract and then the
contract is fully executed.
And then that, that's it.
Right.
So now here's an example of one
where
it's a performance guarantee.
Um, there's a, there's a
performance fee and a guarantee,
right?
So there's all fucking different
kinds of ways that, that, that,
that you, you could write
these things, but I'm just, I'm
just showing you these examples to
help you understand like how
things could be presented.
Right.
So for instance, um, it's pretty
much all the same except for a
couple of things.
So like performance guarantee
agency guarantees that the client
will sign at least
three clients of their own per
month, provided that the client
strictly adheres to the
eligibility
requirements outlined in section
three.
If the client does not sign at
least three clients in a given
month or request a refund, the
terms in section four apply.
So, okay, now we have section
three
eligibility requirements.
To qualify for the, for the
performance guarantee, the client
must spend at
least $10,000 per month in ad
spend paid by the client, not the
agency.
Maintain a minimum 15%
sales call closing rate in all
calls booked by the agency.
Maintain an active ad account in
good
standing throughout the agreement.
Maintain at least eight hours of
availability each business day for
sales call scheduled by the
agency.
Failure to meet any of these
requirements voids the performance
guarantee.
Okay.
So refund policy.
If the client requests a refund
due to failure to sign three
clients in a month, the following
conditions apply.
The client must provide proof of
ad spend of at
least $10,000 for that month.
Sales call recordings of all calls
booked by the agency.
Proof that the ad
account is active in good
standing.
Login access to all the sales call
scheduling tools.
If the client
cannot provide all four items, the
refund request is denied.
Refunds are limited to the last 30
days of work
only.
Performance fees paid are
non-refundable under any
circumstances.
Payment terms.
Base fee,
$5,000 per month.
Performance fee, 10% of gross
revenue generated from agency's
activities.
Gross
revenue is defined as cash
collected from agency's efforts
minus ad spend.
Performance fees are due
within seven days of each month.
Failure to pay within seven days
means that the agency reserves the
right to pause all advertising
activity.
14 days, agency reserves the right
to delete the funnel created for
the client.
These are the client's
responsibilities.
Intellectual property.
Funnels, ad creatives, and email
sequences remain the property of
the agency until all fees based in
performance are paid in full.
Upon full
payment, ownership of deliverables
transfers to client.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, again, I'm not a lawyer.
Like, you can write the shit
whichever fuck way.
Like, you can upload it to ChatGPT
and fuck with it if you
want it to.
But that's not, it's not my, I'm
not giving you legal advice.
You get what I'm saying?
Like, I'm just
trying to convey to you, like,
it's part, like, a part of a deal
with the client are the deal
terms, right?
So you might hear this,
like, if you ever, like, if
everyone teaches you real estate,
you're getting involved in, like,
real estate investing.
Like, real estate investors like
to say this thing where it's,
like, it's not
all about the price.
It's also about the terms.
Like, sometimes terms of contracts
are, like, big
negotiation points where, like,
you can do certain things and,
like, you get what I'm saying?
I'm just
providing these as examples to
you.
And you can fuck with them if you
want to, right?
But yeah,
the links to them will be in the
description.
Peace.