What's going on guys?
Welcome back to another video.
Andre here and I apologize for the
past
few videos or majority of my
videos in this program to be
honest.
I just found that video
having my video on as part of the
video can sometimes be
distracting.
So I've just been
doing screenshots for the most
part to keep your focus and
attention to what's actually
on the screen which is the most
important piece of it because a
lot of this a lot of
the things I'm teaching is very
visual.
But anyways, in this video what
we're going to be
covering is how to ask the right
questions in your onboarding form.
So in the previous video
we walked through the onboarding
process and what actually happens
once you get a contract
signed by your client and
basically the process you should
take them through.
And part of that
process was sending them a link to
fill out an onboarding form.
So you're basically as soon
as you sign a client for most
services you got to assign them
homework because to fulfill
on a service you got to have a
formal manner on your client to be
able to do a sufficient
job.
So like for our agency we do lead
generation and just like what you
learn in module two or three
was in the lead generation module
of the program.
You have to know your offer and
you have to know the
target market otherwise lead
generation is going to fail
miserably.
So for us to do lead generation
for other
businesses we basically have to
put them through questions that
tell us exactly what you guys were
telling us as part of this program
in the lead generation module.
So you'll see throughout our
onboarding form us asking those
questions.
And the biggest thing before we
get into it
is like don't be afraid to ask a
bunch of questions in your
onboarding form like I see a lot
of agencies
just like keep their onboarding
forms really short and brief
because they don't want to make it
like
a hassle for the client to go
through the process.
But what I'm telling you is that
this is just another
sign like this is just another way
to really lock your client into a
committed relationship
not a romantic relationship but a
business relationship where
they're just you're basically
training them to be an active
partner as you're working
together.
And that is just such a core
component of having success with
your clients.
It's like it's just something that
you would not really
think about because everyone's so
focused on how do I get results?
How do I get results?
Well, it starts
with these very basic things like
filling out an onboarding form or
collecting an onboarding form
that answers the most important
questions that you need to get
answered in order to actually
fulfill
and execute on things.
So the onboarding form is
basically like to be honest one of
the only chances
you'll get to basically convince
the client to sit down and fill
out this long form.
Trust me like
we've come up with more questions
and variations to our onboarding
form.
And once you get a lot of
clients, it becomes extremely
difficult to get them to fill out
the new parts of an onboarding
form or
just to fill out anything.
It's like slower and you have to
chase down the clients and it's
going to take
a lot of time.
So really think through this
process and use your onboarding
form.
The onboarding form,
again, is your chance to collect
all the information you could ever
need on your client and keep it on
file to properly and efficiently
fulfill on the services that you
sold to them.
So again, for us,
for lead generation, the whole
point of this onboarding form is
obviously to collect general
information about our new client
so that we could contact them,
invoice them, all that great
stuff,
and then ask all the important
questions that relate to our
campaign.
So we basically break off
our onboarding form into three
sections.
The first section is just general
contact information.
The
second is like basically asking
them a bunch of questions about
their business.
And then the third
and the last section is like their
goals.
So this is another important one
that you'll see how we frame it
and set it up towards the end of
this video, which is asking what
their goals are for working with
us.
So like what results are you
currently seeing and what results
you hope to see as a result of
working
with our agency.
So that's how we set up our
onboarding form.
Of course, you could take a
different format
or strategy here.
But the biggest thing to make note
of is that the onboarding form is
one of your most
valuable tools because you're just
going to collect a ton of
information on your clients
and be able to share it with your
entire team.
You're going to want to study it,
obviously,
so that when you get on that
onboarding call, you know
everything about your client
because they just
spilled the beans on everything.
So you just want to become you
basically are now part of this.
You basically want to treat your
client's business as your own.
So learn everything there is to
learn
about their business by asking the
right questions.
And again, you've heard me say
this already a few
times in this module.
And I think this is our strongest
module because we stand out so
much compared to
other agencies.
We just do it the right way on all
on all cylinders.
We fire out all cylinders.
Like they say we get complimented
on this a lot like the onboarding
form.
Most of the clients that sign
on with us enjoy going through it
so much because it forces them to
think deeper or to answer
questions
that they never even considered
asking themselves about their
business.
So like the onboarding form
is actually a great practice for
you even to fill out on your own
like my onboarding form
specifically
for KnowledgeX.
I would encourage you to fill it
out or to consider some of the
questions in here
because it could really help you
to define your business and get
really clear on what it is you do
and who it is you're targeting
just to extend on some of the
things you learned in the lead
generation
module.
But anyways, the onboarding form,
it's there for you to get all the
answers to all the questions
you could possibly come up with in
order to fulfill your services,
your clients.
And in terms of logistics,
it's really simple.
Like you see on the screen here,
we're just inside of Google Docs,
and we just create a new Google
form.
I added like our banner logo to
the top.
And all you do
after setting up the questions,
it's really simple.
Like you could add different
sections, you could add
questions.
And then in the question, you
could just do like a, you could,
you could do all different
types of questions and answers.
You can make them required or not
required.
You could delete them.
Tons of different options here.
So it's very custom.
And then once it's done, all you
do is you hit send.
And then you copy this link.
So anyone who has this link, they
just paste it into their browser.
And it just looks it's very
professional, like it's really
easy to use, easy to read.
And then the best,
best part is anytime we get a
response, we get an email
notification about it from Google.
So we don't
have to set up any crazy
automations.
All you do for that is you click
these three dots, or actually, you
go to you go to
settings, I believe.
Yeah, I believe you go to
settings, or I'm honestly not even
sure anymore.
I'll figure out where to go
for that.
I think you go to responses, I
just don't want to open responses,
because there's a lot of
sensitive information in there, as
you can imagine.
But you just go to responses.
And you could you could
both create a an Excel sheet out
of this so that all the people
that go through it, you can
basically get
their information in an organized
Excel sheet.
And then you could go through each
response on an
individual level, and either print
it out as a PDF, which is what we
do.
And we onboard that to the
Trello board, because it's really
easy to just open up a PDF, and
see both the questions and then
the
answers written below it, just
like a Google Doc would be.
So it's really simple, the
logistics, just
using something like Google Forms.
I know a few people that use
Typeform, and they just prefer
that.
So
whatever you're comfortable with,
use it.
And if you're new to this, I would
just say,
stick to Google Forms.
It's just like Google Docs or
anything else.
And you don't have to have
anything really on here.
I guess the only thing I would, I
would urge you to do is customize
it a
little bit.
So it's on brand, like with a logo
and with your coloring and
anything else like that.
So anyways, what I want to do for
the remainder of this video is
walk you through each of the
questions in our onboarding form,
and just explain why we ask it and
why we ask it in that order.
And
just try to basically explain the
reasoning behind each part of this
form so that you can take it and
learn the strategies and the
foundations and the fundamentals
and apply it to your own
onboarding
form.
So whether you're offering
Facebook ads, whether you're
offering email marketing, whether
you're
offering web design, or you're
like a staffing agency and you're
helping place people with
companies,
like doesn't matter what your
agency business is, you're always
going to want an onboarding form
for
new clients to fill out like right
away.
It's like the first thing they
should do.
So anyways,
at the very beginning, very
simply, we asked for their email
that just helps us keep track of
everything.
We also asked for their name, who
asked for their phone number to
reach out for business purposes,
just in case like sometimes it's,
it's difficult, or we have trouble
contacting clients through Slack
and
through email.
So if there's ever like an
emergency, or we're just not able
to get in touch with one of
our clients after a long time, we
at least have their phone number
as backup.
We also asked for their full
address of their business office
that's just used for like
invoicing.
So when we invoice our clients,
we could use your full name.
We also have their address and we,
it's just a little bit more
legitimatized and it helps with
like a fraud detection on our
billing software.
We also use that
since we're doing cold email
outreach, we use their address in
our email signatures sometimes to
help
with deliverability.
So it's just helpful information
to have on hand.
And it's also helpful to know
also the time zones.
So like when you're sending
emails, like I live in New York,
so my emails are
sending off from like 8am to 8pm
Eastern time.
And if our client's business
office is in California,
we'd want to do the same thing 8am
to 8pm, but it'd be Pacific time
or whatever time zone that their
business office is located in.
So that, that question asking for
their address has a few different
use
cases.
Right.
We also asked for their website,
which is pretty straightforward
because their website's
going to have a ton of
information.
We asked for their LinkedIn
profile URL.
And then we asked for
credentials.
So like if you, if you need access
to certain accounts, the
onboarding form is a great
place to actually go out and get
that.
So we asked what their LinkedIn
profile URL is.
We asked what
their account email is.
We asked what their account
password is.
And then we ask if they have an
active
Calendly account, because we need
Calendly to perform our services.
And if they do, we ask what
their email is and what their
password is.
And if they answer no, we just add
that to our to-do list of
things we have to do for them,
which is to sign up for a Calendly
account.
So if you need login
information, like if you're doing
SEO and you need access to like
their website or to their backend,
this would be the place to ask.
If you're doing lead generation
and you need access to their
LinkedIn
profile, you could do a very
similar thing like we did here
with both LinkedIn.
And even if you need
access to Calendly, whatever you
need access to in terms of login
credentials, this is a great place
to
do it, which is just the
onboarding form.
We've never really had a client
saying, Hey, I'm not comfortable
putting my password here.
And if they do, we've, I guess,
actually I'd say we've had it
maybe two or
three times.
And anytime that happens, as soon
as we get on the onboarding call,
we address it.
And
we're like, Hey, when we were
going through your onboarding
form, you didn't give us your
LinkedIn
password.
Mind if you spell that for us here
on the call and we could type it
into Trello.
So it's,
it's stored there.
So anyways, that is the first
section.
So again, just really basic
information
about their business.
That's, that's the first section.
The second section is more about
their
business, but like in an offer in
targeting sense.
So like you'll start to see these
questions get a
lot more complex and detail
oriented.
So the first question is really
generic.
It's like, who do you
help?
What result can you get them?
Is there a specific timeframe?
How do you get these results?
Please answer all these questions
in fine detail.
So basically this first question
is starting to get
them to think like, who do I help?
What results do I get?
How long does it take me to get
results?
How do I get those results?
And they're starting to consider
these questions.
It's like a good way to
ease them into our form.
So this is all like, if we could
answer these questions on an
individual level,
who do you help?
What result can you get them?
Is there a specific timeframe?
And also,
how do you get these results?
We're going to be golden.
It's going to be really easy for
us to
do our job.
Like we could write scripts for
that, uh, really easily if we have
answers to all these
questions.
So that's the first one.
It just kind of opens things up
and then we get more detail
oriented into the target market or
their ideal client profile.
So I say, who exactly is your
target
market?
In other words, who would you like
for us to send personalized
messages to?
What are
their job titles?
Tell us everything you know about
them, location, revenue, company
size, job title,
industry, etc.
Please provide detailed answers
for all of these subcategory
questions for optimal results.
So also the way we word this, the
questions is we're explaining like
the reasoning behind the
questions too.
And a lot of the times, and we're
also spelling it out.
It's not just like, who is your
target market?
What are their job titles?
What is their revenue?
Like we're actually adding some
commentary
to it.
So they're not like confused
because some of the times you
might have a question in mind that
you
want to ask.
And it doesn't, it might not
translate or make total sense to
the client and they might
answer it in a way that you didn't
really intend them to answer it.
So you just want to be really
clear with your wording and
language throughout your
onboarding form.
So that's the second question.
A third question we ask is, are
these companies you'd like for us
to target with your campaigns,
hiring for any specific roles that
would give us insight into their
need for your offer?
So this is just like, if we, if
they wanted to target people by
active job posts, like if they're
targeting companies, hiring for
salespeople or targeting
companies, hiring for developers,
like this is especially true for
like the staffing industry or the
recruiting industry is targeting,
like having your ideal client
profile, having like vacancies or
job openings.
So that's a question
we ask to get more detailed and
more targeted with our campaigns
and our strategy.
So we're just using
all these questions to formulate a
strategy for this client so that
we could get the best results
possible.
And I'll tell you the clients that
take the most time to fill out the
onboarding form
responses and get us all the
answers we need in the, in like a
very detailed way, always do the
best,
like always do the best because we
just have so much to go off of.
The next question we ask is,
do your prospects use any specific
technologies that you know of that
we can base our targeting on?
So like, this is very, uh, common
for email marketing agencies, like
they're targeting
e-commerce brands that use Shopify
and Klaviyo.
So that's what that question is
there for specifically.
Sometimes we'll have clients
target like people using
Salesforce, whatever it might be.
Um, this is again, another
question specific to our service
that we like to ask to get more
clarity
on how do we find the best quality
leads for the, for our new client?
Like what are,
who are they really looking to get
in touch with?
And then the next thing we do
is say, uh, please provide us a
list of many keywords as possible,
uh, that we can use a scan
for when building a list of ideal
prospects in your target market to
send personalized messages to.
For example, if you're targeting
SEO and keywords such as SEO would
work well.
Um, and you could also add
like, this is like a sub
description or a, yeah, just a
description here that explains
what you're
asking in a little more detail.
So we just say, we'll scan their
social media pages and SEO website
descriptions for these keywords to
help them understand.
Like what types of keywords
they should include essentially.
So that's another question.
So all these, these last few
questions
are just getting really specific
to, uh, target market and just
targeting and ideal client
profiling
in general.
So you'll probably recognize some
of these questions, uh, or just
understand some of the terms
used throughout, uh, based on what
you learned in, in the lead
generation module.
And again,
I would encourage you to actually
like go through our onboarding
form because it could really help
you
with your lead gen, uh, just to
help answer some questions that
you might not have considered yet.
Uh, the next question we ask is
just asking if they have a list of
prospects to start with.
Um, so like some clients will come
in and they'll have a list of
companies that they want to get
like they want to target.
So if they do, we basically just
tell them to email us with the
data
and then we tell them the process
we'll take from there so that they
know like it's all in our hands
after they just send us the file,
which is basically saying, we'll
take it all off your
hands.
Just send us the file and we'll go
from there.
So again, it's just very detailed.
It's
just walking them through
literally our entire process.
Cause once we onboard a client,
we have to onboard them.
And then in the backend strategy
wise, we're devising a strategy
for their
target market and who to target
and how to build a search around
that.
And then we're devising a
strategy around scripting and how
do we write scripts or write copy
that get the target market's
attention that we're going after.
And literally all these questions
are helping us to do just that.
Cause we don't know, like we're
not experts about these businesses
yet because it's, it's not our
business, but it is our business
to know and know as much as
possible about these businesses as
possible.
Um, I said, it's possible like
three times, I think in that
sentence,
but anyways, uh, to, to ensure
that we get them the best possible
results.
And I said possible again,
anyways, um, before we move on,
we, we have like one of these book
end questions.
So like, what I've seen is, uh,
throughout this onboarding form,
like after a
few questions, it could get blurry
and like shorter types of answers
towards the end.
So like, I basically like to
separate many sections using
questions like this, like, Hey,
just take a second to tell us and
confirm whether or not you
provided as much information as
you could
think of to the target market
question.
So it's just them taking a step
back to say, all right,
let me go back and read, read,
reread these questions and see if
there's anything else I could
think of
that they might, you know, see as
being helpful.
So that question, it could come
off as like
being a little forward, but I
found it to be super helpful for
them to just go back and say,
all right, wait, I'm kind of
zooming through this.
Let me see if there's any more
detail I should add to
really these first few questions.
After that question, it's like,
again, like a checkpoint.
Now we pivot to their offer so
that we know how to explain their
offer and our messaging.
So we say,
what exactly do you sell to your
target market?
Explain it in very fine detail.
Tell us everything
in your own commentary, as many
details as possible.
Then we go into, again, questions
very specific to
our agency.
So like scripting.
So again, it's a little bit easier
for you to understand since
there is a whole section on lead
generation.
So you understand now what our
business does,
like what our service offering is,
which is just to do cold email and
LinkedIn outreach on behalf of
our clients to get them on the
phone with who they define in the
previous questions to be their
target
market or ideal client profile.
And in order to do that, we need
them to define their ideal client
profile.
And we need them to define their
offer so that we could write
really specific and high
converting scripts.
So we also say here, like our
scripting is question based.
With that said,
are there any questions you could
think of that your prospects would
be likely to respond to?
Think about a scenario where you
were cold calling a prospect, what
questions would you ask them?
So
again, these questions are super
unique.
They're not just like,
are like, what questions would you
ask someone on a cold call?
Like we're explaining, we're
putting
them in our shoes so that they
could understand the use case
behind each of these questions as
well,
which incentivizes them more to
actually take the time to fill out
each of these questions with as
much detail as possible.
The next question we ask is like a
great question that really helps
like
overcome objections or formulate
different parts of our script,
which is to say, what are some
problems
your ideal clients have that you
can solve for them?
Or in other words, please share at
least three to
five pain points your clients are,
excuse me, are known to have.
So let me just pause this.
Yeah.
So that question is super helpful
because they'll just list out a
bunch of problems that we
could call out in our scripting or
in our like some of the questions
we ask through email and through
LinkedIn.
So just knowing the problems that
the ideal client is most likely
dealing with or facing
is a super powerful piece of
information to have, at least for
us to perform our services.
So again,
whatever it is you're offering at
your agency, just think what
information do I absolutely need
to have
on each of the clients that I'm
working with to make sure that I
get them the best possible
experience and results by working
with me and just think through it.
Like every just basically
think through, okay, I onboard a
client.
What do I actually have to do?
I have, I know for my agency,
I got to get them a list of leads.
So I got to know what kind of
leads they want.
And I got to know
everything about those types of
leads and the companies and the
size and the revenue and the
industry
and the keywords, right?
Like we already asked and went
through in our form.
And then once I have a
list, I got to write a series of
scripts, like to do the lead
generation and the outreach.
So to write
scripts, I have to know about
their offer.
I also have to know about their
guarantees.
I also have to
know about the problems they
solve.
I also have to know about any
results they've gotten or case
studies,
which we're just about to get to
here.
So the next question is asking
them to type out results
they've gotten for their clients
and if they've profited from
working with them, what niches
they were in and how did they
become a client in the first
place.
So there's actually a lot of
questions packed in here, which is
just basically all geared towards
what results are you able to
generate?
Because if someone that's a common
question and it's also one of the
most powerful pieces of
information to use and leverage
and sales and in general is just
social proof and results like
proof
of results that are in demand or
desirable by other people in the
same industry that you're already
reaching out to based on all the
information you collected in
previous questions about their
target market.
So that's a great question.
The next question is a little more
specific.
We're asking for an actual case
study
and what positive results they're
able to get with that person's
case study and we're asking them
to
use a framework that we provided
for them below.
So we wrote out this whole
framework and gave them,
I think, three examples of how
that framework is supposed to be
used and basically said,
okay, now that you see a few
examples of how this framework
works, give us a few case studies
using
that framework.
And the reason we asked him to do
it in that framework is because
that's part of
our script.
So we don't even have to think
twice.
Most of the time, we might brush
up a few words
and cut things out and just make
things read a little bit smoother
to fit into the overall email
or the overall script that this is
going to be inserted into.
But other than that, there's
different
things you can do in your
onboarding form responses like
this, where like the intention is
for them to
write a part of the script that
you're working on, or at least
give you like a starting point for
that
script.
So that question is super helpful.
The next two questions, again,
also very helpful.
Like,
do you have any guarantee to your
clients?
And if so, what is it?
Because guarantees are super easy
to
leverage when you're in sales.
Like what is the biggest issue
people face in sales is they're
trying to build
trust and get someone to commit
because the person doesn't want to
take on risk.
So if you can mitigate
risk and build trust by offering a
guarantee, and if we're aware of
that guarantee, we can leverage
that
really strongly.
So that's why we asked that
question.
And then the last question, again,
super, super important is what
makes you unique and different
from your competitors?
You're always
going to want to know this about
your clients because you're going
to want to, you're going to
want to press on that a lot and
capitalize on it.
It's like, what is unique and
different about your
client compared to everyone else
in their market that's trying to
grow at the same pace or at a
faster pace, or that's already 10
times the size of their business
and still looking to aggressively
grow?
Like how does your client stand
out and differentiate from clients
that are businesses that are half
the size or businesses that are 10
times the size?
How do they survive?
Why do they deserve
to survive?
What about them is different and
unique?
And if you can get a clear answer
to this, again,
it's just so much leverage.
And especially for lead
generation, because that's like
the most common
question you get is like, what's
different about what about your
lead generation agency compared to
the
10 other lead generation agencies
emailing me asking if they want,
if I want to work with them.
So if you have an easy answer to
that or a clear answer, and also
one that makes sense and shows
value, you'll be in a really good
position.
So that is all for section two.
So again, section two is
just collecting all the
information we need about our
client's business to know them
inside and out,
just like it's our own business.
And also fit it right into our
strategy of what do we actually
have
to do once a client sign?
We have to get them leads.
And how do we get them leads?
We have to build a
list.
And we have to continue to build
this.
So we have to know everything
about how those lists should
be built.
And we also have to write scripts.
And we want to have a lot of
different variations of scripts
to test because you always want to
be testing.
And the only way we have that is
by collecting all this
different information using
different point of views and
perspectives in our questioning,
like you
saw.
And that's really it.
Everything else I can fill in.
So just think about your process
of,
okay, I deliver this service.
How do you fulfill on it?
You want to map that out from A to
Z,
from as soon as someone signs to
when that service has been
delivered, or to the point where
the service
is delivered for the first time
and then is in continuation.
Because like, for the most part,
your service is never going to be
completed, right?
Like for us, we're not like done
after we do
something.
It's we're continually driving new
leads.
And what I think about with the
onboarding form is
what do I need from the client or
what parts of the process will I
need to involve the client in
to get done.
And that's what I fill in the gaps
with, with the onboarding form.
So think about
everything that you need to do to
basically go from having a client
sign to getting their service
fulfilled.
And then ask yourself, which of
those steps do you require insight
from the client on?
And then stick it in the
onboarding form.
Because that's your best chance of
getting
a lot of clarity and a lot of
information.
And then you file it away.
As soon as you get the
onboarding form responses, like I
said, Google just send you an
email that says,
hey, new onboarding form or new
form responses for and then
whatever the name of the form is.
And then you go on there, you
could review them, you could print
them out.
And then you could store
them in the Trello board so that,
you know, three months later, you
get a guy that asks you a question
if you're running a cold email
agency, or whatever.
And they're like, hey, what makes
you unique?
Why should I work with you?
And you're like, hmm, I can't
think of it off the top of my
head.
But I know I got a question in my
onboarding form where I asked them
what makes them unique.
Let's go check that out and
refresh my memory.
So that's why it's just such a
great tool.
Just like the contract, it's like
something that you'll always have
to refer back to
for different parts of your
fulfillment process.
So I think what we're what you're
seeing here is just a trend of
like fulfillment
is not so much.
Obviously, the skill set and
knowing how to actually fulfill
and get results
is super important.
But it starts with having a
legitimatized service agreement.
It starts with
having a rigid onboarding process.
It starts with having an actual
onboarding form to collect
information
from your client.
Like these are all mini steps that
I feel like are completely skipped
or looked over
an effort to try to salivate
results without actually looking
at the real issues, which are
the underlying issues, which we're
talking about here early on in
this module.
So that was section two.
Now, real quick, section three is
really short.
It's just your goals.
So when you're an agency owner,
the only time I heard this from
one of my mentors, like two or
three years ago,
I used to work with a guy locally
who ran a lot of businesses, and
he was one of my first clients
at an agency that I used to run
two or three years ago.
And he said the like we were
working together
and we were very I was very my
agency was very unorganized and it
wasn't very professional.
And he has the client was very
confused.
So he said the only reason a
client would ever be upset
or is ever going to give you a
problem is if their expectations
do not meet reality, right?
So what do they expect as a result
of you working with them?
And then what's actually going to
be
the reality?
So if you set the wrong
expectations from day one saying,
hey, I'm going to get you 20
leads or I'm going to get you 20
booked appointments.
And then at the end of month one,
you get them for
that's the only reason they're
stressed is because they're
they're expecting 20 appointments.
And the reality is that they got
four appointments.
That's the only reason they're
stressed.
So if you
can manage expectations
effectively and be upfront about
it, and obviously where I'm
getting to with
this is to under promise and over
deliver always, you're going to be
in a really good position.
And by asking these questions in
your onboarding form, you kind of
know how to position yourself
because you know what your client
is there for, you know what they
actually want and value
in this relationship.
So as part of your goals and a lot
of this can happen in the sales
call too,
because if you don't under promise
and if you don't set proper
expectations for what your service
or
what your offer can actually
deliver for them, you're going to
be like shooting yourself in the
foot
from the very beginning.
So by the time they get to this
section, they shouldn't be like
guessing like
what type of results they're
looking to get from your service,
they should already have a good
understanding of what to expect
based on the information you
discussed with them on the sales
call in leading up to the signing.
So anyways, it's just a way for us
to like document on paper
two different pieces of
information.
The first piece of information
for us is how many sales calls are
you currently generating each
month on average.
So this is where are you currently
at in your business?
So what is point A?
Basically yeah,
basically this first question is
define point A, right?
Where are you currently at?
And then the
second question for us is how many
sales calls are you looking to
generate from our service each
month?
So that's basically where are you
looking to go?
What is the destination?
What is Z?
And then you just have to fill in
the gap of okay, they're at point
A, they want to get to point Z,
my service is the in-between.
It's what's going to get them from
A to Z, right?
So if they're
currently getting on five sales
calls every month and they want to
get to 10, then all I know is my
service has to fill in another
five calls a month, which I can
reasonably set the expectation to
deliver on.
So this is why it's so important
is you're collecting this
information at the end
to see what are your goals?
Like what are their goals for
working with you?
And what is it that you
have to fulfill on?
Like what is it that you should
shoot for each and every month?
Because it's going
to be different with every client.
Obviously they're all there for
results, but like why and in what
way?
Because you'll have clients that
are just like, I want to get on 20
calls and you'll have another
client that says, I want to get on
four calls, but I want them to be
very qualified, right?
So
clients will care about different
things.
And it's just important to get as
much information
and clarity on those things here
in the onboarding form responses,
which is right at the beginning
of the relationship.
So you know how to adjust or how
to tailor your service delivery.
And the last
question is one of my favorites is
if you could get one thing out of
working with our agency to make it
a
smashing success for you, what
would that be exactly?
And you'll find that the answers
to
this question are very simple.
It's just like, I want to have it
so that I don't have to worry
about lead generation.
I don't want to have to do lead
generation.
I just want someone to do it for
me so that I could focus on other
areas of my business.
And they're really simple things.
So what you can point to is later
on in the relationship, if they've
increased their
expectations or they're being a
little bit unreasonable, you could
refer back to this
question and say, Hey, Jeff, when
I asked you if you could get one
thing out of this relationship
to making a smashing success, you
told me it would just be the peace
of mind that lead generation is
being handled by someone else.
So you could focus on the
fulfillment side of your business.
Do you feel that as you know, our
time together, as we spent X
amount of time together,
you've been able to focus more
time on fulfillment while someone
else has covered lead gen for you?
Yes, of course, Andre.
Okay, then why are you not happy?
Right?
Not actually that this
probably not how the conversation
would go, but it just helps you to
refer back to something again,
just like a contract.
It's like you told me that if you
could get this one thing by
working with us,
it would be a smashing success,
not just a success, a smashing
success.
So just document this on paper,
make them think like, what is it
that they actually want?
Because
for our service?
Yeah, they want calls, but why do
they want calls?
Like, what is the actual end goal?
And a lot of the times it's just
like they want someone to handle
lead gen so they don't have to
touch it.
Like they hate that shit.
They don't want anything to do
with lead gen.
And even if they could salvage a
few calls by not having to touch a
single thing,
they're going to be happy.
And you'll see that typical
response here to this question.
And again, it just helps you know
more about your client.
Like, what are they expecting?
What are
they looking to get out of it?
And how can you then use that
information to tailor your
services,
your fulfillment, and the way you
interact with your clients on a
day-to-day basis
with, you know, knowing that
information?
So these are the last few
questions we ask in our
onboarding form.
And again, it's so, so helpful to
collect that information from all
of our clients,
because we can really tailor the
experience they get from working
with us to what it is they're
looking to get out of it.
So again, just to recap what my
mentor told me, uh, who was once a
client
at one of my first agencies was
the only time clients will ever be
stressed and give you issues
is when their expectations do not
meet reality.
Meaning if you promise 10 calls or
if you promise
being ranked on the first page of
Google, or if you promise $10,000
in added revenue and the reality
is after the first month working
with you, they're not seeing what
they expected.
They're going to be
stressed.
They're going to dispute and
they're going to be shitty
clients, not because they're
shitty
people, but because their
expectations are not met with
reality.
That's most of the time.
Obviously there's other scenarios
you'll run into, but really that's
in the simplest form what it
comes down to.
So the onboarding form can
alleviate a lot of that.
And just like the service
agreement,
it could catch things before they
even happen.
So take the time to study this
video, study our
onboarding forms, study other
people's onboarding forms that you
may have already went through by
working
with other agencies and come up
with something, come up with an
onboarding form,
go.
And then I would say, once you
come up with your onboarding form,
send it to your accountability
partner and ask them for feedback,
ask them to go through it.
And then also go through it
yourself
and time yourself.
What I found is the onboarding
form should at least take 10
minutes at least.
They should at least be
sitting down for 10 minutes to
think about their business and
provide you with the information
you
need to know about their business
to have success with your service
delivery.
So send it to your accountability
partner, send it to the group,
send it to your friends,
go through it yourself and just
refine it over time.
This is again, a livable, edible
document over
time.
So just like our service
agreement, as you learn and go on
with your agency, you're going to
add
and edit and change things up
here.
So like just for example, we never
used to ask if clients had a list
of prospects for us to start with,
but we started to see that a lot
of them did and they would just
never tell us because we never
ask.
And this is like the dream
scenarios.
If, if, if a client has a
list of prospects for us to get
leads from, that's a dream
scenario that makes our process so
much more
simple.
And a lot of our clients end up
having it.
It's just, we never asked.
So they never thought
to tell us.
So we added that question based
off of that learning keywords,
same thing.
We used to only
search by like industries, right?
And then we had this keyword
filter that we started using in
our lead
generation process or list
building process.
And it was super, super effective.
So we added that
question to our onboarding form
responses.
We also added the guarantee
because what we started to see
was if you had a guarantee, which
made basically getting on a phone
call, not even buying the services
or signing on for your services,
but just getting on a phone call,
which is what we're actually
selling
a no brainer, then you're going to
have a high success rate.
So we added this question to say,
Hey, what kind of guarantees you
have, if any, and even if they
didn't have a guarantee,
what you'll see is all of our
clients that don't have
guarantees, they'll say, we don't
offer a
guarantee.
But now that you've mentioned it,
we'll think of something or we
don't offer a guarantee,
but we've never had a client that
hasn't gotten success with us,
which is just like,
we get useful information out of
this question regardless.
And it's just so cool to see.
So
don't worry too much about having
this perfect right off the bat.
It's just going to be a learning
process.
Like with anything else in your
agency, it's like all this stuff
you're learning, you're
going to have to implement it to
continue to get the most value out
of it.
Because I can't tell you
how your agency should be run or
what your agency business is going
to look like.
Every agency is
different, but what I can do is
teach you the fundamentals and the
strategies and the frameworks
that will at least get you started
and get you off the ground.
And then from there,
it's up to you to be an agency
owner, to be a leader, to be an
entrepreneur, to be a builder
and flesh it out from there.
So if you have any questions on
this video and on putting together
or choosing which questions to ask
and your onboarding form
responses, let me know.
But again,
really your action item and your
homework after watching this video
is to put together an onboarding
form and then send it to your
accountability partner and also go
through it yourself a few times
and see, are there any questions
that I should add?
Are there any questions I should
get rid of?
Did I explain the questions clear
enough?
And you'll get a lot of that
feedback just by sending it to
other people.
So let me know how it goes.
Super excited for you to go
through this process.
And yeah, in the next video, we're
just going to continue walking
through some of the more important
aspects of the onboarding process
that we kind of foreshadowed or
talked a little bit about
in the previous video.
But I definitely want to go into
more detail on just like we did
here with
the onboarding form responses.
So yeah, catch you in the next
video.
Thanks so much for taking the time
to watch this.