So this presentation is just
called how to implement ai to
increase capacity without hiring
more people um and you guys know
me just from previous events and
and content and i'm big on
talent in hiring people like
that's what i like to teach on and
that's what i like to do so this
sounds like off-brand um but it's
not what you think it's not like
one of those go replace your
entire workforce with ai agents
because i just don't believe in
that um so it's going to be high
level and i think you guys are
going to get a lot out of this so
we'll just dive straight into it
so
i call this like the ai capacity
revolution so like the biggest
problem you guys are going to run
into
especially after implementing
everything you learned here today
from pager and christian on
partnerships
from daniel on ads and challenges
and from dan on sales is you can
sign a bunch of clients a new
business now but how are you going
to fulfill right what happens for
a lot of you guys is
you hit a capacity wall and i've
heard this from so many of you
guys it's like oh i'm doing so
well
that i had to stop taking on
clients and it's like okay well
that's not good and they're like
bragging
about it well hitting a capacity
wall is like actually the most
dangerous thing you can do in your
business
and so it's my job and in my
businesses and also as one of your
guys's coaches to help you get
past
this capacity wall and plan ahead
for an influx of growth make sense
okay so the way i think of ai is
not a replacement of talent it's a
replacement of or sorry it's a
compliment actually to talent it's
a
compliment to a smart hiring
process and so we all know like
new hires like that process takes
a long
time and it really is not
something that you should rush
like obviously if there's a need
and you need to
fill a gap like speed third and
prioritize that over anything else
but you still have to source
you still have to vet you still
have to onboard and you know dan
just gave a great presentation on
how
to properly onboard like there's a
lot of work involved in doing that
process properly and so
while we know that's true how can
we create capacity real quick if
there's a need for it well
we can use ai and we can implement
ai immediately much lower barrier
than going and hiring new talent
to increase the capacity of your
existing team to handle more
client work and i'll show you some
actual examples on how we do that
at some of our businesses so again
the result of this is not that
you never have to hire talent ever
again and replace your entire
company with a hundred percent ai
agents
because talent acquisition is
always going to be the top
priority like someone was asking
me a question
last night for like list kit we
just brought in uh someone to
essentially replace myself as like
managing the cs team and i think
it was george he's like okay like
how are you going to step into the
the ceo role now like what's your
top priority and i told him it's
talent acquisition and i think
that's like so important as like a
leader or an executive of a
company is talent acquisition so
that
doesn't go away it's just how can
we buy back some of our time that
we're spending in other places
so that we can actually take our
time with talent acquisition and
do it properly and not feel rushed
okay so one of the things that
really changed my perspective on
ai because i was pretty i was
pretty hesitant to implement it
for a while um and and especially
just being on like linkedin and
twitter
you'll scroll through the timeline
and just see like so much
engagement bait of like this ai
prompt you
know completely got rid of my
entire workforce and it's just
it's really distracting and to be
quite
honest like i'm even guilty of
like feeling fomo reading some of
those things like oh what am i
doing wrong or where am i not
implementing ai in the right areas
but you you scroll through and a
lot of
it's just noise but one of the
things that was not noise was the
shopify ceo um he put out actually
he didn't mean to put it out it
was just supposed to be an
internal memo to his existing team
but it
got leaked um and people tried to
leak it and put like a negative
spin to it but he actually just
came
out and posted the entire thing
and said hey like i saw this got
leaked it'll actually be helpful
for
anyone that runs a business in
this new ai revolution and like
the main line or i think the
title of the memo is that
reflexive ai usage is now a
baseline expectation and what he
means by that is
just like you use ai as a default
the same way you log in and use
google to search things right it's
just
you don't even think about it you
just use google because that's
what you've always done and so in
an
organization ai should be used the
same way so i'm not an ai expert
and none of you guys have to be
either and that's not something
you have to like become to be able
to implement what we're going to
talk about today you just do what
you always do with the talent you
have it's just you pass it on to
them and you leverage your
existing talent to lead the charge
of implementing ai the same way
shopify talks about doing it so
the the other key takeaway from
this is like understanding like
again
ai is not going to replace your
entire talent base right ai is
just going to be a force
multiplier for
your best people to get more and
more meaningful work done um and
this this was a quote directly out
of
the memo as well and you guys
should read the memo it's not that
long it's on uh twitter just look
up
toby luke uh shopify memo for ai
and he says before asking for more
headcount teams must demonstrate
why they cannot get done what they
need to get done using ai and it's
like why can't we just implement
that in all of our organizations
it's actually really simple as
soon as i saw the memo posted i
basically
digested it rewrote a really
similar version of it for myself
and implemented that list kit on
that next
team meeting and they loved it it
was so cool to see because ai is
exciting like ai is true
innovation and people want to be a
part of that they don't want to
miss out um and so how do you
implement this at your company
well one ai has to become the
expectation not just a suggestion
um
every team member needs to
contribute ai inspired ideas for
improvement and i'll show you like
actually
tactically how to do that um and
this applies to everyone and as
you guys have heard me teach on
especially when we talk leadership
like it starts with you right so
like even if you're not a very
technical person and even if
you've never used ai before at
least try and lead by example and
see
how your team follows suit right
and so the first thing that i
think uh is is important to do
it's
like you can get so bogged down
and distracted again by just
scrolling through twitter and
scrolling
through linkedin and seeing all
the different ways companies are
are like implementing ai to save
themselves
the most time most of that stuff
is not relevant for you right it
sounds cool and it's like again
you get that sense of fomo but
it's really just not relevant for
you so how do you implement ai in
a way that is relevant and helpful
for you and your business and your
team specifically we go back to
the 72 hour task audit right the
72 hour task audit is something
that you've heard me talk about
multiple times before and it's not
just you doing it you should
actually have your team do this as
well okay and it's really simple
it's just ask your team and you do
it with them right as a leader you
you go first and so you have them
document everything that they're
doing within a 72 hour time period
then you have them categorize it
into buckets what are things that
give you energy or drain your
energy
what are things that are revenue
generating or just administrative
work and what are things that
require your human input
input or things that are just
extremely repeatable like george
was just telling me before i came
up to
present that he he didn't use ai
actually he used a really cool
thing in excel that's similar to
ai
where identify specific keywords
that need to be highlighted in an
excel sheet with like 15 000
records
and before it's just a human going
through and trying to find those
and it's like that's definitely
not
giving them energy that's
definitely not revenue generating
and that's definitely not
requiring their
human judgment because a bot could
do it and so that falls into the
perfect use case of let's use ai
to
replace this super strenuous task
that someone internally is doing
and the benefits of ai are not
just to save
you time and to delegate things
that the team member doesn't need
to be doing anymore but it's also
to lock in
consistent quality across the
board because i was telling george
like what is the human error
involved with
that task you assigned like that
person if they're just doing
brainless work for hours like
they're
gonna make mistakes but like an ai
is not going to make mistakes
right and that peace of mind helps
you as an operator and a leader
not have to get caught up in
things that are not revenue
producing
and so every time we do a 72 72
hour task audit we find so many
tasks that could be streamlined
especially now
in the lens of using ai and one of
the things that i like to do as
well on a daily occurrence because
i
mentioned how do you get your team
members to contribute ai inspired
ideas i implement what
we call a daily kaizen and we
learned this actually at the the
same sdr company that dan talked
about
earlier when we were working in
our first row out of out of school
which is kaizen is just continuous
improvement look it up it's a
business concept i think that the
japanese created big companies
like toyota use
it all the time and it's really
simple it's just in your end of
day type forms with your team
members
simply pose the question what's
one thing you notice today that if
solved would make your work
smoother
and more efficient and if you
collect an answer to that question
five times a week from let's just
say 10 team members you now have
50 ideas on how you can implement
ai in a way that's actually
meaningful to
your team and organization not to
just what twitter and linkedin
find you know really exciting this
makes sense just clicking okay and
what you'll notice just to add on
to that is when you ask questions
like that people typically say the
same shape over and over and over
and over again yeah it's like fix
this
dude it's like yeah you're like
okay i got the message and it's
the same thing when customers ask
the
same question on a sales call you
know back to back to back to back
you know we spend an entire
training
session just focusing on that
question or that objection right
so we got to do the same with
our team um and so this identifies
opportunities and bottlenecks that
we can implement ai to help
improve um and the small things
like the small things that you
don't think actually matter
compound over time when you do
this daily um and it's also on you
to show them like how it
eliminates the
the least fulfilling parts of
their job right because again like
ai is supposed to get rid of
the tasks that drain their energy
and if we can get rid of tasks for
team members that drain their
energy
like how much more fulfilled are
they when they show up to work and
how does that contribute to the
actual tasks that we need them to
be doing right if i'm coming off
the back of what george was
telling
me he had one of his guys doing
reading through a spreadsheet
trying to find specific words to
highlight
like i'm brain dead after an hour
so if i'm then pulled into a high
level task that actually needs
human input
it's not going to get done at the
same quality standard as if they
were fresh and energized with
other work that they were doing
before oh and quick action item
it's super simple you guys can do
this
literally today or right now on
your phones or on your computers
like create a slack channel in
your organization
for your team to literally just
talk about ai that's it like
literally just call the channel
like list kit ai or your company's
name dash ai add your entire team
and share with them this
presentation
and just make it again with toby
luke from shopify one of the most
successful and fastest growing
companies in the world the
standard right reflexive ai usage
is the standard it's not you know
uh
some something that we just do
here and there okay so i'm going
to get into team structure for a
minute
here because i think the
foundation of what you're bringing
ai into is more important than
just bringing
ai in just to say you know can
check the box off so we talk about
this uh as well on olympia and in
some
of the previous presentations
we've given but how do you
structure your team right
especially as you grow so
like i have like the the customer
success team at list kit that's a
department but inside of the
department of customer success
there's teams and there's teams
for onboarding there's teams for
ongoing engagement there's teams
for tech support and so each team
essentially is three to five
people
working together okay and it's the
same way dan describes sales and i
love coming off the back of
dan's presentation because this
stuff is like it it translates
really well it's like you have a
team of sdrs
and you have a team of aes and
once those teams get too big you
create pods right because you
never
want nine people on one team
because it's too strenuous for one
manager to keep all nine of them
on kpi so you break it off you do
the same in in uh customer
successor for you guys i keep
saying customer
success that's a sas term for you
guys it's just fulfillment right
if you're running client services
businesses it's it's just
fulfillment um is all that means
and so not only do you have to
implement
the proper structure for your team
but you also need these teams
working well together because this
is where ai can really come into
your organization have an effect
on the culture so how do they work
well together well again dan
outlined this masterfully on the
sales side and it just applies to
everything
else daily huddles weekly team
meetings with specific kpi updates
i promise i didn't use dan's
presentation as a cheat sheet but
like you see how this translates
um and a clearly identified team
leader right are essential before
ai can really amplify your team's
capacity and then one of the
things that you guys know me
really well for at this point is
performance-based pay right like i
don't
believe in just paying someone to
fulfill client work and get paid a
base salary it to me it just
doesn't
make sense i think it's not the
smartest way to do it for you and
for the team members especially
if they're an a player in their
past history is performance like
they they perform right so they
don't want to be capped to some
preset salary or retainer that
they make every single month so
when pay and this is so great for
ai especially because when pay is
tied to results and performance
it's not ours that becomes the
focus like i don't care if my team
works 40 hours or 30 hours a week
i care what my team is producing
and getting done right and so if
they can use ai to get more done
it
becomes their best friend so let's
look at one of the first real
examples that i prepared for you
guys student success coaches at
client ascension you guys all have
worked with a student success
coach before right and so student
success coaches that's a role
where we have to hire more student
success coaches if we want to sign
more students into the client
ascension program right because
there's capacity i can't just give
all of you guys to one student
success coach and expect that the
standard is going to be where we
need it to be right so like we
measure capacity over time to say
okay
student success coaches can manage
maybe 40 students at a time right
so if i want 400 students
in client ascension i need 10
student success coaches now that's
a really hard role to hire for
sourcing candidates like it's a
high barrier role because you're
giving them the relationship right
they need to know the business
they need to know the course
content they have to be there for
a long
time imagine replacing a student
success coach that has 60 client
accounts and relationships
attached to
them that's that's hard to do so
you have to really take your time
in the hiring process to get rid
of
that risk but you can't do that if
daniel cracks the code on a
challenge and finds out how to get
people signed up in a three-day
span which we literally had last
month that was the capacity for
one student success coach and we
signed that amount of students in
literally three days and so this
is
where ai's become my best friend
as you know someone that has to go
out and do the hiring
uh so let's take an ssc right sscs
get paid per student under
management plus bonuses for
generating
things like case studies referrals
and orchestrating upsells because
it's not just about taking on as
many students it's about doing it
to the quality standard that we
need to ensure so they want to
use ai to handle more students
obviously right because it's going
to make them more money um
and so that's like why
performance-based pay it just goes
so perfectly with with
implementing ai um
the last one here is just never
stop sales velocity right um like
the biggest mistake again that i
see
you guys make or just businesses
in general especially the ones
that come through our coaching
programs
is daniel dan and christian's
content is so good that they
figure out real quick how to sign
clients
and they're just not ready for it
and so they have to quote unquote
pause sales right they're always
like oh yeah i'm pausing sales to
you know fulfill for these clients
and that's always just like
sirens just go off in my brain
because instead of um like
continuing the natural stream of
business
it's this continued stop start
approach that completely kills all
momentum and i've seen it so many
times
where once you make the decision
to pause sales and stop the
momentum that you took so long to
build up
it's really hard to get back and
sometimes you can't get it back
fast enough to the point where
your business
actually completely dies off we've
seen it so many times
um and so
how do you never stop sales
velocity well you build a bench of
pre-vetted candidates so that you
can tap
them in when you need them without
having to restart the hiring cycle
right every single time but at the
at the same time you do what we're
talking about today which is
implementing ai
to expand capacity with your
current team
so the first thing before we get
into uh like actual use cases
there's a perception challenge
that i started to realize when i
talked more about ai
and you guys might relate to this
and your team will definitely
relate to this and whether you
know
it or not this is important as a
leader to understand before you
bring ai into your culture
and so how do we break down this
barrier right let's actually start
at the bottom like many employees
have
concerns about using ai tools
right because when ai first
started a lot of times it was
labeled as
cutting corners or you're being
lazy because you're just
outsourcing everything to chat gpt
so it had
this negative connotation to it
don't use ai because then you're
just going to be seen as robotic
or lazy
right this is super relatable
especially in higher education
it's like very transparent that
like ai is
is completely not allowed like if
you use ai like you're getting
expelled from this university you
guys
have heard this before right this
makes sense and so team members
are probably and i know that they
are
because i've had conversations
about this but let's just say
they're probably worrying about
their job security
number one because ai is advancing
really fast and they're seeing the
same twitter and linkedin threads
that i mentioned earlier that's
like ai is going to replace this
you know cs role forever follow
this thread for you know exact
instructions on how to do it and
it's like it's not you know the
truth it's
just a bait um and it's also again
a lot of times they worry that
they might be appearing to work
less
so these perceptions create
barriers for effective ai
implementation and so again the
way i see it i
don't care if my team works 40
hours or 30 hours a week if
they're getting the same amount of
work
done right and again if we're
focused on increasing capacity the
goal isn't to get the same amount
of
work done it's to get more work
done and the only reason the only
way you could get more work done
in
the same amount of time is by
doing what we're talking about
right buying back your time using
ai
so again i care about performance
so when you make this mindset
shift first you have to make
this mindset shift and then you
help your team to make that
mindset shift ai becomes a tool
for
helping hit kpis that's it it's
not a tool to be lazy it's not a
tool to replace you and your role
it's your sidekick essentially
right ai is a sidekick for your
team it enables your team to hit
kpis
that's all it is and that's how
you should communicate it it's not
to replace them um and
so we also need to reinforce this
thought by making ai a celebrated
behavior in your organization so
one
thing we do at list kit that the
team loves is one of the guys in
client ascension uh tom avesar i
think
is his last name tom um he runs
like a 3d printing company so i
had him do a mock-up of like a 3d
printed
trophy for list kit and i told the
team whoever has the best and most
high impact ai idea this month
i'll ship you one of these ai or
one of these um list kit trophies
and they love that so like they
see that i'm rewarding ai ideas
through something like a trophy
right so it's super important and
you
can do it with like gift cards
cash bonuses or just
acknowledgement right um and so
again it's like
the hours versus results mindset
like i don't time track for a
reason because i don't care if you
work
40 hours or 30 hours and if you
only work 30 hours and don't get
the results you don't get paid as
much
right so i don't pay by hour i pay
by performance and that allows me
to not have to be super in the
weeds tracking specific things
that they're doing or not doing
before i get into the actual
examples
like four ones that i've
specifically chosen for you guys
today that i think might be
relevant
is this is this hitting so far
this is valuable okay all i need
is one it was funny during the
challenge like i do this all the
time i have like an hour
presentation and like every 15
minutes i'm
like guys please like help myself
self-esteem just like put w's in
the chat if this is if this is
anything
of value and it's just like www
i'm like oh my god guys stop
you're gonna break the zoom
servers
and like it's just like stupid
like that that works for b2c
offers or lower trade offers um
but anyways
all right so let's let's go
through this first one so how many
of you guys use slack
yeah not just use slack but like
live in slack yeah so the problem
right so this is the framework
right what's the problem well
there's a billion messages in a
million different channels and
threads
in slack and most of these
actually contain tasks that gear
that i guarantee are not getting
tracked
properly they're not actually
getting completed and they're
falling through the cracks
relatable
right and so what's the solution
there's a an ai tool called chaser
okay in slack that you can add
as an app and it automatically
captures tasks and follows up with
the assigned task owner until this
task assigned due date so really
cool simple tool that you guys can
go and install on slack like
literally right now it's called
chaser it's super cheap i think
it's like 12 a user per month
and literally like they're like in
our slack organization i think i
send like anywhere from
seven to ten thousand slack
messages a month just in list kit
slack and a lot of those things
are like
directives like do this or follow
up on this or go fix this or go
implement this i'm assigning tasks
through slack and without chaser
my job would not be ceo executive
it'd just be project management
coordinator that's what i was
doing for the longest time until i
found chaser um and so how it
works
when someone it identifies when
someone commits to a task and just
like any other ai tool it's not
perfect
right you have to guide it towards
what's actually a task what's
worth tracking all this sort of
stuff
it automatically assigns and
tracks deadlines and if it doesn't
come up with a deadline you can
manually
input it and it sends reminders
before due dates right before like
if i assigned a task in slack
i literally like write follow up
in a draft and then not send the
message so that i can check in my
drafts
two days later that i meant to
follow up on this task i assigned
right so like this saves me so
much time
um and it ensures that nothing
gets lost or falls through the
cracks right so what does this do
well
it allows you to manage your team
without micromanaging your team
make sense okay so
don't sign up until i find my
affiliate link actually
uh actually christian you you
shared that one where's christian
you shared chaser with me right
you create an affiliate link and
put an olympia and we'll split it
and we'll put it on white horse
today for the kentucky derby is
that what i saw that in slaps what
the is that
yeah yeah yeah yeah burn burn them
number nine horse throw throw
whatever we get an affiliate
revenue on
that okay uh this one's super cool
again this this might be super
niche to client ascension but like
you guys are smart enough to like
see how we're doing things and
make it relevant to your
organization
that's why this is like a high-end
mastermind because you guys don't
need to be told
step by step by step by step what
exactly to do and how to run your
business which is what i love
because i could come here share
relevant ideas and see how you
guys go out and make them better
um but the offer creation boss so
this is a problem right creating
offers that have a high likelihood
of actually converting is the top
one percent of the top one percent
skill set that daniel has learned
over the course of being in
business for over five years so
the knowledge transfer that daniel
has
to the sscs to be able to create
and review offers for students is
a huge bottleneck like it just is
right he had hours upon hours with
the student success coaches to to
make that knowledge transfer
um leading to long delays for
students right because if daniel's
the one that needs to review or
create
an offer daniel's doing other
things um and because of that it
also leads to less desired student
results
if it has to be the ssc who's
coming up with the offer because
the sscs will be the first to tell
you
they're not going to come up with
as good of an offer as daniel
that's why they're not the offer
coach
they're the ssc and so before
daniel's with all the offers
needed daniel to review it either
on his
weekly coaching call or through
slack and it just created massive
delays and things got missed and
the student experience wasn't
super ideal because remember if
you're part of fulfillment it's
all about
time to value right and it's not
very valuable if you have to wait
all this time to get your offer
reviewed so what's the solution we
created and trained and ai bought
on all of daniel's offer
as well as the most successful
offers we have ever seen after
interviewing over a hundred
client success or client ascension
students and then the bot analyzes
the info from the client's
onboarding form to create a daniel
approved offer in minutes right
and so the result before when an
ssc
could manage only 40 students and
i need 10 sscs to manage 400
students now the sscs can handle
way more
students at this point some of
those guys are at 60 and they're
telling me give me more students
because again what's the other
important component of sscs and
how this relates to their job
performance-based pay so they're
telling me give me more students
right because they get paid for
the
more students that they get so
again they can handle more
students which also allows them to
make more
money which i want my team to make
more money because then they're
more bought in and like dan said
in
his presentation they can see the
growth right um and also like
again because consuming like their
onboarding form responses and then
using that to create an offer it
was like the most time consuming
thing and not only do they handle
more students but they do it well
like higher quality than they were
before which leads to more case
studies which then sales and
marketing can do or use or
leverage to
get more students right it's this
flywheel um and then daniel can go
and focus on other very high
level strategic stuff like
recording more trainings which we
can feed back into the ai bot to
make it
better more youtube videos which
we can also use to train the ai
bot um and managing ads and and so
on
make sense you know what's funny i
literally made one of these for my
clients off his youtube video
and alex rossi and myron gold and
stuff that's fire that's that's a
great idea um there's a tool
that i really like for creating
bots like the offer creation bot
called poppy.ai um the reason
i like poppy.ai instead of like a
claude project is because you can
literally just copy paste youtube
links
on claude you literally have to
transcribe the entire video then
upload it and then it takes up
like a percentage of the knowledge
base and the knowledge base is
super limited claude doesn't
have like a limit it's just you
get charged more credits which i'd
i'd want to pay for more capacity
if claude would let us they they
don't and i think daniel you even
tweeted about that like the
project
knowledge on claude like that's
the best upsell opportunities buy
more knowledge uh storage but they
don't have they don't let you okay
uh two more so the onboarding
preparation bot all of you guys at
some point in your client journey
have to do an onboarding process
right and so this one actually
might be super relevant for you
guys uh so the problem uh our dfy
like our done for you cold email
setup offer onboarding specialist
for that offer uh at list kit
before this bot was created they'd
spend a ton of time preparing for
upcoming onboarding calls because
information from the sales process
their onboarding form and pre-call
sops were dispersed and difficult
to find plus it took a ton of time
to
consume and translate all of that
information into a strategy for
the call right and so the problem
is
not that they weren't prepared
it's just that we needed to hire
more people to handle the
increased
sales velocity because they could
only take so many of these calls
every single day so again this all
goes back to capacity if daniel
and dan and christian find a way
to double the amount of dfy
onboarding
clients that sign up every month i
don't want to have to go out and
hire double the amount of people
on
my team i want to figure out how
can my team handle double the
capacity and they want to work
with me to
solve that problem because they
get paid more as a result right so
like all components work together
in this so anyways before the
process included the onboarding
specialist reviewing the sales
call
and this is so important i we
talked about it uh to the side of
dan's presentation of like sales
and cs
really have to be on the same page
because if you're on the customer
success team and you have no
insights
into what was talked about on the
sales call and you show up and you
ask the same questions and you
make the customer repeat
themselves customers hate
repeating themselves more than
anything else and so
if you can avoid having them
repeat themselves you're already
ahead and you already have a
better
customer experience than most
businesses and so they had to
review the sales calls the email
threads the onboarding form
responses which a lot of us use
really long onboarding forms so
there's a lot
of information that comes with
that um and so we had to have like
well thought out ideas after
reviewing
all these things on how to best
approach each client's unique
situation and goals that takes a
lot of
time and so the solution was we
created an ai agent that collects
and analyzes all client
interactions
from their application to when
they first signed up for sales
call all of their sales call
recordings all of the
email threads with the sales
people or with the cs team and
then again the onboarding form
responses and
then we organize all this
information into here's what you
need to know for the onboarding
call
in like literally 10 seconds right
all you have to do is give it the
customer's name and email
and it just puts it into a slack
thread in literally 10 seconds
it's the craziest thing
and so the impact is before the
onboarding specialist we're only
doing maybe four really high
quality
onboarding calls every single day
now they're doing anywhere from
six to eight like we quite
literally
doubled our capacity to take on
new customers for the dfy setup
offer overnight without hiring any
additional people and we make a
way better first impression by
avoiding again the number one
thing
customers hey which is having to
repeat themselves it's good cool
no so it it's the agent that
collects it from our crm from uh
fathom which we use for call
recordings
from fireflies from email inboxes
um and then the onboarding form
we'd use uh type form for
so i won't talk about that today
because that will be a longer
conversation but we'll get it
i can dive into the details on any
of these with you guys yeah i
would love to walk you through
some
of this stuff this next one is
going to be even better and then
we can walk through it on one
we can walk through it on
wednesday if you guys want um okay
that's cool though that one was
valuable
then yeah same for us okay um so
this one dan touched on this as
well um call reviews right
how many of us do call reviews any
of you guys um do call reviews for
customer success type stuff
like onboarding calls client
check-in calls okay smear mark
great george also what time is it
okay making a decent time um okay
so the problem right reviewing
calls whether sales calls or
onboarding calls or client
check-in calls was a very
selective guest work and reactive
process that
required executives undivided
attention for at least an hour
right like if anyone's ever done a
call
review you can't like just breeze
your way through a call review you
have to like lock in and hang on
to
every single word pause the video
write something down go back it
was the longest thing that you'd
have
to work on like every week
consistently multiple times right
and so before just like dan i
spent multiple
hours watching calls taking pages
of manual notes spending time with
a team member then to make sure
that
they're implementing my feedback
and i don't know about you guys
but when i watch these calls i get
so
pissed off i'm like why did they
say that what an idiot what are
you doing like no like like i'm
trying to like jump into the call
like and just fix what they said
and it just pissed me off so much
like i remember just being so
angry after doing call reviews and
like i'm just a perfectionist
that's
my personality trait it has
nothing to do with like calls
actually need to be perfect
because they don't
but like man like i just can't
help it but like hang on to every
detail when i do a call review
again because i i nitpick
everything um and i'm like this
with myself too so it's not just
other
people and i'll come back to this
presentation after nathan sends it
to me and i'll be like what
an idiot why did i say that why
didn't i say this at this bar i do
this all the time um so the
solution
use fathom to record calls the
fathom will immediately generate a
transcript of the call
right it'll send it to an ai agent
that'll score it based on a score
of one to five and that's based
on actual examples of all the call
reviews that i've ever done right
and it's a well thought out
prompt davi i'll share the prompt
with you guys on one of these
calls and show you how to make one
similar um and the prompt is just
me explaining everything that
should happen on each of the types
of calls that i want to have an ai
review bot in place for and then
generating also something we
didn't do before super custom
follow-up email ideas right
because you talked about a lot of
stuff on
that call you're now expecting the
person that was on that call to
also have remembered everything
that was talked about and somehow
include that in a follow-up email
good chance though that they just
went to the next call and to the
next call and to the next call and
now it's 5 p.m they're on eight
calls there's no way they're
sending eight follow-up emails
that are super custom and hit on
each thing
that was discussed on all those
calls it's impossible right that's
why we have ai and so it also
makes
it something dan talked on is like
like okay using ai right like you
should in in doing manual reviews
right so like if dan's still
really set on doing manual call
reviews which i even go in and
still
do at some point how does he know
which call review to review right
it's kind of like i said in the
beginning it's more of like a
reactive process or it's guesswork
with this ai bot which calls do
you
think i'm reviewing yeah it's like
i just it's a signal it's like oh
one out of five what happened i
need
to see what happened right and not
only do i review it but i need to
make sure that the
the client's okay right like i
need to make sure that something
okay the call happened i'll review
it later and i'll give feedback so
we improve but let's you know make
that client churn risk
and make sure they're on like a
close watch list so that we can
you know like get back into good
okay so let's see what we're doing
we're doing okay so no but this
is like something i've talked to
dan about like again implement
this on the sales side right i'm
i'm just
doing this for cs but again you
can easily do this for sales um so
same thing it's yeah just reverse
engineer this but for sales calls
give it all of your sales call
reviews and then again give it
what
should happen on a sales call
right and then over time it'll
improve and then what do you think
i do
with the five out of five calls
that but don't look actually but
what do you think i do with the
five
out of five calls because guess
what the bot's not perfect when
you first make it and be like this
is a five out of five use this
when reviewing the next calls to
look for a good call so the bot
gets
better when it has examples of
what a call should look like and
also what a call shouldn't look
like
right so this is the cool stuff
like i love talking about this
because it's really cool and it's
not
again like that super you know
like engagement bait content that
you see on linkedin and twitter
that
pisses me off because i actually
get the fomo that probably a lot
of you guys are getting too and we
really shouldn't but like this
stuff it's like not sexy but it's
so effective um and so yeah not
only can you feed it back into the
bot but like davi said you can
praise that person for crushing
a call um and then you can also
use it to train new team members
right like my favorite way to
onboard and train new team members
is to be like hey go watch these
10 calls because this is what an
onboarding call should look like
and why give them a bunch of
random calls that might be good
might not
be good when i can give them 10
five out of five calls right um
and so it improves over time
because you feed you know more
data back into it and so this is
the craziest stat
our customer success team at list
kit was on 808 calls in the last
30 days 808 calls in the last 30
days 808 calls in the last 30 days
and they were all automatically
reviewed scored and attached with
a
custom follow-up email immediately
after the call ended bro i would
have to hire every single one of
you
guys in this room to do that
without ai as your full-time jobs
and you'd be miserable but ai does
it for us for like 12 a month or
whatever the cost is so this stuff
is is nuts right i think so it's
wild
so anyways ai wrote this whole
presentation remember that so none
of these are my ideas it's just ai
um so a couple more things this
stuff's not as valuable like that
slide was a banger because
it's like real but this stuff is
important too like how do you use
ai in a practical way every
single day so this is one of my
favorite ways to do it like when
i'm creating content when i'm
creating
so my presentation that you're
looking at right now it went
through this process probably a
couple more
times then i'll usually put some
other thing through if it's like a
tweet or if it's a response to you
know a cold email but this
presentation went through this
process like 10 times i was up to
like 1 30 last
night just doing this process so i
had it draft the first piece of
content maybe let's say start with
chat gpt i give that piece of
content to claude and i say review
this piece of content with like
this in
mind right like i want to make
sure i'm delivering a highly
engaged really to the point
presentation to
this mastermind group tomorrow
okay so claude reviews it and then
i'll go to a third ai let's
just say gemini and i'll say
here's what you know mentor number
one gave me here's what mentor
number
two gave me take the best of both
and give me a final version right
so many of you guys just ask chat
gpt
take what it gives you and run
it's like use all of them and
watch how much better the output
is here
compared to just here and it
doesn't really take much more time
and then the final step
is review it as a human because we
really shouldn't be putting out
content and presentations and
training
without our final check and run
through make sense so do you
actually use gemini at all i've
used it
yeah for stuff like this have you
had good outputs like that's been
the worst one for me
again like i'm not the ai expert
it's more of like the concept if
you've not had good results with
gemini just swap it out for
another one but like i've gemini
is nice because it's like native
to google
it's got uh the best limits in
terms of knowledge base outside of
like a more custom like poppy ai
type
solution but again i'm not the ai
expert like you'll find better
information on is gemini the best
is
josh gpt the best is claude the
best it's
okay great so again it's about the
process of one two three and watch
the quality compared to the first
time and the third time and again
always have that human review at
the end super important because
this is specifically for like
content presentations training um
things that
like we're doing right now that
are higher level and should really
stem from your own words right
like
one of my favorite prompts is like
only use things that i've said
because i'll give it like youtube
videos
and docs and call recordings and
i'm like make this as authentic
and on brand to what i would say
or have
said as possible because it's
super important i don't want to
come up here and i want to be able
to
come up here and give a
presentation that like sounds
nothing like what i would talk
about or is talking
about things that i've not
actually done right and so this is
just like a really simple
breakdown
um that could be helpful so like
what does ai do best well it helps
with repetitive processes
that drain energy it helps with
initial drafts and ideas it helps
with data analysis and pattern
recognition it helps with
organizing data from multiple
sources so davi you asked me
earlier you
know i have information over here
about this and over here about
this and over here about this how
do i
organize it in a way using ai well
we can talk about that and then
research okay and then what
do humans do better um strategic
thinking and planning creative
problem solving building genuine
relationships right obviously
you're not gonna have a
relationship with an ai that would
be weird
probably in the future that'll be
true but i'm out on that one um
and then final quality assurance
and judgment that one's so
important because so many people
again especially like the twitter
bros and
the the linkedin professionals um
are so big on like just use ai to
run your entire life and
completely
check out and like that's i'm so
against that it's use ai as a
sidekick like use ai in a smart
way that's
it um and always have the final
quality assurance and judgment and
that way you can actually also
spot
where it needs to improve right
and so yes ai can increase your
capacity to take on new clients
but like you still need a players
right what did i say to george
earlier the number one focus for
me
now going forward is to build my
talent pipeline i wouldn't have
that as my number one focus if it
wasn't the most important thing so
talent acquisition is is number
one and i guess number one is
really
being a great leader so that you
can acquire a players but great
leadership right that's that's
always going to be required to run
a business always a players and
great leadership
and so finally like where do you
go from here again just to kind of
bring it home start with your
biggest problems um don't get
distracted by the fanciest tools
the latest innovations the hacks
the
agent workforce all these
buzzwords that you'll see i
promise you if you open twitter
after this
presentation you'll see it i see
it all the time aka the replace
your entire workforce with ai
agents
don't get distracted by that focus
on what will actually serve your
team now based on what they're
experiencing on a day-to-day and
we talked through how do you do
that um make your team want to use
ai
and not feel like they're going to
be punished if you find out
they're using ai and you can do
that by
rewarding desired behaviors
there's actually a really really
good golden nugget here that you
guys should
should 100 do go and create one of
those virtual credit cards in
mercury and just call it ai team
expenses and then just send it to
your team and say go sign up for
ai tools that you find interesting
and want to test out and play
around with with this card like go
do that and like that builds
culture
because you're supporting
development of a really important
skill set that'll serve them in
this existing
role and serve them in their
future career and it's really easy
to do you can also set like a
limit and
you can see all the charges
obviously if you if you want to
know who you should fire just look
at what
people are spending money on and
if someone's got like an uber eats
on there you can fire them um but
we've never had any issues with
that and you can set limits so
it's like 500 a month if they
spend the
whole 500 a month on ai tools i'm
gonna get an roi from that
guaranteed so i'm okay with it um
so do
that like that's an action item
that in the slack channel of just
like your company name dash ai
and adding all your team in there
to just talk about ai those are
two things you should do like
immediately after this
presentation um make ai part of
your daily routine right again
going back to the
shopify ceo's um memo reflexive ai
usage is the new standard and
expectation reflexive and again
the
best way to describe what he's
saying there is like the same way
you go to google to search things
you should go to ai to do things
and implement new workflows and
improvements to processes to
increase
capacity and then finally um
connect ai to performance
incentives and hitting kpis right
and it's really
easy to do this i've done it a
couple times in this presentation
if you're paying someone for the
amount of students that they can
coach and handle and get to
success if ai can help them to do
more of
that they're going to have the
incentive to use ai and want to
use it more right and so
incentivize usage
by pointing out how you and
specific team members are using it
to improve performance and
increase
their earnings and so this isn't
just a go implement this one time
and and again like check out it's
continual i log into slack and i
see what my team is doing and i'm
looking for ways that they're
using ai
so i can shout them out and
reinforce it for the rest of the
team right like you don't train
someone
just by telling them one time like
you repeat it over and over and
over and over and over again and
that's
and that's how it sticks and
that's how it becomes truly part
of your culture and that's it so
thank
you guys appreciate it thank you