Real quick.
I'll let more people in as they
come.
So I see a lot of new faces today,
which is super
exciting.
And so we'll start with some
intros for anyone that's new here.
And then today, usually on
these calls, it's really like
open-ended Q&A and it's really
like conversational and discussion
based.
But I've been working on sort of
like a masterclass for client
retention, which is really
the topic of conversation people
have the most questions on that
I'm able to help them with.
And so I'll run through that today
and there's different phases.
Maybe we'll make it through
just a few of them and not all of
them.
And we'll have a discussion around
that.
And then hopefully
at the end, we'll have some time
for questions and whatever else.
But I want to get started with
intros.
We have Oscar, Connor, and Jacob
and Avery.
I think all of you are new here to
this call
specifically, the operations call
every Thursday at noon.
So it's great to have you guys
here for
whichever one of you wants to give
a quick intro to the group.
Let us know who you are, what
you're
working on.
That'd be a good way to kick it
off.
I'll go first.
Hey everyone, I'm Connor.
I just joined Client Ascension
yesterday.
I run
a marketing and sales ops agency
for HubSpot customers.
Nice.
Cool, man.
Great to have you here.
Thank you.
What's up, everybody?
I'm in the same boat as Connor
just joined Client Ascension
yesterday.
So really
excited to be here.
I do a good old e-commerce email
marketing, work with four clients
right now.
Nice.
And really keen to get stuck in
with the live calls and the course
content.
Let's go, dude.
I love the email marketing guys.
People ask me if I were to start
another agency
from scratch.
I always say probably email
marketing.
So you're in the right industry.
You have a great
offer.
And so we're excited to work with
you.
Love it.
Appreciate it, brother.
Of course.
Yeah, I'll go ahead next.
Yes, my name's Avery.
I joined Client Ascension last
week, Friday,
I believe.
I run a software development
agency.
Really excited for these
operations calls because
that's probably our biggest
struggle right now.
Solid, dude.
Yeah, we've worked with a lot of
software development, app
development types of
agencies at our lead gen company.
And so I have a pretty good idea
on backend and how to systemize
that.
So excited to work with you.
Great to hear.
What got you into that?
Were you like, are you a coder
yourself or?
Yeah.
So I've been a software engineer
for past five years, working at a
tech company.
And then when COVID hit, I just
started doing some freelance dev
work for clients.
And then as I got
more people to work for, I got
some devs under me and kind of
grew it from there.
So I've been doing
it for about two years now.
And now we've gotten to a point
where we're like an actual
full-fledged agency, not just
freelance operation.
That's sick.
Yeah.
That's usually the transition
everyone goes through.
I've been
just kind of messing around with
agencies for four or five years
now.
And just the past year,
year and a half has really been
like, you know, when things
started to come together.
So
it's cool to hear.
Cool.
I think that leaves me here.
Yes, sir.
All right.
Sorry.
I'm outside with my dog, but I was
outside of my cam on.
Yeah.
Great to be
here.
Operations is also something I
struggle with the most.
I run an e-commerce development
agency.
So very similar to you, Avery.
Started out as a freelance
designer working with tech
companies and just slowly
transitioned into e-commerce as
that's what most of my clients
were in.
Got it.
Yeah.
Super stoked for this.
Likewise, dude.
Good to have you here.
Thanks.
Being here.
Real quick, actually, if we could
go back through, we have Oscar,
Connor, Avery
and Jacob, you guys mentioned like
operations being a really
important reason why you joined
the program.
Like what's one operations problem
or question that you have that we
could get
started with?
And then I'll go into the
presentation I have.
I can, I can just throw one out
there.
So I, you know, doing creative
work, it's, it's
almost like every project is, uh,
a new project is not really a ton
of repeatability.
Um, so
I'd love to learn how to, uh, what
one train people, but also trust
people to do, you know,
as good of a job as, as I think I
do.
Yeah.
Plus one, plus one, plus one.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
Uh, Scott on this call, he's been
in the program for quite a while,
uh, and he's
making really big strides.
So he runs a creative agency.
So very.
Similar.
Like every project is unique in a
way it's very creative video work.
So I think
you can learn a lot from what he's
done successful.
Yeah.
Hit me up.
We'll, we'll, we'll, we'll, we'll,
we'll, we'll, we'll, we'll, we'll,
we'll
write on it.
Yeah, we'll do it.
Well,
solid.
Um, Avery, Oscar, Connor, any
specific questions or focus points
when it comes to operations?
Um, pretty similar to Jacob's
point, you know, like we're doing
custom app development.
So each,
each job is really different.
Um, so I'd be interested in ways
to figure out how we can,
like, I mean, there's no way we
can make them all, um, you know,
repeatable, but as much as
we can, like reduce the difference
from project to project.
Um, and another question that I
had,
I mean, it's, it's sort of vague,
I guess, but like, and maybe this
is what you're trying to get
at, but it's like, how do you
start taming an existing ops mess?
Like, do you have suggestions
on, um, ways to kind of like come
up with a list?
Yeah, where do you start?
Yeah, it'll be a phase
five of my presentation today.
Uh, so it'll be all the way at the
end.
And if we don't make it to
phase five, there's a full lesson
dedicated to what phase five is in
the learning platform that I'll
send
you a link to, but yeah, that
phase five will be a good start
for you.
Sounds good.
Great question,
by the way.
Um, okay, great.
Oscar, Connor, anything to add?
No, yeah.
No.
Okay, cool.
Oh, sweet, brother.
Sweet.
And we have one more new, uh, new
member here.
Zach, if you don't mind,
uh, this is the first I'm seeing
you on my operations call.
So I always like to give the
spotlight to new
members and have them give a quick
intro.
Great.
Hi.
Yeah, I'm brand new.
I signed up the day before
yesterday and I essentially run a
small shop.
I do coaching and, uh, fractional
work based around,
uh, global sales.
So I coach global sales managers
and I do fractional global sales
management for
small to medium sized companies
that are looking to expand
globally.
super exciting.
Awesome, man.
Are you at like a conference or
something?
It looks like I am.
I am.
I'm at a conference today and I
just took a coffee break to join
the call.
Awesome, man.
Thank you so
much for being here.
Really appreciate that.
Right.
All right, cool.
So, uh, again, for anyone that
just
joined, uh, after the very
beginning, my plan for today's
call is quite different than what
I've done in the
past.
Usually these calls are more so
like open question, uh, Q and a
style discussion style,
conversation style.
Uh, but I've been working in the
background a little bit on sort of
like a
presentation on client retention,
like an intro to client retention,
which we'll talk all about like
operations, hiring, uh, stuff like
that.
So I want to run it by you guys
real quick and just get some
feedback and there's multiple,
there's five phases of the
presentation.
So we'll just go phase by phase.
Um, and we'll open up for
questions in between and hopefully
have a discussion around that if
you
guys find it interesting.
So cool.
Let's get into it then.
Where is this document?
Um, I can't, I lost the tab where
the document is on.
So there we go.
All right.
I'm going to do a
screen share and then I'm also
going to hit, or we already hit
record.
So we're good.
All right.
Is
that showing up for you guys?
Yep.
All right, cool.
Yeah.
So this is just in a Google doc.
So like I was
saying in Slack, it's very much a
beta presentation.
Uh, and so I'll run you guys
through it and I'll stop at
certain points just so I don't
bore you guys with just a straight
lecture.
Uh, and again, so this is
going to be all about client
retention and there's going to be
five different phases we cover,
uh, to
go back to, uh, I forgot who I
already forgot who asked the
question, but phase five will
teach you
like really how to implement all
this stuff, but we'll start from
the ground up just to make sure
you
have the right foundation going
into it.
So this is really just now that
you imagine at this point,
you've closed the deal, signed the
contract, collected the onboarding
fee or the initial
payment.
What happens next?
How do you ensure that the rest of
the business runs smoothly and
that
customers, uh, become raving fans
of the business.
Right.
And so the first phase is really
just to start
with your offer, which sounds
really simple.
Uh, but the number one thing that
I've noticed is I've done
agencies in the past where I don't
really believe in what we're
offering and I'm not very
confident in
what we're offering.
Uh, the example I give is in the
past, we used to do like Facebook
ads.
And to be
honest, I didn't really understand
what Facebook ads were or why we
were even offering Facebook ads in
the first place.
So I think you have to truly
believe in what you're offering.
So if you don't
feel like that conviction of, I
really know why, and I can answer
the question, why I'm offering
what
I'm offering, then that's
something, you know, to revisit
and to think about, uh, also with
your offer,
you want to set yourself up in a
way where you can prioritize
results.
So your offer should be set up
so that you can get impactful,
meaningful, and valuable results
for whoever you work with.
And so it's gotta be like that
balance.
It's gotta be something you
believe in, and it's gotta be
something that can get results
consistently.
And then the shit test, uh, that
you always want to
run an offer through is what do
you buy yourself?
Um, and I always think about this
anytime I'm selling
anything, uh, or fulfilling on
anything is what I buy this
myself.
And if you can't answer that
question confidently, then some of
these different action items and
things we talked through today
might help you to layer in more
value to what you're doing so that
you can then say, yeah, I would
buy
this myself.
Uh, and there's a few examples
like client ascension, uh, like
that's my business along with
a few of the other coaches.
And we all actively use client
ascension as if we're students.
So I'm always
learning from guys like, you know,
that are on the call, uh, like
Oliver and Scott and Faison who've
been in
the program for a little while.
We're all learning together.
And so I would buy it myself
because I actively use it.
Uh, another example is my lead
generation business knowledge X.
We sell cold
email Legion and the way we get
our clients is through cold email.
So I'm literally using the same
service that I'm selling to get
clients.
And so it's an active
representation of we would buy it
ourselves
because we're using it.
And then it's not just my
businesses.
It supplies to every business, uh,
like
Apple, like all the guys that work
at Apple, even at the C level
executives use the iPhone and use
the
different products that Apple
sales.
Right.
So you want to start with your
offer and make sure these
three things are solid.
Uh, this is pretty basic stuff,
but it is very important to really
go through
and, and, you know, ask yourself
these questions and have
conviction on all three of these
things.
So
any questions or points to
discussion before we go into phase
two,
anyone, anyone, anyone, anyone,
cool.
All right.
Actually, I'll, I'll, I'll toss
something in just to mix it up.
Um, we've,
we've talked about this a little
bit before, but, uh, because there
are other guys in here who are
doing creative services stuff for
number two, when you talk about
prioritized results, what would be
a
good way to, uh, essentially
quantify results for creative
offers?
Uh, because it's, it's a
different,
different nature than lead gen or
anything like that.
Yeah, that's a great question.
So results doesn't, they don't
have to be like quantitative.
It doesn't
have to be a number result.
It could be, um, the fact that
they now have a video to use in
their
ads.
Like that can be a result that is
successful.
And this is why I love, uh,
agencies like yours and
like the creative agencies like
app development, because the end
result that they're looking for
is a functional app or a new
website that actually works and,
and it loads really quickly and
they're
getting, uh, you know,
complimented on it by their, their
users.
Like that can be an end result.
Doesn't necessarily have to be
numbers, ROI conversion.
It never, it doesn't always have
to be quantitative.
It really depends on your offer
and the service you're providing
and what the goal
of it is.
There's also a question down here,
uh, that we'll talk about later
on, which is how's your
client measuring success.
And you want to get really clear
on that question.
And you should
literally ask your client at the
start of every relationship.
Like how are you measuring success
after 30 days or after the, the
completion of our services, what
does success look like to you?
And so from the very beginning,
you now understand what to work
towards because they told you what
success looks like.
So when you work with someone,
Scott, they might say, Hey, I just
want a really
nice video that I can use in my
Twitter ads, or I want a really
nice video that I can put on my
landing
page that really fits the branding
and showcases what my product can
do for people.
And they're not
good.
And that might just be it.
And so working towards what they
define success to be is, is a
great leverage
point.
Good question.
Any follow-up to that or anyone
else have anything to chime in?
Well, it's not just yourself, but
it's also the team.
If you have somebody on your team
that doesn't
believe in the offer, that's a
problem too.
I've seen that in the past.
Yeah, that's a great point.
That's a great point.
Um, yeah, especially your sales
guys.
Like that's,
that's usually where this matters
most is the sales process.
Um, but also like the point of
asking this
question is if you don't answer
confidently and then, and this is
a great test too.
Like if you find a team
member that doesn't fully buy into
what you're selling, ask them why
and ask them what would they
need to see or what would need to
change for that answer to be
different.
And then that'll just give
you answers and clarity on what
you need to improve or do
differently.
So it's not just, Oh, I don't
believe in my service.
Maybe I should think of something
else.
Or maybe I should quit.
It's like, no, like figure out
what it takes for you to then
believe in your
service.
When I first started doing cold
email, I had no experience with
cold email and I couldn't
see tangible results.
And so I didn't fully believe in
it.
So I tested it myself and I was
able to
see results and therefore I was
able to confidently sell it.
Um, and the more results, the more
success,
the more you're going to believe
in something.
Uh, and so that's that.
Okay.
So phase one,
really basic stuff, right?
I don't want to bore you guys, but
there, there are layers to it that
really often get overlooked that
affect the other phases, which is
why we start there.
Uh, so phase two, this is just
talking about, okay, now you've
signed a client.
Like first
impressions are so, so important.
Uh, and the most common mistake I
see like new agency owners make
is they don't really have an
onboarding process.
And if they do, it's, it's pretty
all over the place.
Uh, I don't want to call out names
or anything like that, but like
recently we bought a service
uh, and I just paid the invoice.
And after I paid the invoice, like
nothing happened for like 24
hours.
And so I was pretty confused.
I'm like, did they get the
invoice?
What's the next steps?
Did I get scammed?
Right?
Like these questions start coming
in your head and that really
affects
the remainder of the relationship.
And so let's talk about
onboarding, right?
The first 24 hours I say
are the most important because in
the first 24 hours, that's when
buyers remorse starts to settle
in.
Did I make the right decision?
Did I get scammed?
Maybe I spent too much money,
whatever.
Like these
are all thoughts that are natural
for humans after they make a big
purchase decision.
And so you want
to confirm to them that they made
the right decision.
And the example I always use is
like,
what happens after you buy
something off of Amazon?
Like immediately they send you a
confirmation
email.
Like imagine a scenario where you
bought something off Amazon and
they never sent you an
email and nothing happened after
the fact.
You'd be confused as shit.
You would have, you would have
been like me last week thinking
that I went to some other website
and put in my social security
number
and got scammed.
Like that's the feeling you'd
have.
And you'd probably never buy from
Amazon again,
because you're scared that you
might get scammed.
So it's the same thing when
someone buys your agency
services and they don't get a
confirmation email, they're going
to be confused.
They're going to be
lost.
They're going to be concerned,
right?
And so have a confirmation email
and not just a confirmation
email, but same thing with Amazon.
They send you emails when your
order ships, when it delivers,
when it's out for delivery, right?
So like each step of the way,
they're notifying you what's going
on
with your order and you should do
the same thing with your agency
services.
And then they have a
feedback loop.
So once your order delivers, they
always send you an email asking
for feedback and
deliver review.
So they constantly have that
feedback loop.
And so you can learn a lot from a
simple
Amazon ordering process, right?
So that's the first 24 hours.
And then the first 30 days for
eight,
this is more applicable to like an
agency service.
You really have 30 days to impress
the client with your actual
service because within 24 hours,
they're not going to see whether
or not
your service works.
So the first 24 hours are more so
about reassuring that they sign up
to something
that's legit and structured,
right?
You just got to show them that
you're professional.
Within the
first 30 days, you have to show
them that you actually have a
roadmap to get them to where they
want to
be.
And so it's similar to like
university.
When you go and sign up for
university, not all of us went to
school here.
But when you go and sign up for
college, you get a syllabus for
each of the classes,
which outlines exactly what you're
going to cover for the entire
class, like for three or four
months.
It's outlined step by step.
And it also outlines exactly what
you need to bring the class, what
to
show up with materials.
And so you can learn a lot from a
college syllabus.
There's also a campus map.
So similar to an offer like Client
Ascension where we have weekly
calls, like imagine you
didn't know where these calls were
being hosted.
We'd probably have no one showing
up.
So we have to
constantly remind students of
where classes are or where they're
taking place, where to find
things,
right?
We have to give them a map.
And then there's also a portal,
which is where they're able to
communicate with you or with other
students.
And that's essentially what we use
Slack for.
And so the whole idea behind this
first part is you want to recreate
the same experiences
that the universities are creating
and that companies like Amazon are
creating because they're
successful
for these reasons.
And first impressions and agency
services, it's all about making
an experience out of it, creating
an experience that really gets the
attention of your clients.
So
I'm going to stop there for a
second because there's a lot we
just covered.
What are the questions or
points of conversation you guys
have based on this stuff?
I got one.
For a lot of the companies that
I've talked to, they'll have net
15,
net 30 payments on invoices and
stuff.
So there's not that immediate
thing that they can get,
because usually there'll be a
deposit.
There's not an immediate payment
that they can make to trigger
a lot of onboarding actions.
What are those triggers
that would kind of set in place,
like the onboarding email or that
type of stuff?
Yeah, the way we have it set up at
our agency is as soon as we get
the signed contract.
So when we get this, we do two
different things.
When we get the signed contract,
we basically send them like an
Amazon email saying, "Congrats,
you're now a client of KnowledgeX.
Keep an eye out on your inbox.
Within the next 24 hours, our team
will send you an onboarding email
with more information." So even
though we send them the onboarding
email right away,
there's some point of
communication saying, "Hey, we got
your order.
We're working on it."
Right?
And it's like that simple step in
the process goes a long way.
Let me actually pull that
up to share it with you guys
because it's so simple, but it is
so effective because the
onboarding
process for a lot of agencies is
manual.
There's certain links and assets
that you have to put in
an onboarding email that's
different for every client.
So unless you're on your computer
24/7,
there's most likely going to be a
delay between when someone signs
or pays and when they get the
onboarding email.
So adding a really simple
automated step in between goes a
long way.
I'll find this for you real quick.
Yeah, this is the onboarding
email.
And again, it's like,
let's see the emotion that this
produces when you see this email.
It's the same thing your client's
going to feel right.
So think of going into, you just
paid or you just signed a contract
and you're
kind of like nervous and you're
all tense and you're stressed out.
And then you see this email
with like the minions cheering and
a jiff.
And it's like, you now have a
smile on your face and you're
happy and it like brings up these
different emotions.
And it's kind of childish and
silly,
but it really works.
So it's as simple as this, like
welcome, name, let's grow.
Congrats.
You just took
a huge step towards scaling your
agency.
Keep an eye out for an email from
our CEO outlining the next
steps.
We couldn't be more excited to
work together.
Simple, right?
Like not, like not much goes into
that at all.
Yeah, that's great.
This is, uh, yeah, this is a major
step of the process.
That's all
automated.
Um, cause there's really not much
there.
Same with the client ascension
onboarding process.
I think we have that pretty
dialed.
So if you go back and look like,
what do we do when we first,
you know, when you first like paid
or signed the contract, you could
kind of recreate a lot of that
as well.
Yeah.
That's, that's what I've been
modeling it off of is client
ascension stuff.
Yeah.
So client ascension is, is
there's, there's not much
uniqueness to the onboarding
email.
So we
could automate it for something
like knowledge X, it's a little
bit different.
We have to like
set up different assets that we
then link in an onboarding email.
So we add in that buffer email
before the actual onboarding email
gets sent out.
So regardless, there's a
confirmation email of
some sort and then order updates
basically feedback comes later on,
but yeah, great question.
And we'll get more to the onboard.
I mean, we can kind of talk about
it now since we're
headed in that direction, but like
in onboarding email is so
important.
Uh, the number one goal of
an onboarding email is to include
specific next steps for yourself
and for the client.
Like, don't be afraid to
give your clients next steps.
Like this is the time when you
should be asking your clients to
do specific
things.
Basically give them homework.
Like we do for client ascension.
We ask you to watch a welcome
video.
We ask you to fill out an
onboarding form and we ask you to
schedule an onboarding call.
Like we're
giving you homework.
Uh, so a lot of service providers
are hesitant to ask their clients
to do something for
them.
So don't be that guy.
Um, and then one thing we also do
for knowledge X, at least again,
let me pull this up real quick as
an example, because it's helpful
to see it as we do a personalized
welcome video.
So like right here, I'll just show
you this.
And this is also in the learning
platform
as an example, but like, this is
our knowledge X, uh, onboarding
email that is sent like manually.
And right away we say, I recorded
a quick welcome video for you.
Check it out here.
And it's literally just me in my
Tiger Woods hat after a nice golf
round that morning.
Uh,
like literally reading them
through the email.
That's it.
And it goes such a long way
because
they, they get to see my face.
They see that this isn't
automated, obviously, because I
recorded this
video specifically for them.
And, and then it also gives me
control over, okay, there's a lot
of steps
here.
There's a lot of things for them
to do.
Let me give more context around
each of them.
So
there's full clarity and they're
not confused or lost.
And so the welcome video, I'll
post this in
the chat.
If you guys want to take a look at
it after the call, it goes a long
way.
Um, so that's that.
Any questions on, uh, anything
we've talked about so far?
I'm working now.
This stuff going once going twice.
All right, cool.
And again, this is pretty
generic stuff.
It's very surface level.
The, the idea behind this is to
introduce you guys to client
retention and what like the core
concepts are, and then to dive
further into real examples, like
I've
been kind of showing and then also
in the learning platform.
But anyways, onboarding email is
super
important.
Um, and then scheduling an
onboarding call.
Uh, so I think an onboarding call
is a really
important step for service
providers to have, uh, cause it
allows you, uh, and your client to
actually
meet and synchronize as a team.
It's basically like an, yeah, it's
an onboarding slash a launch call.
So on an onboarding call, a few
things I always like to accomplish
is team introductions.
They want to know specifically who
they're working with and you want
to know who specifically from
their team you're working with.
So get aligned on that and just go
through like basic roles.
Like,
Hey, I'm focused on design.
I'm focused on software
development.
I'm focused on admin level task.
I'm focused on project management.
Like just make sure there's
clarity, uh, between roles.
You'll then want to talk through
the roadmap.
So, uh, we use this roadmap at
knowledge X, I'll do another
screen share.
That, uh, is a really great visual
for these onboarding calls.
What is it?
And it just helps them to
visualize like where we're going
with everything.
And you could recreate this pretty
easily for your own agency.
And it's a helpful exercise
anyways,
because it'll tell you like, what
are the steps working with
someone?
Scott also does a great job
with this.
This is a lot more simple, uh,
cause it's just a video.
And so come up with a roadmap.
Like,
what is the actual process week
one or week zero, week one, week
two, week three, week four,
what is the process for working
with your agency?
What does that look like?
And you could just literally
talk through it on the onboarding
call.
Right.
So there's, uh, Scott, actually,
if you don't mind,
could you share, uh, like your
version of a roadmap?
Cause you have a great, uh,
Yeah, I'm going, I'm, uh, going to
my Twitter.
I'm going to send the link.
Tweeted a while back.
Yeah.
It's just so much more simple.
It's like,
it's much better.
Um, but anyways, okay.
So we'll go back to this.
Here we go.
Let's see if this opens.
Yeah.
So like, literally like this is
Scott's and it's just so helpful
for someone to visualize
because they see what's the
process.
Well, I upload the files that I
want in my video to Dropbox.
I request the videos in the Trello
board.
I requested changes in frame.
And within five to seven days,
I received my video and it's like,
that's so simple, but it's so
effective because clients
now know exactly the four-step
process and the tools involved.
They're not lost and there's no,
um,
typo.
Yeah.
Another thing I'll note too, on
not, not the typo thing, but kind
of in that spirit is that
when you do this in the, I would
still encourage you to do it
obviously in the early stages of
your
business, but like, it's going to
probably change significantly.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
So at this point, like this is not
even accurate to us.
Cause like we moved away from
Dropbox.
We were not using Trello as much.
Uh, the timeline's different, but
yeah, it's still a really
good concept to utilize.
Yep.
Great.
Thanks for that, Scott.
Uh, yeah.
So talk through the roadmap.
Uh, and then the onboarding call
is a great opportunity to set
expectations right in the
beginning.
Cause at the time of the
onboarding call, like your service
hasn't really been performed
yet.
It's more so like a preparation
slash a launch call.
Uh, and so it was a great
opportunity to set
expectations.
Even if you've already done this
in the sales process, even if
you've already done this
in your onboarding emails, set
expectations multiple times, even
30 days into working with
someone reset realign expectations
because people are going to
forget.
And what I mean by UP and OD is
under promise and over deliver.
Uh, so a great example of this is
that our agency, we used to
promise
like 10 calls booked per month and
majority of the time would fall
short of that.
We'd get anywhere
around like five to eight calls
booked and clients would be pretty
upset because we didn't get 10
calls
booked.
And so we didn't change anything
about the service we provided or
how much we charged or
anything like that.
The only thing we changed is we
told clients instead of 10 calls,
we expect five.
And that allowed us then to a more
majority of the time actually hit
it, hit KPIs, hit expectations.
And when clients would get five
calls or eight calls, they'd be a
static and literally nothing
changed except the expectation we
set in the very beginning.
So it's crazy.
Like how that works.
And in a story, I always love the
reference here is Warby Parker,
where I buy my glasses from.
They're also a public company.
They're huge.
What they do, anytime I've ordered
a pair of glasses from
their website, they give me a
timeline on when I should expect
to get them.
Usually five to seven days is
like the shipping time.
But they always deliver within the
next one or two days.
And even though
at this point, since I've ordered
so many times from them, I know
that they're going to show up
earlier,
it still tells me five to seven.
And so in my head, I'm expecting
them to come later and they show
up
early.
And that's a really great feeling
as a consumer and as a customer.
If they just told me, if they told
me like Amazon, it's going to be
next day or overnight delivery.
And it was overnight.
It's like, okay, whatever, like
that was supposed to happen.
And it's not as exciting.
So great example of under
promising and over delivering,
just set yourself up for success
when you set up expectations.
Cool.
Connor, good to see you here.
I'll have the recording in the
learning platform later.
Appreciate you being here.
The other thing you want to do on
the onboarding call is just answer
all the questions.
Like most of the time,
between the sales process and the
onboarding, your clients are going
to have questions about different
things that they've seen that are
new to them.
And so make sure you get very
clear on answering those
questions for them.
And then at the end of the
onboarding call, set next steps.
What happens next?
What do you need the client to do?
And what are you going to do?
And be very clear about that.
So that's phase two, making a
really good first impression.
The two really big leverage points
here is an onboarding email and an
onboarding call.
What questions do you guys have on
this stuff?
I actually had a question on that
for like the onboarding call.
Yeah.
So like for someone, I know like
mine's more specific, but the
onboarding call for me,
or maybe someone that's more
creative, it'd be much more
heavily based on
like questions to understand their
voice, what exactly they're trying
to go for.
Should I keep like, you know,
should I even set expectations,
like say it briefly or just
like, cause I want like most of
that time probably to be asking
them about what do they want out
of the
content or videos that I'm making
and stuff?
Like, should that be everything
and changing the order of
stuff here?
No, this is a great.
So we did something similar within
our agency where we would kind of
run out
of time on our onboarding call
because we'd try to cover too
much.
So if you can relate to what Kyle
just said, listen up, because this
is something that had a huge
impact on our agency.
So what we would
do on the onboarding calls, we
just focus on some of the more
generic stuff, like you said, like
trying to like, just ask them
follow up questions based on their
onboarding form, basically nothing
crazy.
And you just take out this piece,
setting expectations, and you move
that down to another
call, which is what we call an
alignment call.
So the onboarding call is fully
focused on strategy and
making sure you have everything
you need to launch campaigns and
implement your strategy.
And then you set an alignment
call, which is like, it could be
like five to 15 minutes,
where you literally hop on the
call and you say, okay,
everything's set, very clear on
what needs
to happen, strategies, campaigns
are live, whatever.
Here's what to expect.
Let's get aligned on
expectations.
And then you literally just go
through your expectations on that
one call and nothing else,
you're fully aligned.
And then you could even implement
alignment calls once a month or
once
a quarter.
It's a healthy practice to
continue to stay aligned with your
client.
So I'm happy you asked
that question.
Is that clear?
Does that like help?
Definitely.
Yeah, that helps a lot.
Cool.
It's like a checkpoint call,
essentially.
Yeah, because a lot of the times
with our services,
there's just so much to talk about
on one call.
And it's like, you spent 45
minutes talking about
strategy and answering all their
questions.
And then you spend the last 15
talking about expectations.
And like, because there was so
much information, they don't even,
they didn't even remember what the
expectations were.
They didn't even have the mental
capacity to process them at the
time.
And so they'll usually forget, or
they'll probably just ask again
later on and be confused.
So yeah,
if you could dedicate like a two
call process to that.
Very smart.
Dope.
Anyone else to follow up on what
Kyle said or any other questions
on phase two?
Dope.
All right.
So going into phase three, it's
all about ongoing management.
So now that you've
retained them for 30 days, which
is usually like one billing cycle,
you know, you're, you did a pretty
good job.
You're like, you're started.
And so this is where the ongoing
management is really shifts
in the focus.
And it's just a good reminder to
continue to prioritize results.
Above everything
else, like no matter what tactics
you implement here, no matter how
cool your onboarding process is,
no matter how often you check in
with your clients, if the results
aren't there, they're not going to
be
there.
Because at the end of the day,
they might be friendly and you
might be boys with them.
But if
the results aren't there, as long
as they're a good business owner,
they're not going to stick around.
And if they're not a good business
owner and they continue to stick
around, they're not going to be
in business to be able to pay you
anymore anyways.
So it's like, you're going to lose
them if results
are not there.
And so always prioritize results.
And there's different ways to work
around this.
It's not
just results are all that matters.
If you don't get results, you're
screwed.
Or if you're getting results,
you don't have to do anything.
There's still a process to follow
here.
And so one thing to highlight
is that communication is
everything.
I think the number one reason why
people lose clients outside of
not getting the results they could
be is because they don't
communicate enough.
Or they communicate
enough about certain things, but
not other things, which we'll talk
about.
So over communicate,
like, over communicate, remind
yourself to over communicate, like
every single day,
if there's a thought that enters
your mind, like, hey, maybe I
should do this for a client,
or maybe I should ask this
question.
Like, don't even think about it
past that thought,
like implement it, communicate.
And I've had that happen before.
The more you communicate better.
And there's two sides to it.
When you're performing well, let
the client know.
A lot of times,
like if things are going well,
you're like, oh, great, like
things are going well,
whatever.
I don't have to do anything like
you want to let the client know
when and that things are
going well.
A lot of people just forget to do
this, because then they'll know
that things are going
well.
A lot of the times on your end,
you're like, oh, yeah, like, for
Kyle, like, I just got them a
LinkedIn post that got 1000
impressions.
That's huge.
But the client might see that and
not really know the
impact or understand that it is a
successful accomplishment.
So Kyle has to let them know,
hey, dude, like, I don't know if
you saw, but the post that we put
up last week just passed 1000
impressions.
That's 10x what we've seen on
average from all of our other
clients just wanted to say
congrats.
And I'm happy to be working with
you.
And it's like, oh, shit, like that
makes the client feel
good.
And it makes it reaffirms that
they're getting the results that
they're there for.
So let the clients know when
things are going well.
Right?
Okay.
And then the other thing, the
harder thing is when things are
not performing well, or when
things are not going to plan, let
the client know.
And this is like the toughest one
for people is
they try to hide things or they
try to kind of, you know, like
tunnel vision, I'll fix it myself
kind of vibe and mentality without
involving the client or without
letting the client know.
And this is a recipe for disaster.
It's just a ticking time bomb all
the time.
If you do this for long
enough, you're going to lose the
client and it's going to blow up
in your face.
And they're not
pleasant conversations to have.
It's just confrontation.
And it's shying away from
confrontation.
And it's not, I mean, I struggled
with that a lot.
I struggled with it for the
longest time.
And I feel like I've gotten even
better at it now, but it's still
difficult conversations
that have to be had in business.
It's just part of the game.
And the key thing here is just to
deploy
honesty because it's really easy
to be honest with someone.
It's very natural and you don't
have to,
you know, strategize around how to
present it to them.
And so what this means is just
always be
the first to address problems.
Clients really, really appreciate
that.
So again, like if you see
a problem in the business, don't
be like, oh, maybe we'll fix this
in a week and the client won't
even
notice that we had a really bad
week.
By the time we fix it, things will
be going well and they won't
even notice.
Like address the problem always.
But also on the flip side, never
address problems
on their own.
Always address a problem with a
potential solution.
Clients are not going to be
so upset if things are going wrong
as long as you have an action plan
on what to do on the other side.
What is your solution or what are
you going to try differently that
is going to get things back on
track?
Every time that I've done this,
you have to do it enough to like
see that like clients are humans
as well and they're understanding
and they're not all douchebags.
And so if you deploy honesty
and you let them know that things
are not going well and you also
let them know about your plan
and why you think it's going to
work and get us back on track,
they really appreciate that.
Like most of the times we do this,
it buys us another month with our
client.
And even if things
don't end up working out, there's
no bad blood when we have a client
breakup.
And a lot of the times
they'll refer us clients after.
And that's important because a bad
client is a really big risk to
have
out in the marketplace because
they'll bad mouth you to other
people and they'll ruin your
reputation
even after the fact.
Uh, and so this is really
important.
Integrity in businesses is
something
that's just not talked about.
Okay.
Again, a lot of information
covered there.
What questions
do you guys have or points of
conversation to bring up?
Um, I'm not quite sure how to like
exactly phrase this, but so, you
know, we have quite a few existing
clients and I think in the last
month or two, there's, there's a
couple of them we haven't
done a great job for.
Um, like we've been behind on some
things.
Um, we pushed some bugs out to
production apps and like, there's
just been a few things that have
been going out so smoothly lately.
And I was wondering how you would
approach like, say you haven't
been doing a great job of checking
in with, with clients up to now.
And you want to start like, how
would you approach those, those
situations like maybe, you know,
maybe where we haven't done the
best job for them in the last
month or two?
Yeah.
How would you approach that?
It's so easy for you.
Uh, if I were you, what I would
say is, uh, I'd basically put
together a
loom video and say, Hey guys, you
know, Avery here just wanted to
address, uh, just give you an
admin
level update about the business
and how things are going.
Uh, you know, with, with the team
and I,
one thing we've noticed after
doing an audit and kind of looking
back these past 60 days is we're
not doing as good a job as we can
with client communication.
Uh, and we still have a lot to
learn when it comes to that.
And we appreciate your patience.
We appreciate your understanding.
Uh,
and so one thing that we're doing
differently is we invested into
this program, uh, this coaching
program where we're working with
other agency owners and we're
learning different tactics and
strategies and systems we could
implement to better communicate
with clients.
So we're investing in
ourselves, uh, and we're
implementing everything we're
learning.
And so I think you're going to
have
a much better experience.
And one thing that we ask, uh, of
you as a client is to be honest
with us,
provide us all your feedback and
give us things that we can work on
and do a better job at.
And we can
work together as a team like that
right there.
If I'm a client and I hear that
message, like,
first off, you're addressing the
problem, which is key, right?
Like, Oh, okay.
He, he,
he's notices that he could be
doing a better job of, uh, of
communicating, but two, you
brought
them a solution.
You just told me that you noticed
it.
And so you took action and
actually invested
profits that you probably earned
from them into a coaching program
for the sole purpose to get
better and fix these problems.
Like that right there tells me
everything I need to hear.
And that's my
guy.
Like I want to be working with
Avery and his agency because he's
displaying a willingness to learn
and
improve.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
Thanks for that.
Yeah, dude.
Well, I didn't really help you at
all.
You made the decision on your own.
So I just kind of gave you the
different words to say.
So
props to you, man.
Yeah.
I think that's a great idea to
like record a video and send it
over to
him.
I appreciate that suggestion.
Yeah.
People appreciate honesty and they
also appreciate effort.
Uh, and so I think videos get
across a lot better because it can
show like your emotion and like,
it's not just like a typed out
message that can be glossed across
pretty easily.
good stuff, dude.
Um, okay.
So moving on just cause I want to
make sure we get through
at least the first four phases,
uh, is to hire a client success
team.
So basically what this is
saying, I mean, there's different
reasons to hire a client success
team.
Uh, I think like everyone
should have a client success team,
but another reason for this, and
to be honest, part of the reason
why I
hired a client success team is so
that I don't have to have these
difficult conversations with
clients
because it's just not my strong
suit.
It's very similar to sales.
Like I hate sales.
I never want
to be on a sales call.
And so I outsource that to someone
that's really good at it.
And so it's just
self-awareness.
Um, but at the same time, you're
eventually going to need a client
success team
either way.
If you're growing to, you know,
different levels where you have
too many clients to manage.
Um, and the goal of this team,
like their job is to ensure client
success, right?
Just like the job title
says, uh, and the number one goal
you should have for your client
success team is to get
out of email and Slack.
This is so important.
Get out of email and Slack and
onto phone calls.
And this is why you're, you're
probably going to have to
outsource it because us as
business owners
have so much other shit to deal
with and so much other things
going on that we probably don't
have
enough time to get on calls with
all of our clients every week or
every other week or every month.
Right.
And so the whole goal of a client
success team is so that they could
get onto calls.
Um,
and this is so important.
So, so important because we're all
really accustomed to using email
and using
Slack.
And it's similar to what I was
just telling Avery, but there's a
big difference between text
and calling.
Right.
It's just like, if you were going
to break up with a girl and like,
are you going to text her or
you're going to call her?
Like what's more respectful?
What's the right
thing to do?
Uh, it's pretty obvious.
Right.
And it's the same thing in
business.
And the reason is
because tone often gets
misinterpreted through text.
You, and, and we're all guilty of
this and we all do
this probably every day.
Like you get an important text
from a client or a client sends
you a message
and they're frustrated.
Like, Hey, like you're not getting
the results and you read that.
And it's
probably right in a very different
way than they had intended for it
to be interpreted.
And so it helps
to just get on a call rather than
overanalyzing text and just
written word, obviously like
there's
the time and place for email and
Slack, and you're still going to
use it a whole lot, but be sure to
implement calls with clients
often.
Uh, cause if you don't, there's
going to be tone that gets
misinterpreted that can lead to
confusion, um, and
misunderstandings, which can lead
to churn,
which is the worst way to lose a
client.
That's an important concept that,
uh,
I just want to make sure got
across.
Good.
How would you go about, um,
I guess differentiating client
success manager versus project
manager when your primary service
provision is one time?
Yeah.
So I think for you, Scott, like
this is not a role you need to
hire
for, but a responsibility that you
can add onto what the project
manager is doing.
Right.
So it,
it doesn't have to be its own
role.
It could be a lot of people refer
to client success managers as
project managers or account
managers.
So it's, it's more so the actual
responsibility
of getting on calls and
communicating with clients.
And it's easy for a project
manager since they're, they're
really accustomed to what the
project is
anyways.
And so they can have those
communities.
They can have those conversations
in an intelligent
way.
Um, and I think that's the hardest
thing for people is to find client
success managers that
actually understand the work that
you're doing, because if they
don't understand the work you're
doing, your client's going to have
a conversation with them.
They're going to notice that they
have no
idea what's going on and they're
going to ask to talk to you
instead.
And so that's like the number
one pain point with people hiring
this role.
So I think, uh, actually doing
what Scott did
is a, is a really good strategy is
to find someone that's already
somewhat involved in these
campaigns.
And they understand the work
that's going on with these clients
and either make them a client
success
manager or give them these client
success manager responsibilities.
It's very simple.
Just,
it could be as simple as adding a
weekly call or adding a call, uh,
an alignment call one week into
the project.
They're adding, um, an exit
interview.
Uh, we do an exit interview
anytime we churn a client
and it's just an opportunity for
us to understand why that client
churned, uh, which most of the
time is just
stupid reasons that we could then
resolve on the call and actually
end up retaining the client,
which is pretty funny.
Um, and then if it is a real
reason, we can figure it out and
we could improve
based on that conversation.
So like calls are so important.
Um, and Scott, you could even have
a
project manager.
As soon as you deliver the
project, you can say, Hey, uh,
this is great.
Everything's
good.
You know, go and use this however
you intended.
It'd be great if we could set up a
call,
a check-in call 90 days from now,
just so I can get an idea for how
you end up using the video
and how it worked for you.
And that call could be actually
part of your sales process
because you can basically pitch
them another video at that point.
Yeah.
I should, I should do, I should do
that.
Like a quarter delayed exit
interview.
Yeah.
Or just a check, just a status
call.
Like how, how did the video work
for you?
I'm,
I'm just curious to know how you
used it.
Uh, what is the feedback that you
got on it?
And it's just an easy way for you
to have like that open
conversation, that continued
conversation
with clients.
Um, yeah, so that, that's, uh, all
about conversation.
The other big thing
about all of this is not to let
emotions fly.
Um, I think like a lot of times,
especially early on,
and especially for us, like
smaller agency owners where we're
doing a lot of the work and it's a
representation of like who we are,
negative feedback can be really
like emotionally damaging
to an agency owner.
And so my biggest piece of advice
is not to take things personally.
Like usually when a client is
complaining, it's a reflection of
something that's going on in their
business that actually has nothing
to do with you.
And even if it's about your
service, that's not
you.
That's your service.
So separate business from
personal.
Uh, because a lot of times agency
owners get really discouraged and
depressed because they take
negative feedback as a negative
mark on
who they are as a person.
And that's never the case.
Super important.
Um, a few more things here.
So ongoing management, you always
want to over deliver.
Uh, if you could
kind of hold back certain pieces
of your offer and drip them out as
surprises or bonuses, that's a
great strategy.
Uh, so we do that by educating our
clients and building community.
So that's not really
part of our offer.
Like people come to work with us
to do cold email campaigns, but we
add bonuses
in value to help them with other
areas in their business through
training, sharing our learnings
and weekly emails, newsletter
style emails, super simple.
So think of ways you can over
deliver
outside of what you're doing with
your service.
Um, it could even be one thing
that I've seen people
do here is, uh, sending books to
their clients, sending, um, gifts
to their clients, uh, sending
thank you letters to their
clients, just what are different
personal touch points you can add
to show that you really care and
that you want to, you know, uh,
impress your clients.
Events, right.
It's something we're doing with
client ascension events.
Stuff like that.
What do you do, Andre?
Uh, this is what we do at our
agency.
So for the most part at knowledge
X, at least we just
bury them in training.
Uh, so the nice thing with
knowledge X is we work with agency
owners
and they come to us for cold
email.
And what happens is when we do
cold email, it just shines light
on
the fact that they need help with
sales.
And then if they do a good enough
job with sales, it shines
light on the fact that they need
help with fulfillment and all
these different parts of the
agency.
And so we just help them with each
of those parts because we have
experience.
We have client
ascension, which coaches people to
do these things.
So we just train the shit out of
them
when they didn't even pay us for
training to begin with.
They just paid us for cold email
strategy.
And, and that could be different
for everyone.
Right.
And then we also have community
another,
oh, this is a great one.
The, so for us, we do a power
intros.
So because we work with so many
agency owners, chances are like we
could make some really powerful
connections within our own
network.
So some of the guys on this call
might've experienced this.
I think I I've done a few
for Oliver where I've connected
him with some of my clients where
it made sense.
And that goes a long
way because you can help, you
know, cultivate business
relationships with your clients
and other
people in your network.
Uh, and, and for you too, Lucas,
like this is something you do
email
marketing, build connections with
other e-commerce agencies that
have complimentary services.
Cause most likely if someone's
using you for email marketing,
they might be looking
or needing someone to help with
Facebook ads or TikTok ads.
And if you could be the person
that introduces them to that
person that does it, you're now
way more valuable to that client.
Zach give you some ideas.
Yeah, yeah, no, for sure.
Thank you.
Sick.
Uh, of course, dude.
So, okay.
Last thing here, expectations
versus actual results.
This is probably the most
important question on the entire
document when it comes to client
retention is
getting an answer to how is your
client measuring success.
Uh, and a really easy way to ask a
client,
this is like, what does success
look like for you in 30 days or in
60 days or in 90 days?
And then it gives you something to
work towards.
Um, and a lot of the times what
happens,
uh, this is the thing, like we'll
sometimes get on an alignment call
and we'll ask this question,
like, Hey, what does success look
like for you?
And they'll be like, Hey, I want
to get 20 calls a
month.
And I'll be like, Hey, to be
honest, it's just not possible
with our service.
What we can do is get five really
good ones, focus on those.
And if it makes sense, we can
scale
it up to 20 and it's just getting
on the same page.
And now that we set that
expectation
and if determine what success
looks like, there's not any
friction later on.
Okay.
Uh, so how's your client measuring
success?
Super random.
I don't know why I thought of
this,
but Scott, like when you set a
timeline for people that order a
video from you, you should
tell them like 14 days and always
deliver it within seven.
And I think that the satisfaction
that people
have after working with you
instantly boost for, yeah, I've
been, I've been, uh, I used to
tell
people like a week and a half or
some shit.
I tell them like three weeks now.
Um, and then the script
is delivered within like a day and
a half preview frames are done in
like four days.
And then the
video is done like a week after
that.
So it's probably like half the
time, like including revisions,
it's usually three weeks, but
that's like their, their fault,
you know?
Yeah.
So we're actually
delivering within like half the
time we tell them.
So, okay, great.
I don't know why I thought of
that,
but anyways, good stuff.
You're on it as always.
Um, so yeah, get very clear on how
is your client
measuring success.
Uh, so for like a Klaviyo agency,
they might be looking for a
specific boost
and email revenue, uh, for a lead
gen agency.
They might be looking for a
specific amount of leads,
uh, for a content posting agency.
They might be looking for a
certain amount of followers
that they want to gain every
month, figure out what that is.
Right.
And that'll allow you to actually
come up with a strategy that's
aligned with what they see as
successful.
And again, a lot of the times
it's not just, Oh, they want 20
calls booked.
Let me figure out how to get 20
It's like,
no, I have to realign expectations
and let them know we can only get
five and make sure that they're
still content with getting five.
And then I'll give them a roadmap
to scale up to 20, but they need
to
understand first that we could
only get five and they got to make
sure that that's okay.
Cause a lot
of the times will happen is you
could get five calls and then
they're like, yeah, we want to get
20.
And it's like, okay, sick.
Let's see if we could get really
good results then let's aim for 20
and
guaranteed you fall short of that
they're pissed off because you
were enthusiastic when they ran
it by you in the first place.
Whereas if you said, no, we can't,
we could get five.
And then if we get
five, we could focus on getting
10.
And then if we get 10, we could
focus on 15.
They're going to stay
with you each step of the way.
A lot of information today, guys.
Fuck.
All right.
Last few things.
So
expectations versus actual
results.
Another way to do this is first
figure out how are clients
measuring
success and then give them updates
on where you're at in regards to
that every single week.
So weekly
recap messages are a really
effective way to do this.
Really practical for our lead gen
agency.
Every week we'll give them an
update on how many leads we
generated.
So if their goal is 10 leads a
month and they see this week, we
got four leads, they know we're on
track.
Or if this week they saw we
got one lead, they know we're
falling behind and we could then
shift our attention towards what
needs to
happen to get back on track,
right?
Weekly cadences for messages.
And then live calls.
So there's different types of live
calls you can do at an agency.
You could do check-in calls.
You could do alignment calls like
we talked about earlier.
You could do a training call.
And you can do audit calls to
really figure out what's going on
with campaigns and what you might
need to pivot on.
I went through this super fast
just because I want to cover phase
four on this call.
And then I'll send you guys the
lesson in the learning platform
about phase five.
All right.
Let me just wrap up phase four and
then we could do any last
questions.
So phase four is
all about raising your prices.
So if you've successfully retained
clients up to this point
pretty consistently, it's time to
raise your prices.
And most people just raise their
prices and that's
it.
Like they just think raising their
prices is all of a sudden going to
attract like higher quality
clients and nothing has to change
other than the price.
And that's just not true.
You have to be able
to justify the price increase,
right?
Part of the justification is the
fact that clients are
actually retaining, meaning
they're getting the value from
your service.
So that's part of it.
But the other part of it is how
can you make your service more
valuable, right?
And so, I mean,
Avery honestly could go and raise
his prices and justify it by
saying we invested in new
education or new
information to make our services,
our team, our tech stack better by
learning from other agency owners,
right?
So if you're going to raise your
prices, use that additional money,
that additional cash flow
to invest in making your service
more valuable and worth more
money.
It's something that
everyone forgets and nobody talks
about.
Everyone just says raise your
prices and that's the end of
it.
It's not the case.
The reason raising your prices
works.
And if you want to raise your
prices and
never have to lower your prices
after the fact and do this,
because I've seen plenty of times
where
people raise their prices and they
don't do anything after the fact
and they initially and then they
then
have to put their prices down
again.
For us, our agency,
our lead gen agency in the past
year alone went from charging $600
a month to $800 a month to $1,100
a
month to $1,500 a month to $2,500
a month.
And then today we raised it to
$3,000 a month and our service
has gotten dramatically better at
each step of the way, which is why
we've never had the lower prices
after a
price raise.
And it's why we've been able to
consistently raise prices even
more.
It's because
we have the formula for increasing
the value every single time we
increase prices.
Super important.
A few ideas here again, invest in
new technology, invest in the team
members is the easiest one.
And it's the, I would say the
biggest lever you could pull as an
agency owner is just invest in
more team members.
And that's an easy way to justify
raising your prices.
So I glazed through
that really quickly.
What do you guys have for me on
that?
I've got a quick question.
With that, Andres, have you ever
experienced like an objection
from like an existing client when
raising your prices?
And how would you go about
handling that?
Oh, really good question.
So this is something I did not
clarify, but when we raise our
prices,
at least at our agency, it doesn't
affect current clients.
That's just our way of doing it.
Okay.
Yeah.
I found that to be a lot easier to
do it that way.
But a lot of the times agencies,
like I remember Lemlist, they're
SaaS, so it's a little bit
different, but like they just
increased
their prices for everyone and they
didn't grandfather anyone in.
But I'm a pretty firm believer in
like
grandfathering in early adopters
and rewarding them for making
decisions earlier on in our
journey.
But it's really depends on your
preference and what you want to
do.
So I don't necessarily have
an answer for that.
But if like, I guess I do.
It's just, again, like the reason
you should ask
these questions is so you have an
answer for that.
So if you're going to increase
prices for existing
customers, just explain to them
why.
I'm increasing prices so I can
invest in more team members so we
could communicate with you more
consistently and we could get you
better results.
Pretty simple.
Yeah.
Sweet.
Awesome.
That pretty much answered.
Appreciate that.
Gotcha, bro.
Sweet.
Yeah, go ahead, someone.
Just want to let you know, is it
possible for you to link the
document in Slack?
No, dude, I'm keeping this
forever.
I'm burning it after a call.
Yeah, that's an extra 2K,
actually.
Yeah, that's an epic call.
Yeah, of course, dude.
I'll share it.
Again, this is a beta, so I would
really appreciate any feedback you
guys have.
Like, I kind of just threw
all this together randomly.
I was bored the other night.
And so if you guys have any
feedback,
if this was valuable, I'd really
appreciate anything.
And then, yeah, I'll share the
document,
I'll share this recording, and
then I'll probably continue to add
to it for a few more days or
weeks.
And then once I feel like it's,
you know, finalized, I'll do a
whole lesson on it for the
learning platform.
No, bro, that was fucking solid.
I really liked it.
Sweet.
I appreciate that, dude.
And yeah, phase five is just
talking about how to optimize
operations.
So if you go on the learning
platform, it's the lesson titled
"How to Optimize Operations."
And I think it was Avery, or one
of the newer guys, asked about
like, where do you actually start?
Like, how do you know what to
tackle first?
That is going to cover exactly
that question.
Cool, guys.
Oh, I got to jump.
So I'm going now to a hotel in the
area here in Tampa to tour a venue
for our event in October,
on October 22nd.
So that's super exciting.
I'll probably send some pictures
and stuff in the group.
But just a reminder, if you guys
haven't heard about it yet, check
it out.
And hopefully you can
make plans to be there because
it's going to be pretty dope.
And there's going to be a lot more
information coming on that
probably starting next week.
Sweet.
All right.
Thank you all for being
here.
And I'll talk to you in Slack.
Until next time.
Thanks, Dondra.