What's up, guys?
Welcome back to another video.
And in this video, I want to talk
about setting
up proper communication channels
between you, your team, and your
client and their team.
So this is key.
It's so, so important to do this
right away early on because as a
client,
the biggest frustration is low
turnaround time or long turnaround
times when it comes
to communication or like slow time
to response and also not being
organized, like not knowing
where to actually communicate with
your service provider.
So you want it right from the get
go.
You want to be really transparent
and clear with your client about
where they can reach
you.
So traditional ways to do this can
be through email.
But the reason Slack has blown
up as much as it has in recent
months and just the past few years
is because it truly is the best
tool for client services business
and for tons of other different
stuff.
Like obviously, we use it
for the client ascension program
and it serves that purpose.
But anytime you want to centralize
communications and organize it and
do it in a way that's fun.
Because one thing that I'm not
sure how
much I talked about it in previous
videos in this module, but when it
comes to onboarding and
fulfillment, it always comes back
to experience.
You want to create the ultimate
experience for your
clients.
Like you want them to enjoy the
experience, right?
It has to be enjoyable.
It has to be easy
to access.
It has to be fun, new, exciting.
Like you don't want to bore them
with just back and forth
emails.
And emails are super unorganized.
You know, you might start a new
email thread and you might
want to refer back to something in
another email thread.
And you might not have included
everyone
on your team and their team in the
original email.
So you got to forward it.
So email is super messy.
But Slack is super organized.
So right from the get go, like you
saw in some of our onboarding
materials, we include Slack, like
a link to join the Slack
workspace, or maybe we just send
them an invite
through email.
But it's really simple.
You just want to use Slack to set
up communications with your
client.
And in the beginning, I'd keep it
really simple.
Like all you do is set up a
workspace,
right?
So you go to slack.com and you
create a new workspace, right?
And you just log in with your
account or whatever.
And when you create a Slack
workspace, you just name it like
whatever your
agency's name is.
So like for us, it's knowledge X.
So we just name it knowledge X
client workspace,
and that's it.
And then you could throw, you
know, your your company logo in
there.
And you're pretty
much all set up at that point.
So once you're in the knowledge X
client workspace, you're going to
have, I believe, three channels
that are default to any new Slack
workspace.
And that is a general chat,
a random chat and then an
announcements chat, I think, or
maybe as general and then chat and
then
random.
I forgot because I haven't started
a Slack group in the longest time.
But basically in real
quick, just for people who are not
too familiar with Slack and the
terminology, right?
So there are Slack
workspaces, which is what we have
here within client ascension.
This is a workspace here, right?
This,
this whole thing.
And then you see, I have two
different workspaces on the side.
So I have a
regular knowledge X workspace and
that's for me and my internal
team.
And then I have a knowledge X
client workspace.
So that's for all of our clients.
And then I have the client
ascension workspace, which
is for our coaching program.
And then within the workspace are
channels.
So all these things you see on
the left-hand side, like
announcements, chat, weekly call
links, wins, and then all these
private
channels are channels within a
workspace.
So you have a workspace and then
you have channels, right?
So you want to create a workspace
for your clients.
And then within the client
workspace, you want to
create a new channel for every
client you sign.
And then, so you'll have, so like
in our client
ascension, right, we have
announcements and then we have
chat, weekly call links, wins, and
then all
these private channels.
So when you sign on a client, I'd
keep announcements.
And basically announcements,
the way I look at that is like an
email newsletter.
So every client will be in the
workspace, meaning
they'll also have access to the
announcements channel.
And you could tailor the
announcements
channel, like the settings to, so
that like only you or other admins
from your team can post in
there.
So it's like a read only chat.
And then you could also do it so
that everyone is in it,
right?
So like every one of your clients
that are anyone in the Slack
workspace is in the
announcements channel.
So you could, you could treat it
like an email list because it's
just
like sending to the entire list,
the entire list of clients.
And then they can't like respond
back.
So like you won't really see, you
know, David can't respond or Abdi
can't respond to these messages.
So it's not like just another chat
area that's going to blow up.
It's just going to be like
strictly important messages, like
how we use it in client ascension.
Just pay attention because
that's how you'd use the
announcements channel in your
client workspace.
It's just anytime there's a
really important announcement that
applies to every one of your
clients.
Like, you know, right now
it's almost Christmas.
So I might send a Merry Christmas
update in the announcements
channel for
all of our clients and wish them a
happy new year and let them know,
you know, what our plans are in
the new year.
Right.
So that's the announcements
channel.
You don't need a chat or a weekly
call
links or a wins channel.
Like this is just for our program.
So the only general channel that
you
should consider having in your
client workspace is an
announcements channel because all
of your clients
will be in that channel, including
you and all your, the guys from
your team.
And then the only
people that could post in that
channel are the admins of the
Slack workspace, which is going to
be you
and most likely others from your
team.
Then in addition, what you're
going to do is have private
channels.
So if you look at the private
channels, every single student in
the client ascension program
has a private channel set up for
them.
So you do the same thing for your
clients, right?
And the way we
set it up was we just named these
channels, like the person's first
name, dash last name, dash
private.
So you could do like the same
thing.
So if you sign knowledge X as a
client, you could just do
knowledge X and you don't have to
put private.
You could use whatever naming
convention you'd like.
And all you do is you, instead of
leaving it open, so like open
channels have like this hashtag
next to it, meaning like anyone in
the workspace can join.
You just want to create it as a
private
channel.
So there's like a lock next to it,
which is super easy to do.
Like when you create a channel
in Slack, you hit add channel,
create new, and then you could
just set it to private.
And then you could
name the channel, right?
Like a knowledge X channel.
You could put a description if you
want
to like explain to your client
what it's used for, and then you
can make it private.
And then once you
create the channel, you could
decide who you want to invite.
And obviously when you first
onboard a
client, the client's not going to
be in your Slack right away.
So you'll first send them like the
general
invite link to join the Slack
workspace.
And then once you see that they've
joined the workspace,
you just go into, you know, like
the specific channel, and then you
could add them as a member
now that they're in your
workspace.
So that's, that's Slack.
So you could set it up however
you'd
like.
But like I said, you'd set up a
workspace specifically for your
agency.
So set up a agency
name and then dash, like I have it
here.
So you'll see like clock, like
knowledge X, right?
And then
there's that line.
And then it says client workspace.
So you just do, you know, your
agency's name,
client workspace.
And then within that workspace,
you'd have an announcements
channel, like I have
set up here.
And again, the announcements
channel is basically like your
email list that has all of
your clients on it.
So you could send important
information and updates through
the announcements
channel.
You could even call the channel
like important or company-wide
updates.
Like you don't
have to use the same naming
convention that we use, but
that's, you know, a standard one.
So you'll use
the announcements channel for
that.
And then anytime you sign a new
client, you'll just add a channel
and the channel would just be that
client's specific name.
And here's the thing, like
sometimes people
like to get super like complicated
with Slack and they'll set up like
multiple different channels
for one client.
We've done that in the past too.
But what we found is like the
client is looking for
the most straightforward way to
communicate with you as a service
provider.
So just set up one channel for
the client.
That's really all you need.
If you really need like another
channel, like for example,
we actually, for our clients, we
have a client name chat and a
client name calls.
So like the chat
is like where, you know, we would
discuss anything.
And then the calls is only for an
automation that we
have set up through Calendly.
So anytime a call is booked, since
we're doing a lead gen and we're
scheduling appointments for our
client, that's like the service we
provide, a notification will be
sent in the
calls channel.
And that's just for tracking
purposes.
And it's, it's nice for the client
to be able to go
to that channel and see all the
calls we've booked for them.
But that's really like the only
use case
I could think of to have multiple
channels set up is if you need to
like use automations in aggregate
data in real time to another
channel.
So the calls channel is only used
to keep track of all the calls
that we're booking from our
services.
And it's just easy for them to see
that in real time.
But the chat channel is where all
the activity is happening.
So that's how I would set up
Slack.
And it's so, so important, again,
to have this set up
professionally, right?
As soon as you onboard a
client, you want to get them into
your professional workspaces so
that they're not confused on like,
where do I reach out to their
team?
How do I know what's happening?
I haven't heard any updates.
Are
they working yet?
Have they gotten started?
Where are they at?
How long is it going to take?
What did
they need for me, if anything,
right?
So you want to make sure you're
super organized and set up on
Slack
right away.
And you can include a link, an
invite link to join your Slack
workspace right in that
onboarding email that you'll send
out to new clients.
So if you have any questions on
this,
let me know.
There's tons of videos and tons of
education around Slack and how
it's used.
And
that you could get super into it,
like with the private channels and
the automations and the
workflows.
But really, like Slack is such a
simple tool.
And the best way to learn how to
use it is
through actually using it.
So that's part of the reason why
we use Slack for our coaching
program,
where most other people use like
Telegram, or like a Facebook
group.
The reason
we use Slack is because as agency
owners, it's like necessary to use
Slack at this point.
Like,
I don't know any agency owners
that manage clients that don't use
Slack.
So with that in mind, I want
you guys to be comfortable using
Slack.
So now, you know, being part of
our Client Ascension Slack
workspace, you're learning how
Slack is to be used.
So you're watching me in the
announcements channel,
sending, you know, important
announcements, and you're watching
how people are communicating in
the chat,
and you're seeing how you could
like react to messages.
And you're seeing like the
difference
between a public channel and a
private channel.
And you're seeing how you could
send like direct
messages and DMs.
And you're seeing how you could
add all these different apps to
speed things up and
automate things, right?
So there's so much going on here.
And you'll even notice like in the
weekly
call links, like obviously, these
are all automated messages, I'm
not sending, you know, manual
messages
at the same time, twice every
single week.
So that happens through Zapier.
So Zapier works really
nicely with Slack to set up
different automations.
But really, just to keep it simple
is, as soon as you
sign on a client, the standard
workflow should be that you
already have a client workspace
set up for
your agency.
So that once you have signed a
client, you invite them to Slack.
And then in Slack, you have
the private channel set up for
your client.
And then you also have the
announcements channel
that everyone new to the workspace
gets added to.
So if I'm a client, the way I see
it is that I signed
on, and then I got an email that's
inviting me to Slack.
And in Slack, I'm being invited to
this Slack
that gives me two channels, the
announcements channel, where I see
like company wide announcements,
and then my
company's name, as a channel
that's private, where it's just me
and the service provider, or the
agency, and I just
communicate with them that way.
So set the standard and the
precedent with your clients on
where and how to
communicate with you.
And the nice and everything can be
done through Slack, literally
everything.
It's so, it's so
dope.
And like, for example, right, like
you could send files in Slack, you
could attach literal files, like
PDFs,
pictures, screenshots, right?
Like you're seeing in here,
there's nothing like you can't do
in Slack
that you can do an email, from
what I found, at least.
And the other nice thing that you
can do in
Slack is you could record audio
notes, right?
You can literally record audio
clips, which is a nice feature,
because sometimes it's a lot
easier to communicate through
audio, whether that be for you or
for your
client.
You could also record video clips.
So you could send video clips
right through Slack.
And then another nice thing is if
you're on like the premium trial
or the premium plan or whatever,
which is like $8 a month per user,
which is nothing, just add that to
your, you know, monthly cost per
clients, like eight bucks a
person, which I highly, I
recommend.
You could do this thing in the
bottom left,
which is a huddle.
So when you're in, like, say, I
want to huddle with Abdi or say,
this is like my
client A, I'll navigate to their
private channel and I'll just
flick this on.
And I could actually
do calls right through Slack,
instead of having to set up a zoom
and having to be on camera on my
client,
when, you know, 90% of the time
when we have client calls,
they're, they're really just
quick catch up calls that don't
require us to have our cameras on.
Right.
And you even on the huddles,
you can share your screen and you
could record them.
So it's like, you're getting the
same thing
as you are through zoom.
You're just not getting the video
right now, which is, is ideal
because when
we're meeting with clients, like
why put on video, if you don't
need it, like just hop on an
audio,
it's like a conference call, talk
about stuff and then hop off once
you're done.
And if you need to
share your screen, you can do that
right through Slack.
So why use multiple tools like
zoom
and Slack, when you could use
everything all within Slack, it's,
it's just a no brainer.
So I'm not a salesman or anything
for Slack.
Um, but I know that if you're an
agency owner,
you're going to need to be using
Slack and you're going to need to
get really good at using Slack
because most of your clients are
probably not going to have
experience using Slack.
So you have to guide them through
it and be able to answer their
questions and, and, you know,
build their comfort level with,
with Slack, but it's, it's
required communication with
clients is key.
It's probably the number one
thing, uh, that, that retention
relies on is, is communication.
You have to properly communicate
with your clients.
Um, and just using a tool like
Slack
will, will put you already at an
advantage, um, as opposed to using
email and just not having
any organization on, uh, how
things are communicated between
you and your clients.
So, uh, look into Slack, get
comfortable, uh, and really your
action item after this video
is to set up a client workspace
within Slack.
If you don't already have one set
up an announcements
channel, delete all the other
channels, uh, you know, write
descriptions for, for the
announcements
channel.
If you want to write a mock
description for what a client
channel will look like, uh, if you
want, and then if you have clients
already start setting up channels
for them within Slack so you
can invite them to it, uh, and,
and just basically migrate all of
your communications over to Slack.
Uh, and this is going to be like
key for making an impression early
on, uh, creating an enjoyable
experience early on and just
retaining clients long term.