All right, so the onboarding call.
This is like the last piece of
onboarding a new client and this
might not apply to everyone, but
if it makes sense to offer an
onboarding call, I highly
recommend that you do this and you
implement it.
So basically, when you first sign
a client, you get to sign service
agreement, you collect payment,
you get them into all the
different professional workspaces
that you have set up.
And then once they're onboarded
into the different workspaces and
they have all the materials filled
out, like the onboarding form,
right?
We want them to submit the
onboarding form.
We want them to do those tasks
first.
We just want to make sure that you
as the agency has everything they
need to begin work.
And then the last step is getting
on the onboarding call.
The onboarding call is key for so
many different reasons.
The first reason the onboarding
key is so important to conduct is
because it allows you to build
credibility with your client and
to start the relationship off on
the right track.
Like, think about if you're a
client, you want to be able to
meet the people and interact in
like a live way with the people
who are working on this project
for you.
So by getting on the onboarding
call and doing it through Zoom
with your camera on, you get to
spend some quality time with your
new client and they get to see
your face and they get to interact
with you, which really helps build
credibility and also give the
client, you know, reassurance that
they are in good hands working
with you.
So the onboarding call is like
really important to establish
yourself, uh, or to, sorry,
establish the relationship and to
build that level of trust right
away.
So that's the first thing.
The other thing the onboarding
call is super useful for is, uh,
to clear any confusion or
questions, right?
So I'm sure like when you're
overloading your clients with an
onboarding form and an onboarding
payment in a Slack workspace and a
Trello board, there's going to be
some questions.
There always is.
Um, and rather than going through
Slack and doing back and forth
that way, uh, the onboarding call
is a great opportunity for your
clients to ask those important
questions that are on their mind.
And the less questions your client
has, or, uh, as long as all the,
the questions your client has are
answered, you're, you're in a good
spot, uh, with that client
relationship.
So you, it's, it's a platform for
your client to ask questions and
get answers in real time.
And then the other thing, the
benefit for you, uh, you know,
these are all benefits obviously,
because it's working in your favor
longterm for building trust, uh,
which, you know, will have a
direct effect on retaining these
clients.
Longer than if you did not do an
onboarding call and, and, and if
you did not establish that level
of trust in the very beginning.
Um, but some of the other things
that.
The onboarding call is useful for
us collecting information or
getting more clarity.
So the reason why it's so
important for clients to fill out
the onboarding form and to go
through all of those tasks, uh,
that we talked about, like
onboarding onto your professional
workspaces, like with Trello and
Slack.
Um, and filling out the onboarding
form is because it gives you the
opportunity to review all of that
information and see what other
information might I need?
Or what questions do I have?
Right?
So like, for example, they fill
out the onboarding form and
they're telling you about their
target market and you're not
really, you know, clear on it.
You get on the onboarding call and
you could talk through that and
you could record the onboarding
call.
So it's all documented and then
you could just take notes and add
that to the onboarding form as
like an attachment rather than
trying to explain yourself, uh,
back and forth through Slack.
Same thing with their offer.
If you don't fully understand
their offer or maybe they filled
out the onboarding form the wrong
way or misinterpreted one of your
questions, right?
The onboarding call is like a
workshop call in that sense, uh,
where you could collect more
information or get clarity on the
information that they provided.
And even, uh, and, and other use
cases, like a lot of the times,
uh, for our service, we require,
uh, LinkedIn logins from our
client.
And a lot of the times they either
don't provide a login or the login
credentials are not correct.
Or I go to log in and I'm hit with
one of those like two factor
authentications, right?
And it's a pain in the ass to sync
up with the client, uh, at the
same time they're available to,
uh, to get into their accounts.
So what we do is like right on the
onboarding calls say, Hey, by the
way, you know, you gave us your
LinkedIn login, but I got hit with
this two factor authentication.
You know, while we have you on the
call, do you mind if I log in
right now and you just check your
phone real quick for the code?
And then we, you know, get that
taken care of and put away.
And we'll do that a lot of the
times.
Um, so the onboarding call is
super useful, uh, for all these
different reasons, but just to
take a step back, I want to break
down the way we conduct our
onboarding calls.
So that you can, uh, create a
structure for yourself as well,
because having a structure on
these calls is, is so important.
Uh, again, you want to lead your
clients.
You want to direct them on
everything.
Like they hired you as the expert.
So you want to use opportunities
like the onboarding call to
present yourself as the expert in
the room.
So the way we like to do
onboarding calls is really in, uh,
like three or four different
phases.
So the part one, and, and they're
not long calls too.
Like it's not a huge time
investment.
Some, some of them will go longer,
but we really like pencil in 30
minutes, uh, for the call and we
do it through zoom.
Um, so, you know, it is face to
face at least most of the time.
Um, but it's like a 30 to 45
minute thing.
Usually sometimes it's a little
bit shorter.
Sometimes it's a little bit
longer.
It just depends on the flow and
how many people are on the call
from the client side and how many
questions they have and, you know,
how detailed they want to get.
But you really only need to do a
lot, 30 minutes most of the time.
So back to the agenda.
So the agenda of, uh, the
onboarding calls is the first part
introductions.
So for the most, most of the time,
it's going to be the first time
you're meeting your client.
But I guess for some of you,
you're running solo agencies and
you're also taking your own sales
calls.
So you might've already met your
client face to face, like on the
sales calls.
But for our agency, uh, since Dan
is doing all the sales calls and
Christian and myself, Andre are on
the backend doing fulfillment.
It's the first time that Christian
and I are meeting the clients and
the same for the clients.
The first time they're seeing
Christian and I, and they they've
seen Dan and they've talked to him
on the sales call, but it's a
completely different, uh, role
he's playing now, Dan, Dan, like
what's your role in the client
fulfillment process?
Like what does the client go to
Dan for at this point in the
relationship?
So basically, regardless of, of
how you got to that point, you
want to introduce them or
introduce yourselves in your job
roles for this person.
Now that they are officially a
client, right?
So you're out of the sales, uh,
you're out of like the sales
portion of, uh, the work and
you're into the fulfillment
portion.
So you do introductions in the
beginning.
So like the way we'll do it is,
Hey, you know, client, the way
this works is we'll just, you
know, in the beginning, we'll do
introductions.
So you get to know like who's on
our team and what we're
responsible for.
So, you know, who to reach out to
specifically, uh, when you, when
you have questions.
And then once we go through
introductions, we're going to, uh,
do a screen share of our Trello
board, uh, and basically show you
where everything is and what we've
been working on so far and, and
ask if you have any questions.
And then at the end of the call,
we'll open it up for questions and
we'll also let you know, you know,
what needs to be done, uh, next to
launch campaigns and what happens
when campaigns are launched.
Right.
So this is a little bit specific
for our lead gen agency.
It'll be different for really
every agency, but the framework's
really the same.
So it's introductions in the
beginning.
You want to introduce yourself,
who you are.
And when I say introduce yourself,
like tell the client what your
role is going forward.
Like, what are you going to be
doing in relation to what they
signed on for?
So when they do, they sign our
clients sign on for lead gen.
So when I introduce myself on the
calls, uh, I'm telling the client,
Hey, like I, uh, am the one that's
kind of crafting the overall lead
gen strategy for our clients.
And I also, uh, am the one that's
working on the targeting in the
leads list for our campaign.
So if you have any questions or
additional information when it
comes to, uh, strategy and target
market or just targeting in
general, that's what I'm
responsible for.
Then Christian will go and
Christian will be like, Hey, I'm
the creative director at the
agency.
So what that means, uh, for you is
that I'm writing all of your
scripts.
So all the messages we're sending
out are, uh, being written by me.
So if you have any
recommendations, feedback, or
suggestions when it comes to
scripting and messaging, you could
come to me for that.
And then Dan will go on and he'll
say, Hey, you know, I'm really
just a sales guy.
So, you know, once you get on
sales calls or once you get leads
in your pipeline, if you need any
help or have any questions on how
to make the most of the leads
we're generating for you, you
know, just give me a, give me a
shout.
And I'd be happy to consult you
and just give you some overall
direction on, on how to handle the
sales process at your business.
Uh, so then they have a very clear
understanding of who to go to for
what, uh, which, which is great
because there's full clarity on,
on who our team is.
And they see that we have our shit
together and that we have all the
bases covered.
And then of course, like if you
have a project manager or a client
success manager or an inbox
manager, you could explain that
person in their role.
They don't necessarily have to be
on the onboarding call.
I think the onboarding call is
just important for the founders
and the partners and the C-level
guys to be on the call.
But if you want to have other
members from your team that are
pitching into this project on the
call, you know, you could do that
too.
Something to consider.
And then after you introduce
yourself and your team, you'll
want to turn it over to your
client and you, because the
onboarding call is not going to be
scheduled immediately after they
sign on.
Usually, right.
It's not going to be like the next
day because they have in it, in
it.
Sometimes it can be.
Um, but a lot of times what you'll
find is you'll sign.
They take a little bit to like
review the contract.
They take a little bit to pay the
onboarding fee.
They take a little bit to get
onboarded to all your different
professional workspaces.
They take a little bit to go
through the onboarding form and
then they schedule an onboarding
call.
So the onboarding call is like a
little bit after that initial
sales call.
Uh, so what we like to do is like,
Hey, you know, if you could real
quick, I know you filled out a ton
of information.
In the onboarding form.
And we learned all about your
business on the sales call.
But if you could just give us a
quick intro to who you are, what
your role is, the company, who
else might be involved in this
project specifically, uh, and
where you're at as a company.
And then more importantly, what
you're looking to get out of this
question or this portion is what
are your goals and working with
us?
What are you hoping to accomplish?
Right?
So we talked about this a little
bit in the onboarding form about
how we should be asking, uh, at
the end of our onboarding forms,
like what are their goals and what
do they hope to accomplish by
working with our agency?
So if you want to reiterate that
on the onboarding call, um, so you
want, this is going to allow you
to align yourself with their goals
and to also set expectations,
right?
So if their goals are way out
there, you could set expectations
properly on the onboarding call.
Because the only way clients leave
you or, uh, or churn for that
matter is when expectations do not
meet reality.
That's the only time you'll ever
run into stress or negative
feedback from your clients.
And it's the only time you'll ever
potentially lose a client is when
reality does not, or when, when
expectations do not meet reality.
And obviously that happens a lot
because not all of this is fully
predictable, um, and not always
expectations can be met, but if
expectations are not set or fully
understood from day one, you never
give yourself a chance.
So make sure to be on the same
page in the beginning of this
onboarding call when it comes to
your client's expectations.
So you give yourself the best
chance to make them a reality and
in turn, uh, you know, satisfy
your clients so that they stay on
with you, uh, and keep coming back
to, to give you guys business.
So that's, that's, that's, that's
super important when it comes to
introductions, ask your clients
straight up, you know, what are
your goals and what are your
expectations, uh, you know, with
working with us.
And that'll help you to make sure
they're in line with, with what
they can expect and, and what you
believe, uh, realistically you
could provide for them.
And, and, and, and that's that.
So once you do introductions, once
you get on the same page about
what's to be expected, uh, and,
and, and really, uh, align with
goals for the relationship.
The next thing is to go through
like the roadmap.
So for us, we do lead gen and we
do, uh, we, there's a lot of
information when it comes to lead
gen.
So really what we do is a screen
share and we'll, we'll share them.
Uh, we'll see, we'll share the
Trello board that we already
invited them to.
Um, and we'll show them where they
could find everything.
So like login credentials for the
cold email account and the
LinkedIn account and the Calendly
account.
We show them where all that
information is.
And then really most, more
importantly, what we do, uh, on
the screen share is all go through
the leads list and I'll show them
where they could look at the leads
list and let them know that an
action item for them is to review
the leads list and to approve it.
And then another action item or
another thing we do is I'll pass
it over to Christian at this point
and say, Hey, you know, here's the
scripts that we've written for
your campaigns.
Christian is going to read through
them and then you guys can kind of
brainstorm and collaborate on any
potential changes and feedback.
So then we'll screen share the
scripts that we wrote for this
specific client that are going to
be sent out through our Legion
campaigns.
Christian will read through them
and then the client will provide
us feedback.
And most of the times they're
like, oh, these are good.
Like we trust you.
That's why we hired you.
So, you know, you know, if these
work, you know best, you're the
expert, you know, run with them.
But some of the times like our
client will be like, oh, these are
great.
But but we don't want to say that
that's that's inaccurate or be
careful there.
So it's good to lean on the client
for feedback and approval on
certain areas or certain things
throughout the process.
So we'll run them through the
scripts.
We'll run them through the list,
make sure they approve both of
those.
And all of this is for
transparency.
That's another thing that's
working here in the background is
we're showing our clients that we
can be transparent.
And when we be transparent with
our clients, we build more trust,
which is, again, like so
important.
You have to have trust with your
client.
Your clients must trust you and
have confidence in your abilities
to get results for them.
And this is all everything we've
talked about up to this point is
working towards that.
That's what we're working towards.
So after we do a screen share, we
show them some of the work we've
done and basically get their
feedback on it.
We ask if they have any questions.
Right.
So we like to stop in and see what
questions they might have about
the process or what questions they
might have had coming into the
onboarding call that we can
answer.
If we need to do logins, we'll do
those on the screen.
A lot of times like we'll need to
get them.
We will need their help getting
into their LinkedIn account in
their Calendly account.
So we'll do that on the screen
share.
And then after that, also on our
Trello board, we set up like a to
do list in a completed task list.
So we'll end on that and we'll
say, OK, here's all the tasks
we've completed for you so far.
And really, all that's left for us
to do is X, Y, Z.
And that's just letting them know
like what else we'll be working on
and what else we need to get done.
And then also what we need from
them.
Right.
So like we need them to review the
leads list and we need them to
review the scripts and we need
them to provide the credentials
and make whatever else we need
from them.
We have to outline and make clear
the action items for them and for
us.
And then after we do that, we'll
talk about what happens when
campaigns launch.
So we have like an ongoing
service.
Right.
So like for Legion, we talk about
what we need to do to launch and
get them fully on board and set
up.
And then what happens when
campaigns launch?
That's like another question.
So once campaigns launch, we talk
them and walk them through that
entire process on what they can
expect,
how long it's going to take to get
results, where they're going to be
able to find the results,
what to do when they get results,
how to provide feedback on the
results.
And then we're detailing literally
everything.
So we're not leaving any room for
doubt or for questions.
And that's on purpose.
So you want to you want to
rehearse this.
We've done so many onboarding
calls and have gotten really good
at it to the point where it's a
science.
Right.
We get on.
We introduce ourselves.
We ask them about their goals.
We make sure their goals are in
line with what we think we can
provide.
We do the screen share.
We walk them through where they
can find everything.
We ask for their feedback on the
list and the scripts.
We get into all the accounts we
need access to if we haven't
already.
And then we tell them what's left
to do to onboard them and to get
campaigns set up.
Once we have clarity on all that,
we let them know what to expect.
Once campaigns launched, make sure
they don't have any questions on
any of that.
So there's full clarity on the A
to Z process.
And then literally from there, all
we're doing is saying, OK, great.
If you have any other questions,
you know, that's what Slack is
for.
We have Slack set up to handle
communications.
But other outside of Slack, the
other way we'll communicate is
through, you know, monthly
checking calls or whatever it
might be for you.
For us, we just do a 60 day review
call.
And then from there, after the 60
day review call, we could continue
to schedule, like, calls every 60
days or every 30 days.
We even say on the onboarding
call, like, hey, if you ever, you
know, need to reach us or if we
ever need to connect for a call.
A lot of times things of this
nature can be resolved through
Slack.
So we don't like to set up monthly
checking calls.
But if, you know, something comes
up where a call is necessary and
you guys feel more comfortable
getting on a call with our team,
then we could do that.
And we'll set up a call and we'll
send you our Calendly link for
that because we have a Calendly
link for client checking calls.
So we go through that and then
we'll just schedule that 60 day
review call and then we'll wrap it
up.
So I know that's a lot, a lot of
information.
And that's just one way to do it.
That's how we like to do it.
And the in the middle stuff there
is going to be different for
everyone, depending on the service
you set up and what visuals you
have.
But really to break it down and to
keep and to recap and keep it
simple.
The beginning of the call is you
and your team introducing your
roles and responsibilities in the
project.
Once the client is clear on that,
you turn it over to them to hear
about where they're at in their
business and what their goals are
and expectations are and what they
think success looks like with
working with you.
And as long as everything is
aligned there and you guys
understand their goals and you
think their goals are accurate for
what they might be able to expect,
you can move on and you move on
into basically introducing them
into your workspace.
So for us, we share our Trello
board and we go through where they
can find everything and we go
through a few materials that we
need their feedback on.
So we like to do the script review
and the leads list review right on
the call because we have them
there and we can get live feedback
and we could workshop it a little
bit.
So the middle part is like a
workshop session on some things
that we need from the client.
So we'll do that we'll fill in the
gaps that that we think are there
again like in regards to the
onboarding form like we might need
to collect a little bit more
information.
So we'll do that and that's this
part of the call might be really
short for you, which is fine.
It just depends on what
information you need and what you
need approval on.
And then, like I said, we also get
access to their accounts if we
weren't able to get access before
the call for whatever reason, like
two-factor authentication or
whatever.
And then once we wrap up that
part, we'll let them know what
else we need to do, like what the
action items are, just like we do
on our check-in calls and client
ascension every week.
Like I always say this, like I'm
doing my job if you are clear on
your action items at the end of
that call.
So just like you're my clients,
you guys in this coaching program
are my clients and so you want to
treat your clients the same way.
You want to make sure that they
are clear on what's needing to be
done to accomplish whatever it
might be, like launching the
campaigns or finishing the project
or starting the services or
getting results for that matter.
So be clear on the action items
for you and for the client.
It's important to always talk
about what you're working on
because that builds trust and
transparency with the client.
They know exactly what it is
you're working on.
That's why I love Trello and I
love like the to-do list and the
completed task setup in Trello
because you could literally show
them everything you've worked on
and everything you still have left
to work on.
And you could tag cards with
labels.
So like one's labeled, you know,
for your agency and the other
labels for the client so they know
exactly who's assigned to what.
So once you lay out the action
items and they're clear on what's
about to happen next or what needs
to happen next, you just let them
know what happens after all those
things are done.
So like once campaigns are
launched or once the website is
completed or once the emails
campaigns are set up, whatever it
is that you're doing for them, let
them know what happens next,
right?
Is there is there going to be some
form of reporting that they can
expect, right?
Are they going to get like weekly
reports?
Are you guys going to get on
monthly check-in calls?
Are they going to get update
messages two or three times a
week?
What can they expect as like the
ongoing services, right?
So what is the ongoing management
or the ongoing services look like
for something like this?
And then once that's clear, you
basically just wrap it up by
saying, all right, let's get to
work.
Do you have any questions?
And then if they don't have any
questions, you say, no worries.
If you have, if you think of
anything after the call, you know,
just let us know in Slack.
Like basically we'll say, hey,
let's continue the conversation in
Slack after this call.
If you think of anything else and
then if you need to get on a call,
we'll do it.
But for the most part, we'll get
to work.
We'll get these campaigns launched
and we'll keep you updated through
Slack with anything important or
relevant if anything comes up and
we just ask you to do the same.
So that's the homeboarding call.
So I talk really fast.
So if you need to watch this back,
please do it.
But it's really simple.
The onboarding call is so
important, though, because it
accomplishes so many things.
It just makes sure it's like
confirmation that you and your
client are on the same page.
And that simple accomplishment of
being on the same page with your
client, especially early on, is
key to long term success in
retention in the client services
space.
Because this thing as soon as
things get unorganized and lost
and there's doubt, right?
There's doubt clouding your
client's judgment about your
capabilities and the actual work
that you're doing.
They're going to start to devalue
your services and just, you know,
not have an interest to continue.
So what you're doing is you're
you're literally just making your
case on why they're paying you a
certain amount of money and
showing them that real work is
going into it.
That's why I love the to do list
and the completed task list,
because a lot of the times, like
when we're doing lead gen, they're
not there's it's a lot of
automation and things are
happening behind the scenes.
But the more we could show them
visually that real work is going
into it, the more they are they're
going to put about like the higher
value they're going to put, the
higher the value that they're
going to put on on the work that
we're doing.
And they're going to be, you know,
happier to pay us the amount that
we're charging.
So, yeah, onboarding call is super
important.
It's going to take practice.
So I kind of draft up, you know,
an order or like an outline of how
you want to go about doing the
onboarding calls just so you're
prepared, like an agenda.
I meant like what is the agenda of
the onboarding call and just come
and just start practicing those
like you have accountability
partners as a part of being in
this program.
So maybe that's something you
could do with them is like just do
a mock onboarding call with them
and walk them through your process
or even just record yourself
through loom doing an onboarding
call, whether it be by yourself or
even with a partner at your agency
and just do it like a sales role
play.
But it's an onboarding call role
play, because these are, again,
super important.
And really, the only way to get
good at them is just through reps.
Like like really, it's it's just
like sales.
And yeah, don't put too much
pressure on yourself in the
beginning.
Just just get comfortable with it.
You'll figure it out as time goes
on.
And let me know, you know, how
these onboarding calls go, what
the feedback is from your clients
after hopping on these calls.
And if you have any questions or
different ideas to share in
regards to onboarding calls, you
know, let's let's take let's let's
continue the conversation in
Slack, right?
Let's let's bring this video to a
to a wrap now and continue the
conversation in Slack as you guys
make your way through this
content.