And we got nick max matthew what's
going on michael good to see as
well on the call
wait cool all right guys so uh i
was telling people who were on a
little bit earlier
that for this call i'm just gonna
do uh a quick like mini master
class on how to effectively
communicate with clients because
this is something that i get asked
uh about a lot um and this is also
something that i feel we do a
really good job with uh our agency
uh so for some background i run a
lead gen agency called knowledge x
um and a lot of my responsibility
along with christian who you guys
know is like the scripts guy is to
communicate with clients uh and
put systems and processes around
that
but really more so learning the
foundations so even if it were for
you to do it or someone that you
wanted to go out and hire you
actually know the strategies and
the foundations to teach them so
let me open up the screen share
and we'll dive in and feel free to
use like the the chat um to post
questions and stuff like that
because i'm happy to open up the
conversation rather than just
ripping
right through this like uh like
yeah like a keynote but anyways uh
so yeah effectively communicate
with
the clients i think this is a huge
topic of discussion because a lot
of us put a lot of focus
and emphasis on the actual service
we deliver and making that really
really fucking good uh with
like roi and and actual results
which is great um but sometimes
that takes away from the
communication
aspect which is sometimes even
more important uh and valued by
our clients than the results
uh and you can leverage this is a
really powerful thing to
understand because you can
buy yourself a lot of time with
clients um to get the results that
you originally promised so
we'll dive right in the first
thing to understand is the golden
rule of retention at least the way
i
understand it is it's not so much
about what you do it's more so
about how you make them feel
uh and when i heard this for the
first time it really clicked for
me again it takes the focus away
from it's not just about getting
results but it's more so how you
about how you make them feel
as a service provider because
you're providing a service it's
not a specific deliverable that
they're there for necessarily it's
the service and the experience
that you deliver through that
service which we'll talk a little
bit about the different ways to
cultivate that experience
so that's the golden rule if you
remember anything from this call
remember that
and just you know write it down
and think on it for a little bit
just to fully understand what we
mean
there um just the basics preferred
tools for us at least at our
agency for communication with
clients
is slack uh for written
communication just like what you
do through email or text message
and then zoom
for video conferencing you can use
whatever you like here um but i do
think it is important to
understand the difference between
written communication and video or
live communication similar to like
we're on a call
now and having systems to
implement both and understanding
the ups and downs of implementing
both right so that's pretty clear
on the preferred tools so we'll
start with written communication
uh and
when and where to use it and just
different ideas and examples um so
the the number one thing with
written communication uh is to
keep it short and sweet i see a
lot of agency owners trying to be
like very very professional with
their punctuation and the capital
letters and writing it as if it's
like a college essay um but what
clients really appreciate is quick
consumption of the point you're
trying to get across um and the
other thing to understand is not
to be afraid to repeat yourself so
uh at knowledge yet you're sorry
at client ascension specifically
we recently hired uh closers.io
which a lot of you guys know is
like cole gordon's company is like
a fifteen thousand dollar
investment
to work with these guys and so
they're a really good example to
learn like how do they manage a
client that pays them fifteen
thousand dollars and so i brought
you guys three examples of
check-in
messages that we received from
their team and this is a perfect
example of effective written
communication keeping it short and
sweet so literally you see three
instances of check-in messages
from steve who's on their team
saying yo guys how is it over here
yo dude happy labor day anything
i can help with yo guys how's biz
like that's it and this is super
effective because they're
questions that elicit a response
from the client uh and so me as
the client will naturally go in
and
fill them in on everything that's
going on with the business and if
you're a business owner
your business is super important
to you so you you're naturally
inclined to share the positives
and the wins so really the the
layer underneath here to
understand is like just asking
general
questions about how the business
is is almost always going to get
you uh an idea or some insights
into
the wins that they're experiencing
right or at least where they're at
with the business so you can get
them closer to experiencing those
wins or those results that you
originally promised uh so don't be
afraid to
repeat yourself if you look at
these messages they're actually
kind of out of order um but
basically it's it was monday on
september 5th tuesday on september
13th so like eight days later and
then tuesday again on september
20th
so every single week i'm getting a
really simple dumbed down check-in
message from the guy in this team
consistently i know it's coming
every single week and throughout
the week i'm thinking of things
now
because i know steve is going to
check in with me at the beginning
of the week what can i share with
him when he asks how the business
is going so i'm subconsciously
building a list of things to
update him on
and questions to ask him uh for
help with right so brain
communication keeping it short and
sweet
these are really general
open-ended easy questions to ask
your clients right how's it over
there
anything i can help with this week
how's business simple right any
questions so far uh before i go
into
some more examples feel free to
throw them in the chat if it's
easier that way
okay cool all right so a few other
examples of written communication
is uh holding them accountable
um so a lot of service providers
have you know obviously a scope of
work or a division of work
between what the service provider
is responsible for doing and then
what the the client is responsible
for doing and an easy way uh or an
effective way to use written
communication is to hold your
clients
accountable another example from
our work with the team at
closers.io they have our training
program
very similar to how client
ascension has a training program
and so they'll constantly remind
us about
specific lessons based on the
information and the insights we
share about how our business is
doing
at that point um and they'll share
specific and relevant trainings
with us to go through because they
know that if we were to watch the
trainings we'll probably be closer
to the results that they initially
promised so holding clients
accountable to go through the
action items or at least their
side of the
board when it comes to scope of
work and responsibilities is is
really key so again a
really simple message like have
you guys gone through this and
then he links the kajabi link
and then ends it with it'll change
your life to be honest like that
keeps you like interested oh let
me let
me check this out what does he
mean by that um and so hyping it
up as well it's super important so
if
you have clients that need to do
specific things like filling out
an onboarding form um or going
through
training like we have in client
ascension right that's that's
obviously a big part of your guys
responsibilities is to go through
the training um a message is like
this work really effective
the next one to cover is
celebration of wins um and this is
one of the the key takeaways that
i'll recap
at the end but celebrating wins is
so freaking important um because a
lot of times what happens is
clients
are winning um but you just don't
know about it because you're not
asking the question and because
because the communication is not
there so what we like to do at our
agency is to straight up ask our
clients on a regular basis if
there are any wins to celebrate
and we do this not only through
slack but
also like when we hop on a call
with a client uh every every so
often we'll start to call like hey
yeah like how's everything been
going with the business any wins
to share and so always be asking
clients if they have any wins to
share and we do this also with
client ascension right in the wins
channel if we didn't have a wins
channel in client ascension we
wouldn't be seeing all the success
that
our students are having or not as
much as we would because of the
fact we have a wins channel
right we're always always
eliciting students and clients to
share their wins because it makes
them feel
better and it actually allows them
to see the progress that they're
making because a lot of
us just get caught up with the
day-to-day and we don't really
take a step back to zoom out and
see
how far we've gone right with the
business and everything else so
here's a great example actually
of that hey any wins and he like
basically was typing again as he
was thinking nah i haven't signed
up a
client in a few weeks been able to
build out a team now i can focus
more actually i wasn't counting
this but it's definitely a win one
company went from four links a
month to 14 links so he basically
upsold the client and he wasn't
thinking about it until we
actually straight up asked him any
wins
to celebrate which is so important
because we wouldn't have heard
about this and we wouldn't
have been able to celebrate these
things with the client if we
didn't simply ask another one
right
here this is a great example this
is like a pretty more complex
detailed example but i'll just
talk you
guys through it real quick so
basically what happened here is
someone from my team sent a kpi
update at the
end of the week reporting specific
stats um congratulating them on on
hitting a specific
kpi all that great stuff um the
client then said they're happy
with the rate we're seeing
meetings
getting booked obviously not
netting is a hit not everything
netting is a hit but the
conversion rate
isn't bad so in this scenario
we're basically pointing out a win
for the client because we we see
it
ourselves um and the the client is
saying they're happy but they're
also kind of downplaying it a
little bit by
saying the conversion rate isn't
bad and so i come back in here and
say wow huge improvements being
made here five out of seven calls
booked is way ahead of our kpi of
50 percent lots to celebrate
here as a team especially
considering where we were a few
weeks ago right and then i kind of
highlight
how we had weeks with one out of
six conversion and two out of
eight conversions um and then just
basically setting them up for uh
to look forward to next week i
hope everyone has a great weekend
let's continue the success next
week um so there's a lot of
different elements that go into
this specific
example um but the biggest piece
of it is is uh celebrating the
wins and also showing them where
they're at compared to where they
were when they started uh which
we'll go into a little bit more
that's a lot easier to do through
uh live communication on like a
zoom call which we'll talk
about in a second here one last
example uh is this one here simple
check-in message from daniel on
our
team saying how's your week been
uh just giving them a little bit
of an update on where we're at
with
everything um and again the client
saying hey there's been a few more
positive responses and i was
able to book a call so there has
been improvement thanks for your
help right so again celebrating
these
wins eliciting them uh our clients
to report these wins to us is so
so important and it's really
simple
you just ask how's your week been
any wins to share any positives to
know however you want to frame it
right any questions this is all
pretty simple to be honest but
it's really important so any
questions
uh on how this might apply to what
you're working on
nothing yet okay dope
doing this at scale simple answer
is the higher team um client
success managers a lot of it as
well uh
is uh it can be automated that's
why i really like slack uh because
i could go through every
single client channel and schedule
a message like these ones like i
can almost guarantee these are
scheduled send like yo guys how's
it over here copy and paste that
in every single client channel and
schedule to send on monday at 8 30
a.m if that's when you want to
send it all right so slack has a
lot
of great features to do things
like this at scale um and i also
think it's important to uh
automate a lot
of the written communication as
much as possible so that you can
make more time to do the verbal
live zoom communication which
we'll get into in a little bit
here um but a lot of it is not
really
um scalable in a sense the way you
scale is through people which is
why we have trina now in our
community and it's why we have uh
at our agency we have daniel uh
and another client success manager
stephanie uh that are like
full-time hires at our agency to
manage a select group of clients
to do
these specific things for does
that help or cool and and brooke
asked if we use zaps i for the
things
you're seeing here so far we don't
in slack it's really easy you
could just type a message and then
schedule it to send at a specific
day and time so it's it's all
right within slack at least for
like
the schedule send messages can you
do recurring ones as well um i'm
not 100 sure but i honestly
wouldn't
recommend it um because if you
continue to frame the same exact
message it could what happens is
the
client gets accustomed to it and
they start to ignore it because
they know it's automated and
there's not much
effort so like the the slightest
difference is like happy labor day
like obviously you don't want to
send that every single week
because it's not labor day every
week so the smallest things like
that go
a long way they really do um and
obviously like these are all
asking the same thing but in
slightly
different phrases something to
think about um and and or you ask
like if we check in every
wednesday
and do a report every friday so
the framework we use at our agency
is every single friday we'll do
a kpi report uh which i'll walk
you through that'll be the last
piece here in the ring
communication so
every single friday we report kpis
and then we like to check in uh
usually anytime between monday uh
and
wednesday ideally monday tuesday
earliest in the week to do a
check-in like the one you're
seeing here
how's it over there how's business
anything i can help with that's
usually a good way to start
the week you can drop nuggets like
this throughout the week like this
was just kind of randomly on a
friday um but the actual kpi
messages we like to do on fridays
uh so that leads me to my next
point uh
which is reporting kpis so again
it's more so about how you make
them feel not all about the
results you
get in in what you actually do but
it's still important to get
results right because at the
end of the day we're all business
owners and we want to make smart
investments in our business that
give us potentially generate an
roi so just because someone's
delivering a really nice service
and there
is a cool experience and there's
they're really nice to us if
they're not actually reporting
kpis and
getting results and doing the work
we're gonna fire them right so you
still need to report kpis or you
should be reporting kpis um and i
think the most important thing
that gets missed here is
collecting
relevant metrics in the onboarding
form and all this is saying is if
you can get a really good
understanding for where they're at
currently before they start
working with you that gives you
all the
leverage to report kpis because
even if you have the slightest
improvements you just compare them
to
where they're at now compared to
where they started with you right
so like this message here uh was
actually that kpi message you saw
on the other example uh where
we're just checking in with the
client hey reporting to you with
campaign stats from this week the
way we do it at our agency again
for
some background we run an email
lead generation agency so the
things that we specifically want
to
point out are how many positive
replies we got out of those
positive replies how many turn
into calls
booked and then we just do a
percentage of how many of the
calls booked or how many of the
positive
replies turn into call booked
which is 71 and then we'll even
put like a kpi right there so they
can see
the difference like oh wow we got
71 when 50 is the goal like we
overachieved this week added value
to the
pipeline we come up with this
number based on the first year
contract value that they provide
to us in
their onboarding form and then
expected revenue and and then we
just set the expectation that
these stats are estimated based on
what we're seeing and please
correct us if there's any
inaccuracies
so a lot of shits happening
throughout the week especially
with a cold email lead generation
agency
and so it's important for you to
list out the highlights that they
might not be seeing or fully
understanding a lot of people in
business are very visual and
numbers oriented so if you can
show them the
numbers or the results of what
you've produced or worked on
throughout the week in a format
similar
to this it goes a long way and so
here's an example of like us doing
really well getting above 50%
conversions and celebrating and
pointing out that to the client
like congratulating them right
love that
we've been seeing this recently
two weeks ago we were at you know
3600 and now we're at 18 000 great
things
being done here so we're over
celebrating we're letting the
client know that this is good
because
a lot of times clients don't
really know is this good could we
be doing better stuff like that
right
here's an example on the flip side
of reporting kpis that are not so
good right so we're reporting
these kpis
three positive replies but zero
calls book so zero percent calls
book conversion rate where the
goal
is 50 percent right and so the
message is a little bit different
here not a lot of activity which
gives
you the opportunity to follow up
on older prospects um also this is
a great time to get on an inbox
management session to see how we
can convert older prospects and
the book calls so we're suggesting
next
steps because there's not a win to
celebrate here we're recommending
or suggesting the best next step
uh which in our agency is to
schedule an inbox management
session so we could go in and help
them convert more of these
positive replies in the calls book
and so that's the way we report
kpis at our
agency you guys can use a similar
framework but the important
takeaways for anyone here is to
understand where
your client is at when they're
first starting to work with you
which is really done simply
through
collecting relevant metrics in the
onboarding form and then using
these kpi updates to show them the
numbers and how they've
transformed or improved since you
started working together and what
the value
of that is to their business with
things like expected revenue or
added value to pipeline
uh connor great question so connor
asks if we tend to avoid the why
to underperforming in these
messages
i do uh with written messages i
don't like to explain too deeply
uh through a written message
because i
think it can confuse process or
confuse clients and the tone often
gets misunderstood which is why
the call
to action anytime we're
underperforming or have to explain
performance to a client is to get
on a call
because it calls the easiest way
or the better way to explain the
why behind what they're seeing
here
otherwise you could send it and
they might perceive it differently
or they might not fully understand
it even if they say they do which
over time is like a ticking time
bomb
and if you over explain it in this
weekly recap message we used to do
weekly recap messages that
were much longer than this and
nobody would ever read them now
it's really easy i look at this
these
messages for you know five seconds
and i know seven positive replies
five calls book this much value
added to my pipeline this much
expected revenue based on those
numbers where we're at or we're
not where
we're at um and a beer great
question so for people that uh
won't use slack we'll we'll
definitely do
check-ins via email we'll do
exactly what you're seeing here in
slack just through email um it is
very very ideal to get them into a
platform like slack but that's not
always the case
and uh okay a lot of questions
this is awesome so or a great
question how do you determine
pipeline
value so the way we do pipeline
value is um shit honestly i forgot
the formula but it's something
along the lines of in the
onboarding form we ask them what
the ltv is of a client so say it's
ten
thousand dollars ltv we'll look at
how many positive replies we've
received and i think we we either
multiply it by we multiply it by
the number of positive replies
yeah i think yeah i'm pretty
sure that the equation is as
simple as each positive reply um
is a potential for them to close
a client so seven replies times
ten thousand ltv would be seventy
thousand dollars added to their
pipeline
right again these numbers like
they're not as relevant as the
idea the foundation behind it
what number can you show them what
unit of measurement makes sense
for the service that you
provide that uh that you can
implement into these types of
messages hopefully that helps and
let
me know if you have follow-ups to
that um yeah nico we we do these
manually um there are different
things you could do in slack like
you could schedule send these
messages if you want to do them
all in
like a one hour time block and
schedule send them for two or
three days later um but the way to
scale
this is truly through hiring uh
client success managers which we
could talk a little bit about
after the call we've talked about
it on previous calls but i'm happy
to go through that again
uh and walk you through some of
the things we have set up there um
or we could even cover that next
week but let me just see there's a
lot here to catch up on so
okay yeah connor yeah teams is
very garbage um i agree
uh in positive plans to get that
goal okay zach said i have one who
i call every week because he never
reads his emails i'm dealing with
three or four different platforms
yeah so zach ideally you'll want
to get
all of your clients onto the same
platform um and just let them know
for you to perform your service
to the highest level this needs to
happen which is either join slack
uh or to get on weekly calls with
you so i think it's a lot about
setting the frame and also the
incentive is important instead of
you
saying hey let's use slack because
i like that better than teams that
doesn't really give me much
of an incentive it's just oh
because you like it we're going to
use it i don't think that's how it
works
but if it's like i have to use
this because i can't get you the
results i promised without it
it's like oh shit okay use it
whatever i'll learn how to use it
and and that's worked really well
for us
um yeah beer make non-slack
qualifying criteria 100 um yeah
with the older clients definitely
um and i
think for those guys it's really
focusing on the the live calls the
zoom calls um which we'll talk
about in a second here okay lots
of great questions um and we'll
i'm just going to continue because
i
want to i honestly did not expect
this presentation to go this long
but it is which is fine because i
i think there's value here but
anyways the just to recap the
written communication uh section
the
most important thing to understand
is the downside which is the tone
often gets misinterpreted the
written communication right and
that can cause lots of problems
with clients it's just like any
relationship this is basically
this is a presentation on how to
effectively communicate
drop the clients part it doesn't
have to be clients it could be
relationships with family it could
be
anything um isn't just
communication one-on-one
specifically for you know our
what's relevant
for us which is right now clients
um so yeah the down the downside
is the tone gets misinterpreted
which is why it's important to
implement live video communication
through zoom or whatever you use
there doesn't really matter or
even a phone call a phone call is
just as good so any form of
live communication is is key um
and the number one thing that i uh
see people make mistakes with
here is they have no structure
like they just get on a call
because andre said it's important
to get
on a call with clients and then
they they hop on the call the
client and they're like how's it
going
and there's no direction there's
no control there's no structure um
and so i think it's important
to always have an intention when
you get on the phone with someone
because if you get on
the phone with a client for the
first time and it's really just
like a big waste of time both
you and the client are going to be
discouraged from getting on future
calls um and again you want
to make this like a weekly or a
bi-weekly or a monthly practice
and you're not going to be able
to do that if you make a bad first
impression um so really simply
like structure is key and a few
different elements that go into it
is before building just like
anytime you get on the phone with
someone maintaining control of the
call just like you do in the sales
process having high energy
right now i honestly feel low
energy but the higher energy will
just evoke more engagement
throughout
the session is really important so
when you go and you're looking for
client success managers and you
get on that initial call with the
client success manager to do like
a screening interview the number
one thing you're looking for is
high energy i knew as soon as the
first time i met trina
she's high energy like it's
infectious right like she brings
the energy no matter what and uh
and
and the positive vibes and that's
communication one-on-one like that
makes people want to hang out
around you and spend time with you
um and so that's super important
right when you do live
communication
uh the simple structure that i
think is applicable to really any
agency owner or business owner
uh that i use on the calls is
first off talking about where they
were right press the pain points
you uncovered during the sales
process just recap hey so when we
first started to work together
um you were letting me know most
of your clients were coming
through referrals you maybe have
one or two
calls uh being booked through your
website inbound um and so let's
see you know where we're at now a
few
weeks in their campaigns this is
where we're at so tell them where
we're at right so i'll just kind
of walk you through a scenario let
me walk through all these first
and then i'll walk you through a
scenario um tell them where
they're at and then let them know
whether this is ahead or behind
the
schedule it's easy to tell them
we're ahead of schedule and we're
doing well it's not so easy to
tell them hey we're behind we're
not doing so well but you need to
um and and that's really the the
the end of that um and so the then
the next thing to cover is where
they're going so this is where
we're at here's where we're going
and how are you going to get them
there what is the action plan what
are the steps look like uh other
important things is to constantly
reconfirm they're engaged right
ask
them simple things like how's this
done how does this feel any
questions right these are all
really
important so an example structure
would be like hey um client you
know when we first started working
together you were getting maybe
one or two calls booked a week uh
either from referrals
uh or inbound your website where
we're at now is we have campaigns
launched uh last week we had seven
positive replies which led to two
calls booked which is great
because we just doubled the amount
of calls
booked uh from when we first
started working together but to be
honest it's still a little behind
schedule uh with seven positive
replies we want to see at least a
50 call book rate which would put
us
right around three or four calls
um so we have a gap that needs to
be filled around one or two calls
so we're going to get on more
frequent calls like this to just
really you know press on uh the
training and what we talked about
on our onboarding call and we're
going to take a better look at
campaigns to see you know why
prospects are not booking calls
right away or whatever just
explaining what
what you're going to do next how
does that sound any questions boom
right really simple format and
obviously like that just happened
in the matter of like minutes but
you're going to go through each
of these steps with more detail
maybe even screen sharing and
walking them through specific
things
if your service is more visual i
know a lot of you guys do klavia
like this would work extremely
well for klavia like hey when we
first started working together you
had 2 000 people on your list
you're sending maybe an email a
month um and i think what was it
four percent of your revenue was
coming from email now uh you still
have you have 2500 people on your
list more people are subscribing
less people are unsubscribing
we're sending an email a week
consistently which is resulting in
uh 20 of your revenue to come from
email and so we're right where we
need to be what we should now
focus on is obviously continuing
the system but also adding more
people to your email list so you
can see
more of these benefits how can we
make that happen boom right go
into it so this is a good format
for
weekly calls again uh simple
things to buffer uh what you're
saying like how does this sound or
any questions
go a long way um okay how how is
that before we recap or wrap up
this last piece because the last
piece
is is just how you like end the
call basically questions in the
chat
all right um cool so hopefully
this makes sense i think the
structure again is really
important
where were they where are they
where are they going super simple
but it's super effective uh
and gives you something to plan
around um anyways at the end of
the call you want to give them
clarity on what needs to happen
next you always want to have
action items or next steps which
is
something that we started to
implement recently on our coaching
calls which is after the call i'm
going
to ask you what was your main main
takeaway and what is an action
item based on what you learned
on this call because you always
want to have implementation if we
just talk about
shit and and you think you're
learning but you're not
implementing none of the stuff
really is going to
matter um so here's a few
different things you could use to
wrap your call right so
this is a super loaded question um
which is actually honestly really
scary to ask uh on a
live call it's easier to ask
there's black but it's important
that you ask this on a live call
so the the question is how is your
perception of our services today
the reason it's scary is because
a lot of times you might not feel
super confident about the what
what the client's going to say
they
might say they're not too happy
with your services and that's not
information that agency owners are
wanting to hear all the time um
what do you consider it successful
what else would you need to see
out
of this partnership to make it
successful so this is a super
important question as well
straight up
asking them based on this
conversation based on where we're
at based on where it looks like
we're
going what do you need to see out
of our work together to make it
successful like in your words
what is success and then based on
what they say if they say oh i'll
be for this to be successful i'll
have to close three clients uh
before the end of month which is
uh tomorrow actually don't just be
like okay we'll do our best we'll
try to make it happen you still
have to set realistic expectations
like to be honest that's not at
all uh reasonable and we discussed
this in our sales process and the
onboarding process what we can
what we can expect is x y and z
how does that sound would that be
successful to you to close one
more client in the next week and
and have that conversation it's
not
an easy conversation to have um
it's just reps the more you can
force yourself into situations
like
these the better you'll get at
them and it's just going to
improve your service uh which is
the most
exciting part out of all of it a
few other things uh at the end of
these calls you can do is schedule
a
follow-up call if it's relevant
just like you do at the end of
your sales calls
if you don't get to close right
away always get time on calendar
again if it makes sense to send a
recap in the slack channel uh
shout out trina she does recaps
for us now in fine ascension and
they're
incredible um don't try to live up
to trina's recaps that'll be
really hard for you to do um but
any recap will do at least the
start and and then you can build
on that um and then maybe trina
will do a master class in here at
some point on on how she does her
uh recaps and everything else
and then the last thing which is
super important is if you feel
that the call went well and the
client's pretty happy overall ask
for referrals people don't do this
agency owners do not do this
uh practically ever and so if you
make it a habit to ask for
referrals and there's really easy
lightweight ways to do this such
as hey uh you know we're looking
to grow our business going into q4
we've done a lot of great work
together do you have any friends
uh or other business owners that
might
get value from from similar
services if you could put us in
touch that'd be great and a lot of
times
you'll get referrals uh that can
lead to new clients which is you
know obviously a good thing so
that is um
live video communication and again
this is important to pair with uh
written communication
because written communication a
lot of times uh the tone gets lost
and so video communication really
makes
up for that it provides more
structure you have higher
engagement um and you can do a lot
more uh
of explaining the why as connor
put it so questions on that let's
let's use that as a stopping point
and then i'll go into a recap and
then we could do full end q a
no questions on the video stuff
okay here we go how often do you
ask for referrals anytime i'm on a
call
with a client i ask for a referral
unless i feel like i don't deserve
to ask that if it's if there's
if you're underperforming and you
get the vibe the client is is
pretty unsatisfied don't ask for
referrals it's more like a vibe
check if you feel the call went
well energy is high positive vibes
ask for
a referral every time um and and
don't and be confident in that ask
uh we also ask for referrals
in our onboarding form which is
which people find crazy but you'd
be surprised at the end of our
onboarding form the last question
and think about this right because
this is the client hasn't seen
any of our work they just signed
on with us so all they've done so
far is they've paid us and filled
out
an onboarding form and the last
question in the onboarding form is
who might also be interested
in our services it's crazy because
i when i first heard of this idea
i was like no way like anyone
would refer us to people before
even working with us right now i'm
pretty sure it's over 50 percent
of people that have filled out our
onboarding form which is close to
100 clients have given
us a referral and it's not going
to lead to a client every time
it's usually just like an email
address or a name or a twitter
handle but we've signed clients
out of that uh i think three or
four
in recent memories so add that i
mean why not right and and yeah
we'll we'll always give them a
referral
kick uh i'll actually show you
guys the wording because i'm
getting questions on this
um so this is an updated
onboarding form uh the old one was
a little bit different but okay
here's
here's the way we word it give the
gift of growth we want to give you
a fat discount in month
two refer us to fellow agency
owner and you'll both get 500
discounted from your second
invoice
so there's obviously some
incentive it's not just like who
else might want our services
um but when we word it this way
again over 50 response rate with
someone's email or their phone
number
whatever else um do you give them
a referral kick isaac asks are you
doing monthly check-in
calls along with weekly check and
update via slack um so these calls
that we talked about here
live communication it really
depends on the service um but like
for our agency if we could get on
a call
a month with a client we're happy
i found it to be really difficult
to get clients to come on the
calls
and to be able to share relevant
updates in these three categories
if if you're doing it weekly
you're
kind of just saying the same shit
and they're going to get bored and
it doesn't buy you enough time to
implement this part where where
are we going right because if
you're on a call and you're like
okay
we're not getting the best results
we need to implement the training
we need to do x y and z
before you know it you're on a
call again with them seven days
later and you're like yeah we
still need
to do these things and to them it
feels like no progress is being
made so i'm more of a fan of
uh you know doing the weekly
check-ins through slack like we
saw here and then supplementing
that with
bi-weekly or monthly live calls
again depending on on your service
what else questions questions
questions
are you setting expectations with
check-ins calls um yeah the
onboarding process uh we set
all the kpis and expectations so
this is really important great
question isaac
so our onboarding process we have
them fill out an onboarding form
and then we have them
schedule an onboarding call and
then after the onboarding call we
schedule them for an alignment
call and on the alignment call we
show them this which is the cold
email sales funnel and we say
here is the sales funnel uh the
typical sales funnel through cold
email you can expect the 50%
open rate 10 reply rate 25
interested reply rate 50 call
booked rate and a 20 close rate
so we're setting these kpis and
this is what we're coming back to
so when we do a call or we do a
kpi or
we do a check and we're like okay
70 open rates check 15 reply rate
check out of those 18 are
interested
so let's see you know what we can
do to the copy to get a more of
those interested but because the
open
open rate and reply rate are so
high we're actually still well
above kpi overall um call book
rate
it's 30 sounds like we need to go
uh through the training a lot more
here to increase that and then
your close rate is too early to
tell and that's how you do the
updates every single time so the
alignment
call is like a 15 minute call
right after the onboarding call
like a few days after the
onboarding call
the reason is i've found uh
onboarding calls are are really
content heavy when you're on an
onboarding
call it's like the first
interaction you're trying to
explain all this different stuff
that goes into
your work and it's very
overwhelming chances are the
client's not going to remember
everything
and if there's one thing you
really need them to remember it's
the kpi as you said so instead of
doing it on the onboarding call
you can do it on an alignment call
and that's how you know they're
going to receive that information
because it's all you talk about on
an alignment call and you could
also do it as nick just mentioned
through uh videos you could record
a video for them and say hey
campaigns are launched here's what
you can expect let me know if you
have any questions
um response times i always tell
clients monday through friday uh
give us at least 24 hours
again this goes into what we'll
talk about in a second here which
is under promise over deliver
most of the time i can get back to
someone within 24 hours i mean i
have two people on my team to do
this but if you set the
expectation i won't get back to
you within 24 hours and you get
back to them
constantly within a few minutes or
a few hours like they're
constantly going to be delighted
because it's it's
about you're over delivering
you're you're exceeding
expectations
love the questions this just makes
the the presentation so much more
valuable and relevant to
your guys's experiences with this
stuff i'm going to quickly recap
uh and then we'll dive into we
have
like 15 minutes left uh for
questions so the recap here number
one always always always always
always be
looking for wins always always
always always be looking for wins
i can't stress how important
that is um again because it's how
you make them feel it's not about
what you do so if you make them
feel like they're constantly
winning and if you get them into
the house it's like a gratitude
journal
right it's like oh why would you
write down what you're grateful
for every morning like what's the
point of that it's because it
forces your subconscious to
constantly look for things to be
grateful for
it reprograms your mind and that's
what you're essentially doing here
with your clients is you're
forcing them to always be looking
for wins and seeing wins in
situations that they might not
have
perceived originally as a win so
it's really cool so that's the
first part the second part is
under
promise so you can over deliver
right you always want to set
yourself up to over deliver and
the
easiest way to do that is to under
promise um and doing that in a way
where you're not compromising
the sale like you're like hey yeah
this service doesn't work at all
but you should pay for it anyways
like don't under promise to that
extent but enough to where um you
are set up to over deliver uh
leverage client success stories to
encourage action um so if you're
managing a large client base
leverage other client success
stories hey this client did x y
and z and got this result would
love to see
the same for you um a lot of times
what happens is you're in this
bubble with just you and the
client
in the private channels and they
don't take you so seriously or
they don't believe that what
you're
asking them to do or what you're
updating them on is actually
getting you anywhere so if you
could pull
in other examples of similar
clients that are getting the
results and this is why again the
wins channel
incline ascension is so great
because everyone is seeing all
these other students winning and
it's
validating the fact that it's
possible and that it's real right
and that encourages action i know
for me
even and i'm like a coach and one
of the co-founders about the
program going through the wins
channel
encourages me to take more action
i'm like well shit like i didn't
have a win like this today let me
go
back on my email and see if i can
make a deal happen or go on
twitter and put out more content
right so leverage client success
stories encourage action
consistently communicate via slack
and zoom
have that dynamic of both written
and live communication depending
on the tools you prefer
and and to read to end it just
over communicate i think that's
the the biggest thing that people
miss uh with client management
ongoing client management is they
just don't communicate nearly
enough so if you could force
yourself to over communicate um
and i think this this presentation
is is helpful to do
that because it gives you real
examples ideas and frameworks to
implement to do exactly that uh i
think
you'll retain clients a lot longer
and therefore you know increase
the value of uh your business
the ltv everything else so uh a
lot of talking from me today um so
i'll open it up to questions i'm
gonna stop the share for now i'll
obviously share this document uh
with everyone and the recording
will be in
in kajabi pretty soon too so yeah
what do you guys think overall
reactions was that valuable
relevant
interesting boring
super helpful
yeah straightforward stuff like
that sounds so simple but it is
helpful because you don't show
up to something like what should i
say what's the best way to say
this like it really is
yeah that's straightforward 100
what does kpi stand for um
key performance indicator key
performance indicator i was gonna
say campaign i was like campaign
wait
campaign starts with a c um it's
like performance yeah key
performance it's just like what
what are the
expected metrics right like if you
have a big client base of like
fitness coach clients their kpis
would be weight like circumference
measurement like exactly exactly
yeah what is what are we trying
to achieve here yeah like kpi for
a fitness program would be
dropping 10 pounds in in month one
or in 30
days right oh we dropped seven
pounds in 30 days we're well
here's what we're going to do to
live
up to the cake guy we talked about
x y and z we're not going to give
up right and so this this again
is relevant to really any business
model where there's a service
involved one of the biggest
takeaways to that
i didn't mention enough uh
throughout this is it's an
experience you want to create an
experience for
your clients and obviously you can
do that through what we just
talked about through communicating
in
slack and through zoom but just
really think on that like create
an experience something that
will put a smile on their face
something that they'll remember
something that uh they'll want to
tell their friends about it's like
that book uh i think it's the
purple cow by seth godin and the
whole
concept of the book is like if you
were to drive by uh like a ranch
or a farm and you saw a purple cow
like you'd go and tell all your
friends you'd take pictures of it
and tell everyone about it because
it's you've never seen anything
like it before and so that's the
experience that's the vibe you
want
to create with your service is be
the purple cow um i completely
oversimplified it but as connor
mentioned
or yeah connor uh it's a great
book and a great lesson
hey andre uh thanks for the
presentation i want to ask is
there anything special that you
first seven days like i was
reading in uh you know alex
harmosi's book the first seven
days is when the
client is like most invested yeah
so like deliver some quick win
during those yeah first week 100
so we've
done uh some calls on onboarding
so so there's i break it into
onboarding which is really like
the first
seven days or even the first 24
hours um and then ongoing client
management so this is after the
onboarding process now that you
have the client how do you
ongoingly manage and and wow them
uh for the
for the onboarding stuff uh i
would recommend the client
retention master class we talk a
lot about
onboarding in there and then in
that same module in the course i
think there's two or three videos
in regards to onboarding
specifically so go through those
and then on the next call and you
can talk
about this in your action items
when you post them in slack after
but on the next call we could go
through what you've come up with
for the onboarding process but 100
for mosey says seven days i say
honestly 24 hours uh is when you
win or lose a client um and we
talk about it in in the content
that i
mentioned i think brooke uh you
have your hand raised so yeah um
with our clients like we kind
of we don't have a set process we
offer a few different services we
do like google ads facebook
ads and cro are the main three um
so what we need from the client
varies depending on their
situation
like if they they have like a
shitty website we'll start with
cro if they have like
uh terrible google ads but a great
website we'll start with google
ads um so i'm finding
like with clients i've had so far
i've only had still like a new
agency i've had three i'm finding
like i'm constantly bugging them
for access to stuff like can i get
access to this xyz and then two
days later oh i need xyz as well
you know what i mean yeah so like
my my thinking was like is it
would it be a bad idea to ask them
to just create me an email like
for example i've had to ask them
to
create like four ad accounts where
if they just made me an email at
their company i could make
everything for them yes so i
remember uh tyler who was one of
like our very first students in
the
program he asked me like basically
the same exact question and i said
don't stress about it in the
beginning because it's not really
going to happen with your first
few clients but make sure to point
out
and keep a list of all the things
that you eventually end up asking
your clients for and then ask it
in the
onboarding form so you never
forget and you never have to ask
um so all these things that you've
come across that you need access
to like their ad accounts or their
their uh social media whatever
ask that in the onboarding form uh
and if you've made the observation
that it'd be a lot easier if
they were to create me an email
account add that into your
onboarding process the first thing
they do
after signing is they add you to
their g suite as a user and they
send you the credentials so you
could
start right away all right so like
you made the observation you
already did the first part now
just
implement it whether it be they
set up an account for you or you
just ask for all the credentials
in the onboarding form that makes
sense another thing you might not
have a direct experience with this
but
um if i want them to install like
shopify apps and i want to pay for
the apps for them like just as
part
of our service is there like an
easy way to do that without
because right now i'm having to
say like
like if i'm not on the store back
end like if i'm just like a an
agency partner they have to go and
install it and pay for it on their
card and then i absolutely
essentially reimburse them but
it just doesn't seem like a great
experience from their perspective
yeah that's interesting um again
if you could get the login and do
that on your own i'd recommend it
what we did we encounter something
similar uh because we would set up
calendly accounts or we would we
would need them to upgrade their
calendly a lot of clients we
worked with didn't have like
premium calendly which means we
couldn't set
up like zapier and so we'd say hey
like can you upgrade your calendly
and what we would do is just
add our card to the account um and
the way i did it is i would use a
virtual card there's like a
website called privacy.com and you
can basically create a card for
every client and so it makes
it really easy to track expenses
uh for each client account
essentially and you could set like
daily
limits and you could limit it to
only be used on certain websites
so that gets rid of like the
security risk of like i don't want
to have my card on someone else's
account but that would probably
be the easiest way is to get the
login and have a privacy or a
virtual card created specifically
for
that client account yeah i
actually use jeeves it's a it's a
credit card platform and it allows
you to do that like create
unlimited virtual cards connected
to the same parent card so that
that
should actually work perfect okay
sick yeah let me know on that uh a
lot of the stuff you have to
test it because it's your process
it's your business and then get
back to me on whether or
not it was successful and we could
just continue to work through
potential solutions that's the
thing
with operations it's not like an
instant like oh yeah do this it's
like maybe do this try it and and
maybe it'll work and then even if
you think on it for a little bit
longer more ideas will start to
come to you another one is uh i
worked for an agency and we had a
va who just had access to the
company
card and knew like everything that
was in the air quotes starter pack
and so she would just like
set up the zoom set up the
calendly set up the gmail and then
hand it all over as a package with
the
the right memberships for each
like thing over to the person so
they just all have it all in one
go obviously that took a few like
clients to learn but yeah that's
that'd be ideal just like one one
here you go and be able to pay for
and stuff yeah yeah yeah and again
the virtual card aspect is so
key because i wouldn't want to
give like my amex to va no offense
but like that's definitely a
security
risk uh because there's no like
limit on that car but if i could
do like a a privacy card and set
the limit to like 100 bucks a day
like if i'm you know on vacation
for three days the worst that
could
happen is 300 in expenses like
that gives me peace of mind i've
never heard of that that's fire
yeah it's sick
what else questions you know on
privacy are you just using the uh
free one or do you got pro or
teams
i just use the free one but to be
honest i don't use it as much as i
used to it looks like uh broke
you shared an alternative solution
which looks interesting right yeah
i'm looking into this right
now because especially if i'm a
buy domains with a va yeah to be
honest i use uh mercury has
virtual
cards you can create unlimited
virtual cards in mercury and set
limits do the same exact thing
um in there so that's also another
solution just set a limit for like
100 bucks a day or something
yeah exactly and name the card
like jeez we expenses and then
that's how you know like that
card is just for google domains or
whatever yeah makes sense yeah i'm
getting to the exciting
point where i can take myself out
of stuff you know so it's a big
step for me at least it feels
feels like one yeah it's a big
step uh it's not gonna happen
overnight i'm still in that phase
uh and i
think i will be for a long time
it's just a continued process um
of backing yourself out of certain
things that
you've already mastered or or have
processes in place where someone
can come in and do it effectively
so
yeah it's a good good spot to be
in
any last questions or things that
i can help with based on what you
heard today
should be a lot of action items
i'd imagine
simply go in and send a check-in
message to your client
what else
was this valuable are these
formatted calls where there's more
structure and not just
open-ended q a for the whole time
are those valuable it's not going
to be a
a permanent thing but if i have
something shared that week all is
worth doing this way
yeah this is solid yeah i really
like
like not just a and not straight
lecture like combo yeah yeah yeah
getting some of like your
your like going through the
document and hearing something
like your thoughts or best
practices like
inspire so many other questions
that we wouldn't have thought of
in an open q a so
helps that's what i feel too yeah
and again like i literally just
typed this document up
this morning and so i did not
realize there's 45 minutes worth
of me talking um so what i'll
focus
on going forward is just shorter
uh on the content side so we have
more time for questions and
can stop in the middle and
whatever else but
feels like it worked out good we
went the full hour got a lot of
questions out of it um i'm sure
train is working up a great recap
which i'm really personally
excited to see and then
uh i'll share the call recording
and the document as well in slack
and if you guys have uh questions
or
um even just examples of
implementing this stuff throughout
the week i'd love to i'd love to
see it
sweet yeah and oliver it's a great
idea as well uh the the
quote-unquote master class
sessions um can
have their own section
wait thanks guys for the time uh
have a great rest of your day and
we'll talk to you soon thanks
Thank you so much for being here.
Thanks, everyone.
Take care.