My name is Andy.
I'm the head of Student Success.
So I've made this kind of document
here in
presentation just because I've
noticed probably the most common
theme with students and client
ascension, whether you are just
beginning or you are well into
your agency, is just time
management
and how to scale and people just
kind of really running out of
time.
And depending on your life,
whether you have a relationship,
family, whatever it is, or just
realistically, most people just
kind of want to have some sort of
work-life balance to a certain
degree and typically don't enjoy
working until 8 or 9 p.m.
at night, you know, trying to get
up and catch up on tasks because
certain things come up.
And I found out when I reverse
engineered like all my top 5%
students,
I was like, what was their common
habits and what do they do?
And basically I kind of crafted
this
kind of playbook of like
realistically how you can craft
your day where you can get
everything you
need to get done with your
business while also being able to
maintain your fulfillment, keep
the
business operating, and be able to
finish up at a relatively early
time.
So you actually can enjoy
a few hours of your life and your
day and maintain your hobbies and
your goals and things like that
as well.
Because sometimes you can get
really lost in, you know, just
like the business, the business,
the business, and it can just kind
of get very consuming.
And you're basically on a, you
know,
fast course to burning yourself
out as soon as possible.
So if you're not doing anything to
really
benefit your life or even make
this process even slightly
enjoyable.
And yeah, you're not gonna
have a great time with it.
So how do people look from scale
your agency?
So this outline plan,
is it going to be easy?
No.
Is it realistic?
Yes, very much so.
So by following this guide,
you, and by the way, it'll be
linked in the Kachabi below.
So don't worry, you can actually
read it in
thorough depth.
I'm just going to give you an
explainer basically as much fast
as I can.
So this is going to offer you
freedom of long-term stress.
The majority of our stress comes
from
not getting things done on a
day-to-day basis that we need to
get done for the business.
You
need to do stuff that is going to
be for business growth.
It's going to move the needle.
And then
you also need to do the actual
work for your clients, manage your
team members, all that sort of
fun stuff.
So organizing your time
effectively.
I've managed over 150 businesses
at this point.
And the worst thing that you
actually can do on a day-to-day
basis,
is what I've seen commonly, and
you're probably even guilty of
this from working with your SSE or
even on a day-to-day basis, is the
plan of your day is just way too
loose.
It's just, there's no
finite kind of timetable.
There's no structure to it.
You know, you're making some
content and then
you're putting out a fire with a
client and then you're doing some
fulfillment and then you've
scraped a new lead list or do
something new generation or send
some DMs.
And you're kind of
doing everything in multiple
different kinds of avenues.
And you're kind of messing your
brain around
because now it's like, you know,
you're in one mode, you're in like
sales mode one minute,
then you're in content creation
mode, and then you're in like
fulfillment mode.
And it's just
throwing you way out of sync.
It's actually much better if you
can just kind of try and do your
best to batch everything up.
And if you are, especially in the
beginning phases of your
business, this is absolutely going
to be perfect for you.
And you need to implement this as
soon as
absolutely possible.
And if you are for the guys that
feel like they have this kind of
like mixed
cocktail of a day where every day
seems to be completely different,
that there's no structure
to it.
This is how you can also just pull
everything back and start working
more effectively.
So this is based off all the most
successful students I've worked
with.
So the gold in rule
is you actually just need to get
up early and do your, you do your
work for your business early in
the
morning.
This is if you actually want to
have proper work-life balance.
If you're someone who
prefers working late tonight,
that's all you.
You go ahead, you enjoy it.
I typically don't find it
too productive.
I find like when you've done a
whole day of fulfillment work and
calls, then you're
trying to do something to move the
needle.
There's not really too much brain
power left for you at the
end.
These things require brain power.
These are things that are actually
going to have an effect on
the business.
So it's better to do it first
thing in the morning and just get
it off your back
instead of leaving it for the end.
It's always best to get the
hardest stuff done first.
And as much as you hate to admit
it, it is true.
You have to be an early riser.
You have to get
stuff done when people are asleep,
where clients basically can't
reach you, where your team members
can't reach you, where
realistically you need to find
three or four hours in your day,
five hours of
your day, where you are not going
to be bothered on Slack.
You're just going to be really
left alone.
And that is best to do when the
earth is still asleep, when
everyone's still asleep, when
everyone's, you know, not paying
any attention to you.
6 a.m.
to 10 a.m.
is gold, you know, but even
9 or 9.30.
Now, the reason why I say even up
to 10 a.m.
is because realistically, not many
of us are
taking sales calls at 9 a.m.
It's probably once in a blue moon,
realistically.
And even then, did you
have to?
It could have been 10.
Your team members aren't really
coming at you with any fires that
need
to be put out.
Your clients aren't really asking
too much of your attention.
So you can kind of get that
extra hour in and out of the day
anyway, which is actually quite
useful and beneficial.
So from
6 a.m.
to 10 a.m.
is gold.
And what you're going to do here
is you're going to set a timer for
a 15
minute sprint to focus on one
specific task.
You know, give yourself a breather
in between as well,
like give yourself 10 minutes, you
know, go outside for a quick walk,
make a cup of coffee, use the
bathroom, do some push-ups, listen
to some music, pray, meditate,
whatever you feel like, you know,
something that's just going to
help you just kind of give your
brain kind of a little bit of a
rest.
But what to not do under
absolutely no circumstances
whatsoever is anything that's
going to be a quick
dopamine hit or a vice.
And that means no phones, no
social media, no YouTube, no TV,
no video games,
like just keep your phone away
from you.
Like you're, you know, put your
phone on like airplane
mode if you need to and use it
only strictly as a timer.
Do not go on any of these apps.
They will completely distract you.
That's how you fall into
daydreaming and your concentration
breaks
and your focus breaks.
Like, you know, we're only human.
We get easily distracted, but you
really need
to be disciplined about this.
Like this is a category here where
it's like, you really can't
dick around.
And I really can't stress that
enough because once you start
entertaining, like those
ideas and thoughts of like, Oh,
well, what if, or whatever, or
you're scrolling on Instagram,
it's
like, Oh, she's pretty cute.
My texts are whatever your brains
you're gone.
You're just gone, dude.
You just, you're not going to get
it back.
It's like watching a movie and you
zoned out or you're on
your phone for it for 50, you
know, 50% of it.
Like, did you watch it?
No, you didn't.
You know,
you zoned out.
You didn't actually consume the
movie that you were kind of
watching because you
kept checking your phone.
It's, this is very much the same
thing.
Just lock in and stay focused.
And it's really not that bad once
you get used to it as well.
Um, so, and again, it's like going
to
the gym as well and just like
spending more time talking to
people and getting ready and doing
stretching.
It's like, you didn't actually get
a workout in, you know, you did a
couple of bumps.
You didn't actually do shit.
So now to achieve your goal, you
know, and by neglecting these
things as well, you're just asking
yourself to be stressed.
Like the majority of your stress
comes
from generally not doing the work
that you need to do.
You didn't do the work that was
absolutely
necessary for you to like
generally feel at ease for your
day.
You know, going, you can go for as
many walks as you want.
You can puff your vape as much as
you need to.
You can pop as many zins.
Your stress isn't going to go away
because you just actually didn't
do the work that you know you
needed to get done that day.
You're just not going to feel good
about it.
So,
and this is also how people have
these things called what I call
white noise days.
These are days, and I think
everyone's had them before where
you think back to yourself and
think,
what the fuck did I do today?
Like what happened?
Like what, where did the day go
wrong?
You know, you just get, you wake
up, it's maybe eight, 8 a.m., 8.30
a.m.
You're logged on to Slack
and you have fulfillment to do
from the night before.
Then all of a sudden the team
members asking for
your attention.
You know, you have to do
check-ins, inbox management.
You're checking your DMs.
You're
checking your socials.
You might be checking out how this
content's performing.
You know, you need to
kind of do all of that first and
foremost, and then you just can
get sucked into doing so many
different things.
And then, you know, you're trying
to make it this YouTube script,
and then you have
to do this bit of fulfillment, and
then Slack's going off, and
clients are asking this.
And it's
just, you know, you snap your
fingers.
It's been 6 p.m., you're tired,
you're burnt out, and, you know,
you need a rest because, you know,
you're only human.
You've been going for like 10
hours, 11 hours
already, and you're just like,
what have I done today?
Like what's actually after
happening?
Like what did
I do to really move the needle in
the business?
The truth is you didn't actually
do shit.
You just worked.
So this is what we're going to
cover here.
And these things are, this, these
white noise days are
actually really dangerous because
these can really seriously
compound over time.
You may genuinely at
some point feel like I'm getting
stuff done for my business, and
you're not.
And it's a really
dangerous game to play because you
get into that habit.
It can, you can have a white noise
day,
a white noise day can turn into a
white noise week, and then it can
turn into a white noise month.
Like, genuinely ask yourself, how
many times has it been when you
did a BHA with your student
success coach, and you're going
through all the action items that
you've done, and you've only
gotten like 50, 60% of the stuff
done.
But you're kind of sitting there
like, that was a really busy
month though.
Like I was flat out.
And then you look at your stats
too, and you're like, everything's
kind of the same.
Same amount of booked calls, same
amount of deals closed, same
amount of
revenue, or maybe you just
slightly went up, but you also had
some churn in between.
So you kind of
balanced out.
It wasn't like too much of a
spike.
I hate to tell you, it's because
your day is kind of
screwed up and your scheduling is
completely screwed up.
So we want to avoid these as much
as humanly
possible.
So you want to do three to four 50
minute blocks.
And you know, when the world
doesn't have a
chance to break your
concentration, you don't also have
an excuse to do so.
Now, what should you do
during these 50 minute time blocks
in your morning?
Well, every single day without
fail, one of them
has to be lead generation.
You know, this is the time of the
day to scrape a new lead list for
a
campaign, write a new cold email
sequence to test, set up a new
campaign and launch it, test your
own
deliverability in your cold email
setup, you know, do some Dream 100
outreach, do some Dream 100 list
building.
If it's past 9am, do some cold
calling, do some DM outreach, do
some script writing,
personalized email outreach,
LinkedIn connections, social media
engagement, making new ad
creatives
for you.
If you're doing any paid ads or
making and send any looms that you
need to send to for any
clients that you know, you may
have promised a loom to maybe the
day before, which by the way, you
should
be doing as soon as possible.
I'm just giving you a note, but
like just in case, and some people
apply
to their personalized messaging
process.
And then CRM reactivation.
This one is absolutely key.
The amount of times I've spoken
with students and be like, have
you, what's up with your CRM?
And
they're like, oh, it's like six,
seven interested prospects from
the entire year.
Like we're in
October right now, pushing
November.
And it's like, okay, so you have
basically a year of a CRM of
prospects that responded
positively to either your cold DM,
your D you know, your cold DM,
your cold email, or maybe a cold
call.
And just they slipped through the
cracks and follow up with
them.
So follow up with them.
Now you have now an hour, you have
50 minutes to just start
chat ramming messages.
Just do it.
Next is going to be content.
This is the perfect time to,
again,
record a YouTube video, script a
YouTube video, make some reels for
short form, write your newsletter,
make a LinkedIn post for the week,
like using Hypefury and other
tools like that.
Link, you know,
your Twitter posts for the entire
week.
Again, just load them up into
Hypefury.
Write a sales
assets, write a lead magnet, you
know, update your landing page,
which you should be doing every
three
to six months, because you should
be having new case studies that
need to be uploaded.
There may be
new adjustments that the offering
or the messaging that we need to
test.
And, you know, we need to
adjust.
This should be happening very
frequently, and especially
rewriting and re-recording your
VSL,
which also should be done every
three to six months.
It's kind of insane that some of
you are
not doing this on a consistent
basis.
It kind of drives me insane.
It's like testing the same email
copy for an entire year.
You're going to find some winners,
winning aspects of it.
You're going to find
some losing aspects of it.
Do some market research on this as
well.
And I'll explain to you actually
how
to do that right now.
And that is going to be in the
most neglected phase, which is
your sales analysis.
This is something I see absolutely
none of you do.
Some of you, you're like literally
in the five
percent.
Like it's extremely rare.
And this is re-watching your sales
calls and taking notes.
If you re-watch your sales calls
and you take notes, and then you
listen back to analyze and flesh
out your objections, be better
prepared.
You can apply those objections and
apply your most common
objections to your new VSL.
It is an absolute hack.
This is why you should be
uploading it every so
often.
If there's an objection that you
commonly faced on sales calls,
pretty much 80% under your
sales calls, you get this
objection.
You should put it to your VSL and
basically upfront that objection
before they even get a chance to
book the call.
Your booking rate will increase.
So, and your qualified rate will
also increase.
So, doing these things as well.
Practice your three
pillars.
Something I don't see many of you
doing enough.
You need to have good tonality.
It needs
to be natural.
It needs to be clean.
It needs to be efficient.
Another thing as well is like, you
know,
if someone's willing to get up
early with you as well, run a mock
call.
A good time to actually sit down
for an hour and just flesh out and
go back to back and toe to toe.
Another tip for when you're doing
any sort of mock calls with people
is practicing your frames.
Don't just sit there on a call and
go
easy on each other.
Say to someone, hey, can you run
through the commodity frame with
me?
Hey,
could you do the power frame with
me?
Hey, could you do the time frame
for me?
Like, what frame do you
commonly get in your ICP in your
nation or the industry that you're
working with?
And practice that.
Let them practice theirs.
If someone doesn't know their
frames and they're doing mock
calls,
they need to go back over the
modules from David and the Kajabi.
Just giving you an FYI.
You're
probably wasting your time with
that person.
They're too early on.
So you need to know your frames
when
you're doing mock calls.
And learning your numbers.
I've seen you many times on sales
calls not actually
know your numbers off by heart.
You need to know your numbers.
You need to know the numbers of
your
case studies when you're on a
sales call.
That is called drip feeding the
information.
You just need to
just be able to throw it out there
in a moment's notice.
There's nothing more awkward when
someone asks
you a metric or a number of one of
your clients and you have to go,
let me think about that.
And so just learn your
numbers.
Again, analyze your objections,
incorporate into your new VSL, key
for conversions.
So listen to other
people's sales calls and take
notes.
Again, listen to someone else's
sales call.
I cannot stress this enough.
There are many of them in the
Kajabi that you can watch and
analyze.
So please do so.
And here's the next one is
learning.
I would say on average, most of
you get through about on average
30% of Kajabi, which is just
baffling.
Like there are so many videos that
answer so many of your standard
questions on a day-to-day basis
where you could really, in theory,
like take that information and
just apply it to your business.
Now,
and this is, I often hear from
students, like I just can't find
the time to get through Kajabi.
You know, you get through the
sales section and that's it.
You drop it like a bag of bricks,
like it's just gone then.
But you really need to go back and
rewatch these modules.
There's a lot of in-depth
knowledge here and something that
when you're at 5K may not have
made sense.
But now you're at 15K and it's
like, oh, now this is starting to
make sense.
Now this is starting to click into
place, especially things like
Daniel's offer videos, especially
Daniel's offer videos.
This is now going to make sense
when you're at a different, you
know, a different, you're just
more sophisticated business owner.
You're more experienced now.
You've more clients, you've more
MRR, you've team members probably.
And it's just going to make a lot
more sense of the tips and tricks
that he's going to tell you.
So you probably need to rewatch
them every so often.
I know for a fact that all the
SSEs do once every so often.
And the biggest tip for when
you're watching the content is to
watch the video at 1.5, 2x speed
and watch it in a 15 minute
sprint.
Like just super concentrated, just
lock in.
Like it's the last thing you were
ever going to, like it's the last
time you'll ever be able to watch
it.
Like it's the last thing you will
ever be able to watch in your
life.
Just watch it like your life
depends on it.
And as soon as you hear strategy,
a theory or something you can put
into practice for your business,
pause the video.
And instead of like writing down
notes or typing out notes, use
otter.io.
It's a real time voice to text
app.
It's a really, really good one.
You get 303 minutes, so you don't
have to go on any payment plans
and stuff like that.
Just press record and voice the
actual notes.
Force yourself to contextualize
the information and how you're
going to apply it to your
business.
You're now no longer just mentally
copying and pasting notes that
realistically you're not going to
look back on or really understand
in like a month's time.
But when you force yourself to
contextualize it, you're actually
forcing yourself to learn and
absorb this information and apply
it.
And when you look back at these
notes, these notes are actually
going to have a lot more effect
for you.
You're going to look at it and go,
oh, yeah, that's when Daniel was
talking about lead generation
versus lead capture.
This is how I applied it to my
offering.
This is how I applied it to this
ICP.
I noticed one ICP was a demand
capture, but I actually noticed
this ICP that I'm targeting is
lead generation.
So I need to come up with a
different content strategy or a
different targeting strategy or a
different email sequence.
You see where I'm coming from
here.
We need to contextualize the
information.
Otherwise, we're just going to sit
around here and go in circles.
So watch the video, pause it.
When you hear something useful to
your business, record it and apply
the information to your business.
Very, very straightforward.
And then you actually have long
detailed notes that you can
actually go back to.
Another time and area you can do
this, and sometimes depending on
the scale of your business, of
course, you may look into doing
some operations or some admin
work.
This is a time to go and build out
a Loom SOP tutorial.
This is maybe when you can clean
up your CRM.
This is when you can just clean up
your Slack.
Maybe you've just a bunch of
messages all over the place.
Things are in threads, buried.
Channels have a bunch of pin shit
that don't need to be there
anymore.
There might be one or two channels
that aren't necessary.
You know, you need to deactivate
certain members.
Like, this is the time to go
through all of this.
You know, and audit all of your
staff's end-of-day type forms.
Audit their work.
Look at the stuff that they're
working on.
Make sure all the Google Drives
are in order or whatever that you
use.
Like, just make sure that your
house is tidy in the back end here
because it can get messy very
quickly, especially if you're
using something like Notion.
Like, clean up your Notion
documents, especially.
Map out your fulfillment timeline,
you know.
Start using, like, a Miro board
and build out your entire process
like a company brain of, like,
right, from the moment of
onboarding to the moment of
fulfillment.
Like, break out every single step
in between of, like, what's
happening in the business and who
the work is being allocated to and
what department and what team or
what do you do and what do you
cover?
And then you can send that to your
team and you can just pin that to
your channel and say, like, hey,
this is your entire process just
so everyone knows how this machine
works.
And you trust me, your operations
will massively increase from doing
that.
You know, audit your onboarding
process and your onboarding calls.
This is absolutely crucial.
Someone's after paying you a
couple of thousand dollars to sign
on to your service and if you have
a shitty onboarding process or a
shitty onboarding call, you're
never going to, that's the
greatest way to create buyer's
regret.
Every one of you that came to
client ascension, you can see that
all of us as the SSEs have done
onboarding many, many, many, many
times and we practice that
thoroughly.
So, one, we can build a pretty
nice relationship with you.
You can trust us.
You get the right information.
But really, you feel like, hey, I
can message you if I need you.
That's really the goal of this.
You know, you need to feel like,
yeah, I'm in good hands.
So, update your agency's contract.
This is massive.
I've seen many of you do this
before.
The amount of times as well where,
you know, you said, oh, this
client is causing this problem and
it's not the contract and causing
this.
And then I would say to you, cool,
add this stipulation to your
contract for future cases so you
don't run into this problem.
And it falls through the cracks.
And I asked you, did you update
your contract?
And you go, no.
And I go, why?
You ran into this problem before.
You think you're not going to run
into it again.
This is the time to do it.
If you find a gap in your
contract, this is a good time to
sit down and just hash it out.
Building out your next higher
scorecard.
You know, again, my report.
And building out a project plan.
Or just build out an automation
that you need to build out.
Anything that simple as, like,
from your smart lead to your Slack
to say, hey, you got a positive
notification.
You got a positive reply.
Whatever it may be.
You need to be doing stuff like
this.
Now, listen.
I know this list of stuff here is
a lot to do.
Like, it is a lot.
You know.
And I'm not going to sit here and
pretend it isn't.
And the operations stuff,
realistically, as well, depending
on where you're at with your
business, you could do that during
the day, too.
It's mainly for the first three
things that you need to kind of
really focus on the most.
But, again, completely depends on
where you're at with your
business.
You need to just kind of put your
head on a little bit here and try
and map this out and apply this to
your business and where you're
currently at.
But everyone in different MRR
rates is going to be a little bit
different.
Like, realistically, if you're a
little under 5K, you have time to
do tons of this stuff throughout
the day.
And you should be.
But if you're busy, you have,
like, 12 clients, you have, like,
three team members, you have team
calls, you have sales calls coming
in, you have a bunch of other
stuff to do.
Like, this is where you need to
really apply, you know, your
thinking brain.
But by doing this, even if you
commit only three tasks every
morning, you've done 15 hours of
deep work for the business a week,
which I don't think anyone is
realistically able to do.
I really don't think so.
So if you can do this, you now
have to, you've now gotten some
really high leverage tasks done
every day.
So you build sales assets, you did
some Dream 100 outreach, you know,
you cleaned up your CRM, like,
brilliant.
Most of you aren't able to get
that done in a day.
And if you can do four hours,
you're getting 20 hours done a
week.
That is absolutely massive.
And you've done it all before,
like, really the day even begins,
and you can really be unbothered.
So, listen, while Rome wasn't
built in a day, you know, you may
see an immediate ROI from doing
this.
You may see nothing for about a
month or so.
But that's fine.
It's just completely dependent on
the business and where you're
currently at.
But by doing this, after 10 a.m.,
you're free to put out any fires
you need to do, take any team
meetings you need to do, take any
sales calls, do any client calls,
new hire interviews, work on
fulfillment.
Go to a coaching call in the
evening time that you need to go
to if you need to talk to, like,
Nick or David or Connor or Mario
or Andre.
Like, now you actually have that
time in your day to go and do
those things because you pretty
much have the day covered because
you've got every high leverage
task for the business done here.
And you can call it a day at 5
p.m.
or 6 p.m.
or 5.30 p.m.
Whatever you need, like, depending
on your business.
But most of you can actually call
it a day at 5 p.m.
You can generally, like, close
your computer at 5 o'clock and go
about your day and enjoy your
life.
And I mean, yeah, no one's really
had an emergency at 9 o'clock in
the morning.
Completely depends on the agency.
But, like, you know, have an SOP
in place that if there is an
emergency at 9 a.m., tell your
team to call you.
Just huddle you.
You know, like, you'll know.
Like, it rarely happens, but you
know.
Not to mention, what fire is
really coming out that can't be
fixed within the hour anyway.
So, manage to do the inverter by
blocking your time.
If you block your time, like, your
four-hour block in the morning and
get your high leverage task done,
perfect.
I personally like the first hour
after that is, again, to just kind
of check house a little bit.
Check your email box.
Check your DMs.
Check your content.
Check in on Slack.
See what's going on.
Announce yourself to your team.
Let people know that you're here.
You're present.
You're ready to work.
And, again, you're not going to do
this every day.
But, like, stack your team calls
together back to back to back.
Like, literally get really
disciplined in giving people just
30 minutes of their time.
And you should be constructing
your time.
And if you have any problems
about, like, if your team calls
are going a little over or, again,
they seem really unnecessary, talk
to, you can feel free to talk to
myself or Andre.
And we'll show you how this kind
of, like, how we construct our
calls.
And then blocking your sales calls
as well.
And then on top of that, one thing
that people really need to do is
that if you have any outside work
tasks,
like if you know Monday I have to
go get my hair cut, Tuesday I have
to go to the bank,
Wednesday I have to go grocery
shopping,
Thursday I have to go and drop
this thing back into my friend or
whatever, like that, don't do
that.
Just stack it all into one day and
just do everything in a three-hour
gap.
Go get your hair cut, go to the
bank, go get your grocery
shopping,
and then pop into whoever you need
to see or do or whatever at the
end of the day.
Just block it all off and get it
done in one fail sweep and just
get it done and finish in the
week.
All right, ideally after 3.30, 4
p.m.
if you can.
But, like, if it has to be sooner,
it has to be sooner.
It depends completely on how you
organize your business.
So most of you fall into
exhaustion because, again, it's
just a cocktail of all this
madness.
And your day is just, you're being
pulled in too many directions.
I think anyone would love to see
this be their day if they could.
If you can have an ideal business
day, this would be something most
of you would love to see.
You're getting YouTube scripting
done, Dream 100 Outreach, watching
a module that you needed to watch,
write a sales assets, do some
check-ins, and then straight into
just doing some back-to-back sales
calls.
Have an hour gap in between to
check on anything, do some sort of
fulfillment,
cover whatever you need to do,
maybe take a break, whatever it
is.
Do some back-to-back team calls,
and then go back on about your
day.
Most of you would love to have a
day like this.
That is an extremely productive
day, and you log off today at 5
p.m.
That's gold.
This is just an example, but, you
know, most of us would love to see
that.
And you can have those days if you
just take this and apply it to
your business, you know.
So, here's another thing.
But what happens if I can't wake
up?
What happens if you're just like a
really shitty sleeper like myself,
and getting up in the morning
sounds absolutely horrendous,
and I'd rather, you know, pull
nails out of my eyes or something?
I don't know.
But I'd love to say, yeah, I just
have to do it.
In one sense, yes, you do just
It's just going to have to be a
necessity.
But if you have a genuinely shitty
sleeping schedule, and you wake up
at 11 a.m.,
and you're going to bed at like 2
or 3 a.m.,
well, one, you need to kind of
pull that back a little bit.
It's just not super healthy in the
long term.
But if that's your jam, that's
your jam.
No judgment.
You go off and do whatever you
want to do.
But this is just my personal
preference here, opinion of, you
know,
what's the most productive way.
So let's just say you usually wake
up at 10 a.m., start waking up at
9.
Just slowly go into it.
Don't force yourself to just get
up at like 5.30 a.m.
one morning.
You're just not going to be
productive.
It's going to shell shock the
body.
Start slowly integrating it until
you can get to sleep at like
waking up at like 8 a.m.,
you know, 7 a.m.
Then when you start doing that,
start hitting your early hours.
So like you probably want to wake
up.
If you want to start work for 6,
you need to get up at about 5.30
a.m.
Go look at the sun, like Leary, go
outside, sit there for like 15
minutes.
Just go outside for five minutes.
You know, at the start, go back to
bed then.
You know, wake up then at your 8
or 9 o'clock or 7 o'clock then at
that point,
but just try and get kind of used
to it into a flow.
Get up for five minutes and stay
outside.
Then the next day, get up at the
same thing, but stay outside for
10 minutes.
Then you can go back to bed.
And then the third day, you know,
you're trying to push yourself to
about 15 minutes.
Now you're starting to train your
body a little bit to wake up.
Associating like the sunrise or
going outside, do all that.
And don't do any work for that
half an hour.
Just take a chill pill for
yourself.
Sit around, have a coffee.
Good time to actually journal and
like map out what you want out of
your real life
and what are your goals and what
are you actually doing all this
for?
And start, you know, planning
like, all right, I'm currently
here.
I want to be here next year.
What are steps I need to do here?
It's a very good motivating time,
but it's just nice to sit there on
your own
and just be with your thoughts for
half an hour just before you deep
dive into your work.
So that's how I'd personally
recommend doing it.
Again, the document goes into more
detail, so you can read it over
there.
And then again, you need to stay
accountable to this.
And that is another factor that a
lot of you need a lot of help
with.
And accountability is a massive
factor.
Accountability is just really
disciplined.
And really what I recommend is
Jeremy Newsom's tactic.
I spoke to him about this just in
Tampa.
I asked him, like, how I can keep
people more accountable.
And he was like, challenge them.
You made a really good point.
So challenge yourself, though,
because that's the ultimate form
of accountability
is if you don't need to be told to
do something, you just can do it
yourself.
And it shows that you have
discipline.
So when Jeremy needed to hold
himself accountable and he failed
a task, he punished himself.
He gave himself a pretty severe
punishment so that he learned a
lesson.
He maintained what he was meant to
do.
And that meant donating money to
the opposite political party,
going vegan for a month,
running until you puke, quitting
alcohol for a month, a cold shower
every morning before work.
Like, come up with something that
you would genuinely hate to do and
do it.
And punish yourself from doing it.
And commit to that punishment.
You'll never make that mistake
again.
You just need to get an iron
mindset on things.
And that's the way to do it.
So you just actually, there needs
to be consequences for not being
accountable.
I mean, you can ask your SSC to do
it.
But I mean, sure.
But like, what are we going to do?
Virtually slap you?
I don't know.
Maybe.
But you need to do something.
So.
And here's some final notes.
These are just some off-topic
things that, you know, I've
accumulated from over the years.
And it's like, perfection's a
silent killer of productivity.
When it's good enough, launch it.
Move on.
Don't let shiny object syndrome
kill your progress.
You can only climb one mountain at
a time.
Don't let others deter you from
climbing your mountains.
Don't stop halfway through.
Just see it through to the end.
If you're in the early stages of
your agency, make looms.
Videos of all your fulfillment.
Start building a catalog of
training videos.
So that when you do make a hire,
you actually have a library of,
like, videos and trainings already
set to go.
I'm going to call this now because
it's 30 minutes.
You can read the rest of this.
The document is at the bottom.
Or you can, like, pause this video
and read some of these here.
Yeah, go get to work.
Love you.
Bye.