Welcome back to another video.
It's Andre here and in this video,
basically where we're at currently
in the onboarding process is we
talked about the service
agreement.
So when you have a client ready
to sign up, you want to basically,
the first thing you want to get
them to do or the first thing you
have to get them to do is review
and sign the service agreement and
you can use a tool called
HelloSign.
There's also DocuSign.
There's also like PandaDoc.
There's a bunch of tools out there
where you can send PDF contracts
like the service agreements, like
the one we are creating and
editing in Canva and send it to
someone's email and get them to
sign it electronically, which is
still valid legally.
So look into those tools.
But basically by this point, you
already came up
with a service agreement and
contract, got it signed by your
client.
You also decided on how
you're going to set or how much
you're going to charge for a setup
fee or your onboarding fees
so that you can invoice your
clients.
So basically right now, all that
you've done is you got that
signed service agreement from the
client.
And then now you have to
understand what are the next
steps.
So you had the sales call, they
signed the service agreement.
What are the next steps?
And what you're looking at here is
a tool called Trello.
This is what we use for our
agency.
It's
basically like another tool or
version of Notion.
It's just we prefer to use Trello
because we've used
it forever and it works for us.
So we actually don't use Notion at
all at our agency.
We just use Trello.
And again, you could also use
ClickUp.
There's so many tools out there
for basically it's just project
management or task management or
task management, however you want
to call it.
So we have a very set and standard
set of procedures in place for
what happens once we get a signed
contract.
So as soon as we get a signed
contract,
we go to this board here, which is
a template board.
So in Trello, it's really just a
template.
And it's really nice because we
don't have to change anything to
this specific template.
We can create a board that looks
just like this from the actual
template.
So this is part of being
like a Trello pro member or
whatever, which we are.
And all I'll do in the top is hit
create board from
template.
And then usually the way I name
the board is I'll put the client's
name and then X our business.
So like X knowledge X and I'll
create the board.
And now I just created like a
workspace for our
client and I'll walk you through
the entire workspace.
So you understand what each card
is there for.
And obviously this is tailored
specifically to knowledge X, my
lead generation agency and the
services that we provide.
So it won't look the same exact
for you because your business is
unique in
in various ways, obviously.
But I'll walk you through
basically how to leverage a tool
like Trello or
any other project management tool
to have a very rigid and set
process in place to go through
next steps.
Because once someone signs a
contract, you have a very short
window of time to make a really
good
first impression.
That's like one of the most
important things in the agency
base
or agency business, excuse me, is
to make a good first impression.
It's so, so important in client
services.
You want to impress your clients
right out of the bat, because what
that does is it gives it
gives them comfort in the decision
that they just made.
Because when you make a big
decision,
like signing on with an agency,
which is probably going to cost
you a couple thousand of dollars,
at least without any like
guarantee of results or any like
way to predict what's actually
going to happen
or unfold with full certainty,
giving them comfort and
reassurance and more reasons to
trust you is
the best thing you can do.
And you can do it very simply by
having a rigid set of processes in
place,
ready to basically fire off as
soon as that signed contract or
the service agreement is signed.
So for us, as soon as the signed
service agreement or the service
agreement is signed, I keep
messing that
up.
As soon as we get that service
agreement signed, we go into this
Trello board and we create a
we create a board from the
template.
And then all we have here is
resources.
So we have general resources,
campaign resources, educational
resources, which I'll explain, and
then a to do list.
So you'll see,
and then obviously completed
tasks, because we'll move things
over in Trello.
You just simply move
cards over from the to do list to
the completed task.
And that'll help us know where
we're at with this
specific project and with this
specific client.
So like, I'll just walk you
through everything on this
Trello board.
So the first thing you'll notice
is that there's some cards are
labeled in green,
which is actually what the client
is supposed to do.
And then other ones are labeled in
blue,
which is called knowledge X,
because that's what our agency is
supposed to do.
So as soon as we get a
signed service agreement from the
client, the first thing we have to
do is if we open this card,
there is a checklist of two action
items.
The first is to add a signed date
to the signed service
agreement card.
And the second is to attach the
signed PDF to the signed service
agreement card.
So that's a card here under
general resources, where if you
open it, it says when the contract
was signed.
And it also says when the first
campaign was started.
So that's helpful information
to have.
So you can get an idea for how
long does it usually take to start
campaigns after a contract's
been signed?
Because that's a common question
you'll probably get on sales
calls.
It's like, okay,
great, let's do it.
How long do you think until the
first campaign is going to get
started?
And you can give them an accurate
answer by just recording those two
very important dates.
And you'll want to add an
attachment of the signed service
agreement to this card,
because what you're going to do,
you're going to invite the client
by email
to this Trello board.
So they have access to it.
So it's super nice for them
because they come on here
and they could see when they
signed, they could see when the
first campaign started,
and they could see when their
invoices do each month.
And they could also see a PDF
version of
the signed service agreement in
case they have any questions or
whatever it might be.
They might
be wondering, oh, what happens in
this scenario?
And then they could go back or you
could do the same
thing and say, hey, you know, you
didn't pay the invoice on time.
So based on the signed service
agreement, which you could refer
back to in this card here on
Trello, we're going to charge you
a 3%
late fee, you know, something like
that.
But anyway, so that's the first
action item.
So you want to add
the signed service agreement and
the date it was signed, and then
you just simply move it over to
the completed task.
And that's all we're doing.
So this is almost like an SOP for
us.
It actually is
like our SOP for the most part.
What do we do when a client signs?
First thing we do is we download
the
PDF version of the signed contract
and we upload it to this card in
Trello.
And we also put the date
of when it was signed in Trello.
And before that, we actually had
to create a board in Trello for
the
new client.
So that's really the second step.
The third step now for us to do is
to send an invoice
in Stripe for the setup fee or for
the onboarding fee.
And part of doing that is to set
up the client
as a new customer in Stripe or
whatever billing system you're
going to use to collect payments
from
your customer.
So that's the second thing.
The next thing is actually for the
client to do,
and that's for them to review and
pay the invoice.
So the reason I have this as a
card
is so I can keep it here at the
top of the to-do list card until I
get confirmation that they paid.
Because if I don't have this here
and I just send the invoice, I
might forget and I might,
it might be a week or two after it
was actually due and I might
realize, oh,
shit, this client still hasn't
paid the invoice.
I should reach out to him about
it.
But if we keep it
at the top of the to-do list, the
client will see that and I'll see
it so that if I continue to see
it and it stays there, I can reach
out and say, hey, this still
hasn't gotten paid,
you know, pay it.
But let's just say the client paid
the invoice, we can move it over
to completed
task.
And this is all that's happening
is we're moving our to-do list
items to completed task items.
And we're having a very specific
set of processes to follow as soon
as the client is onboarded.
And the next one is just to set up
the Trello board.
And all we have to do to set up
the Trello
board is what we did in the very
beginning of this video, which is
to create a board from the
template
and then invite anyone you need to
invite to the Trello board.
So I'd invite like my partner,
Dan,
I'd invite my partner, Christian.
And then what I do is I just
create a link and I include that
in an
onboarding email, which we'll get
to in a second here.
So just we'll come back to the
actual link
and I'll show you where that's
relevant.
I'm not actually going to invite
Dan and Christian,
because this is just an example
board that I'm going to delete
right after this video,
because it's just for example
purposes for this program.
So what is involved with setting
up the
Trello board is just inviting
everyone that needs to be invited
and obviously actually setting it
up.
So I'll move that one over.
The next thing I want to do is set
up a shared Dropbox folder for the
clients.
So for us, we get on Zoom calls
with our clients.
We get on an onboarding call
initially,
which is part of this process
we'll talk about.
And there's going to be a video on
how to prepare
for the onboarding call and what
you should actually discuss on
that call.
But we get on an onboarding
call and then we also get on
check-in calls, which we'll talk
again about, I think in the next
module,
which is how to like retain and
just, yeah, just retain clients
and what you should be doing once
you're actually working with
clients for a long time.
So we record all of those Zoom
calls.
And since
Zoom calls are pretty large files,
we just create a Dropbox folder
because we have a Dropbox account
for our company or for our agency.
And we just have a folder for
every client.
And anytime we get on a
Zoom call, we just save the drop,
the Zoom recording to the client's
Dropbox folder.
So it's just nice
to have because obviously on the
onboarding call, we'll talk about
a lot of important stuff.
And then also on the check-in
calls, we'll talk about a lot of
important stuff.
And that will be added.
Once we set that up, part of that
setup process is linking it,
including a link in this card here
on Trello.
And that's important because
everyone from my team and
from the client's team is on this
Trello board.
So they could see and access all
the information
here.
So if I have a Dropbox folder that
has all the recordings, then my
team can access those too,
because I also want my team to
know what's going on with this
specific client.
And if we need to refer
back to a call where we discuss a
lot of important things, we can
easily access that Dropbox folder
right there in Trello at any time.
So that's the first, that's the
next thing.
The next thing is
talking about setting up Slack.
So the next thing we'll do is set
up Slack, which is where we
communicate
with the client.
I'm not going to open this card
because there's some sensitive
information in there.
And I'll also do another video on
how to use Slack for your agency
because Slack, and we're already
using
Slack right now for our program.
And part of the reason we're using
Slack is because not everyone is
familiar with Slack and I want to
just train you guys and get you
comfortable with using Slack
because it's just another one of
those things that's an absolute
must for running an agency
business.
But basically what we do, and
again, I'll have a more expansive
video explaining some of this
stuff,
but we just set up channels for
the client and then we'll invite
the client to Slack and we'll
include
a link in the onboarding form or
the onboarding email, which we'll
get to.
So I'm going to move this
over just to pretend like it's
done.
And there's multiple tasks there
that I have to check off
because there's multiple channels.
And then I have to basically do a
few other things, which again,
will be talked about in one of the
later videos.
But so far, let's just look at
what we've done.
So as soon as we get confirmation
from HelloSign or whatever signing
tool or e-signature tool we're
using that the client has signed
our service agreement, we went to
the Trello board or to the
Notion board or however, wherever
you have this set up, we created
something from the template and
we,
or we just created a board.
And basically the board tells us
that we, what we need to do.
The first
thing we needed to do was attach
the signed service agreement to
this card, add the contract signed
date.
The second thing we needed to do
was send an invoice to the client
through Stripe.
Part of that
process was adding them or setting
them up as a new customer in
Stripe.
Then we see here that the
client has to pay the invoice
before the next step can happen.
After that, we have a few more
steps
that we completed, which consisted
of setting up the Trello board.
Again, it's a project management
tool
that we use.
I think it'd be great for you to
use Trello because then I could
really, really help you.
And because I have experience with
it, hands-on experience, but if
it's Notion or something else,
it's the same framework and
concepts.
So as long as you're comfortable
with the tool, that's really
all that matters.
So we set up the Trello board and
really all that was, was creating
a
a board from the template and then
also inviting everyone that needs
to be on the board to be on
here.
So they all have access, including
the client, obviously.
We set up a shared Dropbox folder
so that
we can have a place to store
specific files that we're going to
want everyone involved in the
project
to have access to at any time
throughout the working
relationship.
And also added that to the card
here
here on Trello.
And then we set up the Slack
channels and invited the client to
Slack so that
there's a workspace to
communicate.
So the two most important tools
for our agency, at least with
onboarding clients and managing
clients is Trello because Trello
is basically like our project
management dot.
It's a dashboard.
It has all the information we'll
ever need to have to answer all
the questions that will come up
about how our campaign is going.
Where can I find this?
Where can I
find that?
It's like a storage unit.
Um, but also like, uh, it covers
everything because there's
also a to-do list to see like the
progress and what we're currently
working on.
So it, oh my God,
you'll be, if you've set up
something like this or even
remotely close to it, especially
in the early
days, it'll pay off immensely
because people are so, so
impressed about our onboarding
process.
Again, it's like something we get
complimented about all the time.
And the onboarding process is
everything from having a very
professional and attractive
looking signed service agreement.
And it's also all the way to
having, uh, an professional
onboarding email being quick to
actually onboard them.
Once you get confirmation that the
client signed, there's so much
involved
in making a first impression in
the onboarding process.
And it's everything that we're
discussing
here in this module.
So every piece is part of a
greater puzzle that we have to put
together fully
to, to really experience the true
benefits of.
So anyways, that's where we're
currently at.
Um,
these next two items for us are
getting very specific to some
internal processes that we have
at our agency.
So to be honest, like it won't
really make much sense to you, but
basically we have a
scoreboard.
Uh, so we could keep track of all
the results we're getting for each
client.
And we also
have like an invoice tracker sheet
so we can keep track of how much
to invoice the clients.
Um, so we want to add a new row
and a new tab to both of those,
uh, documents.
Once we sign a new
client, um, we also have inbox
managers that we hire, uh, and
inbox managers are also using,
like we have a KPI sheet for them.
And we also have a Trello
dashboard specifically for our
inbox
manager team.
Um, so basically when we get a new
client, that new client has to
have an inbox manager
dedicated to their campaigns.
And that step basically reminds us
to assign an inbox manager
to this new client and then also
follow through with what needs to
be done there.
Um, and then the,
the next step is to send the
onboarding email.
So the onboarding email is
basically it's recapping
everything you just did and
outlining what you need the client
to do now that all this stuff that
you
did is done.
So one thing I'll grab real quick
is just, uh, I'll create the link
so that I can invite
the client here and I'm going to
open the onboarding email.
So before I open and show you our
onboarding
email, what I would say is just to
not, please don't copy this word
for word.
Um, like with anything
here, like there's no value or use
to copy things exactly how they're
laid out for our agency because
every agency and every business is
different.
And if you start to copy things,
your business is not
going to be unique and it's not
going to be sustainable.
That's the most important thing
is to have a sustainable business
or have a sustainable agency.
You have to understand the
frameworks and the reasonings
behind why we're actually doing
all this stuff.
So if you're just
copying everything mindlessly,
you're not actually going to
understand things and they're
going to break
or they're going to crumble with
your business as time goes on.
So we want you to have a
sustainable
business and skill sets and a
foundation that you can build off
of for the rest of your life.
Like
past just this agency.
Sure.
Like you have a goal to scale your
agency in the short term.
That's awesome.
But these skills and these
practices that we're teaching you
are going to be the foundation to
so much more
success as life goes on.
And that only happens if you go in
with the mindset that I just
explained.
So anyways, in this card in
Trello, another reason why Trello
is so great is because we could
have
information like this stored.
So here in the description of this
card is our onboarding email.
So the first thing I do is that
Trello card.
I'm just going to add it here.
So we have it and then
I'll explain basically what you're
looking at.
So this first line here is our
subject line.
So I'll
say client company name x
knowledge x basically the same
naming convention we use for the
Trello board
and then with a dash that says
next steps.
And then here's the actual body of
the email says hey
and then their client name.
My name is Andre.
I'm one of the co-founders here at
knowledge x because
they haven't talked to me yet.
At least for my agents, the way my
agency works, I have not
interacted
with this person at all because
Dan is actually in charge of sales
and he's the one getting on sales
calls
and having those conversations
with prospects, right?
So I'm introducing myself because
they
don't even know who I am yet.
And then basically, I just premise
it with hey, I just wanted to
share
some tasks for you to work on as
we were as we get you fully as we
get you fully onboarded, right?
So the whole premise of this email
is what are the next steps because
once they sign a contract,
it's they're probably going to be
like, all right, what's next?
Do I just wait to hear from them?
When do campaign?
There's all these questions that
are going to come up and at the
same time,
doubts, right?
They're going to doubt like was
that actually a good decision?
Should I have signed that
contract?
Is this going to pay off?
Right?
So that's why this onboarding
process is so important to keep
it rigid and professional and
systemized because you're going to
get rid of that doubt and you're
going to build trust and it's
going to result in client
relationships that last a lifetime
if you do this correctly.
So anyways, the premise of this
email again is to outline next
steps for
them to work on.
And then I added this.
This was like a modification since
we started collecting
onboarding fees and setup fees.
So just to kind of expand on what
we discussed in the last video,
I add this note in our email
before going into what needs to
happen next.
I say important note,
we're not able to begin working on
this project until you receive
payment for the onboarding
invoice.
The invoice was sent to you via
Stripe to your email address.
If you're experiencing issues when
trying to pay the invoice, please
don't hesitate to contact us.
So it's basically saying, Hey,
we signed on, we did all this work
up to this point, but we can't do
anything else until that gets
paid.
And it was already sent to you.
If you have any issues trying to
find it or pay for it,
let us know we're here to help.
And that's really it.
So we're setting that,
uh, we're setting that expectation
that nothing's going to move
forward until the invoice is paid,
which is super important because
even when we're, so the reason we
added this modification
is because even when we started
charging setup fees, they wouldn't
be paid
as quickly as we would have liked
them to.
And we even ran into a scenario
where we signed a client
and we started doing all the work
because we're excited.
Anytime we sign a client, we're
excited.
Like we want to be on top of
things and we want to impress them
and build trust by
getting all this stuff done for
them as soon as possible.
Like a lot of agencies,
this is actually important to
mention our agency.
Um, we onboard, like as soon as a
client signs,
we could get their campaigns
launched within seven days.
And a lot of our competitors take
14 to 30 days
to launch campaigns.
So like right there, that's an
instant, um, selling point for us
is,
hey, like we're going to be really
quick to launch.
We're going to, as soon as you
sign,
we're going to hit the ground
running.
We have a very rigid process and
place to follow.
And we're going to get campaigns
launched within a week, which is
way quicker and sooner than any
other agency would be able to do
that, uh, that you might be
considering working with.
And it's true.
And again, it's one of the biggest
reasons why we have such great
success retaining clients and
building trust with clients and
having great relationships with
clients right off the bat.
It's because we're, we're doing
our work very quickly.
And it's because we have these
processes
set up in order for that to
happen.
But anyways, back to the, to the
email.
Um, yeah, we, oh,
okay.
We had a client that signed and we
did all the work super quick up
front because we were
excited and they ended up not
paying the invoice and like a week
or two went on and we just didn't
hear from them.
They didn't pay the invoice and
that we literally just never heard
back from this
person.
So they literally entered into a
legal agreement.
They signed the service agreement,
but just after that ghosted us.
So that's why it's important to
say like you're charging an
onboarding fee and a setup fee to
get compensated for all the work
that you're going to be doing
before campaigns are even started.
And in, you know, the 90 days that
you're going to be working
on this relationship or 30 days or
whatever you decided on in the
last video,
so just make sure you collect that
payment.
Um, and it's a very fair standard
to set.
Like
we've never had anyone say, oh, we
work on this.
I'll pay it later.
Like no one would ever say that.
Like it's a very fair standard to
set.
Uh, just be sure to be clear about
it and set that standard.
So that's the important note.
Um, and then we go right into the
task for them to get started.
So this is
also super important.
Like psychology.
If you keep your client busy,
you're setting a great.
So
you want to engage the client.
You want to involve the client as
much as possible in the working
relationship.
Obviously they hired you to save
them time.
And so that a lot of this can be
done
without their input.
But at the same time, in order for
you to have a successful
relationship
with the client, they have to feel
like they're involved.
They have to feel like they're
playing a
role in the process.
And the way we can do that is just
by giving them actual work to do
and actual
work that we can use and benefit
from.
So we could get them better
results and just make everything
better is, is really the way to
say it.
So we want to involve the clients
day one of the working
relationship.
As soon as they sign, we want to
start giving them homework, just
like we're doing
with you here in this program.
Like as soon as you signed on,
we're giving you homework.
You got to get on these calls.
You got to watch these videos.
Like we're giving you tasks
that we need you to accomplish.
And that's what you want to do
with your clients.
Now that they signed
on and agreed to work with you,
here's what they need to do to
make this a smashing success.
And
obviously it has to be reasonable.
And we'll explain why each of
these is reasonable and why you
should
have something similar with your
agency.
So the four tasks we give them.
The first is to fill out our
onboarding form.
So we just call it like something
fancy, new client onboarding form
by clicking here.
And then the email will include a
link to our onboarding form, which
is just a simple Google
form.
So you could use type form.
You could use a form on your
website, or you could just use
Google
forms like we do.
It's really simple.
And I have a whole video
explaining our onboarding form and
how
to come up with an onboarding form
of your own.
It's just what questions or what
answers do you need
to know or to have so that you can
go about doing everything else you
have to do
to work on their campaigns or
their project.
So that's the first thing.
So an onboarding form is
super important.
You got to collect an onboarding
form because there's lots of
information that you
and your team are going to need to
operate off of that obviously you
don't have access to yet just from
the sales call in the contract
that they signed.
So that's the first step.
The second step is you
want to get on an onboarding call.
So we call this the onboarding
zoom call.
So you want them to schedule
an onboarding call.
And we could use Calendly, which
we use for our sales process to
actually coordinate
the scheduling of those onboarding
calls to make things really easy
for both you and for the client.
Again, another way to look
professional.
So we send this link in our email
and it just says KnowledgeX
new client onboarding call.
And basically they could see when
I'm available and when the entire
team is
available to get on an onboarding
call.
And all we ask is for their name
and email.
And then we also
ask if they completed the
onboarding form, because what
started to happen sometimes is
they would book an
onboarding call.
But by the time the onboarding
call happened, they didn't yet
fill out the onboarding form,
which makes the onboarding call
pointless.
So again, we'll have videos
specifically talking about
the onboarding form in the
onboarding call and why it's
important to have the onboarding
form responses
before getting on the onboarding
call.
But that's like the process we
use.
So that's the second thing
we ask for.
So they filled out a form, they
booked the call with us.
And the onboarding call is great
because it's basically them
getting a chance to meet the
entire team behind the project.
And those calls
are usually like the easiest way
to build trust because you have
some face to face time on a
zoom call.
You can answer all their questions
and you're just spending time with
the client.
And that's why going back to the
last video, it's important to
charge a setup fee because there's
real time that you're committing
early on to this relationship
before the campaigns are even
launched.
And you want to be compensated for
that time investment, right?
You want to protect
your time as a business owner.
It's one of the most important
things to train yourself to do.
And then the last two tasks for
them involve, again, Slack and
Trello, like the two most
important tools for us to manage
our work and relationship.
So the first one is Slack.
So we
give them a link to join our Slack
workspace.
So when you set up a workspace in
Slack, you'll have
like a unique link that you can
send to invite people to your
workspace.
And then once they're in your
workspace, you could add them to
the specific channels that you set
up.
We use Slack for
everything.
We even have an announcements
channel in our Slack, similar to
like we have in our Slack
workspace for the program where
all the clients are in that, in
that announcements channel.
Also,
just to take a step back, I know
there's going to be another video
on, on how to use Slack for your
agency, but just pay attention to
how Slack is set up for this
program specifically.
We have an announcements
channel, which is basically like
company-wide announcements or
program-wide announcements in
our scenario.
So have something like that.
We have a general chat channel,
which actually isn't really
applicable to this because you
don't want your clients chatting
amongst themselves in most
scenarios.
So that you could probably do away
with.
But just really pay attention to
the two things,
the announcements channel, which
is like company-wide
announcements, and then also
each of us having our own private
channel.
That's basically how you set up a
channel or a workspace for
your agency and for your clients
is you'll have announcements which
everyone has access to.
So you could send any relevant
updates for your company that'll
be sent to all people involved
or all the clients involved in or
working with your company.
And then you could also on a
lower,
on a more specific level, have a
channel that's private and only
includes the client and anyone
from their team.
And then everyone from your team
that's working on that client's
project.
So pay attention to the way we set
these things up because there's
intention behind it to start to
train you guys to think in this
way and then in this framework.
So that's the third thing.
We send them the link so they
could join the Slack workspace.
And Slack is where they could
start communicating with us.
So once they join there, we'll
send like
a message saying, "Hey, welcome.
Thanks for being here." And we'll
just kind of kick off the
conversation
and give them a warm welcome
there.
And then the Trello project
management board, which you're
seeing
here.
So basically that's why I copied
the link because every board has a
unique link.
And so I just
basically copied it into the email
and had that as a fourth step,
which is to join the project
management board on Trello.
So the client will join it and
they'll just see exactly what
we're seeing
here.
And for the most part, they'll be
super overwhelmed.
But what I say, I give them some
guidance here in the email, which
kind of helps.
So first, after I go through all
the steps that they
need to do to get properly
onboarded or fully onboarded, I
say, "That's all for now.
I'm excited to formally
welcome you as a client.
I speak on behalf of my entire
team when I say we're grateful for
the
opportunity to work with you."
Enthusiastically, Andre.
So that's the onboarding email.
Again,
this has worked extremely well.
And we try to send this to our
clients that sign.
The timeline for this
is, excuse me, we try to send this
out to clients the same day that
they signed the contract.
So we want
to have a really quick turnaround
time.
We almost want them to think it's
an automated email for how
fast it's sent since when they've
signed the contract.
But then they go in the email and
they're
like, "Oh, no way.
This can't be automated." Because
there's so many custom things that
are set up here,
like the Slack workspace and the
Trello board being specifically
customized to their company.
So anyways,
it's not an automated email.
There's probably ways to automate
this, but I manually send this
because
I enjoy the onboarding process and
the clients also really value it.
So our onboarding process,
again, out of all the things we do
at our agency gets complimented
more than anything else.
So that's the whole email.
So I include a PS because there's
a lot of information here and
a lot of our clients aren't
familiar with Slack or they're not
familiar with Trello or they're
not
familiar with Google Forms or
Calendly.
So we want to give them some
guidance.
Obviously,
they could respond to this email
with questions.
But in a PS, I just kind of give
them like a starting
point.
So I say, "When you join the Slack
workspace, please read the pinned
messages in the announcements
channel." So that's the first
thing.
When they join Slack, I'm like,
just basically catch up to all the
recent announcements we've put out
to our client
base.
So you can see where we're
currently at as a company and if
there are any important updates
that we've shared recently that
might be applicable to your
working relationship with us and
you might
even have questions on.
And then I also say, "When you
join the Trello board, please
review
the first few videos in the
educational resources column." So
I have this column here in Trello
called
Educational Resources and
basically I just recorded videos
to help the client onboard
themselves.
So I have a video on how to use
the Trello board and I literally
just recorded a Loom video
saying, "Hey, thanks so much for
being here.
This is our Trello board.
This is what it's used for.
Here's what every single card is
meeting and what you might want to
use them for." So I have a video
explaining Trello and then I have
a video explaining Slack.
That way they know exactly how to
use Trello and
they know exactly how to use Slack
because of the videos that I
recorded for them.
So what I would
recommend is, yeah, you need SOPs
internally so your team knows what
to do, but also consider SOPs for
your clients so that they know
what to do and they get the proper
guidance because that's always
forgotten
about from my experience.
People forget about the clients
and they just assume that the
client knows
everything.
But if the client's confused, it's
going to lead to doubt.
It's going to lead to more
uncertainty.
It's going to lead to more doubt
and it's going to spoil the
relationship from the very
beginning,
which is you never want to do
that.
So how do you flip the script
there and ensure that the
relationship goes well and ensure
that there's confidence instilled
is by setting up a process
like this.
So that's the next step in the
to-do list.
So I drag that over here.
And now those are
the completed tasks.
And then in the to-do list, the
next few things are for the
client.
So they have
to fill out the onboarding form.
So we'd move that over once they
fill out the onboarding form.
They have to book an onboarding
call.
So we'll move that over once they
book an onboarding call.
And then, yeah, everything else is
basically what we would work on at
our agency to get them onboarded.
So since we're a lead gen agency,
I'll just quickly run through some
of this stuff.
We'll set up a Google workspace
account for them.
We'll set up a Google Chrome user
for them.
We'll begin the email warmup
process for them.
We'll create a leads list for
them.
The client
has a task here real quick.
They only have a few more tasks
after the initial onboarding
process,
which is to approve the leads
list.
That's all discussed on the
onboarding call itself,
which again, there's going to be a
separate video on.
So they'd approve the leads list.
We'd also craft the scripts for
the campaigns and they'd approve
the scripts as well.
Again,
this is all discussed on the
onboarding call.
We'll configure their Calendly
event because that's
what we use to schedule calls for
our clients and to track
everything in an automated way.
We'll set up Zapier workflows for
the client.
We'll set up their sky lead
account.
That's what we're currently using
to do our outreach.
And then we'll start the sky lead
sequences.
And then basically that's like the
last step.
And then the two last steps are
for the client,
just as a constant reminder to
review the educational resources,
because there's also
some good resources here on how to
optimize their LinkedIn profile.
Since we're doing lead generation,
that's what our agency does.
We want them to have the most
optimized website and LinkedIn
profile
possible because that helps us get
the best results.
And then we also have like a
project timeline here,
which just talks about what they
can expect now that they're an
onboarded client.
So again,
we want to like give them as much
guidance as possible.
So they know exactly what's the
deal.
Like, what can they expect?
What do they need to be doing?
What are we supposed to be doing?
And they could see all of that
here on the Trello board.
That's why Trello is so great,
because they have,
again, they have access to this
board so they could see, okay,
KnowledgeX still has all this
stuff to do.
And then they could come tomorrow
and say, oh, KnowledgeX just
completed a bunch of tasks, right?
And now it looks like we're
actually pretty close to having
campaigns started.
And all this will be discussed.
So like on the onboarding call,
the onboarding call is really
simple because all I do is I share
my screen and I just share what
you're
seeing here, the screen I'm
currently sharing, which is the
Trello board.
And it's just a logical way to
walk through exactly what they
need to do and what to expect.
So just to kind of backtrack, I'll
explain some of this stuff here.
So general resources,
you have a signed service
agreement.
And what you'll do is you'll
upload the actual PDF there.
So everyone has access to it.
And you'll also keep track of when
that contract was signed and when
the
first campaign was signed or
started.
So you know when to invoice them,
like what day of the month
to invoice them each month.
We have a link to the Slack
workspace.
So this sometimes happens when
we'll invite, obviously in the
onboarding email we send, there's
a link to join Slack, but
sometimes
the client will say, Hey, you
know, we just hired this other
person or my partner after seeing
how
this relationship has been going
wants to join the Slack.
So they always have a link to join
the Slack
workspace right on the Trello
board anytime they need to add
someone.
So that's, you know, convenient.
There's a Dropbox folder, which we
talked about.
And then we have credentials.
So basically we set
up a cold email account.
We ask for the LinkedIn account
credentials through their
onboarding form.
We set up a Skylite account and
then we ask for their Calendly
credentials through the onboarding
form.
And then if they don't have it,
we'll set it up.
But basically the credentials are
all there.
And the clients especially love
this because it's transparency.
We're giving them credentials
to all the different tools we're
using to perform our services.
So even though the client will
probably never log into the cold
email account or never log into
Skylite, they at least have access
and they know they have access,
which gives them peace of mind to
say, Hey, we're not doing anything
fishy.
Like everything we're doing is
transparent and right there in
front of you to review, ask
questions
about, give feedback on, and
clients really love that about our
process.
So I'd recommend, you know,
implementing something similar if
that's something you want to do.
And then, so we already talked
about educational resources
basically being just SOPs for the
actual client on what to do now
that
they're our client and then the
to-do list and completed tasks.
So the last thing is campaign
resources.
This again is super specific to
our agency.
Our agency is a lead generation
agency where
we're scheduling calls for our
client.
So campaign resources could be
whatever makes sense for you
depending on the services you're
offering.
But that first card and another
card down here could
be the same for you.
So the first one is client
onboarding form responses.
So as soon as you get
that onboarding form filled out by
the client, whether it be through
Google forms or type form or
something
you have on your website, you want
to have the onboarding form
responses available here.
The
reason I like using Google forms
is because I could download it as
a PDF and just upload it here to
this card, which makes it really
easy for everyone to refer back to
the questions and answers that the
client filled out.
And our onboarding form responses,
again, there's going to be another
video on this, explaining it
further.
But our onboarding form responses,
we always refer back to those
because there's
all the information we'll ever
need to know to perform our
services.
So that's why it's like at the
very
top.
And then there's another card down
here called any additional
resources.
So we use this card like
this is for the client.
Anytime they have, uh, like case
studies or new information that
they want us
to include, um, in, in like their
campaigns or use to perform our
services.
Cause obviously when they
fill up that onboarding form,
they're still writing their
business.
So they might create a new case
study
or get a new video testimonial
from a client, something that
might help us to get better
results
with our services.
That's what this card is for.
If they have like a customer list,
they want to exclude whatever it
might be, any additional
resources, really
self-explainable.
It's helpful to have both these,
uh, like cards or places to have
both of these,
the onboarding form responses, and
then a card for the client to
continue to provide you with any
additional resources.
And again, this card you'll
explain to the client on the
onboarding call
what it's used for.
So they know like, Oh, I have
this, this testimonial.
Should I email it to
them?
Should I send it to Slack?
No, you should upload it to this
card here in Trello.
Okay.
Um, so it's just training the
client on how to be an active
participant in the working
relationship.
Other than that, we have a leads
list tracker spreadsheet.
So that's like, again,
specific to our services.
And then we have our scripts for
our campaigns.
So the client at any
time can access the leads list and
they could see what the scripts
are that we're sending.
And again,
for transparency purposes, they
love this.
Like they get to see everything
that we're using and
everything that we're doing.
Like there's nothing happening
behind the scenes that that
they're not
aware of and that they didn't sign
off on, or they're not okay with.
Um, other than that,
we have a sales appointment
feedback form.
So basically again, our service is
lead generation
and we're getting clients on
calls, uh, or on sales calls.
So we collect feedback after every
sales call.
And we just have that, uh, as a
card here in Trello.
And again, with like a lot of the
things we do, we have the form
here in Google, and I'll just open
this in case you're interested in
seeing, because I think having a
feedback loop, regardless of the
agency you're running is
important.
So we have a feedback loop with
our clients.
Every time they get on a sales
appointment,
they fill out this form.
They tell us their email, they
tell us the name of the prospect
they're
providing feedback on.
We ask if the client or the
prospect showed up, we ask them to
score the
quality of the appointment with
the prospect, and then tell us the
detailed reasoning for the score
and anything else we might need to
know to make improvements.
So even though you don't run,
or you might not run elite
generation agency or a
pay-per-call agency like I do,
use something similar where you
could create a feedback loop
behind, uh, a feedback loop
between
you and your client so that they
can be an active participant in
the relationship.
Otherwise,
they're going to feel left out.
This has been one of the best
things we ever implemented
because we're not just so that
they could feel involved, but
because we actually value our
client's
feedback.
They could tell us whether or not
a sales appointment is valuable
and we can learn from
that and adjust our targeting or
just our scripting or whatever, or
our qualification process like
this
is valuable feedback.
So again, a reoccurring theme here
is that the clients, if you can
get them to be
an active participant in the
working relationship, the chances
that you have success with that
client
skyrockets, I promise you.
I've seen it happen time and time
again.
We've had clients that have
so much potential and we, we
showcase that potential and we
show it to the client and they're
just not
engaging.
They're not involved.
They're not available for
questions.
They're not available to get on a
quick
call.
They're not filling out the
feedback form.
Those relationships don't last.
They just don't
last.
That's the reality of it.
So by putting these systems in
place day one, right after someone
signs
your service agreement, you're
putting good standards in place
and expectations in place that
will carry
throughout the relationship.
And I already admitted, we've had
clients that just aren't active.
And we do all
this stuff the same way we do with
any other client that we sign on
and they're still not active for
whatever reason.
So it's not a hundred percent
success rate.
We can't always control other
people,
but this is everything we can do
in our control to help the
situation, at least from my
understanding.
Oh, and just to touch back on
this, we have the feedback form.
And then again, I have a loom
video.
So loom is super important to, as
an agency, because you could just
record SOPs.
So I have an SOP here where I'm
recording myself explaining the
feedback form so that they know,
like, what is this actually used
for?
Why does it matter?
Why should they invest their time
into filling out the feedback form
every single day or anytime they
get on a sales call?
Because
it's still, it's a time investment
for them.
So I'm explaining how it's used
and why it's important
and making sure that there's no
questions or that all their
questions are answered more
specifically.
So I think I covered everything
here in this video.
And man, I gotta, I gotta be
careful.
I've been doing
videos for this program and a lot
of them are going like close to an
hour on end without stopping and
And I might lose my voice.
So I gotta be really careful, uh,
with this stuff.
But anyways,
with all that being said, just to
recap, it's again, so important to
properly communicate with
your clients and to also set
expectations and answer any
questions that are looming in
their
brain as soon as they sign the
contract.
Once they sign the contract, that
is like basically the race
begins.
You, you hit start.
You're the game started.
You're in.
That's it.
It's go time.
And once they sign the contract,
you want to have systems and
processes in place to follow
without
question.
Like mindlessly, anyone can follow
this.
It's like an instruction manual
where you go into
Trello or you go into Notion and
you copy a project management
board and you know exactly the
steps
that have to take place to get
this client signed.
And basically the steps that we
took was
setting up a Trello board, getting
the signed service agreement
uploaded to Trello, um, saying
what,
when the signed service agreement
was signed and including the date
in that card, sending an invoice,
waiting for the client to pay the
invoice, setting up the Trello
board, inviting all the people
that
need to be invited to the Trello
board, setting up a Dropbox
folder, setting up Slack channels,
uh,
adding different things to some of
our internal processes that aren't
really worth explaining because
again, it's, it's very, very
specific to the way we do our
business.
But again, like think in terms of
what do I have to do that is
similar to what KnowledgeX is
doing here?
What do I have to do that's
similar to what KnowledgeX is
doing here?
Like, do I have to assign someone
to this account?
Do I have a project manager?
Do I have an account manager?
Do I have inbox managers that I
have to
assign to new clients?
If so, replace what you're doing
with what we're saying here.
Um, and then
send an onboarding for email.
And that onboarding email is,
should be sent again, the same
day,
for sure, the same day that the
client signs the contract so that
they get the sense it's automated
for how fast the turnaround is.
And if you do it like that, and
you include all this information
that
you're seeing here, you let them
know that you can't start until
the setup fees paid.
You let them know
all the steps that you need them
to take to make this relationship
a smashing success.
I guarantee you,
if you start here with these
processes, not only is your agency
going to run a lot more smoothly
and
be a lot more organized, but your
clients are really going to see it
and appreciate it and be retained
a
lot longer because of it.
It's just really simple stuff,
guys.
It's, it's, it's also necessary.
Like, I would rather have this in
place than running an agency where
I sign a client and I
just am kind of going off of my
memory of, Oh, what do I do now?
Because even for you, like,
this is serving you as much as it
is the client.
Like, what do you do when a new
client signed?
Right?
Like, it's not always an easy
answer.
And sometimes you'll forget, but
if you have it all
documented, this is like creating
an SOP.
And also the best thing you could
ever do for client
retention all in one video.
Like this could be the most
valuable video that I create in
this entire
program.
And I hope you agree, or at least
we'll consider it because I think
this is like,
again, just from our experience,
we get complimented on this stuff
more than anything else in our
agency.
And it's consistent and it's
really meaningful compliments.
Like, wow.
And from big companies,
like fortune 500 companies saying,
wow, like we really need to brush
up our onboarding process.
This is great.
Or wow.
You give me a bunch of ideas on
how I can make my onboarding
process or my
business run a lot smoother or
more professionally.
So I'm, we just gave you the, the,
we just gave you
it all.
I just showed you exactly how we
get those compliments.
And again, the biggest thing that
what I'll end this video with is
make it unique to your business.
Copying everything you're seeing
here is not going to do you any
good.
It might in the short term, it
might look good for a little
while, but like with anything
that's copied without a complete
and full understanding of
the reasonings behind it and the
foundations and why it actually
works.
If you can't answer those
questions and answer why, why,
why, how is this unique?
How is this unique?
Your business, your agency, it's
going to crumble.
It's going to not be sustainable.
So again,
by actually investing the time,
actually doing things with your
unique spin, come on, like that's
all it
takes.
It's really that simple.
And you'll have a sustainable
skillset and a sustainable
business.
And again, I want you not only to
just scale your agency to where
you want to scale it,
but throughout this process, one
of my proudest achievements.
And one thing I'm super excited
about is I'm 21 years old.
I'm not even a year into my agency
business.
And even though the agency
business is super successful, I
know that everything that I've
learned from building this agency,
if this agency goes to zero
tomorrow, I have all the skill
sets and the know how to basically
do it all
over again or start another
business or have success somewhere
else.
And I hope that after you go
through
this program, regardless of where
your agency is, obviously our one
goal is to get you to where you
want it to be and where you want
to get it to.
But in addition to that, I want
you to feel super
confident knowing that if your
agency goes to zero or for
whatever reason you want to stop
doing your
agency, you have the skill sets
and the know how and the
foundation to build on great new
businesses.
And that's really it.
So thank you so much for taking
the time to watch this video all
the way through.
I know a lot of this stuff is
super long.
And for a lot of you, this might
just be basic and repeating
what you already have set up or
what you already know.
So if you, if that's you and you,
you hung on
until the very end, I really do
appreciate it.
And yeah, I'm looking forward to
hearing your feedback
on this one because man, my voice
is like fading away.
I don't know if you noticed
towards the end
of the video, but it's really
starting to fade.
So I'm going to hang up now and
just wait to hear
feedback from you guys and any
questions that you might have
looking forward to them and happy
to
help answer them either through
Slack or on the next coaching
call.