What's going on guys Andre Hakel
Jr.
here from client Ascension and in
this video I'm gonna walk
through how to conduct a case
study interview so if you've made
it to this point congrats it means
that you've generating meaningful
results for one or some or all of
your clients and that's a huge
win that you should be extremely
proud of and excited about and so
now not only did you just
capture a win for that client but
you want to make sure that it's
properly documented and that you
can
cash in on the amazing work that
you've done so that you can do
amazing work for even more people
and so the three objectives just
to start us off of why you should
conduct a case study interview
a lot of people don't think about
a case study interview as a
mechanism for retention but I see
two out of the three objectives
working towards retention and in
one of them working towards new
sales so the first objective is to
draw attention to the actual
client and make them feel good
about
their success now what that will
do is help retain that client so
you've already turned them into a
case study which means you've
gotten them meaningful results
which means they should retain
anyways but
doubling down and getting them on
a case study interview where
you're hyping them up in front
of your entire audience is going
to double down on that draw
attention to them make them feel
good
and retain them even longer the
second objective you should have
is to help other clients in your
business learn from this client's
success right because not every
single client you work with will
get the
same results or as meaningful or
as successful results as this
client you're choosing to do a
case study interview with
and so by interviewing your
successful clients you can share
those interviews with your less
successful
clients and show them that yeah
results like this are possible
just follow what this guy is doing
and what
this guy said about our services
and either stick it out because
it'll eventually work or apply the
same
strategies and concepts it's more
applicable I would say to a
coaching program like with client
attention some students
you can get great results but then
I'll send them one of our case
study interviews and they'll learn
from another
student in here that talks about
the keys to their success with
getting results in our program and
so it can
work to retain your other clients
because now they're building the
belief that your service can
actually work
for them even if it hasn't worked
up to this point and then the
third is a driver for new sales
which is to encourage
process prospects to become
clients and the way you do that is
by showing them that your services
produce
meaningful and awesome results for
other people's businesses and
other people who are like them and
so
i'm just going to go through the
before the case study interview
the after during the case study
interview and
the after the case study interview
so i'll break this down into three
sections so before your case study
interview
obviously you just have to ask
this is the part that most people
overthink like it's really really
simple
all you do is ideally after a big
win you reach out to the guy and
say well huge congrats on the
recent
success and you should be more
specific and personalized with
this like huge success on signing
a new
client or huge success on passing
this big milestone or huge success
or congrats on achieving your
wildly
important goal in the program i'd
love to feature you on my youtube
channel for a client spotlight
interview like i've done for
however many other clients let me
know if you'd be interested and we
can schedule a day and time for
the interview so something along
these lines don't overthink it
this
works for me every single time
nobody ever turns down the
opportunity to be featured on my
youtube channel
and if you're thinking well my
youtube channel is not like
andre's well my youtube channel is
not even
that big i don't even i barely
have a thousand subscribers i
don't get a ton of views these
videos are
not um gonna make anyone famous
but just the sound of being
featured on someone's youtube
channel
especially someone that was able
to produce meaningful business
results for them is an enticing
offer uh
right away and so that's all you
have to do don't try to think of
like ways to to persuade people to
to do
this like simply ask there's no
need to overthink this there's no
need to send out starbucks gift
cards
for them spending their time with
you on an interview you are the
prize right remember that david
jacob the sales coach and client
ascension probably already
ingrained this into your brain at
this
point but you are the prize right
you uh hosting someone on your
youtube channel is a huge win and
a huge value add for them plus
you've already gotten them amazing
results and so they kind of owe
you one
right and so uh ask right and
again ideally after a big win
timing here is super important if
a client is
complaining or it's not going very
well their campaigns it's not the
right time to ask so be patient as
well
you don't need to do a case study
interview with every single client
right away there's always the
right time and place for it the
next thing here is to craft a
unique angle so the the the thing
i see
people miss all the time with
their case studies is it just
sounds robotic hey what revenue
did you start
with okay um what revenue are you
now at thanks to my services okay
end interview and it's the most
boring
video i've ever seen there's no
story to it and like sure like the
revenue and the results are
impressive and you're making a
decent point there but stories are
what sell people relate to other
people's stories right if you look
at all the client ascension case
study interviews the revenue
numbers
are pretty much the same across
the board it's like they started
at 0k or 3k or 5k a month and they
got to
30k or 50k a month cool but it's
the stories that sell because all
your prospects have a unique story
that they're telling themselves
about themselves and if they can
relate to someone else in the
program
that had a similar story or a
unique situation like they did
then it's just going to help them
to
relate to someone that was in your
program and got results which is
going to help them believe that
they too can get results with your
program and so a couple of
examples from right within client
attention is master teffin so the
unique angle we use with max is
that he's running his business
while
still being a college student and
so this interview is the one we
send to people that come on our
calls
and say hey they don't have time
well hey max is a college student
and he's managing a full course
load
while also scaling his email uh
e-commerce email marketing agency
what's your excuse or even to
existing
college students that come through
our funnel we can point to this
specific example or canaan
who's from lebanon right that many
would consider their rural country
or a country that's suffering
during an economic crisis if he
could make it from lebanon what if
someone else in lebanon is
thinking
hey like i'd love to join but i
don't think it would make sense
for someone from lebanon well we
have
now a case study and a story of
someone who joined from lebanon or
someone who's a lot younger like
rafael who joined at only 17 years
old and is already a case study
for client ascension what
if we have a younger prospect
that's feeling a little unsure
that he might be the only younger
person in the community and that
younger people in the community
don't succeed well that's not true
or adam who started at zero
dollars with his agency right what
if someone wants to join client
ascension but their limiting
belief is that they don't have a
business yet and they haven't
gotten it
off the ground well we have
someone that started at literally
zero or someone that's looking for
much more results than just adding
10k profit to their agency well we
have an example of matt larson
who scaled his agency to 900 000 a
month and had a huge exit so if
someone wants to exit their
business
we now have a story for those
specific prospects that they can
relate to and get them in or
someone
like erwin who signed whale
clients like grant cardone and ed
mylett or lucas who joined the
program and
then eventually became a coach in
the program and so there's so many
unique stories or and unique
angles
for every single case study
interview that i do and that
should all be prepared and thought
through
before you actually do the case
study interview that's that way
you can like prepare and craft the
questions and craft the opener and
the intro and all that sort of
stuff and so that's the the before
a lot of work happens before right
you have to prepare but during is
is really simple so i use a
tool called riverside uh dot fm to
actually record my podcast uh or
sorry my case study interviews i i
really just treat them like a
podcast honestly um this tool is
super simple to use there's
another
video on client ascension that
walks you through how to use it
and set it up but it's dead simple
it's really similar to zoom um so
once you create the recording
it'll create a link for you to
send to
them the reason i like riverside
is because it records in 4k so
your videos look super crisp
on youtube where if you do this on
like zoom or google meets it's
gonna look like and so uh pay for
riverside if you're gonna do um if
you're gonna do these case study
interviews it's it's very much
worth
it um and then once you actually
do the interview like ask
questions that make it easy for
them to tell
their journey right again or tell
their story is probably um the
better the better uh we're here
but journey is important too
because the journey through your
program is is the story you want
them to tell you don't want them
to tell their life story that has
nothing to do with you
or their business or the services
that you perform and so the
questions that i usually like to
go to
are in this order right you'll
start to see like the the trend in
the timeline here is like who are
you
and what do you do for work so
that the audience understands who
we're speaking with how did you
hear about my company or services
so i frame this as how do you hear
about client ascension and i
always get interesting answers to
this some guy told me he heard
about it from his college
professor
another guy told me about how he
ran into christian in the men's
locker room at his gym and heard
about client ascension that way
and so there's always interesting
stories some people heard about
it just through uh one of daniel's
youtube rants and so this is
always a fun question to ask um
and
then what were you struggling with
before signing up for our services
what was your business like
and don't overload this question
with really anything else figure
out what they were struggling with
before they signed up and how they
described their business a lot of
times you'll hear pain points
that are similar to the pain
points your current prospects have
such as i was spending too much
time the business was a pain um i
couldn't generate leads there was
no consistency my team
wasn't loyal i was paying people
too much i wasn't getting paid
enough um i was relying on
outdated
lead methods i was spending too
much on ads um i had a way too low
of a close rate so they'll tell
you all the pain points that your
uh target market currently shares
as well so this is a gold mine
of a question and a pro tip for
this one is try to get them to
share specific revenue numbers um
any specifics here is is key but
again like you're weaving this
into a story you're not right out
of
the gates being like hey what's
your revenue before you join
what's your revenue after again
you don't
want to make this robotic you want
to make it into more of like a
podcast style um so try to get
specific
revenue numbers of what they're
struggling with and where their
business was at um maybe they
started
at zero or they were doing 3k but
the 3k felt like they were doing
the effort of doing 30k while only
making 3k right like try to get
that out of them and the more
open-ended you leave the questions
the
better uh chance you get towards
that um and you can even say
before the interview just hey when
i ask
you the question of like what
you're struggling with or what was
business like before i'd really
appreciate you share specific
revenue numbers and same thing for
um what they achieved later on
but the next question here is why
did you decide it was time to sign
up for my services this will help
people that are on the fence about
whether or not they should use
your services make a buying
decision
because maybe they can relate like
they're just sick of whatever
their current circumstances are
and
they decided it was ready um or
who knows what else but ask them
why did they decide in that moment
in
time to sign up for the services
um especially if they heard about
the services even before uh they
signed up right a lot of people
heard about client ascension a
year ago and then signed up a year
later and so why did they wait all
that time that's going to help
people in your pipeline to make
faster
purchasing decisions which is what
you want right um how did my
services help you solve what
you're
struggling with right so this ties
into this question it's like okay
you're struggling with it you
joined
why did you decide to join and
then how did my services help you
solve that pain point um what
have your business results been
like since joining since joining
what are some wins or milestones
you've
achieved um so these three
questions are just three different
ways to ask like how your services
benefited their uh pre-existing
situation before working with you
and again the pro tip here is to
try
to get them to share specific
revenue numbers not everyone's
going to be open to sharing
revenue
numbers so at least try to get
them to share significant results
um like number of leads
generated or number of calls
booked and so on whatever is
applicable to the services you're
offering
um then we wrap it with uh what's
one piece of advice you have for
other clients to get the most out
of
our services again this is more
applicable to let's say a coaching
program but this this question i
think
holds value really for any type of
service offering um because it is
to be said like there are dream
clients that you're working with
and clients that are not so ideal
so what does an ideal client look
like and what do they do that
makes them ideal um and also
primed for getting the best
results working
with you and then what would you
say to someone considering working
with us again leave these
open-ended
um that way you're not like kind
of pushing them towards what to
say but letting them kind of come
to
the idea in their own words and so
those are really the questions i
ask um but also i'm not afraid to
go
off script like i want to show
genuine interest in the client's
story um their business what
they're
actually doing what the journey
looked like how they navigated
certain things and so like these
are the
core questions i always come back
to but if you watch any of my case
study interviews you'll hear
other questions as well that come
up as the interview is going on
and on so don't be afraid
to go off script and again like
don't make this robotic where
you're just reading off questions
like you
want to make it fun you want to
make it entertaining while still
being educational um and again the
best
example or way to think about this
is like making it like a mini
podcast right um that has
structure
to it obviously and intent and
objectives right like we talked
about here in the beginning
um and then the last thing is is
just in terms of like time uh try
to keep the recording anywhere
from 20 to 30 minutes you should
be able to get 20 minutes worth of
content from these i've seen case
study interviews that are like two
or three minutes or even five
minutes long it's like what are
you
doing like you're you're not
getting any story uh whatsoever
it's just focused on what was
revenue
when you started and what was
revenue after um i did my magic
and it's not as valuable as you
think
you you really want to tell the
story um so people can invest
their time into hearing you know
how
that story relates to their
current story or the story that
they're telling themselves and so
that's the during
and then the after is really as
simple as share with the client
the link to this again like the
strategy here is you want to post
this um on youtube right that's
kind of the main selling point as
to
like why someone would want to uh
get on and do this with you um you
want to post it to youtube and it
doesn't have to have a pretty
thumbnail it doesn't have to be
edited at all after you run it
through riverside
just upload it to youtube it could
be very low effort it does not
have to have any editing or
thumbnails to it just upload it to
youtube once it's uploaded to
youtube share it with your client
and have them share it with their
audience or anyone else they think
might benefit from hearing their
story and again like they're
incentivized to share that with as
many people as possible because to
them
it's an opportunity to show off
their success and the results they
got um thanks to your services and
or
your program and so share with
them to get maximum views um this
is also a great opportunity to
upsell
your client if it makes sense to
um obviously if the interview went
well and they're happy with how
it came out and they're sharing it
with people in their audience and
their friends and whatnot
that's a prime opportunity to
upsell that client and increase
their ltv so not even just retain
them
but increase their ltv um so this
is some a missed opportunity i see
a lot of the times
right i can't tell you how many
times i've gotten someone on a
client ascension case study
interview
and then upsold them into our
mastermind offer right um so make
sure to do this and then for your
own
uh social media strategy this is a
great post that should go on all
of your social medias
this is also an asset that should
exist forever in perpetuity and so
that should go to your website or
landing page or uh vsl
so if you're remaking your vsl be
sure to include it and then just
in general on your landing page or
on
your website add it um so that
you're just keeping track of all
the case studies you have over
time
you should also send it as an
email broadcast again to both
existing clients and to prospects
in your
pipeline again with existing
clients just showing them that
other people with your services
are getting
results and achieving um success
is going to encourage them to
continue on um even if results are
not as
great now and then obviously for
prospects they'll be able to see
that hey like you just helped
another
person out right case studies as
daniel points out in a lot of his
modules and trainings are one of
the
most powerful tools and assets to
um to uh sales and marketing right
the number of case studies you
collect are like in direct
proportion the number of new
clients you're probably going to
sign so you
want to make people in your funnel
and in your sales process aware of
these case studies right
because just recording the case
study does not accomplish all the
objectives it only accomplishes
one
um and then really after that make
a lot more money that's pretty it
this is pretty much it um the
objectives of before the during
and the after and if you want to
see this in action you can go to
my
playlist on youtube it's got uh 54
case study interviews um they're
all using and implementing the
exact
strategy that i just walked you
guys through and so like i
obviously implement this um i i
practice
what i preach i'm not just telling
you guys a theory like if you go
on my youtube channel like just in
the past um month literally just
in the past month i've done one
two three four five six seven
eight
nine ten case study interviews on
my youtube channel ten case study
interviews on my youtube channel
in the
last month and so i implement this
up i know it works i know it gets
views i know it also gets
conversions
right because those two things are
not the same um and daniel does
these as well not as often
um but when daniel does them
they're fire and so i highly
encourage you to check these out
as well
you'll see some recent ones in the
past three months there's been um
three really really good ones
um daniel's a little more reserved
in terms of like making sure that
the person he's interviewing
got insane results like how
chandler did three and a half
million dollars in one year with
cold email
um i like to just find the great
stories and and more than just the
results again get the story
out um because that's really what
sells and the sales team is giving
me this feedback uh as well
um and there's just so much you
could do with your case studies
you can create so many assets if
you go to
my uh twitter account um and just
look at my pin message like i'm
i'm repurposing my uh case study
interviews all the time um like
this one right here like the
biggest misconception about client
ascension is that you need to be
at least at 10k to join that's not
true am and join at 2k and scale
to
93k max join at 0 and scale to 50
max join at 5 and scale to 50k
these are all links to the case
study
interviews right so i use case
study interviews all over the
place we also have a school
community
which is like our lower ticket
product and of course like the
only reason we have a lower ticket
product
is to get people into our higher
ticket product and so in the
program we have a section for
client
ascension that goes over the
reasons you should join and then
all the success stories right
which just
link out to all of our youtube
videos and so these are assets
guys it's not just to be recorded
once
and then forgotten about it's like
to be repurposed in your school
communities and your low ticket
products
on all of your social media pages
on your website on your vsl um
literally everywhere uh after
you've
done the work already to create it
in the first place and then the
law of reciprocity this is the
thing
i'll end it with if someone asks
you to do a case study interview
for their services and you're
happy
with their service and the results
that they helped you to achieve um
say yes and and like i said here
maybe i'll be reaching out to you
soon uh to do a case study
interview but say yes i see people
all the
time that like would never do a
case study interview they've never
done um a testimonial for someone
else
even though other people have
provided them good services and
then they get mad when they do a
bunch
of outreach to their clients and
none of their clients are willing
to do it so the law of reciprocity
say yes more often to your
existing service providers when
they reach out to Kate uh reach
out for case
studies and when you reach out
when the time comes for you to
reach out um even if it's not to
them
specifically it's just the law of
reciprocity um more people will
say yes to you so if you say yes
to more people more people will
say yes to you this is a truth of
life it applies literally to
everything
and so uh take that part seriously
but anyways that's how to conduct
a case study interview
um i'm really excited to see more
case studies come out of uh client
ascension agency owners just
because i know you're all doing
great work already and now it's
just time to showcase that uh for
the
world to see and again if you've
made it to this video um you've
made it to the end of the video
like i appreciate your commitment
to to doing a case study interview
the right way and and also again
just want to congratulate you for
not just signing a client and
collecting the cash but also
delivering
on your promise um keep doing that
it'll serve you well it'll serve
your clients well
and it'll make the world a better
place much love guys thanks so
much for watching