What's up guys, today, we're going
to be talking about where you
should host N8n, should you
do self hosted on your own server?
Or should you go through the N8n
cloud?
So we're going to start
off by going through just the
basic pros and cons of both.
And then I'm going to show you if
you
choose to do self hosted, how to
set that up.
It's very simple, but let's run
through it.
So
let's look at self hosted, which
is the called the N8n community
edition.
There's zero software
costs aside from hosting it on the
server.
This offer is open source and
free, you can run an
unlimited number of workflows and
executions.
This is the key part here, the
only constraints you have
are your server hardware.
You've got full data and
infrastructure control yourself,
as long as you can
manage the server effectively.
As highly customizable, you can
add custom code nodes and API
integrations,
custom nodes are very, very
helpful.
People make their own N8n nodes
that you can install very easily
to give you access to other
platforms and features, having to
use direct API calls.
And it is much
lower in terms of cost.
You get a VPS from anywhere
between five to $20 or euro per
month.
And overall,
it tends to work out a lot
cheaper.
The cons, however, is that it does
require time to set up,
and it is a bit more technical
effort, although not much, as I
will show you how to do it very
simply.
The hidden costs are mainly to the
hours installed, setting it up,
potential troubleshooting and
downtime.
It is missing enterprise features
or collaboration tools.
If you want to have multiple
people as part of a team using the
instance, much, much harder to do.
And some like audit logs, things
like that.
And there's no official support,
aside from the community forum,
compared to N8n Pro,
the cloud version where you do
have an official forum, where
people that are working on N8n
will
get back to you with information.
So the cloud version, it's fully
managed, it's essentially an
instance setup, you sign up, you
pay, and it is ready to go.
It is predictable pricing, it's
got different
plans you choose from, you know
how much you're going to pay every
single month.
For instance, if you
are self hosting, and one
automation has a ton of runs on
it, that can end up costing you
more money.
Whereas with the N8n plans, you'll
know exactly how many executions
and how many workflows you're
allowed to use and how much it's
going to cost.
It does have an enterprise plan
that allows team
collaboration and things like
that, although not something we're
going to be going into here.
And
it does have very reliable
support, you can contact them
directly.
And there is a paid forum where,
as I said, N8n developers will get
back to you.
It is much more expensive though.
So the starter plan
is 24 year a month for 2.5k
executions, it's about $26.
The pro is $50 to $60 for
10k executions and a more
workflows.
The enterprise is like way, way
more is available by a quote.
Starter gives you five workflows,
the pro gives you 15, the
enterprise is unlimited,
you do have less control in
general over your data
infrastructure setup and custom
features.
So we look at the pricing
comparison.
Again, we're looking at cost
estimate of a cell phones to one
anywhere from $5 to $20 a month
for your VPS, which is a virtual
private server.
The N8n starter cloud
is looking at 24 euro by $26 per
month, five workflows, 2.5k
executions and execution is the
number of times that our workflow
is run.
So you've got a total of 2500
runs.
This sounds like a lot,
but when you're testing out
something, or something, you know,
errors out and excuse a bunch of
times,
it can eat up pretty quickly.
And you've only got five workflows
and we are giving you guys a lot
more
than five workflows to use.
The pro cloud, if anywhere between
$50 to $65 is 15 workflows,
10,000 executions, and then
enterprise cloud is unlimited.
So we look at the feature
comparison.
Executions, self hosted, unlimited
clouds, cap by plan, active
workflows, self hosted, unlimited
cloud,
plans between 515 and unlimited on
the enterprise.
The number concurrent executions,
the self hosted is
server dependent, the cloud is 520
or 200.
Then enterprise tools, single sign
on environments,
get log streaming, they're only
available in self hosted
enterprise or cloud enterprise and
support
community only versus email such
SLA backed in paid.
So basically in the self hosted,
you've got the
community support, but in the paid
cloud, you've got email supporting
email and developers or their own
forum.
So when to choose which self
hosted is best.
If you want full control of
customization,
you can manage infrastructure
reliably, and you need unlimited
scale and lower ongoing costs.
I think
that is the biggest one and likely
something that you will need.
And then cloud is ideal.
If you prefer
convenience, and speed of setup
and no maintenance, you need team
collaboration, support and
reliability,
and you don't mind paying a bit
more for managed services.
I think the only real drawback is
the team
collaboration, you do have that on
the NN cloud, but not so much in
the self hosted.
A hybrid approach
you can take is you can prototype
your workflows in the cloud and
then transition the critical ones
to
self hosted to help with cost
savings.
So overall, that's what we're
looking at here.
My personal
opinion is you guys should do self
hosted.
It sounds complicated, but it's
really not.
And in the next
part of the video, I'm going to
walk you guys through exactly how
to set this up easily in the
cheapest way
possible.
So now we're going to go through a
few ways to set up N8N.
If we go to the official N8N
website,
which will be a link to every site
I'm going to in the description
below.
So it's N8N.io go to the
pricing page, you'll see here the
different options as we talked
about the difference between each
of these
already.
But when I click start free trial,
you simply fill out your
information here, and your free
trial will begin.
And then you'll be asked to put in
your card details in order to
continue paying for the
plan.
So then if we take a look at the
next option on my preferred one,
we're going to look at railway.
This is railway.com.
And it is very simple to set up
N8N here, you essentially pay $5
for your account,
and then you will only pay for the
usage you actually use in total
while running N8N on the server.
It is
usually using tons of resources,
no more than about $19 to $20 per
month.
But to get N8N set up,
it's very simple, you're going to
mouse over product and go to
templates.
When you scroll down,
one of the first thing you'll see
is here is N8N with workers, this
is what we want.
We click this,
we're going to click deploy now.
We just click deploy, as you can
see everything's ready to be
deployed, it's all good to go.
Click deploy.
And we'll watch as it actually
sets up the server here for us.
It's going to apply 101 changes.
This might take a little bit so I
might cut out some time in this
video.
But basically set it up to go and
it is now going to create a new
server with our N8N on it.
So you can see it's initializing
now.
Okay, so let's talk about two
minutes to fully set up, very,
very short amount of time.
And now when I click primary here,
which is when you're always going
to want to click,
you'll see we've got a link here.
And when I click this, it will
take me to my N8N instance,
where it allows me to go through
the onboarding process.
Just put in your details and
you're done.
That's N8N set up, good to go.
You will see your workflow screen.
The other option you have is
Hostinger, which offers a very
good VPS for N8N and is quite
cheap to run as well.
You're probably
going to want to go for the $6.99
a month plan.
When you set this up, it's very
simple process as
well, very similar to Railway.
You just simply click choose plan.
Now this is the way they do their
pricing.
You can either pay upfront for two
years,
one year or one month.
I see one month's about $10.
I would recommend doing daily auto
backup because
again, I will be giving you a
script that will copy your
workflows to GitHub or to Google
Drive,
but it's a good idea to have all
of your data backed up as well.
The auto backup is only $6 a
month,
probably worth it.
You'll select the location closest
to you and then you'll choose N8N.
Then you'll do continue.
You'll sign into your account.
Let's do it here with one of my
accounts.
You'll fill out your details.
You will pay for the server and
it'll be automatically set up for
you.
So it's a pretty similar process
for all of them.
That's why I think self-hosting is
the best way to
go.
And I think Railway is definitely
the best option to do it.
It's very secure.
It's very, very good uptime,
very easy to update.
If you ever want to update N8N,
which there are regular updates
rolled out,
you would literally just select
your primary again, select here
and click redeploy.
And it will pull
the latest version of N8N and
deploy it.
It takes maybe a minute or two for
it to update and you're
good to go again.
So I would definitely highly
suggest using Railway out of all
of them.
It is the
cheapest.
It is easy to run.
If I look at my usage and I have a
lot of usage on my N8N account,
as you can see, we're looking at a
total bill of $26 and that's me
running thousands of executions
across hundreds of workflows.
So definitely would highly suggest
you guys using Railway.
And if not,
if you want to just simple one
click N8N cloud on N8N.io is
probably the easiest way to get it
set up.
But this would be my, my
suggestion.
So hopefully this gives it up for
you guys.
And any problems
with this, feel free to reach out
to me and I will help you get
through this ASAP.
Peace.