What's up guys?
Lucas here, the head of AI at
Client Ascension.
In this video, I'm going to give
you guys a quick rundown of the
basics of N8N and kind of the core
workflow building blocks you guys
are going to use.
Now, just to be noted, this is not
an N8N course.
This is not, you know, something
super in-depth you're going to
have to get really, really good
at.
But you will have to learn how to
basically edit the N8N workflows
we're going to give you guys.
And the best way to do that is to
give you an understanding of how
the software works.
So I put together here some of the
kind of core blocks you're going
to be using as part of these
workflows.
I'm going to show you briefly how
they work and kind of how to edit
them.
So the first section we'll look at
here is triggers.
As you can see, I've got a few
added here.
We've got a total of seven added.
The first one is when clicking
execute workflow.
So basically what that means is
that when you click this big
execute workflow button, the
workflow is going to begin.
That's a pretty simple one.
This is what you want to use
mainly for testing your workflows
and making sure that everything is
working correctly.
Then we've got the schedule
trigger.
This means that the workflow will
run on a schedule.
You set the schedule how you want
it to and it will run at that time
every single day as long as your
N8N instance is open running.
On form submission, N8N is a
pretty powerful form builder and
you can build forms in N8N that
when they're submitted, it'll
begin the workflow.
This is very simple for client
onboardings and things like that
or if you want to fill out the
details of something just to kick
off an existing workflow, that's
the perfect way to use that.
A webhook basically means that
when the N8N instance gets
information from another app or
system.
So for instance, with something
like Zapier or if you're building
a front end to an app, that's when
you'd use a webhook.
When executed by another workflow.
This means that your N8N workflow
can start another N8N workflow
that's separate from it.
So say you had a large workflow
you wanted to break up into
multiple pieces.
You could have a trigger set that
when the other workflow finishes,
it executes the next workflow.
When chat message receives.
That means when you send a message
down here in the N8N chat here, it
will begin the workflow.
And then there's multiple app
related triggers.
So this one is a Google Sheets
trigger, but there is a ton.
If we hit the little plus button
over here and we look for
triggers, another trigger on app
events, you can see there's tons
here.
This one, essentially, I've set up
that when there's a new row
created in Google Sheets, the
workflow begins.
Now, when they begin, we want to
connect them to something else.
So say we wanted to get all of the
bases in our Airtable instance.
We would connect when clicking
execute workflow to get many
bases.
And then when we click this button
here, it will get all the bases in
Airtable.
Then say on a schedule, we want to
send a Slack message to remind us
of something.
Schedule trigger goes to Slack
message.
It will send a Slack message.
On form submission, we want to
store the data in Google Sheets.
On form submission, append or
update row in Sheet.
Now, there's tons of actions here.
I only put three in here.
But if we click this here and we
go to actions in an app, you can
see there is a huge amount to
choose from.
This is very similar to if you use
Zapier or anything like that.
It's just choosing what app you
want your workflow to interact
with.
So next, we have the
transformation section.
The transformation section refers
to how we transform data that
comes through.
The first one we have is called a
set node or a field node.
And essentially, this allows us to
set certain data and variables.
The best way, I think, to use this
is, for instance, if you have a
number of APIs as part of a
workflow.
You're connecting to a number of
services.
You will have a number of API
keys.
You might have, say, your Blotato
API key for connecting to Blotato
to schedule your social media.
You might have a Facebook API key.
There's a ton there.
But basically, in here, if you
double-click on this, you can add
a field.
And so I can name it, say, Apify
API.
And then here, I'll put my Apify
API key.
Now, then when we get later on
down to the HTTP node we need to
use to execute this, we don't
actually have to go and copy and
paste in the full API key.
We can just find it.
It'll be over here.
We can find the API key here and
just drag and drop it in.
It just makes it easy to manage
and organize things.
Then the merge node.
The merge node refers to taking
two different inputs.
So, say, you have one kind of
section of a flow that creates a
Google Doc and then one that
generates AI content.
You can merge them at the end to
combine the AI-generated content
into the Google Doc.
Aggregate basically takes multiple
inputs or items and puts them all
into one item.
So, if you were creating a list,
you had, say, an AI agent that was
creating, you know, or multiple AI
agents creating a big list of
information.
You can aggregate all that
information into one item at the
end that then, say, you might add
to, like, a Google Doc or
something.
And spit out does the opposite of
aggregate.
It basically takes multiple or
takes one item and then splits it
out into multiple.
So, if you, say, had a form that
had first name and last name as
one input, then you could split
those into two separate outputs.
You'd have two outputs that would
be the first name and the next one
would be the last name.
Logic is pretty simple.
If this is essentially just, you
know, if this is true, then this
happens, you know?
So, I click here.
If this value is equal to
whatever, then it's true.
And then you can change these.
So, these are very simply, like,
if it exists, if it doesn't exist,
if it's empty, not empty, it's
just a number of, you know, date
and time number.
This is basically just saying when
it should continue, when it should
not, you know?
So, say, for instance, we use this
for an error node.
If we, you know, do a scrape of a
website, if it returns
information, so if, you know, data
field is, you know, equal to true,
then continues.
If it's not, then it'll go to an
error node when it alerts in Slack
or something that it's not, not
working.
A switch is just rules.
So, essentially, if this value is
equal to this value, then this
happens.
It just is how you route this is
just determined by that.
So, you just basically can add
multiple routing rules.
If I add a few more here, you see,
there you go, 0, 1, 2.
So, I can say, you know, if the
name is equal to Brian, then it
goes to the Brian flow.
If the name is equal to Steven, it
goes to the Steven flow.
Things like that.
The wait node is exactly what it
sounds like.
It just pauses the workflow for a
set amount of time.
So, you will just set the time by
choosing the wait amount of time,
five seconds, and it will just
wait for five seconds.
This will be handy if you're
sending information to be
processed by something or waiting
for something to generate.
So, if you send the information to
an AI generator, you want to wait
until it's generated for a few
seconds,
and then it will, you know, say,
get that information and move it
on through the flow.
And filter just removes things we
don't want.
You know, if this value is equal
to this, then it removes it.
And finally, we have the AI
section.
So, we have an AI agent.
Now, the AI agent is very, very
powerful because what we can do
with this, if I choose to find
below,
is we can set not just a prompt,
the user message, which you are
probably used to,
going to ChatGPT and typing in,
you know, how do I do XYZ?
But we can also add a system
message.
And this basically tells the AI
what its role is.
This message will be sent to the
agent before the conversation
starts, so it will know how it
should act.
And this can be super useful for
giving an extra added information
for telling it the role that it's
going to be playing,
giving it rules around how it
should operate, things like that.
And then you can put your variable
information in here.
So, for instance, here you can
say, you know, you're an expert
YouTube script writer.
And you get a bunch of information
on writing YouTube scripts, the
format thing and all that sort of
stuff.
And then here you can say, I want
you to write a YouTube script for
this client.
And the variable will be the
client's name.
And then here's their research.
The variable will be all the
research document, all that sort
of stuff.
And then it will write basically a
perfect YouTube script.
A question and answer chain is
very similar.
Essentially, what this just does
is it allows you to tell it how
you want it to act and just ask
questions and answers.
It's more so for kind of, you
know, getting information from a
knowledge base or something like
that,
or giving a kind of, you know,
basic sort of retrieval of
information.
Down here, each of these needs a
chat model connected.
So you can connect, for instance,
a OpenAI chat model and Anthropic
chat model, which is Claude,
Google Gemini chat model.
My suggestion is that you use
OpenRouter.
OpenRouter is a service that
allows you to get access to
basically every single model out
there.
So from every company.
So whether that's a Claude,
whether it's Grok, whether it's
ChatGPT, Perplexity, any of them.
And there's a few free ones in
here as well that are actually
very good, such as DeepSeq.
So I think that using OpenAI gives
you access to everything.
That means you also only have to
set up one account as well.
You only have to set up your
OpenRouter account.
Get your details in here.
And then you're good to go.
So that's the basics of these
nodes.
They are not super complicated.
You probably really don't need to
know a lot of this stuff.
I just want to give you guys a
quick run through of the basics of
what these are and what they do.
So that if you are editing the
workflows later on and you come
across them, you're not completely
lost.
And you kind of know how they act.
Of course, we'll be going into
much more detail on each of the
workflows specifically and how to
edit them in the workflow videos
you'll find later on in the
course.
But this is a quick intro to N8N.
And hopefully this gives you an
idea of kind of how this works.
It's not that complicated.
It looks complicated when you
first start off.
But especially if you've used even
just Zapier, you can kind of see
the basics of how this sort of
operates.
We'll be over some more stuff
later on in this section, which is
just the enough to be dangerous
section to do with N8N.
Showing you kind of how these sort
of work and how to connect them
all together and when to use
certain nodes and, you know,
what's appropriate when it's not.
So keep moving on through the
course.
Watch the rest of this one and
keep at it.
If you have any questions, feel
free to reach out to me.
Hit me up and we will get you
sorted ASAP.
Thank you.
Peace.