So guys, Lucas here.
So in the last module, we went
over a little bit about triggers,
AI agents,
HTTP request nodes, and, you know,
sending files to platforms and
things like that.
So now we're going to go over
briefly, how do we deal with
errors in our workflow?
Because no
matter how good you make it, there
often will be times you still will
get the odd error here or
there.
So I'm going to show you how we
set this up.
First of all, we're going to look
at one of the
most likely nodes to error.
For instance, it's relatively
unlikely that a set node you've
tested
repeatedly is going to error out.
But it is definitely possible that
a AI agent might have an
error, right?
So how do we deal with that?
For instance, an example of why an
AI agent may have
an error, say you're using Claude
to generate your script or
something, and Claude's down, you
know,
the API is not available, then
also we're going to get an error.
So we're going to have to simulate
an
error here because everything's
currently working.
But I'm going to show you
basically how this
works.
So first of all, we're going to
double click on our AI agent here,
and then we're going to go to
settings.
And you'll see on error currently
set to stop the workflow.
So if there's an error, the
workflow just won't run.
Now, this is not ideal.
If you know, you are have a a
workflow like this, where
you know, we want to send messages
to a telegram in order to get a
response out, use me sending
messages and getting no response.
So what we do is we set this to
continue using error output.
So this
means that we will get a separate
error output that we can route
information to.
So now we've got a
success branch and an error
branch.
And we go down here, I'm going to
recreate an error.
You can see
just here, if we zoom in, we now
have success and error, right?
So let's disconnect this chat
model,
because that way, when we run this
again, we're going to get an error
no matter what, right?
So if I just
click run, you'll see, yep, we got
now here, this is green.
So the success one is green error
out.
So
what do we do next?
Next, we're going to want to
format our error message.
So to do that, we're just
going to choose a set node.
And we're just going to add a
name, or we're just going to call
it error.
Now we are, as you can see, this
is connected to the success one,
we don't want that connected
there,
we're going to connect it to the
error node.
So we connect error there.
We've named it error,
and we can see the error message
here, a chat model sub node must
be connected and enabled.
So let's add that as the value
here.
Now, we want to send this
somewhere, we want to get alerted
about this.
So let's just assume that we want
to get this alert in Slack, we
want a Slack message to
DM us and say, Hey, you know, this
is self working.
So we choose Slack, and we're
going to click send a
message.
Now, just for the purpose of this,
we're going to send a message to a
user, and we're just
going to pick me.
So we're going to type in Lucas,
and get a job.
There you go, there's me, Lucas,
right?
So we are going to run this to get
the error again.
Error branch there.
Going to here to set the field.
There is our output at chat model
sub node must be connected and
enabled.
Now over here, we're going
to write our message as an
expression.
So we're going to say error
detected.
And we need to know what
workflow this is in because this
could be in any workflow.
So we name it workflow.
And we're going
to do two curly brackets.
And if you actually scroll down
through here, you can see some of
the things
you can input in here.
So we're looking at metadata,
right?
And if we go down to workflow,
it's
information about the workflow.
And if we just put dot name, I've
named the workflow example.
So it's
going to name the workflow
example.
So all we did there again, I'll
just redo that again.
Curly brackets, two of them.
Scroll down until you get to
metadata, you'll find workflow.
Then we're
going to press a full stop and
name.
And that's how we get the name of
the workflow.
So now when we get
this error message, we'll know
it's in this particular workflow.
And then we'll just say error.
And we're
just going to drag from our edit
fields one over here, error.
And so now if we open this
expression,
you'll see what it looks like
error detected workflow example
error, a chart model sub node must
be
connected and enabled.
So now we know what the error is.
Now with the other ones, you do
the same thing,
you can essentially go in here.
And you can do on error continue
using error output.
And then you can
connect the error output to a set
node.
And we can do the same thing
again.
So we'll get wherever the error
comes from, we'll get it in here,
right?
So long.
And we'll get sent a message.
Now this is vital,
because you will be dealing with a
lot of complicated workflows we've
set up for you,
and we'll have the error nodes
built in.
But this is just an idea of how if
you're making your own
workflow, how you would set this
up to ensure that you are getting
alerted properly of any potential
issues with the workflow.
Do you should always run multiple
tests of every single workflow
that you
create or that you use, even the
ones that we give you, I want you
to make sure that you know you
modify them appropriately, and
then you test the hell out of them
to make sure that this working the
way
that works for your particular
operations and setup.
For instance, some of you may not
be using Slack,
you may be using, I don't know,
maybe you run everything off
Telegram or WhatsApp or something,
maybe use ClickUp, something like
that.
So there will be some mild
modification of the workflows
I'll be showing you guys later on
in the workflow setup modules.
And for that, I just want to make
sure that you know how to set up
any errors that may turn up if you
know you're using a separate
sort of setup that we make for you
guys.
But again, these will all be set
up already inside the
workflows we give you, there will
be error notifications created.
So you shouldn't have
to worry too much.
But yeah, hopefully that was
helpful.
And let's move on to the next
module.
See you guys the next one.
Peace.