So guys, Lucas here.
So today we'll be showing you how
to import N8M workflows into your
own N8M workspace.
This is very important for you
guys as part of this course,
because we've developed a
number of automations and
workflows to handle with your
operations and your fulfillment
for
your clients.
So this is going to be the key
thing you're going to be doing.
Now, there's a few ways to import
workflows, but I'm going to show
you just the easiest
one.
So this is one of the YouTube
creator workflows that we've
created.
This is a YouTube script writer
and first I'm going to download
this workflow.
To do that, I'm going to click
these three buttons up here and
just click download.
When I do that, you'll see here
I've downloaded a JSON file, a
JSON file.
Now when I want to import this
into a new N8M instance, I'll
click the plus button, workflow,
create in personal, or if I go
back to my personal one here and
click create workflow, it opens
a new workflow.
Now these ways to do it is just to
do import from file.
So we'll open the file selector,
double click your JSON file, and
there we go.
Now it's imported.
Now you will see a bunch of red
nodes.
And the reason for that is that
you have not created the accounts
for these.
So you'll have to double click and
you have to modify it, you have to
add your account or
maybe whoever you send the message
to.
And you'll also probably see it on
your, the AI agent chat models.
You'll have to modify these with
your correct accounts, et cetera,
and get it all set up.
Now we walk through, I had to do
that a little bit in one of the
previous modules, but just
to go over it again, just like I
did there.
Say for instance, it is the slack
notification, you'll double click
the node and you probably
won't have a credential here.
And so you'll do create new
credential.
And then you'll connect with
slack.
You just use a lot.
So you connect my account and then
it will bring you to log into your
slack workspace.
You'll do that.
And then it will have your account
in here.
I already have my account here.
So I'm good.
She was that one there and you'll
have to select you to send the
message to see it select from
the list again.
I can select, say you want to have
it in a particular, there's just
for now as a user, but we can do
it from a channel where you can
have like all the YouTube scripts
approved.
And I type in my name here, give
it a moment.
We've got a lot of slack users.
There's Lucas.
I select that.
And then now that's all set up and
good to go.
And you do this for any of the
ones that are showing up as red
again, like I said, as well,
your, your open router nodes will
probably not be connected properly
too.
So you'll double click this.
You will add a new open writer
account.
And do that by getting your API
key from the open writer website.
to do that, you just go to open
router, I'm going to sign in.
And now when I go to, uh, keys up
here, there we go.
There's my editing key, but you
create API key, it'll give you the
API key.
And then you just paste it in
there and you are done.
So I can leave this as well and
that's all you got to do.
So you have to just connect up any
of the accounts that are not
connected.
You have to connect up.
And after that, you're ready to go
and your workflow will be live.
You just make sure you always
click save.
The NNN does not automatically
save these when you make changes.
So after you make the changes,
click save.
This is very important.
I've lost a few workflows because
I've built them out, forgotten to
click save and left.
So make sure you do that.
If it's a workflow that's going to
be getting information from
somewhere else, for instance,
from a webhook or from, you know,
uh, triggered on a schedule or
anything like that, make sure
you have set it to active as well.
Uh, that way, uh, I'd say for on
form submission, anytime, when
you're finished with it, set it to
active so that when you submit a
form or you get information from
wherever, uh, it all comes
through correctly and it
automatically flows and works.
Uh, we will be going over this
specific automation later on in
the course, right?
Break down exactly what it does
and how it works, but this is to
show you how to import workflows.
Uh, another method you can do just
delete this for now.
When you will often find any
templates online, you can import
them the exact same way,
but you can also just open this
with, uh, your text editor, open
the JSON file that you've
downloaded and you can copy the
whole thing.
Just control a or command a
command C and command V and paste
it in.
And you get the exact same thing.
Uh, if you are using, for
instance, a tool like Claude to
help you build your workflows,
which we'll talk about a bit, a
bit as well, uh, this will do the,
uh, you'll get them, uh,
output as text within Claude.
You can just copy it, paste it and
you're good to go.
Let's briefly look at what if we
want to modify this a bit more
than it currently is.
So we're only ones we should be
modifying are probably the script
writer agents,
depending on how you want your
scripts written.
You can see here how this is, uh,
this is set up that it says your
professional script writer
specializing in this category, uh,
the content strategy, the target
audience.
We give it all the information
from the other AI agents so that
it knows what to do.
But, uh, say we just want to
change a, you can obviously modify
all the system messages and
things in here.
Uh, this one tells it, you know,
how it, uh, acts as a YouTube
script writer,
but we can make these more
detailed depending on, uh, you
know, the particular
format you want your super script,
YouTube script to written in.
Well, let's say we want to send
this, uh, information somewhere
else.
So we don't want this for
instance, to say, be sent to
client in an email.
We can delete this directly, uh,
or we can choose a different email
service.
Let's say we want to use Gmail
instead.
We'll just go to Gmail.
Uh, we would do send a message.
And here you can then set up your
credentials.
As we talked about, you do create
new credential,
sign in with Google and connect up
your account.
Uh, we're not going to do that
right now, but, uh, you'll put
clients email in here.
And then you would, uh, set the
subjects, you know, new, you
described it delivered.
And from the message, we would
send exactly what we have in here.
It'd be the subjects would be
copied from here.
Email format will be taken from
here.
Uh, then you can delete this
again.
So that message is being sent via
Gmail, uh, to the client.
So now let's say that, uh, you're
not using Slack for your
organization.
You are using, uh, they're doing
everything via telegram, right?
So you could do telegram and then
you could do, uh, send a chat.
Let me go find it.
Just move my camera.
Uh, send a text message.
And here you set up your telegram
bot.
Like we showed in one of the
earlier, uh, uh, videos.
And the, the child ID would also
come from that bot chat and the
text.
Then you would just take what we
have in Slack.
So we take this and we go back to
send a text message.
It says expression.
And there we go.
So now we will have a message
saying, you know, script
delivered, uh, the client name,
the category, the email, the dry
folder, script doc, uh, the
follow-up scheduled and delivery
ID.
And then, uh, now when we can
delete the Slack, then when we're
done with that now,
the, uh, once the whole thing is
created, we will send the message
via Gmail to the client.
And then we'll send it to a
telegram message to ourselves to,
uh, say, you know,
that it's a, it's good to go and
that it's ready, ready and done.
So those are just a few ways to
modify some of the existing
workflows that we, that we have.
Uh, again, it's really about
importing the ones that we have.
You're gonna have to do some
modification around mainly
accounts.
Most of them should be pretty much
set up exact as they are.
You should generally follow the
structure that we suggest for the,
uh, business setup.
So like Slack for, uh, client
communication and management, um,
is a pretty key one.
So, uh, hopefully this was helpful
and, uh, we will be just going
through some places
to find some resources for
workflows in the next video.
And then you guys are going to
move on to learning a bit about
poppy AI and then choosing
your agency that you're going to
be creating.
And then we'll get into the
workflows for all of those.
So hopefully, uh, you guys are
getting through the course.
Okay.
So far, any problems as well, feel
free to message me or post in
Slack.
See you guys the next one.
Peace.