What's up guys, Lucas here.
So I'm going to be showing you
what I think is maybe one of the
most annoying parts of
self-hosting, which is that you
will have to, when you're
connecting your Google nodes
and your Google account, there
will be a little bit more setup
compared to if you're doing
it through the N8N cloud.
So let me show you what that looks
like.
So first of all, I already have a
Google account on here, but let's
just create a new one.
Now, when you click create new
credential, you're going to see
this, which looks very,
you know, threatening and kind of
ominous.
So first of all, the actual N8N
documents in this are really
detailed.
So let's open these first and see
what we need to do.
So the first thing we're going to
do is we're going to create a
Google cloud console project.
So you go to console.google.com.
Now I've got this open over here
and I've made a new project to do
that.
You just click the project picker
and click new project.
Once you're in here, let's go back
again and let's see what we're
going to do.
After it's created, we need to
enable the APIs for what we need
to access.
So if you need to access, for
instance, your Google Sheets, your
Google Docs, you have to enable
these in here.
And to do that, this was going to
click navigation menu, APIs and
services, enabled APIs and
services.
And we'll click enable APIs and
services again up here.
So we'll start off with Google
Drive API and we'll click enable.
That'll take a second to do.
And when that's done, we're going
to enable some other ones.
For now, you'll want to go through
and enable, you know, Google Docs
and maybe Google Calendar for any
of your workflows using Google
Calendar.
But for now, I'm just going to go
and enable Google Sheets as well
because that's the node that we're
connecting.
So you can see Google Sheets API
here and we're going to click
enable.
Okay, so that's enabled now.
We're all good.
So let's go back to the docs.
So when that's done, now to
configure our OAuth consent
screen.
Now, this is probably the most
complicated part, but once you do
it once, it's done pretty much
forever unless you're adding a new
Google account.
So we're going to go over to APIs
and services and we're going to go
to OAuth consent screen.
Now, we're going to click get
started.
We're going to give it a name.
So just name it, you know, N8N,
right?
Use a support email.
Just use your own email.
This is my test account.
For audience, let's select
external so we're able to contact
our server with a host N8N.
Again, I'm just going to put my
test account for the contact
information and agree.
Continue.
Click create.
Okay.
So, again, follow the docs.
Let's see what it says next.
So we have the op name, the
audience, email address, all done.
So the next thing we're going to
do is we're going to go select
branding.
And for authorized domains, we're
going to add our domain from our
account.
So, okay.
So on the left, we're going to
click branding and then we're
going to scroll down to where we
have authorized domains.
And here we're just going to put
in railway.app as this is the
domain that is hosting our N8N
instance.
If you're using hostager, it'll
obviously be the, you'll get the
domain name from the domain of
your actual thing here.
So that's what we're going to be
going for.
So railway.app is what we're going
to put in there.
After that, we click save and
that's done.
So next part.
So let's go to credentials.
We're going to create credentials
and create an OAuth client ID.
So if I go back to the console
here and we go to APIs and
services and credentials, we've
got no OAuth2 client IDs.
So we're going to set that up with
the OAuth consent screen.
Create OAuth client.
Application type.
We're going to choose web
application.
Name it.
N8N.
And then authorized redirect URLs.
This is what we got here.
This is our OAuth redirect URL.
So we're going to take that.
We're going to put it in here.
And click create.
So now we've created our OAuth
client ID.
We're going to copy the client ID
here.
We're going to go here and paste
that there.
Then we're going to copy our
client secret.
We're going to paste that there.
Now sign with Google is there, but
we're not going to click that yet.
Instead, we are going to go to
audience.
We're going to publish the app.
The reason we're doing this is so
that our server can contact the
app.
So now this should be good.
Now we go back here.
We're going to click sign in with
Google.
We're going to choose the account
of our Google account that's
registered here.
You'll get this screen.
It has verified the app.
That's fine.
Click advanced and click go to
railway.app.
Give it the access.
Continue.
Done.
Right.
So we're all set up.
So that's how you do it.
Again, very simply
straightforward.
It seems complicated, but all
you're going to do is you're going
to go to create a new project
because you're going to create a
new project.
Then you're going to enable the
APIs you want.
Then you're going to configure the
OAuth consent screen.
Put it in railway.app or
hostendure.com.
Or whatever the URL is for your
accepted URL.
Then you are going to add the
credentials by creating a new
OAuth client ID.
You've got the client ID, the
client secret.
You paste those back in.
You make sure the app is published
so it's available for it to use.
And then you sign in with Google
and you're good to go.
So hopefully that helps you kind
of walk through this.
Now, again, if you're using a
different Google account, you have
to do the same thing again
on the different Google account.
But that is the basics of how it
works and how you connect it all
up.
This should be something that you
only have to do for self-hosting
N8N.
If you're on the N8N cloud, then
you'll automatically be able to
sign in with Google.
You won't have to put in this
client ID and client secret and
stuff.
But that's one of the downsides of
using self-hosting.
But obviously there's a lot of
upsides too as we discussed
before.
So hopefully this is useful.
And any problems with this, feel
free to reach out to me and I will
walk you through it again.
Thanks, guys.
Peace.