What's up guys, Lucas here.
In this video I'm going to be
showing you guys how to connect Go
High Level to N8n.
The reason I'm showing you this is
that unlike some of the other apps
that
we have in N8n that are pretty
easily integrated, Go High Level
requires a little bit more setup.
Now it's not super complicated,
it's very similar to the Google
OAuth video that we've done,
but this is to show you kind of
what it looks like and how to get
it set up.
So I've added just a Go High Level
node here and I've already got my
High Level account added, but
let's create a new credential.
The first thing we're going to do
is
open the docs because I believe
that N8n documentation is very
good and that for any
account you should usually check
out the docs, make sure you're
doing it the right way.
So for this we're going to be
using the OAuth 2 API because I
believe the V1 API is actually
being depreciated.
So like we had with our Google
Docs one, we have to do a client
ID and client secret
and so for that we will need a Go
High Level developer account.
To do that just go to
developers.gohighlevel.com and
click sign up.
This is different to your
regular Go High Level account.
So I'm already signed in, click
sign in.
And again, the document
tells us, go to my apps, create
app.
So we're going to click create app
here on the my apps page,
rename it.
As you can see, we've done a lot
of test accounts on this.
We're going to make sure the app
is set as private.
The target user of the app is sub
account.
Anyone can install the app and the
listing
type is white label.
So we're going to click create
app.
Now there's some basic things
we'll put in here.
You will have to put in an app
logo as we forge with 400 pixels,
uh, minimum.
And then we'll choose a
category, a tagline, and a
company, everything else you can
leave blank.
So I've just got a basic image
page.
I'm going to use here for this
category.
Does it not matter?
Tagline test company client
ascension.
And let's save that.
And you'll see their basic info
that ticked off.
So next we need profile details.
This one, right?
Just test, test, test.
We offer to upload, I believe a
minimum of three images.
I'm just going to use the same
one.
one, two and three, maybe it's
four.
I think it's three images.
Save.
There we go.
And then the next thing you see us
took off that too, uh, support
details,
support email, your email address.
And phone number number.
Save.
Okay.
All those are done.
Pricing details.
You can actually leave blank
because this is a free app.
So it actually automatically sets
it as free.
So that's fine.
But now we need to go to advanced
settings and off.
The first thing you see here is
scopes.
And if we look back again, the
credentials, we need to add these
scopes.
So you can just copy and paste
these.
We copy this and just paste it in
here.
There's locations that read only.
We'll do contacts.read only.
We will do contacts.write.
We'll do opportunities.read only.
Opportunities.write.
I believe it might actually also
need opportunities.update.
No, we're going to use it right.
This covers it.
Uh, and users.write.
And users.read only.
So we paste the dot in there.
Now we get to redirect URL.
We're going to get this from N8N.
If we go back to N8N, here's our
OAuth redirect URL.
Copy that to the clipboard.
Let's paste this in here.
Add.
Then we need to get our client ID
and secret.
So we just click client keys, N8N,
add.
And there's our client ID.
paste.
And our client secret.
Now next we need to scope.
So it's the same scopes we just
added are the ones we're going to
put in here.
And luckily N8N has, uh, done a
very good job of actually making a
copy and paste here.
We just copy this.
And we can paste it in as the
scopes.
And then we click connect my
account.
Oh, actually one thing I forgot.
So we're going to please log in
the serum.
The reason for the, we're going to
get that.
Please log in the serum is this.
The authorization URL says white
label.
Set this as standard.
Once you set it as standard,
you're good to go.
So now when you click, connect my
account.
Give it a second to load.
There we go.
There's our app.
We're going to click next.
We're going to choose the sub
account.
Okay.
Uh, there's not much client value.
Let's see why that is.
So did we not copy this correctly?
Maybe it's copy that again.
Let's go back here.
Oh, I think we saved.
So, uh, we've added this.
Yeah, that's right.
So let's click save.
There we go.
Now we should be good.
So now if we try again,
there we go.
We are connected.
So again, make sure you do that.
Make sure you save down here at
the bottom, right?
After you add your redirect URL
and create your client key, I
added the redirect URL, but then I
created the client key and I
forgot to click save.
So just make sure you click save
and now the account is connected.
So, uh, I don't need this.
So I'm going to delete this, but,
uh, that is how you connect, go
high level.
And that'll be important for a lot
of other automations we do later
on.
So make sure you got that set up
and, uh, any questions, feel free
to hit me up and I will see you in
the next one.
Peace.