What's up, guys?
Lucas here.
So today I'm going to be showing
you an existing workflow
we have.
I'm a great believer in general of
showing things practically and,
you know,
breaking down the exact use case
for them rather than just learning
the theory behind
things.
So for this, I'm going to be
showing you a workflow that takes
a message from Telegram
and writes a LinkedIn post based
around the idea you've sent to
Telegram and then sends
it to LinkedIn and lets you know
about it.
So we're going to start off by
breaking down
the workflow and then showing you
how to get it working.
As you can see, there's a few
notes here that are red, and I'm
going to explain why that is what
we do to fix them.
So let's start off by just an
overview of what the workflow does
in total.
So the trigger
referred is a Telegram message.
So sending a message to a Telegram
bot starts the whole
flow.
Then this LinkedIn post agent will
write the post.
This agent will write the title
for
the post.
Then this tool will create a nice
Google doc.
It will move it to the correct
folder.
And then it will send you a
message to Telegram asking you if
you want to approve the post for
posting.
If you say yes, it will prepare it
for the LinkedIn content queue.
If not, it just marks
the automation as done.
Then it'll create the post and
then it will send you a text
message telling
you that it's been posted.
So let's start off by looking at
the Telegram trigger.
Zoom in here.
Double click.
You can see here we've got no
credentials for Telegram.
So we're going to create a new
credential.
And as always, you see we've got
access token
in base URL, but we're going to do
what I always suggest, which is
reading the docs that will
give you the step-by-step
walkthrough of how to set this up.
So to generate our access token,
we start a chat with the bot
father and then enter new bot.
So let's click bot father.
It's
going to open my Telegram here.
We're going to click start.
From here, we're going to do new
bot.
What are we going to call it?
Please choose a name.
So let's just say CA N8N, right?
Username was NN bot.
So CA N8N bot done.
So now we've got our access token.
So that was super simple,
super easy.
Let's copy this.
Let's go back here and paste this
in as the access token and save
it.
Done, right?
So now when we send a message to
that bot, which is now in our, or
should be in our Telegram,
we click this and click start,
this is now our bot where we will
send our messages, right?
So next thing,
I'm going to break down just what
this LinkedIn post agent does.
So if we go here, you can see it's
set as a tools
agent, and we have a prompt and a
system message, a user message, a
system message.
If you set it to expression,
set it to expression, then click
this little button here, we're
going to be able to see what the
whole
thing looks like.
So let's change that to message.
Let's read what this says goal.
Take the idea
provided and turn it into a
LinkedIn post.
Remember that I am Lucas Sennett
and I'm writing the first
person.
Use the general idea, topic,
combine your system of knowledge,
create a high performing LinkedIn
post.
Format the output according to the
LinkedIn frameworks provided,
including a stronghold,
clear structure, and engaging
conclusion.
It's supposed to be purely
text-based.
Write the copy in the voice and
character that myself, Lucas
Sennett would have when writing
content.
It sounds real, naturalized
without using a real to human,
human conversation,
as the owner of a marketing
agency.
In response to include any
formatting or odd characters,
be sure to only reply to the post
copy, don't include any other
texts or explanations.
Like here
we have message.
And the reason for that is that we
are going to send a message to the
Telegram bot.
And then we're going to, from over
here, you'll see the Telegram
trigger.
We're going to get the
message here and paste it in
there.
So it'll send the message to our
agent.
Let's look at the system
message first.
Tells it that you are a persuasive
LinkedIn content strategist.
Use the following
internal reference documents.
Then we have information about me.
This is just my background
and some information.
Then we have a reference document
on writing high converting
LinkedIn posts
and how to do that.
It's just information on what
makes a good post.
It's got some examples,
some frameworks overall, things
like that.
Also, we're going to add in
reference document one, you can
send it.
There we go.
And this is connected to the open
writer chat module, which is
connected to cloud 3.7 sonnet.
Then this one just writes the
title.
So turn the LinkedIn post below
into a 3-7 word title.
We can
insert as the title of the
document that has this LinkedIn
post inside of it.
Don't respond to anything
other than the completed 3-7 word
title.
That 3-7 word title should be the
only thing in your response.
The LinkedIn post, and then we're
going to have the LinkedIn post in
there.
And that is connected to the
DeepSeq R1 free model.
Again, because this is a very
lightweight,
small task, isn't super important.
So we're going to use DeepSeq,
which is a good free AI.
And then over here, we've got the
HTTP request.
And what this is doing is actually
sending our,
the text we output is what we call
markdown, which is, you probably
have seen it's like hashtags and
stuff and weird formatting.
So we're going to send that to
this service called md2doc.n8n.
And what this
does is it creates a very nice
Google Doc in our Google Doc
account.
So you can see there,
my Google Docs account is
connected, and it'll make the nice
post blah, blah, blah.
Then it's going to
move the file to the correct
folder called LinkedIn posts.
Then it will send us a message and
wait for
the response.
If you want to approve of the
posting, if that's true, you can
see here, it says,
here's the poster that's posted,
I'll have a link there, the child
ID we're going to get from our
trigger.
And it's also approval options.
So approve, and then approval,
approve and disprove.
So approve or
decline, right?
Very simple.
And then depending on that, this
will say, if the approved is true
or false,
will determine if it gets sent for
preparation.
Here, all this is going to do is
just give us some
of the it's going to just format
like the content type, text, the
doc URL, the credit day, just
giving
us some overall information that
we need.
And then it's going to create the
post and we have to connect
our LinkedIn as well.
So finally, it'll send a text
message back to us with saying
that it's been posted
and it's good to go.
All right.
So let us start with sending a
message to the Telegram bot.
So
a LinkedIn post about the power of
AI for agency owners, reducing
overhead and staff hiring costs
while
increasing efficiency.
So we're going to send that.
Now, when this is active and on,
this here currently
is inactive, that will run
automatically.
But for now, we can do is we can
just use this as a test
event.
So you can see here, it's got my
most recent message, right?
And we're doing this.
The reason
we have it's activated is we don't
want the whole thing to run yet.
We want to test this step by step.
And if you update a few things.
So as mentioned here, we need to
get the message in the user
prompt.
So we're going to drag text here,
as you can see there, that's what
the message is going to be.
Right.
So that we can now run this.
So like a second to do or so.
Good, we're done.
So now here, we've got a post.
And we have to tell this to, yeah,
it's going to write the title now
using Deep Seek.
There we go.
So we've got a nice title.
And finally, we have our Google
Docs creator here.
So what this is doing is it's
going to take the output from the
LinkedIn post agent, the text
output
from the LinkedIn post agent, and
that is going to be the contents
of the doc.
Then for the name,
we're going to get the output of
the LinkedIn post title doc.
So when we execute that now,
it's going to create our Google
doc.
I can actually open this and show
you guys.
There you go.
Right.
So that's our posts.
Okay.
So we're all good with that.
Let's go back to the
C A N N N.
So now we have it correctly set
up.
Then we're going to move it to the
correct folder.
So we're going to do is this is
the going to move the file.
So we're doing Google drive
account
resource file operation, move by
ID.
And we're getting the ID from our
HTTP request here from the
list, my drive.
Now for here, I need to refresh
this because this is from an old
automation,
we're going to move this to a new
folder here.
So we're going to move to the
client extension AI
folder for now.
Execute step.
So now it's moved appropriately.
Right.
So now we need to send a
message and get the response.
So let's look and see where our
chat ID is.
So chat ID is over here.
This is coming from our telegram
trigger.
So what this means is it's going
to send this message back
to our telegram.
So chat ID goes in there and it's
going to send, we want to say,
here's a link to
post you'd like to post it.
So how do we show the LinkedIn
post?
We want to send a link to the
Google
doc.
So we go to the HTTP request,
which is where it was creating our
Google doc.
You get the URL.
So now we go, here's the post.
You'd like to approve it.
And the link to the Google doc.
And then we get the approve and
disapprove.
So we execute this step now.
I've got it here, right?
So I've got a link.
Here's the post like to post it,
got a link to it.
And let's say let's approve it.
Right.
So when I do that, it's going to
open a webhook.
Got it.
Thanks.
Let's go back here.
Proved equals true.
So is the LinkedIn post approved?
Yes.
Data approved,
right.
So without scanning from is the
last step, the semester, we should
wait for response.
The data is approved is true.
So based on data approved is equal
to true.
Then it moves forward
with the automation.
If that was set to false, it would
stop the automation there.
If we go here,
execute the step here is we've got
the content texts, the text of our
thing.
We got the document URL,
schedule time for it, status, and
the created date.
So our content is prepared.
So what we're going to do now
is we're going to create the post.
As you can see, it's read it out.
So we have to get our credentials
connected.
So to do that, we're going to
create a new LinkedIn credential
and turn off the organization
support.
We're going to click connect my
account.
We're going to click allow, right?
As you can see,
connection successful.
It'll close in five seconds.
We'll close that ourselves.
Accounts connected.
Great.
So we had a little bit of a hiccup
there to refresh the list, but you
can see here,
we've got LinkedIn account
resource post operation, create
post as person.
And then person is obviously
me and the text of the posts we're
going to get from here.
You can see, that's what it's
going to look
like in a category, none.
So we're going to execute the
step.
It's going to make the posts.
I go to
LinkedIn and go to my account.
Here it is.
Now let's take a quick look at the
URL for this.
As you can see,
here's the URL we're looking at.
LinkedIn.com/feed/urlactivity.
Now we're going to want to copy
this,
right?
For the next part of our
automation.
So that's done successfully.
If I want to send a text message,
we're going to get the chat ID
from our telegram trigger.
Again, we're just going to drag
over
ID from the chat.
Post created successfully, find it
here.
And we're going to paste in this,
followed by this.
We're just going to go right after
it.
So this will now give us the
proper
URL that we need.
So if I execute the step now, we
go back to telegram.
Here it is.
Here's the link.
There's the post.
So there we go.
Just delete this because I don't
really want to post
this right now.
That's how that automation works.
And hopefully that'll explain a
bit about you to
you about how to set up these,
these, you know, authentication on
these, how these different agents
work.
How, what this node is doing here
is creating our nice Google docs
and how to make approval
workflows.
That will, you know, you can
approve things we post or not
depending on the message sent to
you
by whatever platform you like.
You can also do this in Slack.
I do this in Slack primarily,
because that's where most of my
work goes on.
So instead of using telegram as
the main, you know,
conversation point or approval
point, I use Slack.
But that's basically ideas behind
some of the kind of
key things you're going to be
doing as part of this, mainly a
lot of what you're going to be
doing,
because we're giving you these
workflows is going to be
customizing them and
authenticating your own
accounts.
So that's one of the most
important things that you can
learn is just how to quickly
authenticate things.
And again, I really think the best
way to do that is always going to
be just
create a new credential and read
the docs, the NADN documents for
every document for every single
account.
And they're step by step walking
through them.
Very, very easy to set up.
And again,
we're gonna be talking a bit more
about AI agents.
But as you can see here, it's
really just a user
message and a system message.
The system message tells the agent
all the information it needs to
know before it receives your user
message.
So it needs to know that it is a,
you know, LinkedIn
content strategist, it needs some
information on headwrite LinkedIn
posts, some information about me
or you specifically to personalize
it to you.
And it's overall provided the
structure it needs to create
the best output possible.
And then your user message is
going to give it the instructions
on what you
want it to do with the information
you're giving it.
So we're telling it to create a
LinkedIn post,
we're going to do some information
about the formatting, some
warnings, and then giving it
the actual text of our, you know,
and what we want the post to be
about.
I'll provide a link in the
description to the information on
this particular tool, because this
is a custom tool someone made
that I love.
Because just sending you can, of
course, to send something to be
create a Google Drive
document directly.
But often you get that annoying
markdown formatting, this creates
really nicely
forming a Google Docs for you.
So you don't have to do that.
So I think that's a very useful
tool to
have.
And yeah, you know, I think that
hopefully kind of cleared up and
maybe some questions you had
about kind of editing these
workflows.
In the next video, I'm going to
take one of the existing workflows
you guys are going to get access
to you, or you guys are going to
get access to break it down,
and show you how to edit it for
yourself.
And make sure that it's all set up
for you to use.
So I hope this was helpful and I
will see you in the next one.
Peace.