What's up guys, Lucas here, I'm
the head of AI at Client Ascension
and I'm going to be
one of the main people you're
going to be seeing throughout this
course.
This video we're just going to go
over the basics of the main
automation tool you'll
be using to help roll in your AI
assisted agency.
And that automation tool is called
N8N.
So what is N8N?
It's an open source workflow
automation tool designed with
flexibility and extensibility
at its core.
Some of the features has
connections to 200+ apps and
services with custom logic, a
choice
between self-hosting or cloud
deployment.
There's a video later on where I
show you how to self-host this for
cheap and gives you complete
control over data and environment
as well as allowing you to execute
JavaScript code inside
of workflows.
That's one of the reasons that we
chose this for your main
automation tool.
It's extremely flexible and as
you'll see as well, it has a ton
of template ability allowing
us to give you templates you can
use to run your agency.
So the core capabilities are a
visual workflow builder.
I'm going to show you what that
looks like in one moment.
Essentially, it's a visual
interface that allows you to kind
of, you know, see exactly
how the automation works and make
edits very quickly and easily.
JavaScript integration, as
previously mentioned, you can run
JavaScript directly inside of
N8N.
Flexible triggers, multiple
different types of triggers to
actually kick off your workflow,
whether that's based on a
schedule, based on an action in
another app, a message response,
something like that.
And extensive integrations
connects to over 200 plus.
As 200 plus people know, it
connects to pretty much any API or
app you can think of.
So I'm just going to show you
briefly what N8N looks like.
And this is using one of the N8N
workflow templates that's actually
provided inside of the app.
I didn't create this.
This is created by N8N as an
example of an AI agent.
This is a voice assistant agent.
Essentially, it allows you to send
a voice message to Telegram, to a
Telegram bot.
And then it will, based on your
message, do things such as respond
to you, like if you're talking
to ChatGPT or it can even schedule
your or get events for your
calendar and tell you what a
couple
of events are.
So I'll just break down briefly
how this is and what this does.
As I mentioned before, a trigger
is the first thing.
The trigger in this workflow is a
message to the Telegram bot.
That's what starts the workflow
working.
The next thing we have here is an
if node.
So this checks if the message is
audio or not.
If it is audio, it then gets the
audio file from Telegram.
Then it transcribes it using
ChatGPT and then sends it to your
assistant agent.
If it's not audio, it seems it
just sets the field.
So it takes the text and just adds
it here as this little text node
and then sends it
to the assistant agent.
The assistant agent, you've
probably heard the word AI agents
thrown around a lot.
An AI agent essentially is just an
AI that has been given very
specific rules and access
to tools.
So tools are what really kind of
separate AI agents.
When they have access to things
like your Google Calendar, then
they can, AI agent can perform
tasks with your Google Calendar.
This one, if we double click into
this, you can see that it was, the
user message is coming
from Telegram.
And then the system message tells
it how it should act.
So it gives it a bunch of rules on
how it should act.
You're a helpful personal AI
assistant.
In the case, you use it through
Telegram.
You handle all text and voice
messages.
And you have access to user's
email and calendar to provide
comprehensive assistance.
And then it just gives it kind of
a bunch of different kind of rules
it should follow
in general.
So tool usage guidelines, how the
email tool should work, how the
calendar tool should
work.
Gives it context to awareness.
Remember the current date and time
today is now and now.
User information provide relevant
time responses.
Reference today, tomorrow, this
week appropriately.
So an example of a kind of a
query.
User, any important emails today?
Let me check your recent emails.
Users get emails tool.
Same for the calendar.
So this is just kind of an example
of having it.
And then at the end, it then
replies back in Telegram with the
response from the AI agent.
So this is just showing you kind
of what the NN kind of workflow
builder looks like.
Adding more nodes is simply the
plus button here.
And then you can either choose
from different AI tools.
Or if you look at actions in the
app, we can see the different
softwares that NN has pre-built
nodes for.
We'll be going into a lot more
detail on how to use NN later on.
But for now, we're just going to
go over what is NN.
This is NN.
So again, we look here at the
advantage of using NN versus other
platforms.
No vendor lock-in.
So NN is an open source tool,
meaning that, you know, it's
harder for them to remove access
to certain things.
You've always got kind of control
over what version of NN you're
using.
Cost and privacy control.
Self-hosting significantly reduces
the cost for a, you know,
someone's going to be using
a lot of executions or workflows.
There's a very active community
behind NN and there's a ton of
existing workflows and
templates out there pre-built.
Now, you're going to get access to
the ones you need inside this
course, but there are
a ton of websites that, you know,
will give you examples of other
workflows you can import.
And I have a video later on going
over that.
And yeah, very open about its
billing and the costs and real
hidden fees.
You're not going to, you know,
really run a workflow and suddenly
get a massive bill out
knowing that, you know, you got a
ton of executions.
It's pretty straightforward.
So you have probably used some
other automation tools before.
Most likely you've used Zapier.
I think that pretty much everyone
that runs some sort of agencies at
some point set up a Zap.
Zapier has a massive ecosystem.
Definitely, I think of all of
these, it has the most app
integrations.
I've come across softwares that
have no API access, but they do
have Zapier integrations.
It's very user-friendly setup.
You don't really need much
technical knowledge.
It's a proprietary platform with
cloud-only deployment, and it has
limited advanced logic
capabilities.
So as you can see here, the main
challenges that agencies face are
pricing scales rapidly
with task volume.
It could cost thousands monthly
for busy agencies, but it's very
simple and easy to use.
Definitely very good for kind of
one to three-step kind of, you
know, simple, straightforward
things, you know, like, I don't
know, when a calendar event, when
a calendar event is booked,
send a message in Slack, you know,
things like that are very simple.
You can do that just as easily in
N8N, but for a lot of people, they
find Zapier kind
of easier to follow.
Then the other one you've probably
seen is Make.com.
Now, Make.com is definitely more
advanced than Zapier and can do a
lot of the things that
you can do in N8N, but I find N8N
to be an easier kind of tool to
get started with.
But Make.com, as you can see here,
positions itself as a middle
ground between simplicity
and power.
It does have a lot of app
integrations, 2,500 plus app
integrations.
It is definitely more advanced
routing capabilities than Zapier.
It does have an kind of AI
integration, but I find that N8N's
AI agents tend to be a bit
easier to set up and easier to
understand and also Make is still
cloud-based with no self-hosting
option.
They do have a free plan, but that
has execution limitations.
So if you do want to kind of learn
a bit about Make.com, definitely
very easy to get started.
But N8N's kind of customization
capabilities and the ease of use I
find about N8N still beats
out Make.com.
You can see here a little graph
head-to-head, N8N versus Zapier
and Make.com.
High openness, low integrations,
open and customizable is N8N.
This is where it really excels.
But Zapier has got high
integrations and high openness.
Wide integrations and easy, Zapier
for sure.
Balance features, Make.com is
middle ground between low
integrations and low openness.
And then cost-effective and data
control, high integrations, low
openness is N8N again.
N8N is really just the easiest one
to get started with, I think, and
is the most powerful when
you're using it in the long run.
You will find as you are going
through these workflows and you're
using the templates we
build and you're probably starting
to maybe create some of your own
that you start to think
in N8N nodes.
It becomes very easy to see kind
of how you will connect the next
thing or, you know, maybe
you use something like ClickUp or
instead of say Slack and you can
figure, it's very easy
to see how you would, you know,
instead switch out a Slack node
for a ClickUp node and what
that looks like, and it's like
kind of has branching kind of
capabilities, I find.
So again, why you should choose
N8N, basically the workflow
templates, I think, are the
biggest
one because every workflow
template that you're going to use
in this course is an N8N template.
It's very easy to customize
workflows to match exact client
requirements rather than forcing
clients out of platform
limitations.
Cost control at scale, you can
avoid escalating costs with
limited self-hosting executions.
You can connect the legacy or
niche tools via their API using
custom nodes.
Very simple to do.
I go over that again in a later
video.
You maintain full ownership and
security of sensitive client data.
And it is, N8N is constantly
evolving and being updated and
there's new nodes, community
nodes,
even nodes created by people
outside of the N8N development
team that are making a kind of,
a real powerhouse when it comes to
automation nowadays, and I think
it's going to be one
of the leading automation tools
going forward.
So that's just a quick rundown of
what N8N is.
I hope this made it a bit simple
for you to understand.
Again, I think the best way to
describe it is by just looking at
the builder like this.
You can see you're just connecting
and stringing together different
actions and different rules.
It's very simple.
Everything comes down to triggers,
if-thens, and AI agents, really.
So hopefully this has made it a
bit clearer for you.
And if you keep going through this
course, you will see me going into
far more detail on what
N8N can do, how it works, how to
set it up, and how to customize
your workflows.
So check out the rest of the
videos and I will see you in the
next one.
Peace.