What's up guys, Lucas here.
So for this final section of the
course, we're going to look over
is where to find other N8N
templates.
Now you do not need these, we've
given you every
template you are going to need as
part of this course.
But maybe
you just really like N8N, you want
to start making some of your
own workflows, or you want to see
what other ones are out there
that people are making.
Now, the I'm going to show you the
number one site that I use for
this three, there's a few sites
that have them.
But by far, I think this is the
best collection
so far.
I'll be linking this in the
description.
This is N8N
workflows.xyz.
And if you come on here, this is
what you'll
see, there's a light mode and dark
mode, I'm in dark mode right
now.
But as you can see, there's nearly
4000 workflows available.
And they range across a number of
categories.
So marketing is a
pretty common one that you know,
most of us in here will
probably like to try out.
And you'll notice here a few
things
about the cards.
So first of all, on the bottom
right here tells
you the level of difficulty for
customizing or using this.
And
then up here tells you was paid or
free.
The vast, vast majority as
you can see here are free 3,321 of
all the templates are free only
are paid.
But let's take a look at one of
them here and show you how
you're going to import this into
N8N.
So we'll just pick a random one.
3d product video generator from 2d
image for ecommerce stores.
So you can see it's an advanced
one.
We click this, we'll get an
explanation of the we're going to
preview here of the workflow
itself and an explanation of how
it works and what it does.
So this moment that's a load,
we'll take a look.
Okay, can connect.
So let's go down.
So you can see three, what it does
work for
or read the work for all this, all
this generation of three part of
the 2d product image sort of by a
form, a whole breakdown of exactly
what every single thing does.
So let's scroll up and see how we
get
this into N8N.
It's very simple.
Over here on the right, you're
going to see download workflow.
If we click this, it's going to
download.
So now it should be saved.
There it is saved in my downloads.
And now if we go back to our N8N
and we do a new workflow, write it
in personal, give it a second
to load.
Then we click the three dots here,
import from file, go to our
downloads.
It's the first one
here.
Open.
There we go.
So that's it here.
And as you can see, as I mentioned
before, and if you watch
the other modules, we've got a
number of red nodes that we will
have to update or change.
There's a number of
things that I'm sure enough to
connect up, just connect my Google
Drive account, my Google Sheets
account, all those sorts of
things.
And then I now have the workflow
ready to go.
So if you look through
this site, there's a ton of
different workflows for different
use cases.
I'm sure there's pretty much
one that for you know, whatever
you can think of before you got in
here, a lot of useful new ones pop
up, you can sort of the complexity
as well, you see the most popular
ones are for the most popular.
An AI agent
chat.
It's pretty basic one building
your first WhatsApp chatbot,
multi-profit social media content
creation.
We have our own version of this
for you guys here on the course.
But there's a number in
here that you can try out and you
guys use it to see how N8M works.
Maybe you can find some useful
ones you can use in your day to
day operations.
But overall, I think the best use
case for this is just,
you know, finding new automations,
messing around with them, learning
how to use N8M, learning how to
customize existing templates,
which you know, we have taught you
as we do here in this course.
So hopefully, it'll be relatively
easy for you to get through.
But we still do suggest you use
the
templates that we provide here in
the course.
But if you do want some
information on any you find here,
feel free to contact me and I'll
talk you through it.
But yeah, that's the basics.
The website again
is N8M workflows to XYZ.
The official N8M website does also
have a number of workflows on
N8M.io.
And if we go to product and to
templates,
you will find a ton in here as
well.
There's almost the exact same as
in N8M workflows XYZ.
I'm pretty sure that these are
mirroring each other.
But you can see here, these are
also sorted by
different categories.
And there's different templates
for different areas.
So you can see
like content creation, YouTube
summaries, market research, social
media, and it works the exact
same way.
You'll click in, and you'll click
use for free.
And you can either import it
directly into
your workspace if you're hosting
on N8M cloud, or you can copy the
template to your clipboard.
If it's
copied to your clipboard, you just
click it, it's copied, then you go
back to your workflow,
just delete these.
And then command V.
And there we go.
It's in there.
So that's the basic idea behind
it.
Useful tool, useful place to find
new workflows to mess around with.
And hopefully you will be able
to learn a bit more about using
N8M through that.
And any questions, you can always
contact me.
Thanks,
Thanks, guys, and I will see you
in the next one.
Peace.